<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Instant Pot Butter Chicken Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/instant-pot-butter-chicken</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 lb ; boneless, skinless chicken thighs ; (910 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 teaspoons ; kosher salt, salt, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">freshly ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; onion, finely chopped ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; ginger, 2 inch () peeled and minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 teaspoons ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ½ tablespoons ; garam masala </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 tablespoon ; curry powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">28 oz ; crushed tomato ; (795 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 cup ; plain whole milk yogurt ; (245 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">basmati rice, cooked, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">naan bread, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">fresh cilantro, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Indian</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
    <category num="2">Date Night</category>
    <category num="3">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/130209/hls24_1555524592.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/130209/landscape_720/1555524592</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">On a cutting board, pat the chicken thighs dry with paper towels. Season chicken on both sides with 1 teaspoon salt and black pepper to taste. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">Set Instant Pot to high on the sauté setting. Melt the butter in the pot, then add the onion and sauté until it begins to soften, 4 minutes. Add the garlic and ginger and cook until softened, stirring occasionally, 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the remaining 3 teaspoons salt, the paprika, garam masala, and curry powder. Cook, stirring, until the spices are aromatic and toasted, about 1 minute. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the crushed tomatoes and the chicken and stir to combine. Place the lid on the Instant Pot and seal to close. Set the machine to pressure cook on high and cook for 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Turn off the Instant Pot and let it vent naturally for 10 minutes. Then turn the quick release seal to “vent” and allow any remaining steam to vent. </step>
    <step num="5">Remove the lid. Using tongs, transfer the chicken to a cutting board. When cool enough to handle, cut into bite-sized pieces. </step>
    <step num="6">Set the machine to high on the sauté setting. Cook sauce until it is reduced by half, 10–15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">. Add the yogurt to the sauce and stir to combine. Return the chicken to the pot and stir to coat completely with sauce. </step>
    <step num="8">Serve chicken with basmati rice and naan and garnish with cilantro. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">On a cutting board, pat the chicken thighs dry with paper towels. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Season chicken on both sides with 1 teaspoon salt and black pepper to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set Instant Pot to high on the sauté setting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Melt the butter in the pot, then add the onion and sauté until it begins to soften, 4 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the garlic and ginger and cook until softened, stirring occasionally, 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the remaining 3 teaspoons salt, the paprika, garam masala, and curry powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cook, stirring, until the spices are aromatic and toasted, about 1 minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the crushed tomatoes and the chicken and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Place the lid on the Instant Pot and seal to close. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Set the machine to pressure cook on high and cook for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Turn off the Instant Pot and let it vent naturally for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Then turn the quick release seal to “vent” and allow any remaining steam to vent. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove the lid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Using tongs, transfer the chicken to a cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">When cool enough to handle, cut into bite-sized pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Set the machine to high on the sauté setting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cook sauce until it is reduced by half, 10–15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the yogurt to the sauce and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Return the chicken to the pot and stir to coat completely with sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Serve chicken with basmati rice and naan and garnish with cilantro. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>