<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Provided by SOCIAL TEAM on FINAL e-mail</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/easy-cast-iron-cheesy-asparagus-quiche</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">olive oil, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 bunch ; asparagus, trimmed and chopped into 3-in (7 cm) pieces </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 teaspoons ; kosher salt, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 teaspoons ; freshly ground black pepper, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">8 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¾ cup ; grated parmesan cheese, divided ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ cup ; cold water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">6 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">⅓ cup ; sour cream ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">⅔ cup ; half &amp; half ; (160 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 ½ cups ; shredded cheddar cheese ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 cup ; cherry tomato, halved ; (200 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="1">Brunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/130828/hls24_1556146539.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/130828/landscape_720/1556146539</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Heat a drizzle of olive oil in a 10-inch (25 cm) cast-iron skillet over medium heat. Add the asparagus, ½ teaspoon salt, and ½ teaspoon pepper. Sauté for 5-6 minutes, until the asparagus is bright green but still firm. Turn off the heat. Transfer the asparagus to a bowl and set aside to cool. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the butter to the hot skillet and let it melt from the residual heat. Allow the pan to cool with the butter in it. </step>
    <step num="3">Once the cast iron is mostly cooled (warm to the touch is okay), add the flour, ½ teaspoon salt, 1 teaspoon black pepper, baking powder, and ½ cup Parmesan cheese, stirring with a spatula until the texture is sandy. Add the water and stir to combine. Using your hands, press the dough evenly over the bottom and about 2 inches (5 cm) up the sides of the pan. Use a fork to crimp the edges of the dough against the side of the pan. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the eggs and sour cream to a medium bowl. Whisk to combine. Add the half-and-half, remaining teaspoon of salt, and remaining ½ teaspoon pepper and whisk until fully incorporated. </step>
    <step num="5">Scatter the cheddar cheese evenly over the crust. Arrange the asparagus over the cheese. Sprinkle the remaining ¼ cup (25 G) Parmesan evenly over the asparagus. Slowly pour the egg mixture into the skillet. Do not overfill. Top with the cherry tomatoes, cut sides up. </step>
    <step num="6">Carefully transfer the quiche to the oven and bake for 45-50 minutes, until the center is set and the edges are golden. Let cool for at least 30 minutes before serving. </step>
    <step num="7">Serve the quiche straight from the pan. Note: Use a spatula to cut, instead of a knife, so as not to scratch your pan. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Heat a drizzle of olive oil in a 10-inch (25 cm) cast-iron skillet over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the asparagus, ½ teaspoon salt, and ½ teaspoon pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Sauté for 5-6 minutes, until the asparagus is bright green but still firm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Turn off the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Transfer the asparagus to a bowl and set aside to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the butter to the hot skillet and let it melt from the residual heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Allow the pan to cool with the butter in it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Once the cast iron is mostly cooled (warm to the touch is okay), add the flour, ½ teaspoon salt, 1 teaspoon black pepper, baking powder, and ½ cup Parmesan cheese, stirring with a spatula until the texture is sandy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the water and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Using your hands, press the dough evenly over the bottom and about 2 inches (5 cm) up the sides of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Use a fork to crimp the edges of the dough against the side of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the eggs and sour cream to a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the half-and-half, remaining teaspoon of salt, and remaining ½ teaspoon pepper and whisk until fully incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Scatter the cheddar cheese evenly over the crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Arrange the asparagus over the cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Sprinkle the remaining ¼ cup (25 G) Parmesan evenly over the asparagus. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Slowly pour the egg mixture into the skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Do not overfill. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Top with the cherry tomatoes, cut sides up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Carefully transfer the quiche to the oven and bake for 45-50 minutes, until the center is set and the edges are golden. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Let cool for at least 30 minutes before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Serve the quiche straight from the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Note: Use a spatula to cut, instead of a knife, so as not to scratch your pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>