<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Bibimbap By Chef Esther Choi Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/bibimbap-by-chef-esther-choi</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">8 oz ; ribeye steak, thinly sliced ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ; green onions, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ ; red chili, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 clove ; garlic, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; soy sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; sesame oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 teaspoons ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; mirin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 cup ; fresh spinach ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; sesame oil, divided, plus 1 tablespoon ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">3 tablespoons ; salt, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¼ cup ; bean sprout ; (25 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ ; yellow squash, julienned </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ ; zucchini, julienned </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">¼ cup ; daikon radish, julienned ; (35 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">¼ cup ; water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">½ ; carrot, julienned </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">¼ cup ; dried shiitake mushroom ; (20 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">½ cup ; hot water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">2 cloves ; garlic, minced, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">1 tablespoon ; gochugaru </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">2 teaspoons ; sesame seeds, plus more for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">1 ; cucumber, halved lengthwise, seeded and sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">4 cups ; purple rice, cooked - equal portions of white, black, and brown rice ; (920 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">4 ; fried eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="25">2 ; green onions, cut into 2-inch (5-cm) pieces, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="26">1 tablespoon ; nori seaweed, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="27">¼ cup ; kimchi, thinly sliced, for serving ; (20 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="28">¼ cup ; gochujang, for serving ; (20 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Korean</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Healthy</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Date Night</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97730/hls24_1528404985.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97730/landscape_720/1528404985</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">To marinate the meat, add the ribeye to a medium bowl with the green onion, red chili, garlic, soy sauce, sesame oil, sugar, and mirin. Mix until the meat is well-coated. Marinate in the refrigerator for at least 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Bring a large pot of water to boil over high heat and season generously with salt. Blanch the spinach for 30 seconds, transfer to an ice bath to shock, and drain. Transfer to a small bowl and season with 1 teaspoon of sesame oil, a pinch of salt, and pepper. </step>
    <step num="2">Blanch the bean sprouts for 1-2 minutes, then shock the ice bath. Strain and pat dry with a paper towel. Transfer to a small bowl and season with 1 teaspoon sesame oil, a pinch of salt, and pepper. </step>
    <step num="3">In a medium skillet over medium heat, add 1 tablespoon of sesame oil, the yellow squash, and 1 teaspoon salt. Sauté for 2-3 minutes, until the squash is softened. Set the squash aside in a small bowl. </step>
    <step num="4">In the same skillet over medium heat, add another tablespoon of sesame oil, the zucchini, and 1 teaspoon of salt. Sauté for 2-3 minutes, until the zucchini is softened. Set aside in a small bowl. </step>
    <step num="5">Add another tablespoon of sesame oil, the daikon, and a teaspoon of salt to the same skillet and for sauté over medium heat for 30 seconds. Add ¼ cup (60 ml) of water and cook until liquid has evaporated, 4-5 minutes. Set aside in a small bowl. </step>
    <step num="6">In the same skillet over medium heat, add another tablespoons of sesame oil, the carrots, and 1 teaspoon of salt and sauté for 2-3 minutes, until softened. Set aside in a small bowl. </step>
    <step num="7">In a small bowl, pour the hot water over the dried mushrooms and soak for 5 minutes, or until the mushrooms have softened. Wring out excess moisture from the mushrooms and thinly slice. </step>
    <step num="8">In the skillet over medium heat, add 1 tablespoon of sesame oil and sauté 1 minced clove of garlic for 30 seconds, or until fragrant. Add the mushrooms and sauté for 2-3 minutes more. Set aside in a small bowl. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the remaining ¼ cup (60 ml) of sesame oil to a liquid measuring cup or small bowl. Add 2 teaspoons of salt, the remaining minced garlic clove, the gochugaru, and sesame seeds and whisk to combine. </step>
    <step num="10">Pour a bit of the seasoned oil over the sautéed beans sprouts, sliced cucumber, and blanched spinach, tossing with your fingers to coat. </step>
    <step num="11">Heat a large skillet over high heat, then add the ribeye and marinade and stir-fry for 2-3 minutes, until the beef is browned. Remove the pan from the heat. </step>
    <step num="12">Assemble the bibimbap: Place the rice in the center of a shallow dish. Add the cucumber, mushrooms, zucchini, carrots, daikon, spinach, bean sprouts, and yellow squash around the sides of the rice. Scoop the beef into the center of the rice and top with the fried egg. Garnish with thinly sliced green onions and nori and a sprinkle of sesame seeds. </step>
    <step num="13">Serve the bibimbap with kimchi and gochujang. To eat, mix everything together. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">To marinate the meat, add the ribeye to a medium bowl with the green onion, red chili, garlic, soy sauce, sesame oil, sugar, and mirin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Mix until the meat is well-coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Marinate in the refrigerator for at least 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Bring a large pot of water to boil over high heat and season generously with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Blanch the spinach for 30 seconds, transfer to an ice bath to shock, and drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Transfer to a small bowl and season with 1 teaspoon of sesame oil, a pinch of salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Blanch the bean sprouts for 1-2 minutes, then shock the ice bath. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Strain and pat dry with a paper towel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Transfer to a small bowl and season with 1 teaspoon sesame oil, a pinch of salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a medium skillet over medium heat, add 1 tablespoon of sesame oil, the yellow squash, and 1 teaspoon salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Sauté for 2-3 minutes, until the squash is softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Set the squash aside in a small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">In the same skillet over medium heat, add another tablespoon of sesame oil, the zucchini, and 1 teaspoon of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Sauté for 2-3 minutes, until the zucchini is softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Set aside in a small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add another tablespoon of sesame oil, the daikon, and a teaspoon of salt to the same skillet and for sauté over medium heat for 30 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add ¼ cup (60 ml) of water and cook until liquid has evaporated, 4-5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Set aside in a small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">In the same skillet over medium heat, add another tablespoons of sesame oil, the carrots, and 1 teaspoon of salt and sauté for 2-3 minutes, until softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Set aside in a small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">In a small bowl, pour the hot water over the dried mushrooms and soak for 5 minutes, or until the mushrooms have softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Wring out excess moisture from the mushrooms and thinly slice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">In the skillet over medium heat, add 1 tablespoon of sesame oil and sauté 1 minced clove of garlic for 30 seconds, or until fragrant. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Add the mushrooms and sauté for 2-3 minutes more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Set aside in a small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Add the remaining ¼ cup (60 ml) of sesame oil to a liquid measuring cup or small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Add 2 teaspoons of salt, the remaining minced garlic clove, the gochugaru, and sesame seeds and whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Pour a bit of the seasoned oil over the sautéed beans sprouts, sliced cucumber, and blanched spinach, tossing with your fingers to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Heat a large skillet over high heat, then add the ribeye and marinade and stir-fry for 2-3 minutes, until the beef is browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Remove the pan from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Assemble the bibimbap: Place the rice in the center of a shallow dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Add the cucumber, mushrooms, zucchini, carrots, daikon, spinach, bean sprouts, and yellow squash around the sides of the rice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Scoop the beef into the center of the rice and top with the fried egg. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Garnish with thinly sliced green onions and nori and a sprinkle of sesame seeds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Serve the bibimbap with kimchi and gochujang. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">To eat, mix everything together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>