<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Homemade Chocolate-Covered Ice Cream Cones Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/homemade-chocolate-covered-ice-cream-cones</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ½ cups ; semisweet chocolate chips, divided ; (435 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; heavy cream ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; coconut oil ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">6 ; ice cream sugar cones </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 gal ; vanilla ice cream, softened ; (2.2 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; chopped peanut ; (125 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/99005/hls24_1529344169.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/99005/landscape_720/1529344169</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a small bowl, combine ½ cup (85 G) chocolate chips and the heavy cream. Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until melted and smooth, about 1 minute total. Cover with plastic wrap and refrigerate until set, about 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, combine the remaining chocolate chips and coconut oil. Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until melted and smooth, about 1 minute total. </step>
    <step num="2">Wrap a 9x5-inch (22x12 cm) loaf pan in foil, keeping the foil taut across the top. Set nearby. </step>
    <step num="3">Spoon about 2 tablespoons of the melted chocolate-coconut oil mixture into a cone, flip upside-down, and spin to coat the inside, letting excess chocolate drip back into the bowl. Poke the cone through the foil to prop upright, and repeat with the remaining cones. Chill in fridge until set, about 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Once set, spoon some of the softened ice cream into the cones to fill, and smooth the tops. Place the cones in the freezer for 10 minutes, or until set. </step>
    <step num="5">Scoop about a teaspoon of the ganache onto a spoon. Fill an ice cream scooper with the ice cream and create a hole in the middle with the end of a spoon. Place the ganache in the hole and place on top of a cone. Repeat with remaining cones. </step>
    <step num="6">Set the cones on a baking sheet and freeze again for 30 minutes, or until solid. </step>
    <step num="7">Using the remaining melted chocolate, dip the cones, turning to coat the ice cream. </step>
    <step num="8">While the chocolate is still wet, quickly dip the cones in the chopped peanuts to coat. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a small bowl, combine ½ cup (85 G) chocolate chips and the heavy cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until melted and smooth, about 1 minute total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cover with plastic wrap and refrigerate until set, about 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a large bowl, combine the remaining chocolate chips and coconut oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until melted and smooth, about 1 minute total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Wrap a 9x5-inch (22x12 cm) loaf pan in foil, keeping the foil taut across the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Set nearby. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Spoon about 2 tablespoons of the melted chocolate-coconut oil mixture into a cone, flip upside-down, and spin to coat the inside, letting excess chocolate drip back into the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Poke the cone through the foil to prop upright, and repeat with the remaining cones. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Chill in fridge until set, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Once set, spoon some of the softened ice cream into the cones to fill, and smooth the tops. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place the cones in the freezer for 10 minutes, or until set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Scoop about a teaspoon of the ganache onto a spoon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Fill an ice cream scooper with the ice cream and create a hole in the middle with the end of a spoon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Place the ganache in the hole and place on top of a cone. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Repeat with remaining cones. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Set the cones on a baking sheet and freeze again for 30 minutes, or until solid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Using the remaining melted chocolate, dip the cones, turning to coat the ice cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">While the chocolate is still wet, quickly dip the cones in the chopped peanuts to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>