<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Easy Chicken Bibimbap Recipe To Help Digestion</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chicken-bibimbap</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 cloves ; garlic, minced, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 teaspoons ; fresh ginger, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ; scallions, thinly sliced, plus 1 bunch sliced on the bias, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; soy sauce ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 tablespoons ; sesame oil, plus 2 tablespoons, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; mirin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; light brown sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 lb ; boneless, skinless chicken thighs, sliced into 1/2 inch (1 1/4 cm) strips ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">4 cups ; fresh spinach ; (160 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">freshly ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 ; large carrots, julienned </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">8 oz ; shiitake mushroom, stems removed, thinly sliced ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 tablespoon ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">sushi rice, cooked </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">cabbage kimchi </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">persian cucumber, thinly sliced </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Korean</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
    <category num="2">Date Night</category>
    <category num="3">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/122189/hls24_1547062071.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/122189/landscape_720/1547062071</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a shallow dish, combine 2 cloves of garlic, the ginger, 2 thinly sliced scallions, the soy sauce, 2 tablespoons sesame oil, the mirin, and brown sugar, and whisk to combine. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the chicken and toss to coat. Cover with plastic wrap and let marinate in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Bring a large pot of water to boil over high heat and season generously with salt. Prepare an ice bath in a large bowl. Blanch the spinach in the boiling water for 30 seconds, then transfer to the ice bath to shock, then drain. Transfer to a small bowl and season with 1 teaspoon of sesame oil, salt, and pepper. </step>
    <step num="3">In a medium skillet, heat 1 teaspoon of sesame oil over medium heat. Add the carrots and cook until softened, 2-3 minutes. Remove from the pan and set aside. Season with salt. </step>
    <step num="4">In the same skillet, heat 1 tablespoon of sesame oil over medium-high heat. Add the remaining clove of garlic and cook for 30 seconds, until fragrant. Add the mushrooms and cook, stirring frequently, until softened, about 2 minutes. Season with salt, then remove from the pan and set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">In the same skillet, heat the remaining tablespoon of sesame oil over medium-high heat. Add the marinated chicken and sauté, stirring occasionally, until cooked through, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Heat a nonstick pan over medium-high heat. Melt the butter in the pan. Once the foaming subsides, crack the eggs into the pan and cook until the whites are firm and golden brown around the edges and the yolks are still runny, or to your desired doneness. </step>
    <step num="7">To assemble the bibimbap bowls, top the rice with the chicken, kimchi, sliced scallions, carrots, spinach, mushrooms, cucumbers, and fried eggs. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a shallow dish, combine 2 cloves of garlic, the ginger, 2 thinly sliced scallions, the soy sauce, 2 tablespoons sesame oil, the mirin, and brown sugar, and whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the chicken and toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cover with plastic wrap and let marinate in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Bring a large pot of water to boil over high heat and season generously with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Prepare an ice bath in a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Blanch the spinach in the boiling water for 30 seconds, then transfer to the ice bath to shock, then drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Transfer to a small bowl and season with 1 teaspoon of sesame oil, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a medium skillet, heat 1 teaspoon of sesame oil over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the carrots and cook until softened, 2-3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove from the pan and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Season with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">In the same skillet, heat 1 tablespoon of sesame oil over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the remaining clove of garlic and cook for 30 seconds, until fragrant. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the mushrooms and cook, stirring frequently, until softened, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Season with salt, then remove from the pan and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">In the same skillet, heat the remaining tablespoon of sesame oil over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the marinated chicken and sauté, stirring occasionally, until cooked through, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Heat a nonstick pan over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Melt the butter in the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Once the foaming subsides, crack the eggs into the pan and cook until the whites are firm and golden brown around the edges and the yolks are still runny, or to your desired doneness. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">To assemble the bibimbap bowls, top the rice with the chicken, kimchi, sliced scallions, carrots, spinach, mushrooms, cucumbers, and fried eggs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>