<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>S’mores Cheesecake Pops Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/smores-cheesecake-pops</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">10 ; graham crackers </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; butter, melted ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">16 oz ; cream cheese, softened ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; powdered sugar ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 teaspoons ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 cups ; mini marshmallow ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">4 oz ; white chocolate, melted ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">16 oz ; milk chocolate, or dark chocolate, melted ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 teaspoons ; coconut oil, optional </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">BBQ</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/28369/low_1491330309.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/28369/mp4_720x1280/1491330309</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a freezer bag or food processor, crush the graham crackers to a sand-like consistency. Add the melted butter and stir until combined. </step>
    <step num="1">Transfer to an 8x8-inch (20x20-cm) baking dish lined with parchment paper and firmly pack it down to form the “crust.” Freeze until the cheesecake mixture is ready. </step>
    <step num="2">While the crust is freezing, combine the cream cheese, sugar, and vanilla extract, and mix until smooth. </step>
    <step num="3">Spread the marshmallows out on a baking sheet lined with parchment paper. Broil the marshmallows for about 1-2 minutes, watching closely to make sure they don’t burn. You want them to brown up a little though to achieve a “toasted” flavor. </step>
    <step num="4">Carefully scrape the marshmallows from the sheet into the cheesecake mixture. Mix thoroughly. </step>
    <step num="5">Transfer the toasted marshmallow cheesecake mixture into the baking dish on top of the crust and smooth until even. </step>
    <step num="6">Freeze at least 1 to 2 hours until the mixture is firm enough to cut. Remove the set cheesecake from the dish and cut into even square shapes, depending on how big you want your pops. </step>
    <step num="7">Dip each stick in melted white chocolate and place into each cut square, this will help secure the sticks into the cheescake. Freeze until solid, about one hour. </step>
    <step num="8">Microwave the milk (or dark) chocolate in 15 to 30 second increments to melt, stirring thoroughly each time. Add coconut oil if the chocolate seems too thick for dipping. </step>
    <step num="9">Dip the set pops into the chocolate and stand upright to set (a cardboard box or piece of styrofoam works best if you don’t have a stand). </step>
    <step num="10">Decorate with the remaining white chocolate and crushed graham crackers. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a freezer bag or food processor, crush the graham crackers to a sand-like consistency. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the melted butter and stir until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Transfer to an 8x8-inch (20x20-cm) baking dish lined with parchment paper and firmly pack it down to form the “crust.” Freeze until the cheesecake mixture is ready. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">While the crust is freezing, combine the cream cheese, sugar, and vanilla extract, and mix until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Spread the marshmallows out on a baking sheet lined with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Broil the marshmallows for about 1-2 minutes, watching closely to make sure they don’t burn. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">You want them to brown up a little though to achieve a “toasted” flavor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Carefully scrape the marshmallows from the sheet into the cheesecake mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Mix thoroughly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Transfer the toasted marshmallow cheesecake mixture into the baking dish on top of the crust and smooth until even. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Freeze at least 1 to 2 hours until the mixture is firm enough to cut. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove the set cheesecake from the dish and cut into even square shapes, depending on how big you want your pops. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Dip each stick in melted white chocolate and place into each cut square, this will help secure the sticks into the cheescake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Freeze until solid, about one hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Microwave the milk (or dark) chocolate in 15 to 30 second increments to melt, stirring thoroughly each time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add coconut oil if the chocolate seems too thick for dipping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Dip the set pops into the chocolate and stand upright to set (a cardboard box or piece of styrofoam works best if you don’t have a stand). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Decorate with the remaining white chocolate and crushed graham crackers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>