<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Peaches ‘N’ Cream Cheesecake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/peaches-n-cream-cheesecake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">nonstick cooking spray, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">10 oz ; shortbread cookie ; (285 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">6 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 ; ripe yellow peaches, quartered, plus 4-5 thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 packs ; gelatin, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; cold water, divided ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">32 oz ; cream cheese, softened ; (900 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ¼ cups ; sugar, plus 2/3 cups (135 G), divided ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ cup ; heavy cream ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 drops ; orange food coloring, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">⅔ cup ; hot water ; (160 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 cup ; prosecco ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Brunch</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/133619/hls24_1558545272.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/133619/landscape_720/1558545272</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Grease and line the sides of a 9-inch (20 cm) round springform pan with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the shortbread cookies to a food processor. Pulse until finely crushed. Add the melted butter and pulse until combined. </step>
    <step num="2">Transfer the cookie crumb mixture to the springform pan. Use a spatula or measuring cup to press the cookie crumbs down to form an even base. Freeze for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add 2-3 quartered peaches (depending on size) to a food processor. Blend until smooth. Strain through a fine-mesh sieve. </step>
    <step num="4">In a small bowl, combine ½ cup (120 ml) cold water and 2 packets of gelatin. Let the gelatin bloom for 5 minutes, until the water is mostly absorbed. Microwave for 20–30 seconds, or until the gelatin is melted. </step>
    <step num="5">In a large bowl, beat the cream cheese, 1¼ cups (250 G) sugar, the vanilla, and lemon juice together with an electric hand mixer until combined. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the heavy cream and melted gelatin and beat for another 2-3 minutes, until well combined and fluffy. </step>
    <step num="7">Spread half the cheesecake mixture over the chilled cookie crust. Freeze for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Mix 1 cup (255 G) of the strained peach puree and orange food coloring, if desired, into the remaining cheesecake mixture. Carefully pour the mixture over the first layer of cheesecake. Spread evenly and freeze for another 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">In a small bowl, combine the remaining ½ cup (120 ML) cold water with the remaining 2 packages of gelatin. Let the gelatin bloom for 5 minutes, until the water is mostly absorbed. Microwave for 20–30 seconds, or until the gelatin is melted. </step>
    <step num="10">Combine the gelatin mixture, hot water, and the remaining ⅔ cup (135 G) sugar and whisk to dissolve the sugar. Slowly pour into the prosecco and stir to combine. Let sit for 5 minutes to cool slightly. Skim off any foam that rises to the top. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="11">Starting from the outside and working inward, arrange the sliced peaches over the peach cheesecake layer in a circular pattern with the curved sides facing out. Begin with the larger slices, overlapping slightly, and continue until the entire surface is filled. </step>
    <step num="12">Spoon half of the prosecco gelatin over the peaches. Carefully transfer to the refrigerator and let set for 30 minutes. Pour the remaining prosecco gelatin over the peaches up to the rim of the pan. Chill in the refrigerator for at least 6 hours, or overnight. </step>
    <step num="13">Release the springform and remove the parchment, then slice and serve. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Grease and line the sides of a 9-inch (20 cm) round springform pan with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the shortbread cookies to a food processor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Pulse until finely crushed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the melted butter and pulse until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Transfer the cookie crumb mixture to the springform pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Use a spatula or measuring cup to press the cookie crumbs down to form an even base. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Freeze for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add 2-3 quartered peaches (depending on size) to a food processor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Blend until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Strain through a fine-mesh sieve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a small bowl, combine ½ cup (120 ml) cold water and 2 packets of gelatin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Let the gelatin bloom for 5 minutes, until the water is mostly absorbed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Microwave for 20–30 seconds, or until the gelatin is melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">In a large bowl, beat the cream cheese, 1¼ cups (250 G) sugar, the vanilla, and lemon juice together with an electric hand mixer until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add the heavy cream and melted gelatin and beat for another 2-3 minutes, until well combined and fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Spread half the cheesecake mixture over the chilled cookie crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Freeze for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Mix 1 cup (255 G) of the strained peach puree and orange food coloring, if desired, into the remaining cheesecake mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Carefully pour the mixture over the first layer of cheesecake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Spread evenly and freeze for another 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">In a small bowl, combine the remaining ½ cup (120 ML) cold water with the remaining 2 packages of gelatin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Let the gelatin bloom for 5 minutes, until the water is mostly absorbed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Microwave for 20–30 seconds, or until the gelatin is melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Combine the gelatin mixture, hot water, and the remaining ⅔ cup (135 G) sugar and whisk to dissolve the sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Slowly pour into the prosecco and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Let sit for 5 minutes to cool slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Skim off any foam that rises to the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Starting from the outside and working inward, arrange the sliced peaches over the peach cheesecake layer in a circular pattern with the curved sides facing out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Begin with the larger slices, overlapping slightly, and continue until the entire surface is filled. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Spoon half of the prosecco gelatin over the peaches. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Carefully transfer to the refrigerator and let set for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Pour the remaining prosecco gelatin over the peaches up to the rim of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Chill in the refrigerator for at least 6 hours, or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Release the springform and remove the parchment, then slice and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>