<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Mental Boost Grapefruit Sage Gimlet Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/mental-boost-grapefruit-sage-gimlet</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ cup ; cold water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; fresh sage leaf, roughly chopped, plus whole leaves for garnish ; (15 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 oz ; gin ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ½ oz ; grapefruit juice ; (45 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Drinks</category>
    <category num="1">Happy Hour</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/130095/hls24_1555430990.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/130095/landscape_720/1555430990</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the sage simple syrup: In a small saucepan over medium heat, combine the water, sugar, and chopped sage leaves. Bring to a low boil, then reduce the heat to low and simmer for 5 minutes, until the sugar is fully dissolved and the sage is fragrant. Remove from the heat and let cool for 5-10 minutes. Strain through a fine-mesh sieve. Store remaining sage syrup in the refrigerator for up to 1 month. </step>
    <step num="1">In a cocktail shaker filled halfway with ice, combine the gin, grapefruit juice, and 1 tablespoon of sage simple syrup. Shake vigorously for 30 seconds. Strain into a coupe glass. </step>
    <step num="2">Garnish with sage leaves. </step>
    <step num="3">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the sage simple syrup: In a small saucepan over medium heat, combine the water, sugar, and chopped sage leaves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Bring to a low boil, then reduce the heat to low and simmer for 5 minutes, until the sugar is fully dissolved and the sage is fragrant. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Remove from the heat and let cool for 5-10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Strain through a fine-mesh sieve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Store remaining sage syrup in the refrigerator for up to 1 month. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In a cocktail shaker filled halfway with ice, combine the gin, grapefruit juice, and 1 tablespoon of sage simple syrup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Shake vigorously for 30 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Strain into a coupe glass. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Garnish with sage leaves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>