<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>How To Decorate Shortbread Holiday Cut-Out Cookies With Royal Icing Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/how-to-decorate-shortbread-holiday-cut-out-cookies-with-royal-icing</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 cups ; all purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (375 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 teaspoons ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">16 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, cubed and chilled </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; large egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 cups ; powdered sugar, sugar, sifted ; (360 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 tablespoons ; meringue powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ teaspoon ; vanilla extract, or almond extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">4 tablespoons ; water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">green gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">red gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">brown gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">blue gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">yellow gel food coloring </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="3">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/118978/hls24_1544463608.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/118978/landscape_720/1544463608</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). Line baking sheets with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, combine the flour, baking powder, and salt. Mix with a fork. </step>
    <step num="2">In a separate large bowl, cream together the butter and sugar with an electric hand mixer for 3-5 minutes, until the butter and sugar are fully combined, but before the mixture becomes fluffy. Add the egg and vanilla and beat to incorporate. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the flour mixture and mix until just combined, but crumbly. Finish mixing with your hands until the dough comes together in a ball. </step>
    <step num="4">Transfer the dough to a floured surface. Lightly flour the top of the dough and roll out to about ¼-inch thick. Use cookie cutters of your choice to punch out cookies. Place the cookie cut-outs on the prepared baking sheets. </step>
    <step num="5">Bake for 8-10 minutes, until lightly browned around the edges. Let cool completely. </step>
    <step num="6">To make the royal icing: In a medium bowl, add the meringue powder to the powdered sugar. Whisk to combine. Add the vanilla and 4-6 tablespoons of water (depending on how runny or thick you’d like your icing.) Whisk until completely combined. </step>
    <step num="7">Divide the icing into smaller bowls and add any desired gel food colors. Immediately transfer to piping bags, or cover with plastic wrap. Do not leave the icing uncovered, as it will develop a film. If this happens, add a small amount of water and whisk to incorporate. </step>
    <step num="8">Decorate the cookies with royal icing as desired and let dry completely, at least 3-4 hours or overnight. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line baking sheets with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a large bowl, combine the flour, baking powder, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Mix with a fork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a separate large bowl, cream together the butter and sugar with an electric hand mixer for 3-5 minutes, until the butter and sugar are fully combined, but before the mixture becomes fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the egg and vanilla and beat to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the flour mixture and mix until just combined, but crumbly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Finish mixing with your hands until the dough comes together in a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Transfer the dough to a floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Lightly flour the top of the dough and roll out to about ¼-inch thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Use cookie cutters of your choice to punch out cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place the cookie cut-outs on the prepared baking sheets. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Bake for 8-10 minutes, until lightly browned around the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">To make the royal icing: In a medium bowl, add the meringue powder to the powdered sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the vanilla and 4-6 tablespoons of water (depending on how runny or thick you’d like your icing.) Whisk until completely combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Divide the icing into smaller bowls and add any desired gel food colors. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Immediately transfer to piping bags, or cover with plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Do not leave the icing uncovered, as it will develop a film. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">If this happens, add a small amount of water and whisk to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Decorate the cookies with royal icing as desired and let dry completely, at least 3-4 hours or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>