<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Marbled 4th Of July 'Box' Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/marbled-4th-of-july-box-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 boxes ; white cake mix, prepared, divided into 3 bowls </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ½ teaspoons ; blue food coloring, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ½ teaspoons ; red food coloring, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; hard red candy ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; hard blue candy ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 cups ; vanilla frosting ; (345 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¼ cup ; blue frosting ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; red frosting ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">3 ; wooden skewers </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/99635/hls24_1529628288.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/99635/landscape_720/1529628288</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Grease and line 3 9-inch (20 cm) round cake pans with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="2">Set aside 1 bowl of cake batter – this will be the white part of the cake. Add 2 teaspoons of red food coloring to another bowl of batter, mixing until fully incorporated. Add 2 teaspoons of blue food coloring to the last bowl of batter, mixing until fully incorporated. </step>
    <step num="3">Take 1 cup (115 G) of each batter and carefully pour into each of the 3 cake pans. Repeat, alternating colors, until all of the batter is used. Gently stir to blend the colors in each pan. </step>
    <step num="4">Bake according to package instructions, or until a toothpick inserted in the center of a cake comes out clean. </step>
    <step num="5">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper and lay 3 wooden skewers 4 inches (10 cm) apart. </step>
    <step num="6">In a small heat-proof bowl, melt the red hard candies in the microwave for 1 minute. Using a small spoon, carefully drizzle the red candy in a star pattern over the skewers. Cool for 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">In another small glass bowl, melt the blue hard candies in the microwave for 1 minute. Using a small spoon, carefully drizzle the blue candy in a star pattern over the red candy. Cool for 10 minutes before gently prying away from the parchment. </step>
    <step num="8">Remove all the cakes from the pans and let cool completely before continuing. </step>
    <step num="9">With a serrated knife, removed the domed tops from each cake layer and set aside the excess cake. </step>
    <step num="10">Place a dab of frosting on a cake stand or an inverted plate. Place a layer of cake on the cake wheel, then evenly spread frosting on top. Place the next layer of cake on top of the frosted layer, and spread frosting on top. Add the last cake layer. </step>
    <step num="11">Add 1 cup (115 G) of frosting on top of the cake, spreading evenly across the top and sides with a spatula. </step>
    <step num="12">Dab the blue and red frosting around the sides cake, alternating from top to bottom, about 3 inches (7 cm) apart. </step>
    <step num="13">Using a spatula, smear the red and blue frosting onto the sides of the cake. </step>
    <step num="14">Place the firework skewers on top of the cake. </step>
    <step num="15">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Grease and line 3 9-inch (20 cm) round cake pans with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Set aside 1 bowl of cake batter – this will be the white part of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add 2 teaspoons of red food coloring to another bowl of batter, mixing until fully incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add 2 teaspoons of blue food coloring to the last bowl of batter, mixing until fully incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Take 1 cup (115 G) of each batter and carefully pour into each of the 3 cake pans. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Repeat, alternating colors, until all of the batter is used. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Gently stir to blend the colors in each pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Bake according to package instructions, or until a toothpick inserted in the center of a cake comes out clean. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper and lay 3 wooden skewers 4 inches (10 cm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a small heat-proof bowl, melt the red hard candies in the microwave for 1 minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Using a small spoon, carefully drizzle the red candy in a star pattern over the skewers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cool for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">In another small glass bowl, melt the blue hard candies in the microwave for 1 minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Using a small spoon, carefully drizzle the blue candy in a star pattern over the red candy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cool for 10 minutes before gently prying away from the parchment. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Remove all the cakes from the pans and let cool completely before continuing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">With a serrated knife, removed the domed tops from each cake layer and set aside the excess cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Place a dab of frosting on a cake stand or an inverted plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Place a layer of cake on the cake wheel, then evenly spread frosting on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Place the next layer of cake on top of the frosted layer, and spread frosting on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Add the last cake layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add 1 cup (115 G) of frosting on top of the cake, spreading evenly across the top and sides with a spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Dab the blue and red frosting around the sides cake, alternating from top to bottom, about 3 inches (7 cm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Using a spatula, smear the red and blue frosting onto the sides of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Place the firework skewers on top of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>