<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Giant Caramel Candy Bar Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/giant-caramel-candy-bar-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (375 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¾ cup ; granulated sugar ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 cups ; unsalted butter, 4 sticks, cubed, room temperature ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¾ cup ; light brown sugar ; (165 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¾ cup ; light corn syrup ; (165 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¾ cup ; unsalted butter, 1 1/2 sticks ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¾ cup ; heavy cream ; (180 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; milk chocolate chips, melted ; (175 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 cups ; milk chocolate chips ; (350 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">3 tablespoons ; coconut oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">baking pan, 12x4½- in (30x11-cm) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/110453/hls24_1538006886.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/110453/landscape_720/1538006886</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). Grease a 12x4½- in (30x11-cm) baking pan and line with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">Make the shortbread: In a large bowl, whisk together the flour, granulated sugar, and salt. Add the butter. Use your hands to work it into the flour until a dough forms. Transfer to the prepared loaf pan and spread evenly. Cover with foil. </step>
    <step num="2">Bake for 45 minutes, then remove the foil and bake for another 45-60 minutes, until light golden brown. Let cool completely. </step>
    <step num="3">Make the caramel filling: In a medium, heavy-bottomed saucepan, combine the brown sugar, corn syrup, butter, cream, and salt. Over medium-high heat, bring the caramel to a boil and let cook for 5 minutes. 5. Then, reduce the heat to low and cook for 10 more minutes, until slightly deeper golden in color. Remove the pot from the heat. </step>
    <step num="4">Pour the caramel over the shortbread cookie. Let cool in the refrigerator for 2 hours or until set. </step>
    <step num="5">Once the cookie has chilled, line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="6">Make the chocolate ridges. Pour ⅓ of the melted chocolate onto the prepared baking sheet and spread into a 13x5-inch (33x12 cm) rectangle. </step>
    <step num="7">Lift the cookie out of the pan using the parchment paper, and remove the paper. Place the cookie on top of the chocolate rectangle. Pour the remaining melted chocolate on top of the caramel. Spread the chocolate to the edges in a zig-zag motion to create textured ridges. Return to the refrigerator for 20 minutes, until the chocolate hardens. </step>
    <step num="8">While the cookie is chilling, make the chocolate glaze: Add the chocolate chips and coconut oil to a medium microwave-safe bowl. Melt in the microwave in 30 seconds intervals, stirring between each, until smooth. Set aside to cool for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Remove the cookie from the refrigerator. Invert 2 jars or glasses on a baking sheet or piece of parchment paper. Set the cookie bar on the jars and pour the chocolate glaze over the cookie. Use a spatula to carefully push the chocolate over the edges of the cookie to coat the sides, being careful not to flatten the edges. Carefully return to the refrigerator to chill for at least 1 hour, until the chocolate is hardened. Keep refrigerated until ready to serve. </step>
    <step num="10">Cut into ¾-inch (2 cm) thick slices with a sharp knife. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Grease a 12x4½- in (30x11-cm) baking pan and line with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Make the shortbread: In a large bowl, whisk together the flour, granulated sugar, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Use your hands to work it into the flour until a dough forms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Transfer to the prepared loaf pan and spread evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cover with foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Bake for 45 minutes, then remove the foil and bake for another 45-60 minutes, until light golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Make the caramel filling: In a medium, heavy-bottomed saucepan, combine the brown sugar, corn syrup, butter, cream, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Over medium-high heat, bring the caramel to a boil and let cook for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">5. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Then, reduce the heat to low and cook for 10 more minutes, until slightly deeper golden in color. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove the pot from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Pour the caramel over the shortbread cookie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Let cool in the refrigerator for 2 hours or until set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Once the cookie has chilled, line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Make the chocolate ridges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Pour ⅓ of the melted chocolate onto the prepared baking sheet and spread into a 13x5-inch (33x12 cm) rectangle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Lift the cookie out of the pan using the parchment paper, and remove the paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Place the cookie on top of the chocolate rectangle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Pour the remaining melted chocolate on top of the caramel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Spread the chocolate to the edges in a zig-zag motion to create textured ridges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Return to the refrigerator for 20 minutes, until the chocolate hardens. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">While the cookie is chilling, make the chocolate glaze: Add the chocolate chips and coconut oil to a medium microwave-safe bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Melt in the microwave in 30 seconds intervals, stirring between each, until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Set aside to cool for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Remove the cookie from the refrigerator. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Invert 2 jars or glasses on a baking sheet or piece of parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Set the cookie bar on the jars and pour the chocolate glaze over the cookie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Use a spatula to carefully push the chocolate over the edges of the cookie to coat the sides, being careful not to flatten the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Carefully return to the refrigerator to chill for at least 1 hour, until the chocolate is hardened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Keep refrigerated until ready to serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Cut into ¾-inch (2 cm) thick slices with a sharp knife. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>