<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Color-Changing Frozen Mojito Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/color-changing-mojito</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 cups ; water ; (710 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 oz ; red cabbage, julienned ; (85 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; lime juice ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ½ cups ; water ; (355 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">10 ; mint leaves </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 tablespoons ; white rum </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Latin American</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Drinks</category>
    <category num="4">Happy Hour</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/43204/low_1499729472.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/43204/mp4_720x1280/1499729472</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Add water and red cabbage to a medium-size pot. Bring the water to a boil, then strain the cabbage in a sieve over a bowl to reserve the blue liquid. </step>
    <step num="1">Pour the strained blue water into an ice tray. You will be left with 1 cup (235 ml) of blue water. Reserve the water and freeze the ice tray for 6 hours, or overnight. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the reserved blue water to a pot with the sugar and bring to a boil until the sugar has dissolved. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">Combine the lime juice with 1½ (355 ml) cups of water and stir to combine. Pour the lime mixture into an ice tray and freeze for 6 hours, up to overnight. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the blue ice cubes to a blender and blend until finely crushed. Put the crushed blue ice in a glass. </step>
    <step num="5">Wash the blender well. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the lime ice cubes and 8 mint leaves. Blend until finely crushed. Put the crushed lime and mint ice on top of the blue ice. </step>
    <step num="7">Slowly pour the white rum and blue simple syrup. Top with a sprig of mint. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Add water and red cabbage to a medium-size pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Bring the water to a boil, then strain the cabbage in a sieve over a bowl to reserve the blue liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Pour the strained blue water into an ice tray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">You will be left with 1 cup (235 ml) of blue water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Reserve the water and freeze the ice tray for 6 hours, or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the reserved blue water to a pot with the sugar and bring to a boil until the sugar has dissolved. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Combine the lime juice with 1½ (355 ml) cups of water and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Pour the lime mixture into an ice tray and freeze for 6 hours, up to overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the blue ice cubes to a blender and blend until finely crushed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Put the crushed blue ice in a glass. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Wash the blender well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the lime ice cubes and 8 mint leaves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Blend until finely crushed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Put the crushed lime and mint ice on top of the blue ice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Slowly pour the white rum and blue simple syrup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Top with a sprig of mint. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>