<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Strawberry Rose Crepe Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/strawberry-rose-crepe-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; unsalted butter, 1/2 stick, melted ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 tablespoons ; granulated sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 cups ; whole milk ; (720 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">8 oz ; cream cheese ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 tablespoons ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">⅓ cup ; heavy cream ; (80 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 cup ; strawberry, thinly sliced ; (150 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">French</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Fusion</category>
    <category num="6">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/87627/hls24_1522694233.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/87627/landscape_720/1522694233</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, combine the flour, butter, sugar, and eggs. </step>
    <step num="1">Add ½ cup (120 ml) of milk at a time, stirring vigorously, making sure that each addition is completely incorporated into the batter and that the batter is smooth before adding more milk. </step>
    <step num="2">Strain the batter through a fine mesh sieve. The batter should be very liquidy and have no lumps. Rest in the fridge for at least 30 minutes or up to overnight. </step>
    <step num="3">Make the filling: In a medium bowl, combine the cream cheese and sugar. Using a hand mixer, beat until combined. Add the heavy cream and mix until smooth. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">In a 9.5 inch (24-cm) nonstick pan over medium heat, pour ⅓ cup (40 g) of the batter in the center, and swirl the batter around to the edges of the pan. </step>
    <step num="5">Cook the crepe until bubbles rise to the surface and the bottom is golden brown, about 3 minutes. Flip and cook on the other side until the edges start to crisp slightly, about 1 minute more. </step>
    <step num="6">Transfer the crepe to a wire rack to cool. Repeat with the remaining batter. </step>
    <step num="7">Stack the crepes on top of each other, then cut in half. Stack the halves on top of each other, and cut the stack into two even strips. </step>
    <step num="8">Place two crepe strips on a flat surface and spread the cream cheese mixture on both. Arrange sliced strawberries on one of the strips. </step>
    <step num="9">Roll up the first strip with the strawberries, then roll the second strip around it. Repeat with the rest of the strips of crepes, alternating between strips with strawberries and strips without. Once it becomes too large to roll, lay the cake on a serving platter. </step>
    <step num="10">Spread the remaining crepe strips with cream cheese and gently press them around the outside of the cake. Refrigerate for 15-30 minutes to set. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, combine the flour, butter, sugar, and eggs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add ½ cup (120 ml) of milk at a time, stirring vigorously, making sure that each addition is completely incorporated into the batter and that the batter is smooth before adding more milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Strain the batter through a fine mesh sieve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">The batter should be very liquidy and have no lumps. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Rest in the fridge for at least 30 minutes or up to overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Make the filling: In a medium bowl, combine the cream cheese and sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Using a hand mixer, beat until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the heavy cream and mix until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a 9.5 inch (24-cm) nonstick pan over medium heat, pour ⅓ cup (40 g) of the batter in the center, and swirl the batter around to the edges of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Cook the crepe until bubbles rise to the surface and the bottom is golden brown, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Flip and cook on the other side until the edges start to crisp slightly, about 1 minute more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Transfer the crepe to a wire rack to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Repeat with the remaining batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Stack the crepes on top of each other, then cut in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Stack the halves on top of each other, and cut the stack into two even strips. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Place two crepe strips on a flat surface and spread the cream cheese mixture on both. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Arrange sliced strawberries on one of the strips </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Roll up the first strip with the strawberries, then roll the second strip around it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Repeat with the rest of the strips of crepes, alternating between strips with strawberries and strips without. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Once it becomes too large to roll, lay the cake on a serving platter </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Spread the remaining crepe strips with cream cheese and gently press them around the outside of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Refrigerate for 15-30 minutes to set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>