<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Baked Eggs Benedict Cups Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/baked-eggs-benedict-cups</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">6 slices ; ham, canadian-style bacon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">6 ; eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 ; egg yolks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; white vinegar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; butter, melted ; (114 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 tablespoons ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">3 ; english muffins, split in halves </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">British</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="4">Brunch</category>
    <category num="5">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32096/low_1495125340.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32096/mp4_720x1280/1495125340</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Egg Cups: Grease a large muffin tin. Place a slice of ham in each tin, then crack an egg over each slice of ham. Cover with tin foil, then bake at 350˚F (175˚C) for 8-10 minutes (eight minutes if you like your yolk very runny). </step>
    <step num="1">Hollandaise sauce: Fill the bottom of a double boiler part-way with water. Make sure that the water doesn’t touch the top bowl. Bring water to a gentle simmer. In the top of the double boiler, whisk together three egg yolks and ½ tsp white vinegar until well mixed. </step>
    <step num="2">Slowly pour the melted butter in the egg yolk mixture, a little at a time, while constantly whisking. If you pour too much too quickly without whisking, the mixture might not thicken or mix properly. If the hollandaise gets too thick, add a teaspoon or two of hot water. Continue whisking until all the butter is incorporated. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove from heat, whisk in lemon juice, salt, and pepper. </step>
    <step num="4">Place a toasted English muffin half down, layer the ham and egg cup on top of the English muffin, then drizzle your hollandaise sauce over the egg. </step>
    <step num="5">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Egg Cups: Grease a large muffin tin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Place a slice of ham in each tin, then crack an egg over each slice of ham. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cover with tin foil, then bake at 350˚F (175˚C) for 8-10 minutes (eight minutes if you like your yolk very runny). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Hollandaise sauce: Fill the bottom of a double boiler part-way with water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Make sure that the water doesn’t touch the top bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Bring water to a gentle simmer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In the top of the double boiler, whisk together three egg yolks and ½ tsp white vinegar until well mixed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Slowly pour the melted butter in the egg yolk mixture, a little at a time, while constantly whisking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">If you pour too much too quickly without whisking, the mixture might not thicken or mix properly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">If the hollandaise gets too thick, add a teaspoon or two of hot water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Continue whisking until all the butter is incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove from heat, whisk in lemon juice, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Place a toasted English muffin half down, layer the ham and egg cup on top of the English muffin, then drizzle your hollandaise sauce over the egg. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>