<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Eggs Florentine Domes Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/eggs-florentine-domes</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">8 large slices ; ham, large slices </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ; english muffins, halved </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">10 oz ; spinach, uncooked ; (280 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">4 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">4 ; large egg yolks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ½ tablespoons ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 teaspoon ; dijon mustard </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¼ teaspoon ; cayenne pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ cup ; unsalted butter, 1 stick, melted ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 tablespoon ; fresh chives, chopped, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="2">Brunch</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/87182/hls24_1522350258.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/87182/landscape_720/1522350258</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the broiler. </step>
    <step num="1">Place the ham and muffins on a baking sheet. Tip: If your baking sheet is not large enough to hold everything at once, place a wire on top of the pan and arrange the remaining ham and English muffins on top of it. </step>
    <step num="2">Broil for 2 minutes, until the English muffins are toasted and the ham starts to crisp. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove the English muffins and ham from the oven. Slice the ham lengthwise, into ⅛-inch (3 mm) wide strips. </step>
    <step num="4">Cover a small bowl, about 3 inches (7-cm) in diameter, with plastic wrap. Place a ham strip across the middle (the edge of the strip should come slightly over the lip of the bowl). Continue placing ham strips across the bowl, overlapping them in a spiral pattern. Repeat with three more small bowls and the remaining ham strips. </step>
    <step num="5">In a large pan over medium-high heat, melt 2 tablespoons of butter. Add the garlic and cook for 1 minute, until the garlic starts to brown. Add the spinach and stir until wilted to half its original volume, 3-4 minutes. Add the salt and pepper and stir for another minute. Remove from heat. </step>
    <step num="6">Make the hollandaise sauce: In a blender, combine the eggs yolks, lemon juice, Dijon mustard, and cayenne pepper. Blend on high for 5 seconds. Reduce the blender speed to low and pour in the melted butter in a thin, steady stream. Blend for 30 more seconds. Cover and keep warm. </step>
    <step num="7">Fill a deep pan with enough water to cover 4 small, heat-safe bowls. Bring the water to a boil over high heat and use a pair of tongs to place the bowls in the water. Carefully drop an egg into each bowl. Cook for 2-3 minutes, or until the yolks are cooked to your desired firmness. Using tongs, remove the bowls from the water and drain. </step>
    <step num="8">Place a poached egg inside each small bowl with the spiralized ham slices and top with spinach. Fold the ham slices over the spinach and place a buttered English muffin half on top. Place a plate over the bowl and invert. Remove the bowl and plastic wrap. </step>
    <step num="9">Serve with hollandaise sauce and chives. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the broiler. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Place the ham and muffins on a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Tip: If your baking sheet is not large enough to hold everything at once, place a wire on top of the pan and arrange the remaining ham and English muffins on top of it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Broil for 2 minutes, until the English muffins are toasted and the ham starts to crisp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Remove the English muffins and ham from the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Slice the ham lengthwise, into ⅛-inch (3 mm) wide strips. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cover a small bowl, about 3 inches (7-cm) in diameter, with plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Place a ham strip across the middle (the edge of the strip should come slightly over the lip of the bowl). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Continue placing ham strips across the bowl, overlapping them in a spiral pattern. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Repeat with three more small bowls and the remaining ham strips. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a large pan over medium-high heat, melt 2 tablespoons of butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the garlic and cook for 1 minute, until the garlic starts to brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the spinach and stir until wilted to half its original volume, 3-4 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the salt and pepper and stir for another minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove from heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Make the hollandaise sauce: In a blender, combine the eggs yolks, lemon juice, Dijon mustard, and cayenne pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Blend on high for 5 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Reduce the blender speed to low and pour in the melted butter in a thin, steady stream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Blend for 30 more seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Cover and keep warm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Fill a deep pan with enough water to cover 4 small, heat-safe bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Bring the water to a boil over high heat and use a pair of tongs to place the bowls in the water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Carefully drop an egg into each bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Cook for 2-3 minutes, or until the yolks are cooked to your desired firmness. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Using tongs, remove the bowls from the water and drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Place a poached egg inside each small bowl with the spiralized ham slices and top with spinach. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Fold the ham slices over the spinach and place a buttered English muffin half on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Place a plate over the bowl and invert. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Remove the bowl and plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Serve with hollandaise sauce and chives. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>