<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Crunchy Taco Ring Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/crunchy-taco-ring</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 tablespoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ; large white onion, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; red bell pepper, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; jalapeño, seeded, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 lb ; ground beef ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 packet ; taco seasoning </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; lime, juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">10 ; flour tortillas </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">nonstick cooking oil spray </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ½ cups ; shredded cheddar cheese ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 cups ; tortilla chips, crushed ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ½ cups ; shredded monterey jack cheese ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">salsa, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Mexican</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="4">Dinner</category>
    <category num="5">Game Day</category>
    <category num="6">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="7">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/84095/hls24_1520880536.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/84095/landscape_720/1520880536</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a large skillet over medium heat, heat the olive oil. Add the onion and cook, stirring occasionally until caramelized, about 10 minutes. Add the red bell pepper and jalapeño. Cook until softened, about 3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the ground beef, breaking apart with your spoon, and mix into the other ingredients. Add the taco seasoning and the lime juice. Mix thoroughly, cover, and refrigerate until ready to use. </step>
    <step num="3">On a cutting board, place the stack of tortillas. Cut off two round sides of the tortillas, leaving a 4-inch (10-cm) wide middle section. Cut the middle section in half vertically. </step>
    <step num="4">Generously spray a bundt pan with nonstick spray. </step>
    <step num="5">Place the middle strips of tortilla in the bundt pan in a fanning pattern. Each tortillas strip should slightly overlap the previous strip. Sprinkle half of the cheddar cheese on top of the tortillas. </step>
    <step num="6">Spread half of the ground beef mixture on top of the cheese. </step>
    <step num="7">Place a third of the round strips of tortilla on top of the ground beef mixture in a fanning pattern. Sprinkle half of the Monterey Jack on top of the tortillas. Sprinkle the tortilla chips on top of the cheese. </step>
    <step num="8">Place another third of the round strips of tortilla on top of the chips in a fanning pattern. Sprinkle the rest of the cheddar cheese on top of the tortillas. Spread the rest of the ground beef mixture on top of the cheese. Sprinkle the rest of the Monterey Jack on top of the ground beef mixture. Place the rest of the tortillas on top of the cheese in a fanning pattern. </step>
    <step num="9">Bake for 45 minutes until crispy and browned. </step>
    <step num="10">Let cool for 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="11">Place a plate on top of the bundt pan, and invert the ring onto the plate. </step>
    <step num="12">Slice and serve with salsa. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a large skillet over medium heat, heat the olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the onion and cook, stirring occasionally until caramelized, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the red bell pepper and jalapeño. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Cook until softened, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the ground beef, breaking apart with your spoon, and mix into the other ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the taco seasoning and the lime juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Mix thoroughly, cover, and refrigerate until ready to use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">On a cutting board, place the stack of tortillas. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Cut off two round sides of the tortillas, leaving a 4-inch (10-cm) wide middle section. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Cut the middle section in half vertically. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Generously spray a bundt pan with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Place the middle strips of tortilla in the bundt pan in a fanning pattern. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Each tortillas strip should slightly overlap the previous strip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Sprinkle half of the cheddar cheese on top of the tortillas. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Spread half of the ground beef mixture on top of the cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Place a third of the round strips of tortilla on top of the ground beef mixture in a fanning pattern. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Sprinkle half of the Monterey Jack on top of the tortillas. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Sprinkle the tortilla chips on top of the cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Place another third of the round strips of tortilla on top of the chips in a fanning pattern. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Sprinkle the rest of the cheddar cheese on top of the tortillas. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Spread the rest of the ground beef mixture on top of the cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Sprinkle the rest of the Monterey Jack on top of the ground beef mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Place the rest of the tortillas on top of the cheese in a fanning pattern. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Bake for 45 minutes until crispy and browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Let cool for 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Place a plate on top of the bundt pan, and invert the ring onto the plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Slice and serve with salsa. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>