<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Cute Cream Puffs Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/cute-cream-puffs</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¼ cup ; dark chocolate, melted ; (45 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; unsalted butter, 1 stick ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; milk ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 tablespoons ; granulated sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 cup ; all-purpose flour ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">4 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ; egg, beaten, for egg wash </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 cups ; heavy cream ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">3 tablespoons ; powdered sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 ; small piping bag, or zip-top bag </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 ; large piping bags, or zip-top bags with standard round tips </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/101028/hls24_1530811250.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/101028/landscape_720/1530811250</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 425˚F (220˚C). Line 2 baking sheets with parchment paper. Chill a large bowl in the freezer. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the melted chocolate to a small piping bag or zip-top bag and cut ⅛ inch (3 mm) off the tip of the bag. </step>
    <step num="2">Pipe 10 sets of ears, eyes, noses, mouths, and paws onto 1 of the parchment-lined baking sheets. Chill in the refrigerator until ready to use. </step>
    <step num="3">Make the puffs: in a medium pot, bring the butter, water, milk, sugar, and salt to a boil over high heat. </step>
    <step num="4">Once the liquid begins to boil, remove the pot from the heat and immediately add the flour, stirring constantly with a wooden spoon until the liquid is absorbed and the mixture begins to form a ball. </step>
    <step num="5">Return the pot to the heat and cook for another 30 seconds to remove excess moisture. Remove the pot from the heat. Working quickly, add the eggs one at a time, stirring until each one is fully incorporated before adding the next. Continue stirring until the dough starts to pull away from the sides of the pan and is thick and glossy. Transfer the batter to a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a round tip. </step>
    <step num="6">Pipe 1-inch (2-cm) dollops of batter on the prepared baking sheet, spacing them at least 1-inch (2-cm) apart. </step>
    <step num="7">Dip a fingertip in the egg wash and gently press down any points, then brush the egg wash lightly all over the puffs. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake for 10 minutes. Reduce the oven temperature to 350˚F (180˚C), and continue to bake for 20 minutes more, until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="9">Transfer the puffs to a wire rack and cool until able to handle. Cut the tops off of the puffs with a serrated knife. Let cool completely. </step>
    <step num="10">Make the whipped cream: add the heavy cream and powdered sugar to the chilled bowl and beat with an electric hand mixer or whisk until stiff peaks form. Transfer the whipped cream to a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a round tip. </step>
    <step num="11">Pipe mounds of whipped cream into the puffs. Add the tops of the puffs and decorate with the chocolate faces. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 425˚F (220˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line 2 baking sheets with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Chill a large bowl in the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the melted chocolate to a small piping bag or zip-top bag and cut ⅛ inch (3 mm) off the tip of the bag. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pipe 10 sets of ears, eyes, noses, mouths, and paws onto 1 of the parchment-lined baking sheets. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Chill in the refrigerator until ready to use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Make the puffs: in a medium pot, bring the butter, water, milk, sugar, and salt to a boil over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Once the liquid begins to boil, remove the pot from the heat and immediately add the flour, stirring constantly with a wooden spoon until the liquid is absorbed and the mixture begins to form a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Return the pot to the heat and cook for another 30 seconds to remove excess moisture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove the pot from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Working quickly, add the eggs one at a time, stirring until each one is fully incorporated before adding the next. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Continue stirring until the dough starts to pull away from the sides of the pan and is thick and glossy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Transfer the batter to a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a round tip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Pipe 1-inch (2-cm) dollops of batter on the prepared baking sheet, spacing them at least 1-inch (2-cm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Dip a fingertip in the egg wash and gently press down any points, then brush the egg wash lightly all over the puffs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Bake for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Reduce the oven temperature to 350˚F (180˚C), and continue to bake for 20 minutes more, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Transfer the puffs to a wire rack and cool until able to handle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Cut the tops off of the puffs with a serrated knife. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Make the whipped cream: add the heavy cream and powdered sugar to the chilled bowl and beat with an electric hand mixer or whisk until stiff peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Transfer the whipped cream to a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a round tip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Pipe mounds of whipped cream into the puffs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Add the tops of the puffs and decorate with the chocolate faces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>