<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chili Cheese Burger Bowls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chili-cheese-burger-bowls</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 tablespoons ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; white onion, chopped ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 cloves ; garlic, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 lb ; ground beef ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">14.5 oz ; crushed tomato ; (410 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">6 oz ; tomato paste ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; light brown sugar, packed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ teaspoon ; ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 tablespoon ; chili powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 teaspoon ; ground cumin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ cup ; water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 ⅔ cups ; grated parmesan cheese ; (295 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 lb ; ground beef, divided into 8 patties ; (905 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">1 cup ; shredded cheddar cheese ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">8 ; brioche burger buns </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Game Day</category>
    <category num="4">BBQ</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/102784/hls24_1532367655.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/102784/landscape_720/1532367655</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Heat the olive oil in a large pot with a lid over medium heat until shimmering. Add the onion and garlic and sauté for 2 minutes, until translucent. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the ground beef and cook until browned, about 7-10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the crushed tomatoes, tomato paste, brown sugar, salt, ground pepper, paprika, chili powder, ground cumin, and stir to combine. Add water and stir. Bring to a boil, then reduce the heat to low, cover, and simmer for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Set a wire cooling rack on top of a baking sheet. Place a metal 1-cup (240 ml) measuring cup upside down on top of the cooling rack. </step>
    <step num="4">In a medium non-stick skillet over medium heat, pour ⅓ cup (35 g) of Parmesan in the center of the pan and spread out into a thin circle, about 5 inches across. Without disturbing the cheese, melt for 2-3 minutes, or until golden and fully melted. </step>
    <step num="5">Once the cheese is fully melted, run a spatula along the edges of the cheese and shake the pan to loosen the cheese circle. Carefully slide the melted cheese over the inverted measuring cup to form a cheese bowl. DO NOT TOUCH, it is extremely hot. Set aside and let cool completely, about ten minutes. Repeat with the rest of the Parmesan to make 8 bowls. </step>
    <step num="6">Lightly grease a large skillet over high heat, then add the beef patties (in batches, if necessary) and season generously with salt and pepper. Cook for 2 minutes without disturbing, then flip and cook for another 3 minutes, or until the internal temperature has reached at least 165˚F (75˚C). </step>
    <step num="7">To assemble, place a bottom burger bun on a plate and put a cheese bowl on top. Lay a burger patty inside the cheese bowl and top with a spoonful of chili, a sprinkle of shredded cheddar cheese, and the top bun. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Heat the olive oil in a large pot with a lid over medium heat until shimmering. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the onion and garlic and sauté for 2 minutes, until translucent. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the ground beef and cook until browned, about 7-10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the crushed tomatoes, tomato paste, brown sugar, salt, ground pepper, paprika, chili powder, ground cumin, and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add water and stir. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Bring to a boil, then reduce the heat to low, cover, and simmer for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Set a wire cooling rack on top of a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Place a metal 1-cup (240 ml) measuring cup upside down on top of the cooling rack. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">In a medium non-stick skillet over medium heat, pour ⅓ cup (35 g) of Parmesan in the center of the pan and spread out into a thin circle, about 5 inches across. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Without disturbing the cheese, melt for 2-3 minutes, or until golden and fully melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Once the cheese is fully melted, run a spatula along the edges of the cheese and shake the pan to loosen the cheese circle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Carefully slide the melted cheese over the inverted measuring cup to form a cheese bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">DO NOT TOUCH, it is extremely hot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Set aside and let cool completely, about ten minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Repeat with the rest of the Parmesan to make 8 bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Lightly grease a large skillet over high heat, then add the beef patties (in batches, if necessary) and season generously with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Cook for 2 minutes without disturbing, then flip and cook for another 3 minutes, or until the internal temperature has reached at least 165˚F (75˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">To assemble, place a bottom burger bun on a plate and put a cheese bowl on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Lay a burger patty inside the cheese bowl and top with a spoonful of chili, a sprinkle of shredded cheddar cheese, and the top bun. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>