<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Healthier Froyo Cookie Sandwiches Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/healthier-froyo-cookie-sandwiches</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; greek yogurt ; (570 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 tablespoons ; honey </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 stalk ; vanilla bean, scraped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 cups ; rolled oats, or 1 1/2 cups (150 grams) oat flour ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; coconut oil, melted ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; honey ; (85 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 teaspoons ; vanilla </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ cup ; dark chocolate chips ; (90 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/34215/low_1497550559.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/34215/mp4_720x1280/1497550559</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 375˚F (190˚C.) </step>
    <step num="1">Combine the Greek yogurt, honey, and vanilla in a bowl. Transfer to a freezer-safe container and freeze for 2 hours, or until consistency is thick and creamy but still scoopable. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the rolled oats to a bowl of a food processor and pulse until it becomes a flour-like consistency. </step>
    <step num="3">Combine coconut oil, honey, vanilla, and egg in a large bowl. Add in oats, baking soda, and a pinch of salt and mix until thoroughly incorporated. Fold in chocolate chips. </step>
    <step num="4">Using an ice cream scoop or a tablespoon, form 8 balls of cookie dough and place onto a baking sheet lined with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="5">Using your hands or the back of a spoon, press down firmly on each ball to form a cookie shape. Bake for 8-10 minutes, or until golden brown on the edges. </step>
    <step num="6">Let cool for about 10 minutes. While the cookies are cooling, you may want to remove ice cream from the freezer and let sit out to soften. </step>
    <step num="7">Flip cookies over so the flat sides are facing up. Add one scoop of frozen yogurt to 4 of the cookies. Use the remaining 4 cookies to form sandwiches by placing on top of the ice cream scoop and pressing down very gently to slowly spread out the ice cream. Feel free to use a spoon to smooth out the ice cream instead. </step>
    <step num="8">Freeze for 1 hour, or to your liking. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 375˚F (190˚C.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Combine the Greek yogurt, honey, and vanilla in a bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Transfer to a freezer-safe container and freeze for 2 hours, or until consistency is thick and creamy but still scoopable. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the rolled oats to a bowl of a food processor and pulse until it becomes a flour-like consistency. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Combine coconut oil, honey, vanilla, and egg in a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add in oats, baking soda, and a pinch of salt and mix until thoroughly incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Fold in chocolate chips. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Using an ice cream scoop or a tablespoon, form 8 balls of cookie dough and place onto a baking sheet lined with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Using your hands or the back of a spoon, press down firmly on each ball to form a cookie shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Bake for 8-10 minutes, or until golden brown on the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Let cool for about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">While the cookies are cooling, you may want to remove ice cream from the freezer and let sit out to soften. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Flip cookies over so the flat sides are facing up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add one scoop of frozen yogurt to 4 of the cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Use the remaining 4 cookies to form sandwiches by placing on top of the ice cream scoop and pressing down very gently to slowly spread out the ice cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Feel free to use a spoon to smooth out the ice cream instead. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Freeze for 1 hour, or to your liking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>