<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Strawberry Lemonade Pie Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/strawberry-lemonade-pie</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 cups ; whole wheat pastry flour, plus more for dusting ; (390 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 cups ; freeze-dried strawberry ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 tablespoons ; organic granulated sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; pink himalayan salt, plus a pinch, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¾ cup ; unsalted butter, 1 1/2 sticks, cubed and chilled ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">7 tablespoons ; ice water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 lb ; fresh strawberry , sliced ; (905 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¾ cup ; lemon curd ; (185 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 tablespoons ; cornstarch, dissolved in 1 tablespoon water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ; large egg, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 tablespoons ; turbinado sugar </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/107616/hls24_1535740258.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/107616/landscape_720/1535740258</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a food processor, combine the flour, freeze-dried strawberries, sugar, and 1 teaspoon of salt. Pulse until the strawberries are fully incorporated into the flour. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the butter and pulse until it breaks down into pea-sized pieces. Do not over-mix. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the ice water 1 tablespoon at a time, pulsing between each addition, until the dough just holds together. </step>
    <step num="3">Transfer the dough to a clean work surface and divide into 2 discs, one slightly larger than the other. Cover with plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator while you prepare the filling. </step>
    <step num="4">In a medium pot over medium heat, combine the sliced strawberries, lemon curd, and a pinch of salt. Bring to a light boil, stirring occasionally. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the cornstarch slurry and simmer for 5-10 minutes, or until the filling thickens. Remove from the heat and let cool. </step>
    <step num="6">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </step>
    <step num="7">Remove the larger disc of dough from the fridge and sprinkle with flour. Roll out to about ⅛ inch (3 mm) thick and transfer to a greased 9½-inch (24-cm) pie dish, pressing down to form the bottom crust. Cut off any excess dough around the edges and set aside. Chill the bottom crust while you roll out the top. </step>
    <step num="8">Roll out the smaller dough disc. Cut 6 1-inch-wide (2-cm) strips from the dough and place on a parchment-lined baking sheet. Combine all of the excess dough, re-roll it, and use a cookie cutter to cut out shapes of your choosing. Add to the baking sheet and chill the strips and shapes for 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Remove the bottom crust from the fridge and poke holes all over the bottom with a fork. Pour the strawberry filling into the crust. </step>
    <step num="10">Lay 3 of the dough strips vertically and evenly spaced across the top of the pie, and lay the other 3 horizontally. Place a cutout shape at the intersection of every vertical and horizontal strip. Trim the edges of the dough, then crimp with a fork all the way around. </step>
    <step num="11">Brush the crust with the beaten egg, then sprinkle with turbinado sugar. </step>
    <step num="12">Bake for 30-40 minutes, or until the crust is golden brown. </step>
    <step num="13">Let cool, then chill in the refrigerator until ready to serve. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a food processor, combine the flour, freeze-dried strawberries, sugar, and 1 teaspoon of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pulse until the strawberries are fully incorporated into the flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the butter and pulse until it breaks down into pea-sized pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Do not over-mix. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the ice water 1 tablespoon at a time, pulsing between each addition, until the dough just holds together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Transfer the dough to a clean work surface and divide into 2 discs, one slightly larger than the other. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cover with plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator while you prepare the filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a medium pot over medium heat, combine the sliced strawberries, lemon curd, and a pinch of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Bring to a light boil, stirring occasionally. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the cornstarch slurry and simmer for 5-10 minutes, or until the filling thickens. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Remove from the heat and let cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove the larger disc of dough from the fridge and sprinkle with flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Roll out to about ⅛ inch (3 mm) thick and transfer to a greased 9½-inch (24-cm) pie dish, pressing down to form the bottom crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Cut off any excess dough around the edges and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Chill the bottom crust while you roll out the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Roll out the smaller dough disc. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cut 6 1-inch-wide (2-cm) strips from the dough and place on a parchment-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Combine all of the excess dough, re-roll it, and use a cookie cutter to cut out shapes of your choosing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add to the baking sheet and chill the strips and shapes for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Remove the bottom crust from the fridge and poke holes all over the bottom with a fork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Pour the strawberry filling into the crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Lay 3 of the dough strips vertically and evenly spaced across the top of the pie, and lay the other 3 horizontally. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Place a cutout shape at the intersection of every vertical and horizontal strip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Trim the edges of the dough, then crimp with a fork all the way around. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Brush the crust with the beaten egg, then sprinkle with turbinado sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Bake for 30-40 minutes, or until the crust is golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Let cool, then chill in the refrigerator until ready to serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>