<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Sherry Mushrooms With Creamy Polenta And Gremolata Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/sherry-mushrooms-with-creamy-polenta-and-gremolata</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 cups ; water ; (720 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; polenta ; (160 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; milk, of your choice ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; grated parmesan cheese ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">olive oil, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 ; medium shallots, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">4 sprigs ; fresh thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 lb ; mixed mushroom, such as shiitake and cremini, steams trimmed, sliced ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ cup ; dry sherry ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">¼ cup ; vegetable stock ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">2 cloves ; garlic, grated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 bunch ; fresh parsley, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">2 lemons ; lemon zest </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Italian</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Dinner</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117902/hls24_1543860467.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117902/landscape_720/1543860467</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the polenta: Bring salted water to boil in a medium pot over medium-high heat. Pour in the polenta and stir for 2 minutes. Reduce the heat to low, cover, and simmer for 30 minutes, stirring every 10 minutes to make sure the polenta isn’t sticking or burning. </step>
    <step num="1">Right before serving, stir the milk, Parmesan, and butter into the polenta. Season with salt and pepper to taste. </step>
    <step num="2">Meanwhile, make the mushrooms: Heat a drizzle of olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat. Add the shallots and sweat until softened and slightly translucent, about 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Season with salt, then add the thyme leaves and mushrooms. Cook until the mushrooms are caramelized and softened, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Pour in the sherry to deglaze the pan and stir to loosen any browned bits from the bottom. Cook off the alcohol, about 1 minute. Add the vegetable stock and season with salt and pepper. Bring to a boil, then let the liquid reduce for about 10 minutes. Remove from the heat. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the gremolata: In a small bowl, combine the garlic, parsley, and lemon zest. Season with salt to taste. </step>
    <step num="6">Divide the hot polenta between serving bowls and top with the mushrooms and gremolata. </step>
    <step num="7">Nutrition, all included

Calories: 413
Total fat: 22 grams 
Sodium: 1351 mg
Total carbs: 42 grams
Dietary fiber: 6 grams
Sugars: 6 grams
Protein: 15 grams </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the polenta: Bring salted water to boil in a medium pot over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pour in the polenta and stir for 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Reduce the heat to low, cover, and simmer for 30 minutes, stirring every 10 minutes to make sure the polenta isn’t sticking or burning. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Right before serving, stir the milk, Parmesan, and butter into the polenta. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Season with salt and pepper to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Meanwhile, make the mushrooms: Heat a drizzle of olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the shallots and sweat until softened and slightly translucent, about 2 minutes </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Season with salt, then add the thyme leaves and mushrooms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Cook until the mushrooms are caramelized and softened, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Pour in the sherry to deglaze the pan and stir to loosen any browned bits from the bottom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Cook off the alcohol, about 1 minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the vegetable stock and season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Bring to a boil, then let the liquid reduce for about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Make the gremolata: In a small bowl, combine the garlic, parsley, and lemon zest. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Season with salt to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Divide the hot polenta between serving bowls and top with the mushrooms and gremolata. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Nutrition, all included

Calories: 413
Total fat: 22 grams 
Sodium: 1351 mg
Total carbs: 42 grams
Dietary fiber: 6 grams
Sugars: 6 grams
Protein: 15 grams </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>