<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Strawberry Cream-Stuffed Pastries Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/strawberry-cream-stuffed-pastries</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; strawberry, stemmed, quartered ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">16 oz ; cream cheese ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; powdered sugar ; (70 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; milk ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ; large egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">11 oz ; puff pastry, 1 packages, thawed ; (310 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 tablespoons ; powdered sugar, for dusting </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">chocolate syrup, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Fusion</category>
    <category num="7">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="8">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="9">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/93400/hls24_1525907474.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/93400/landscape_720/1525907474</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a food processor or blender, puree the strawberries until smooth. </step>
    <step num="1">Pour the strawberry puree through a sieve into a medium bowl to remove any seeds and clumps. Chill for 15 minutes, until the puree is cold. </step>
    <step num="2">In a separate large bowl, beat the cream cheese and ½ cup (80 g) of powdered sugar together with an electric hand mixer. Mix in the milk and strawberry puree. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">In a small bowl, whisk the beaten egg and water together. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </step>
    <step num="5">Roll a foot-long (30 cm) piece of aluminum foil into a tube. Repeat with 3 more pieces of foil to make 4 tubes total. </step>
    <step num="6">On a cutting board, roll the puff pastry out to 13 inches (33 cm) by 13 inches (33 cm). Slice the puff pastry lengthwise into 1½ inch-wide (4 cm) strips. </step>
    <step num="7">Wrap 2 of the strips around a foil tube, brushing the edges with egg wash and gently pressing together to adhere. Repeat with the remaining pastry strips and foil tubes. </step>
    <step num="8">Balance the ends of the foil tubes over the edges of a roasting pan or baking sheet so the pastry isn’t touching the surface of the pan. Brush egg wash all over the pastry spirals. </step>
    <step num="9">Bake for 25 minutes, until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="10">Let the pastry tubes rest at room temperature for 5 minutes. Gently remove the foil tubes. Transfer the pastry tubes to a baking sheet lined with parchment paper and bake for 5 more minutes. Let cool to room temperature. </step>
    <step num="11">Fill a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a round tip with the cream cheese mixture. Pipe the cream cheese filling into the pastry tubes. </step>
    <step num="12">Dust with powdered sugar and drizzle with chocolate syrup. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a food processor or blender, puree the strawberries until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pour the strawberry puree through a sieve into a medium bowl to remove any seeds and clumps. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Chill for 15 minutes, until the puree is cold. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a separate large bowl, beat the cream cheese and ½ cup (80 g) of powdered sugar together with an electric hand mixer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Mix in the milk and strawberry puree. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a small bowl, whisk the beaten egg and water together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Roll a foot-long (30 cm) piece of aluminum foil into a tube. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Repeat with 3 more pieces of foil to make 4 tubes total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">On a cutting board, roll the puff pastry out to 13 inches (33 cm) by 13 inches (33 cm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Slice the puff pastry lengthwise into 1½ inch-wide (4 cm) strips. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Wrap 2 of the strips around a foil tube, brushing the edges with egg wash and gently pressing together to adhere. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Repeat with the remaining pastry strips and foil tubes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Balance the ends of the foil tubes over the edges of a roasting pan or baking sheet so the pastry isn’t touching the surface of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Brush egg wash all over the pastry spirals. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Bake for 25 minutes, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Let the pastry tubes rest at room temperature for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Gently remove the foil tubes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Transfer the pastry tubes to a baking sheet lined with parchment paper and bake for 5 more minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Let cool to room temperature. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Fill a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a round tip with the cream cheese mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Pipe the cream cheese filling into the pastry tubes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Dust with powdered sugar and drizzle with chocolate syrup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>