<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Cheddar-Crusted &amp; Bacon Broccoli Quiche Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/cheddar-crusted-bacon-broccoli-quiche</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ½ cups ; shredded cheddar cheese, divided ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; unsalted butter, 2 sticks, room temperature ; (230 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 cups ; all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 ½ teaspoons ; salt, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">5 tablespoons ; ice water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">4 strips ; bacon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 cups ; small broccoli floret ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">6 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; milk ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">pie weights, coffee beans, or dried beans </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">French</category>
    <category num="1">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="2">Brunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/112990/hls24_1540318024.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/112990/landscape_720/1540318024</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Add 2 cups (200 g) of cheddar cheese and the butter to a large bowl. Mix to combine with an electric hand mixer or stand mixer. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the flour, paprika, garlic powder, and 2 teaspoons salt and mix well. Add 3 tablespoons of ice water and mix. Add the remaining ice water 1 tablespoon at a time. The dough should hold together when pinched, but crumble apart if you break it up in your hand. If it seems too dry, add a bit more ice water. </step>
    <step num="3">Transfer the dough to a clean surface and knead with your hands until it comes together. Shape the dough into a disc, then wrap in plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Lightly flour a clean surface and roll out the dough into a circle about ⅛ inch (8 mm) thick. Carefully transfer the crust to a 9½-inch (24-cm) glass pie dish. </step>
    <step num="5">Trim the edges (save the trimmings to make crackers!). Poke holes in the bottom of the crust with a fork, then use the tines to crimp the edges. Line the dough with parchment paper and fill with pie weights. </step>
    <step num="6">Bake for 30 minutes, until the edges are crisp. </step>
    <step num="7">While the crust is baking, prepare the fillings. In a large skillet over medium-high heat, cook the bacon until crisp, 5-7 minutes. Using tongs, remove the bacon from the skillet and let drain on paper towels until cool enough to handle. </step>
    <step num="8">Add the broccoli to the skillet and cook until lightly browned, about 5 minutes. Remove the pan from the heat. </step>
    <step num="9">Chop the bacon. </step>
    <step num="10">Remove the pie weights from the crust, then add the broccoli and chopped bacon to the center. Sprinkle with the remaining shredded cheddar cheese. </step>
    <step num="11">In a medium bowl, lightly beat the eggs. Add the milk, remaining ½ teaspoon salt, and the pepper. Whisk to combine. </step>
    <step num="12">Pour the egg mixture over the fillings in the crust. </step>
    <step num="13">Bake for 35-40 minutes, or until the eggs are set and the top is lightly browned. Cover the edges with tinfoil if they are starting to burn. </step>
    <step num="14">Let the quiche cool for 15 minutes before slicing and serving. </step>
    <step num="15">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add 2 cups (200 g) of cheddar cheese and the butter to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Mix to combine with an electric hand mixer or stand mixer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the flour, paprika, garlic powder, and 2 teaspoons salt and mix well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add 3 tablespoons of ice water and mix. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the remaining ice water 1 tablespoon at a time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">The dough should hold together when pinched, but crumble apart if you break it up in your hand. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">If it seems too dry, add a bit more ice water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Transfer the dough to a clean surface and knead with your hands until it comes together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Shape the dough into a disc, then wrap in plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Lightly flour a clean surface and roll out the dough into a circle about ⅛ inch (8 mm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Carefully transfer the crust to a 9½-inch (24-cm) glass pie dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Trim the edges (save the trimmings to make crackers!). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Poke holes in the bottom of the crust with a fork, then use the tines to crimp the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Line the dough with parchment paper and fill with pie weights. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Bake for 30 minutes, until the edges are crisp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">While the crust is baking, prepare the fillings. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">In a large skillet over medium-high heat, cook the bacon until crisp, 5-7 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Using tongs, remove the bacon from the skillet and let drain on paper towels until cool enough to handle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add the broccoli to the skillet and cook until lightly browned, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Remove the pan from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Chop the bacon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Remove the pie weights from the crust, then add the broccoli and chopped bacon to the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Sprinkle with the remaining shredded cheddar cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">In a medium bowl, lightly beat the eggs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Add the milk, remaining ½ teaspoon salt, and the pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Pour the egg mixture over the fillings in the crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Bake for 35-40 minutes, or until the eggs are set and the top is lightly browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Cover the edges with tinfoil if they are starting to burn. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Let the quiche cool for 15 minutes before slicing and serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>