<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Mini Caramel Apple Tarts (Tarte Tatin) Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/mini-caramel-apple-tarts-tarte-tatin</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 ; apples, for one muffin tin's worth of apples, preferably Pink Lady or Braeburn </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ ; lemon, juiced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 sheet ; puff pastry </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">large muffin tin </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">French</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Date Night</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31917/low_1495124869.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31917/mp4_720x1280/1495124869</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">To begin, peel, halve, and core your apples (melon ballers make a good tool for coring halved apples). You’ll need one apple for every two tarts. </step>
    <step num="1">In a medium sauce pan, about 3 quarts (1 liter), slowly heat sugar. You’ll want to stir frequently until it dissolves into a brown syrup. Melt 1 tablespoon of butter into the sugar, stirring frequently. Add a dash of salt and the juice from ½ lemon. </step>
    <step num="2">Lower the heat as low as it will go and add your apple halves. Toss to coat with caramel and let simmer 5–10 minutes until tender, flipping once. </step>
    <step num="3">Cut puff pastry into circles to fit just within the top of your muffin tin. </step>
    <step num="4">Place apple halves curve-side down in a large muffin tin. Pour remaining caramel over each apple half. Top with a circle of puff pastry to fit just inside the muffin tin. </step>
    <step num="5">Bake 14–20 minutes at 450°F (230°C). Invert muffin pan onto baking sheet immediately. Serve with vanilla ice cream. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">To begin, peel, halve, and core your apples (melon ballers make a good tool for coring halved apples). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">You’ll need one apple for every two tarts. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a medium sauce pan, about 3 quarts (1 liter), slowly heat sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">You’ll want to stir frequently until it dissolves into a brown syrup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Melt 1 tablespoon of butter into the sugar, stirring frequently. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add a dash of salt and the juice from ½ lemon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Lower the heat as low as it will go and add your apple halves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Toss to coat with caramel and let simmer 5–10 minutes until tender, flipping once. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Cut puff pastry into circles to fit just within the top of your muffin tin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Place apple halves curve-side down in a large muffin tin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Pour remaining caramel over each apple half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Top with a circle of puff pastry to fit just inside the muffin tin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Bake 14–20 minutes at 450°F (230°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Invert muffin pan onto baking sheet immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Serve with vanilla ice cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>