<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>One Pot Classic Ragu Lasagna Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/one-pot-classic-ragu-lasagna</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; ricotta cheese ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 oz ; cream cheese, room tempertature ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; grated parmesan cheese ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; large egg, lightly beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">⅛ teaspoon ; freshly ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">nonstick cooking spray </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 tablespoons ; extra virgin olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ; small yellow onion, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 stalk ; celery, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ; small carrot, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 lb ; ground beef ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ lb ; ground pork ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">½ lb ; ground lamb ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">freshly ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">½ cup ; dry red wine ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">2 tablespoons ; tomato paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">28 oz ; crushed tomato, 1 can ; (795 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">8 oz ; no-boil lasagna noodle, broken in half ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">2 cups ; shredded low-moisture mozzarella ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">¼ cup ; grated parmesan cheese, plus more for garnish ; (25 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">fresh flat-leaf parsley, finely chopped, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="25">garlic bread, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="5">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/112523/hls24_1539884704.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/112523/landscape_720/1539884704</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the cheese cubes: In a medium bowl, stir together the ricotta, cream cheese, Parmesan, egg, salt, and pepper until smooth. </step>
    <step num="1">Grease an ice cube tray with nonstick spray. Spoon the ricotta mixture evenly into the cups in the tray. Cover with plastic wrap and freeze until the cheese mixture is firm, at least 4 hours or up to 3 days. </step>
    <step num="2">Make the lasagna: Heat a large pot over medium-high heat. Add the olive oil and butter to the pot and swirl to evenly coat. Add the onion, celery, and carrot and cook, stirring frequently, until softened and starting to caramelize, 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the ground beef, pork, and lamb and cook, stirring to break up the meat, until no longer pink, 12 minutes. Season with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the red wine and cook, stirring, until completely evaporated, 3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the tomato paste and garlic, and cook, stirring frequently, until lightly caramelized, about 3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Pour in the crushed tomatoes, reduce the heat to medium, and cook the sauce, stirring, until slightly reduced, 6-8 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Unmold the frozen cheese cubes, then distribute them evenly throughout the simmering meat sauce. Using your fingers or a pair of tongs, insert the noodle pieces vertically in the sauce around the pot. Cover the pot. </step>
    <step num="8">Cook for 18 minutes, then uncover the pot and use a spatula to push down the exposed noodles so they are covered in sauce. Cover and cook for 18 minutes more, until the noodles are tender. </step>
    <step num="9">Remove the lid and sprinkle the mozzarella and Parmesan cheese over the top. Cover and cook until the cheese is melted, about 5 minutes. Remove the pot from the heat. </step>
    <step num="10">Sprinkle the lasagna with parsley and more Parmesan, if desired, and serve with garlic bread alongside. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the cheese cubes: In a medium bowl, stir together the ricotta, cream cheese, Parmesan, egg, salt, and pepper until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Grease an ice cube tray with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Spoon the ricotta mixture evenly into the cups in the tray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cover with plastic wrap and freeze until the cheese mixture is firm, at least 4 hours or up to 3 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Make the lasagna: Heat a large pot over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the olive oil and butter to the pot and swirl to evenly coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the onion, celery, and carrot and cook, stirring frequently, until softened and starting to caramelize, 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the ground beef, pork, and lamb and cook, stirring to break up the meat, until no longer pink, 12 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the red wine and cook, stirring, until completely evaporated, 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the tomato paste and garlic, and cook, stirring frequently, until lightly caramelized, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Pour in the crushed tomatoes, reduce the heat to medium, and cook the sauce, stirring, until slightly reduced, 6-8 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Unmold the frozen cheese cubes, then distribute them evenly throughout the simmering meat sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Using your fingers or a pair of tongs, insert the noodle pieces vertically in the sauce around the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Cover the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cook for 18 minutes, then uncover the pot and use a spatula to push down the exposed noodles so they are covered in sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Cover and cook for 18 minutes more, until the noodles are tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Remove the lid and sprinkle the mozzarella and Parmesan cheese over the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Cover and cook until the cheese is melted, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Remove the pot from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Sprinkle the lasagna with parsley and more Parmesan, if desired, and serve with garlic bread alongside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>