<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Vegan Challah Bread Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/vegan-challah-bread</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1.25 oz ; yeast ; (7 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; granulated sugar, plus 1 pinch granulated sugar, divided ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; warm water, plus 3 tablespoons warm water, divided ; (245 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">6 tablespoons ; coconut oil, melted, divided, plus more for greasing bowl </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 teaspoons ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 cups ; all-purpose flour, plus more as needed ; (375 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ½ teaspoons ; salt </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Vegan</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="5">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="6">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/91465/hls24_1524783759.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/91465/landscape_720/1524783759</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium bowl, combine the yeast and a pinch of sugar. Pour 1 cup (240 ml) of warm water over the yeast mixture while turning the bowl so it stirs itself. Rest for 5 minutes, or until the yeast has bloomed and is bubbly, then add 2 tablespoons of melted coconut oil. </step>
    <step num="1">In a separate medium bowl, mix 3 tablespoons of melted coconut oil, the remaining 3 tablespoons of warm water, and the baking powder. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large bowl, whisk together 3 cups (385 g) of flour, the table salt, and remaining ½ cup (110 g) of granulated sugar. While stirring, add the coconut oil and yeast mixtures to the dry ingredients and combine with a spoon. Once the dough is smooth, gradually add up to 1 cup (125 g) of flour and incorporate by kneading the dough with your hands (you may not need all of the flour). </step>
    <step num="3">Knead until the dough isn’t sticking to the sides of the bowl, then transfer to a large bowl greased with coconut oil. Cover with a damp towel and let rest on the counter for 2 hours, or until the dough has doubled in size. </step>
    <step num="4">Punch down the dough and turn out onto a floured workspace. Knead gently to get out any large air bubbles, and form into a log shape. Depending on the braid you are planning to do, cut the dough into the appropriate amount of even pieces. </step>
    <step num="5">Braid into desired shape (braiding options below) and transfer to a baking sheet lined with parchment paper. Cover with a damp towel and let rise again for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="6">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (165˚C). </step>
    <step num="7">Lightly brush the challah with melted coconut oil for a nice shine and bake for 25-30 minutes, brushing with more coconut oil halfway through, until golden brown. To check for doneness try knocking on the bottom of the bread. If it sounds hollow, it’s done! </step>
    <step num="8">Cool completely on a wire rack before slicing. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium bowl, combine the yeast and a pinch of sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pour 1 cup (240 ml) of warm water over the yeast mixture while turning the bowl so it stirs itself. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Rest for 5 minutes, or until the yeast has bloomed and is bubbly, then add 2 tablespoons of melted coconut oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a separate medium bowl, mix 3 tablespoons of melted coconut oil, the remaining 3 tablespoons of warm water, and the baking powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a large bowl, whisk together 3 cups (385 g) of flour, the table salt, and remaining ½ cup (110 g) of granulated sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">While stirring, add the coconut oil and yeast mixtures to the dry ingredients and combine with a spoon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Once the dough is smooth, gradually add up to 1 cup (125 g) of flour and incorporate by kneading the dough with your hands (you may not need all of the flour). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Knead until the dough isn’t sticking to the sides of the bowl, then transfer to a large bowl greased with coconut oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Cover with a damp towel and let rest on the counter for 2 hours, or until the dough has doubled in size. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Punch down the dough and turn out onto a floured workspace. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Knead gently to get out any large air bubbles, and form into a log shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Depending on the braid you are planning to do, cut the dough into the appropriate amount of even pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Braid into desired shape (braiding options below) and transfer to a baking sheet lined with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Cover with a damp towel and let rise again for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (165˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Lightly brush the challah with melted coconut oil for a nice shine and bake for 25-30 minutes, brushing with more coconut oil halfway through, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">To check for doneness try knocking on the bottom of the bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">If it sounds hollow, it’s done! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Cool completely on a wire rack before slicing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>