<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>American Flag Cake Pops Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/american-flag-cake-pops</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 box ; red velvet cake mix, baked according to package instructions and cooled completely </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">⅔ cup ; vanilla frosting ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">4 cups ; white chocolate chip, divided ; (700 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">4 teaspoons ; coconut oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; sprinkles, blue ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ cup ; sprinkles, red ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">36 ; lollipop sticks, 4 in (10 cm) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; hard foam, 10x12x1in (25x30x1 cm) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="2">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/137485/hls24_1561677355.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/137485/landscape_720/1561677355</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, crumble the cake into fine, uniform crumbs. Add the vanilla frosting and mix thoroughly. </step>
    <step num="1">Scoop about 2 tablespoons of the cake mixture at a time and roll into balls. You should have 36 total. </step>
    <step num="2">Working with half of the white chocolate chips and half of the coconut oil at a time so the mixture stays melted, combine in a medium bowl and microwave on medium heat in 30-second intervals until melted, about 2 minutes. Stir until smooth. </step>
    <step num="3">Dip ½ inch (1 ¼ cm) of each lollipop stick in the melted white chocolate mixture. Insert each stick ½ inch (1 ¼ cm) into the center of a cake ball. Refrigerate for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Make the cake pop stand: Use a marker to mark 36 evenly spaced dots on the foam. Use a lollipop stick to make holes where the dots are, about ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) deep. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the blue cake pops: Working in batches of 3, dip 9 cake pops in the melted white chocolate, using a spoon to help coat. Let the excess drip off. Sprinkle the pops with blue sprinkles. Place the cake pops 3 x 3 (7 x 7 cm) in the upper left corner of the cake pop stand. Note: If the melted white chocolate is dripping down the lollipop stick, allow the mixture to cool for 5 minutes before trying again. If the white chocolate cools too much, microwave for 15 seconds. </step>
    <step num="6">Make the red cake pops: Working in batches of 3, dip the remaining 27 cake pops in the melted white chocolate, using a spoon to help coat. Let the excess drip off. Carefully dip one side of the cake pop into the red sprinkle mixture. Let sit in sprinkles for 30 seconds to set. Let dry completely in the stand, with the sprinkles positioned towards the top of the cake stand. Let the cake pops dry completely. Store at room temperature for up to 2 days before serving. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, crumble the cake into fine, uniform crumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the vanilla frosting and mix thoroughly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Scoop about 2 tablespoons of the cake mixture at a time and roll into balls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">You should have 36 total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Working with half of the white chocolate chips and half of the coconut oil at a time so the mixture stays melted, combine in a medium bowl and microwave on medium heat in 30-second intervals until melted, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Stir until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Dip ½ inch (1 ¼ cm) of each lollipop stick in the melted white chocolate mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Insert each stick ½ inch (1 ¼ cm) into the center of a cake ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Refrigerate for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Make the cake pop stand: Use a marker to mark 36 evenly spaced dots on the foam. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Use a lollipop stick to make holes where the dots are, about ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) deep. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Make the blue cake pops: Working in batches of 3, dip 9 cake pops in the melted white chocolate, using a spoon to help coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Let the excess drip off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Sprinkle the pops with blue sprinkles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Place the cake pops 3 x 3 (7 x 7 cm) in the upper left corner of the cake pop stand. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Note: If the melted white chocolate is dripping down the lollipop stick, allow the mixture to cool for 5 minutes before trying again. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">If the white chocolate cools too much, microwave for 15 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Make the red cake pops: Working in batches of 3, dip the remaining 27 cake pops in the melted white chocolate, using a spoon to help coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Let the excess drip off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Carefully dip one side of the cake pop into the red sprinkle mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Let sit in sprinkles for 30 seconds to set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Let dry completely in the stand, with the sprinkles positioned towards the top of the cake stand. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Let the cake pops dry completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Store at room temperature for up to 2 days before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>