<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Pesto Salmon Puff Pastry Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/pesto-salmon-puff-pastry</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ cup ; pesto sauce ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 sheets ; frozen puff pastry, thawed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">9 oz ; salmon fillet ; (255 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">5 leaves ; fresh basil, julienned </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 ; eggs, beaten </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Seafood</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/91190/hls24_1524694183.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/91190/landscape_720/1524694183</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">In a small bowl lined with a strainer, strain the pesto. Set aside the pesto and pesto oil. </step>
    <step num="2">Gently unfold and unroll 1 sheet of puff pastry. Roll out to 11 inches (28 cm) by 16 inches (40 cm). Transfer the puff pastry to the baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="3">Spread half of the pesto onto the middle of the puff pastry in the shape of the salmon fillet. Place the salmon on top of the pesto. Season with salt and pepper. Spread more pesto on top of the salmon. </step>
    <step num="4">Place the other sheet of puff pastry on top of the salmon and press around the salmon fillet to seal. Cut a fish silhouette around the salmon and remove the excess puff pastry. </step>
    <step num="5">Unfold the head flap of the fish pastry. Brush pesto on the puff pastry and layer a small piece of puff pastry on top of the pesto. Repeat once more and refold the head flap. </step>
    <step num="6">Seal the edges by pressing onto the seams of the fish silhouette. </step>
    <step num="7">Use a knife to make indents for the head and fin details. </step>
    <step num="8">Use the tip of the spoon to create indents of the scales. </step>
    <step num="9">Brush the pastry with egg wash. </step>
    <step num="10">Bake for 40 minutes, or until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="11">In a small bowl combine the pesto oil and basil. Brush the pastry with the basil pesto oil. </step>
    <step num="12">Slice and serve while hot. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a small bowl lined with a strainer, strain the pesto. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set aside the pesto and pesto oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Gently unfold and unroll 1 sheet of puff pastry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Roll out to 11 inches (28 cm) by 16 inches (40 cm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Transfer the puff pastry to the baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Spread half of the pesto onto the middle of the puff pastry in the shape of the salmon fillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Place the salmon on top of the pesto. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Spread more pesto on top of the salmon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place the other sheet of puff pastry on top of the salmon and press around the salmon fillet to seal. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cut a fish silhouette around the salmon and remove the excess puff pastry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Unfold the head flap of the fish pastry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Brush pesto on the puff pastry and layer a small piece of puff pastry on top of the pesto. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Repeat once more and refold the head flap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Seal the edges by pressing onto the seams of the fish silhouette. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Use a knife to make indents for the head and fin details. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Use the tip of the spoon to create indents of the scales. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Brush the pastry with egg wash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Bake for 40 minutes, or until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">In a small bowl combine the pesto oil and basil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Brush the pastry with the basil pesto oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Slice and serve while hot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>