<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Tornado Potatoes Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/tornado-potato</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ; medium Yukon potatoes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 tablespoons ; butter, melted ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; grated parmesan cheese, plus more for serving ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">Chopped fresh parsley, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 ; wooden skewers </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">British</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/10655/low_1474665637.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/10655/mp4_720x1280/1474665637</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 325ºF (160ºC). </step>
    <step num="1">Microwave the potatoes for 1-1 ½ minutes, then leave in the microwave for a few minutes to cool down and soften. Insert a wooden skewer into the bottom of each potato and gently push it all the way through the top. Working in a spiral motion from one side to the other, hold a sharp, thin knife at an angle and cut in the opposite direction you are turning the skewered potato, cutting all the way down to the skewer. Take your time and work to make thin, even spiral all the way down the potato. </step>
    <step num="2">Gently fan out each potato down the length of the skewer, until you have even gaps between the slices. Brush the melted butter all over the potatoes. </step>
    <step num="3">In a medium bowl, combine the Parmesan cheese, pepper, garlic powder, paprika, and salt. Place each skewered potato over the bowl and sprinkle half of the spice mixture over each potato until they are entirely coated. Carefully set the potatoes on a baking pan, letting the skewers rest on sides of the pan so that the potatoes are suspended. </step>
    <step num="4">Bake for 25-30 minutes, or until nicely browned. Garnish with additional Parmesan and parsley. Let cool for 5 minutes before serving. </step>
    <step num="5">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 325ºF (160ºC). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Microwave the potatoes for 1-1 ½ minutes, then leave in the microwave for a few minutes to cool down and soften. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Insert a wooden skewer into the bottom of each potato and gently push it all the way through the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Working in a spiral motion from one side to the other, hold a sharp, thin knife at an angle and cut in the opposite direction you are turning the skewered potato, cutting all the way down to the skewer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Take your time and work to make thin, even spiral all the way down the potato </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Gently fan out each potato down the length of the skewer, until you have even gaps between the slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Brush the melted butter all over the potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a medium bowl, combine the Parmesan cheese, pepper, garlic powder, paprika, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Place each skewered potato over the bowl and sprinkle half of the spice mixture over each potato until they are entirely coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Carefully set the potatoes on a baking pan, letting the skewers rest on sides of the pan so that the potatoes are suspended. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Bake for 25-30 minutes, or until nicely browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Garnish with additional Parmesan and parsley. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Let cool for 5 minutes before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>