<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Thai Tofu Collard Wraps Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/thai-tofu-collard-wraps</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">6 leaves ; collard green </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 tablespoons ; light soy sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; red pepper flakes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">16 oz ; extra firm tofu, 1 package, cut into 1/2x2-inch (1x5-cm) strips ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; sesame oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; medium cucumber, peeled and julienned </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; medium carrot, shredded </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 tablespoons ; fresh thai basil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 tablespoons ; fresh mint </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 ; scallions, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ cup ; unsweetened natural peanut butter ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 tablespoon ; sriracha </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">4 teaspoons ; toasted sesame oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 tablespoon ; honey </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">2 tablespoons ; lime juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 tablespoon ; water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Thai</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Healthy</category>
    <category num="4">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="5">Vegan</category>
    <category num="6">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="7">Lunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117247/hls24_1543454993.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117247/landscape_720/1543454993</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil over high heat. </step>
    <step num="1">While the water heats up, prepare the collard green leaves. Trim the stems, then, using a paring knife, carefully remove the thick part of the stem from the leaf. Working parallel to the leaf, shave off any excess stem so that it is flush with the leaf and will roll easily. Repeat with each collard. </step>
    <step num="2">Blanch each collard green leaf in the boiling water for 1 minute, until softened and bright green. Remove from the water and immediately submerge in an ice bath for 1 minute, or until cool to the touch. Dry the collard greens on paper towels until ready to use. </step>
    <step num="3">Make the peanut sauce: In a medium bowl, combine the peanut butter, Sriracha, sesame oil, honey, lime juice, water, and salt. Whisk until smooth. </step>
    <step num="4">In a small bowl, mix together the soy sauce, garlic powder, and red pepper flakes. Pour over the tofu strips and marinate for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Heat the sesame oil in a medium pan over medium-high heat. Add the tofu strips and sear for 2 minutes on each side, until browned. Remove the tofu from the pan. </step>
    <step num="6">To build the wraps, lay a collard green leaf on a flat surface. Spread 2 teaspoons of peanut sauce across the center of the leaf. Lay 1 strip of tofu on top of the sauce, followed by 3-4 pieces of cucumber, 1 tablespoon shredded carrot, and a bit of mint, Thai basil, and scallions. </step>
    <step num="7">Fold one side of the leaf over the filling and dollop a bit of peanut sauce on top. Fold the other side of the leaf over the filling, and using the sauce to secure. Fold the bottom of the leaf up and over the filling. Tuck in all of the ingredients and roll until the bottom half has reached the top of the leaf. Spread a bit of sauce on the top of the leaf and roll to secure the wrap. Repeat with the remaining ingredients. </step>
    <step num="8">Cut in half on the diagonal, then serve with more peanut sauce for dipping, if desired. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
    <step num="10">Nutrition - Per Wrap - Calories: 282, Total fat: 18 grams, Sodium: 484, Total carbs: 21 grams, Dietary fiber: 11 grams, Sugars: 5 grams, Protein: 18 grams </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">While the water heats up, prepare the collard green leaves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Trim the stems, then, using a paring knife, carefully remove the thick part of the stem from the leaf. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Working parallel to the leaf, shave off any excess stem so that it is flush with the leaf and will roll easily. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Repeat with each collard. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Blanch each collard green leaf in the boiling water for 1 minute, until softened and bright green. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove from the water and immediately submerge in an ice bath for 1 minute, or until cool to the touch. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Dry the collard greens on paper towels until ready to use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Make the peanut sauce: In a medium bowl, combine the peanut butter, Sriracha, sesame oil, honey, lime juice, water, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Whisk until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a small bowl, mix together the soy sauce, garlic powder, and red pepper flakes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Pour over the tofu strips and marinate for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Heat the sesame oil in a medium pan over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the tofu strips and sear for 2 minutes on each side, until browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove the tofu from the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">To build the wraps, lay a collard green leaf on a flat surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Spread 2 teaspoons of peanut sauce across the center of the leaf. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Lay 1 strip of tofu on top of the sauce, followed by 3-4 pieces of cucumber, 1 tablespoon shredded carrot, and a bit of mint, Thai basil, and scallions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Fold one side of the leaf over the filling and dollop a bit of peanut sauce on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Fold the other side of the leaf over the filling, and using the sauce to secure. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Fold the bottom of the leaf up and over the filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Tuck in all of the ingredients and roll until the bottom half has reached the top of the leaf. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Spread a bit of sauce on the top of the leaf and roll to secure the wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Repeat with the remaining ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Cut in half on the diagonal, then serve with more peanut sauce for dipping, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Nutrition - Per Wrap - Calories: 282, Total fat: 18 grams, Sodium: 484, Total carbs: 21 grams, Dietary fiber: 11 grams, Sugars: 5 grams, Protein: 18 grams </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>