<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Cheeseburger Pretzel Bombs Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/cheeseburger-pretzel-bombs</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/game-day-ribs-sliders-and-pretzel-bombs</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; pizza dough, left out at room temperature for 15-20 minutes ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">7 slices ; american cheese, cut in half </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">14 ; frozen mini meatballs, thawed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; baking soda ; (45 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">5 cups ; water ; (1.2 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; egg, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">coarse sea salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">yellow mustard, for serving (optional) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="2">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="3">Game Day</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/53877/low_1506542610.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/53877/mp4_720x1280/1506542610</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>72.22</start_time>
    <end_time>106.88</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 425˚F (220˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">Cut the pizza dough into 14 evenly sized pieces. Working one at a time, stretch out a piece of dough into a long strip, about 8 inches (20 centimeters) long. </step>
    <step num="2">Place a piece of cheese at the top, followed by a meatball, and roll up the cheese and meatball in the dough. Rotate halfway through rolling to ensure you are completely encasing the cheese and meet in the dough. Pull tightly and use any remaining slack to cover any possible gaps/holes. Press the dough into itself to seal and place on the prepared baking sheet. Repeat with the remaining dough, cheese, and meatballs. </step>
    <step num="3">In a medium saucepan over high heat, bring the 5 cups of water to a boil. Once boiling, add the baking soda and stir to dissolve. Return the pot to a boil. </step>
    <step num="4">In batches (about 3-5 at a time), add the rolled dough balls to the pot and boil for 20-30 seconds, stirring gently. Remove and dab on paper towels before placing back on the baking sheet. Repeat with remaining dough balls. </step>
    <step num="5">Brush each boiled ball with beaten egg, then sprinkle with coarse sea salt. </step>
    <step num="6">Bake for 15-20 minutes, until the outsides have browned. Serve warm with mustard, if desired. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 425˚F (220˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cut the dough into 14 evenly sized pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Working one at a time, stretch out a piece of dough into a long strip, about 8 inches (20 cm) long. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Place a piece of American cheese at the top, followed by a meatball, and roll up the cheese and meatball in the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Rotate halfway through rolling to ensure you are completely encasing the cheese and meat into the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pull tight and use any remaining slack to cover any possible gaps/holes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Press the dough into itself to seal and place on a parchment-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Repeat with remaining dough, cheese, and meatballs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">In a medium saucepan over high heat, bring the 5 cups of water to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Once boiling, add the baking soda and stir to dissolve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Return the pot to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">In batches (about 3-5 at a time), add the rolled dough balls into the pot and allow to boil for 20-30 seconds, stirring gently. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove and place back on a parchment-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Repeat with remaining dough balls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Brush each boiled ball with beaten egg and then sprinkle each with coarse sea salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Bake in preheated oven for 15-20 minutes, until the outsides have browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
  <duration_human>
    <start_time>02198</start_time>
    <end_time>03243</end_time>
  </duration_human>
</recipe>