<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Dairy-Free Chicken Fettuccine Alfredo Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/dairy-free-chicken-fettuccine-alfredo</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 ; boneless, skinless chicken breasts, about 1 inch (2.5 cm) thick </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 ½ teaspoons ; kosher salt, divided, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ½ teaspoons ; freshly ground black pepper, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">5 tablespoons ; olive oil, divded </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¾ lb ; fettuccine pasta, uncooked ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; large shallot, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">6 ; garlics, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 tablespoons ; all purpose flour </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">13.5 oz ; coconut milk ; (400 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; chicken stock, or vegetable stock ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 tablespoon ; fresh lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">fresh parsley, minced, to taste </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
    <category num="2">Date Night</category>
    <category num="3">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/126188/hls24_1551492535.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/126188/landscape_720/1551492535</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Season the chicken all over with 1½ teaspoons salt and 1 teaspoon pepper. </step>
    <step num="1">Heat 1 tablespoon olive oil in a skillet over medium-high heat. Once the oil is shimmering, add the chicken breasts, 2 at a time, and cook for 4-5 minutes, until golden brown. Add more olive oil, if needed, and Flip and cook on the other side for 4-5 minutes more, until golden brown and the internal temperature reads 165ºF (75˚C). Remove from the pan, set aside, and cover to keep warm while you repeat with the remaining chicken. </step>
    <step num="2">Fill a large pot with water and bring to a boil over high heat. Once at a rolling boil, generously salt the water then add the fettuccine. Cook according to the package instructions. Drain and return to the pot. </step>
    <step num="3">Meanwhile, heat the remaining 3 tablespoons of olive oil in a large pan over medium heat. Once the oil is hot, add the shallots and garlic, season with a pinch of salt, and cook until the shallot is translucent, 3-4 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Stir in the flour and whisk for 3-4 minutes, until golden brown. Add the coconut milk and chicken stock. Bring up to a low boil and cook for about 1 minute, then reduce the heat to low-medium and cook, stirring frequently, until thickened, about 10 minutes. Stir in the lemon juice and season with the remaining 2 teaspoons salt and 1½ teaspoons pepper. </step>
    <step num="5">Pour the sauce over the fettuccine and toss well to coat. Slice the chicken. </step>
    <step num="6">Divide the pasta between bowls and top with the chicken. Garnish with parsley and serve. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Season the chicken all over with 1½ teaspoons salt and 1 teaspoon pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Heat 1 tablespoon olive oil in a skillet over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Once the oil is shimmering, add the chicken breasts, 2 at a time, and cook for 4-5 minutes, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add more olive oil, if needed, and Flip and cook on the other side for 4-5 minutes more, until golden brown and the internal temperature reads 165ºF (75˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Remove from the pan, set aside, and cover to keep warm while you repeat with the remaining chicken. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Fill a large pot with water and bring to a boil over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Once at a rolling boil, generously salt the water then add the fettuccine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cook according to the package instructions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Drain and return to the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Meanwhile, heat the remaining 3 tablespoons of olive oil in a large pan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Once the oil is hot, add the shallots and garlic, season with a pinch of salt, and cook until the shallot is translucent, 3-4 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Stir in the flour and whisk for 3-4 minutes, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the coconut milk and chicken stock. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Bring up to a low boil and cook for about 1 minute, then reduce the heat to low-medium and cook, stirring frequently, until thickened, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Stir in the lemon juice and season with the remaining 2 teaspoons salt and 1½ teaspoons pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Pour the sauce over the fettuccine and toss well to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Slice the chicken. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Divide the pasta between bowls and top with the chicken. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Garnish with parsley and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>