<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Baked Apple Pie Dumplings Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/baked-apple-pie-dumplings</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ; golden delicious apples </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 tablespoons ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ teaspoon ; cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, softened </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ teaspoon ; cornstarch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 sheets ; puff pastry </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; egg white, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; apple cider ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 cup ; water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ teaspoon ; cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 tablespoons ; butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 tablespoon ; lemon juice, half a lemon </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/12798/low_1477332775.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/12798/mp4_720x1280/1477332775</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Peel apples completely, removing all skin and stems. Halve apples across the middle creating both a top and bottom piece. Using a melon baller remove the core, being careful not to go completely through the bottom. Once the core is removed, continue using the melon baller to carve out the interior of the apple, keeping the small pieces of apple seperate. </step>
    <step num="2">In a small bowl, combine the carved out apple pieces with the white sugar, cinnamon, cornstarch, and softened butter. Mix until apple pieces are evenly coated. </step>
    <step num="3">Lay puff pastry out on a lightly floured surface. With a rolling pin, spread pastry out to make a sheet measuring roughly 9x14 inches (23x36cm). Using the round top of a sauce pan (ideally 6-7 inches (15-17 cm) in diameter), cut 2 circles of pastry out of each sheet and set them aside. </step>
    <step num="4">Spoon filling into the hollowed-out core of the apples and place each filled apple in the middle of a round piece of pastry. </step>
    <step num="5">Apply a light wash of egg white to the rim of the pastry and fold toward the center over the apple, crimping the pastry as the edges meet. Continue until all the edges have been brought together. Use your hands to keep shape of the dumpling. </step>
    <step num="6">Once shaped, brush more egg white over the top of each dumpling. Lastly, using a small pairing knife, cut a small vent into the top of each dumpling. </step>
    <step num="7">Bake for 18-22 minutes in a preheated oven, or until pastry is golden brown and filling is bubbling. </step>
    <step num="8">Cider Sauce: While dumplings are baking combine water, apple cider, sugar, and cinnamon in a saucepan and bring it to a boil. Boil for 15 minutes allowing sauce to reduce and become thick. </step>
    <step num="9">Before serving, remove from heat and whisk in the 2 tablespoons of butter and lemon juice. </step>
    <step num="10">Serve by pouring sauce over dumplings while still hot. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Peel apples completely, removing all skin and stems. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Halve apples across the middle creating both a top and bottom piece. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Using a melon baller remove the core, being careful not to go completely through the bottom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Once the core is removed, continue using the melon baller to carve out the interior of the apple, keeping the small pieces of apple seperate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In a small bowl, combine the carved out apple pieces with the white sugar, cinnamon, cornstarch, and softened butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Mix until apple pieces are evenly coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Lay puff pastry out on a lightly floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">With a rolling pin, spread pastry out to make a sheet measuring roughly 9x14 inches (23x36cm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Using the round top of a sauce pan (ideally 6-7 inches (15-17 cm) in diameter), cut 2 circles of pastry out of each sheet and set them aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Spoon filling into the hollowed-out core of the apples and place each filled apple in the middle of a round piece of pastry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Apply a light wash of egg white to the rim of the pastry and fold toward the center over the apple, crimping the pastry as the edges meet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Continue until all the edges have been brought together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Use your hands to keep shape of the dumpling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Once shaped, brush more egg white over the top of each dumpling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Lastly, using a small pairing knife, cut a small vent into the top of each dumpling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Bake for 18-22 minutes in a preheated oven, or until pastry is golden brown and filling is bubbling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cider Sauce: While dumplings are baking combine water, apple cider, sugar, and cinnamon in a saucepan and bring it to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Boil for 15 minutes allowing sauce to reduce and become thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Before serving, remove from heat and whisk in the 2 tablespoons of butter and lemon juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Serve by pouring sauce over dumplings while still hot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>