<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Cookies ‘N’ Cream Icebox Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/cookies-n-cream-icebox-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; unsalted butter, softened ; (230 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ cups ; granulated sugar ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; brown sugar ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (375 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 cup ; dark cocoa powder ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">4 cups ; heavy cream ; (960 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; sweetened condensed milk, chilled ; (300 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97048/hls24_1528133190.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97048/landscape_720/1528133190</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, cream together the butter, granulated sugar, and brown sugar with an electric hand mixer. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the eggs, one at a time, and beat until incorporated. Add the vanilla and beat until combined. </step>
    <step num="3">Sift in the flour, cocoa powder, salt, and baking powder. Beat until combined. </step>
    <step num="4">Divide the dough into 4 equal portions. Place a portion of dough between 2 sheets of parchment paper and roll out into a circle that is about 11 inches (27 cm) wide. Using a 10-inch (25 cm) springform pan as your guide, cut a 10-inch (25 cm) circle out of the dough. </step>
    <step num="5">Use a 3-inch (8-cm) ramekin as a guide to cut out the center, leaving a doughnut-shaped cookie. Reserve the dough scraps and transfer the cookie on the parchment paper to a baking sheet. Repeat with the remaining dough portions. </step>
    <step num="6">Chill the cookie dough in the freezer for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Bake the cookies (in batches, if necessary) for 12-14 minutes, until crisp around the edges. Let cool completely. </step>
    <step num="8">Reroll the dough scraps and use a cookie cutter to cut out 24 1½-inch-wide (4-cm) cookies. Transfer the cookies to a baking sheet lined with parchment paper and chill in the freezer for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Bake the cookies for 7 minutes, until crisp. Let cool completely. </step>
    <step num="10">Make the whipped cream: Add the heavy cream to a large bowl. With an electric hand mixer, whip the cream until soft peaks form, then add the sweetened condensed milk. Continue whipping until stiff peaks form. Transfer to a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a large round tip. </step>
    <step num="11">Carefully place one of the large cookies on a serving platter. Pipe a layer of whipped cream on top of the cookie. Repeat with the remaining cookies and whipped cream, finishing with a layer of cream. Reserve any leftover whipped cream for sandwich cookie garnish. </step>
    <step num="12">Chill the cake in the refrigerator for at least 4 hours or overnight. </step>
    <step num="13">After the cake has chilled, make sandwich cookies for decoration. Pipe a dollop of whipped cream onto a small cookie and sandwich with another cookie. Make 9 more cookie sandwiches. Place the remaining cookies in a plastic bag and use a rolling pin to smash into crumbs. </step>
    <step num="14">Arrange the sandwich cookies evenly around the top edge of the cake. Sprinkle the cookie crumbs over the exposed whipped cream. </step>
    <step num="15">Slice and serve. </step>
    <step num="16">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a large bowl, cream together the butter, granulated sugar, and brown sugar with an electric hand mixer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the eggs, one at a time, and beat until incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the vanilla and beat until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Sift in the flour, cocoa powder, salt, and baking powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Beat until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Divide the dough into 4 equal portions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Place a portion of dough between 2 sheets of parchment paper and roll out into a circle that is about 11 inches (27 cm) wide. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Using a 10-inch (25 cm) springform pan as your guide, cut a 10-inch (25 cm) circle out of the dough </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Use a 3-inch (8-cm) ramekin as a guide to cut out the center, leaving a doughnut-shaped cookie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Reserve the dough scraps and transfer the cookie on the parchment paper to a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Repeat with the remaining dough portions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Chill the cookie dough in the freezer for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Bake the cookies (in batches, if necessary) for 12-14 minutes, until crisp around the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Reroll the dough scraps and use a cookie cutter to cut out 24 1½-inch-wide (4-cm) cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Transfer the cookies to a baking sheet lined with parchment paper and chill in the freezer for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Bake the cookies for 7 minutes, until crisp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Make the whipped cream: Add the heavy cream to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">With an electric hand mixer, whip the cream until soft peaks form, then add the sweetened condensed milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Continue whipping until stiff peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Transfer to a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a large round tip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Carefully place one of the large cookies on a serving platter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Pipe a layer of whipped cream on top of the cookie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Repeat with the remaining cookies and whipped cream, finishing with a layer of cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Reserve any leftover whipped cream for sandwich cookie garnish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Chill the cake in the refrigerator for at least 4 hours or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">After the cake has chilled, make sandwich cookies for decoration. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Pipe a dollop of whipped cream onto a small cookie and sandwich with another cookie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Make 9 more cookie sandwiches. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Place the remaining cookies in a plastic bag and use a rolling pin to smash into crumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Arrange the sandwich cookies evenly around the top edge of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Sprinkle the cookie crumbs over the exposed whipped cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Slice and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>