<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Ultimate Homemade Pizza Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/ultimate-homemade-pizza</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">7 cups ; flour ; (875 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ teaspoon ; active dry yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">4 cups ; water, at room temperature ; (960 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ; cornmeal, or semolina, for the pizza peel </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">flour, extra, for shaping </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">6 oz ; tomato paste ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; hot water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 tablespoons ; red wine vinegar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 teaspoons ; maple syrup, or honey </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">3 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ teaspoon ; dried oregano </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">½ teaspoon ; dried basil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">½ teaspoon ; dried marjoram </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">¼ teaspoon ; cayenne pepper </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/75868/hls24_1517422661.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/75868/landscape_720/1517422661</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a very large bowl, whisk together the dry ingredients. </step>
    <step num="1">Make a divot in the middle of the flour mixture and add a few tablespoons of water. Stir with a wooden spoon, gradually adding more and more water until the dough starts to come together. You may need a tablespoon more or less water, depending on the consistency of the dough as it forms. </step>
    <step num="2">Using your hands, ensure the dough is well incorporated, but do not knead. Be careful not to overwork the dough. </step>
    <step num="3">Cover with plastic wrap and store at room temperature overnight, or for at least 12 hours, until doubled in size and porous. </step>
    <step num="4">Make the sauce by combining tomato paste, water, vinegar, maple syrup, salt, pepper, garlic, oregano, basil, marjoram, and cayenne pepper in a medium bowl. Let sit at room temperature for an hour before canning or jarring. Refrigerate as necessary up to 2 weeks. </step>
    <step num="5">Once the dough has risen, transfer to a clean, floured work surface and form into a large ball. Cut the dough into 6 equal parts and form dough balls by folding the corners into themselves. </step>
    <step num="6">Place the dough balls on a floured sheet pan, sprinkle with flour, and cover with a damp towel for about 30 minutes to an hour. </step>
    <step num="7">Preheat oven with a pizza stone in it to 500ªF (260ºC) or a low broil. </step>
    <step num="8">Work each dough into a disk on a floured work surface. Knuckling the edges of the dough and tossing it gently will help thin it out. Be careful not to rip the dough. </step>
    <step num="9">Place the dough disk onto a pizza peel generously floured with semolina or cornmeal. This will prevent sticking. Top with desired sauce, cheese, and toppings. </step>
    <step num="10">Slide the pizza onto the stone and bake for about 9 minutes, watching carefully to make sure it doesn’t burn. Look for the edges to become charred and crispy and the cheese to bubble. </step>
    <step num="11">Let the pizza cool for 5 to 10 minutes before cutting and serving. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a very large bowl, whisk together the dry ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Make a divot in the middle of the flour mixture and add a few tablespoons of water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Stir with a wooden spoon, gradually adding more and more water until the dough starts to come together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">You may need a tablespoon more or less water, depending on the consistency of the dough as it forms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Using your hands, ensure the dough is well incorporated, but do not knead. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Be careful not to overwork the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cover with plastic wrap and store at room temperature overnight, or for at least 12 hours, until doubled in size and porous. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Make the sauce by combining tomato paste, water, vinegar, maple syrup, salt, pepper, garlic, oregano, basil, marjoram, and cayenne pepper in a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Let sit at room temperature for an hour before canning or jarring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Refrigerate as necessary up to 2 weeks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Once the dough has risen, transfer to a clean, floured work surface and form into a large ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cut the dough into 6 equal parts and form dough balls by folding the corners into themselves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Place the dough balls on a floured sheet pan, sprinkle with flour, and cover with a damp towel for about 30 minutes to an hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Preheat oven with a pizza stone in it to 500ªF (260ºC) or a low broil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Work each dough into a disk on a floured work surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Knuckling the edges of the dough and tossing it gently will help thin it out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Be careful not to rip the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Place the dough disk onto a pizza peel generously floured with semolina or cornmeal. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">This will prevent sticking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Top with desired sauce, cheese, and toppings. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Slide the pizza onto the stone and bake for about 9 minutes, watching carefully to make sure it doesn’t burn. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Look for the edges to become charred and crispy and the cheese to bubble. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Let the pizza cool for 5 to 10 minutes before cutting and serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>