<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Vegan Snowflake Sugar Cookies Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/vegan-snowflake-sugar-cookies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ cup ; organic sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¾ cup ; refined coconut oil, solid but not cold ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ½ teaspoons ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 cups ; all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">5 tablespoons ; unsweetened non-dairy milk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 cups ; organic powdered sugar ; (360 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">4 tablespoons ; water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">blue gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">sprinkles, of your choice, for decorating </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Vegan</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/120670/hls24_1545252256.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/120670/landscape_720/1545252256</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). Line 2 baking sheets with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, cream together the sugar and coconut oil with an electric hand mixer until fluffy. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the vanilla and salt, and stir with a rubber spatula to combine. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">Sift the flour and baking powder into a medium bowl. </step>
    <step num="4">Gradually add the flour mixture to the coconut oil mixture and stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="5">Gradually add the non-dairy milk and stir until a crumbly dough forms. Using your hands, knead the dough into a ball. </step>
    <step num="6">On a lightly floured surface, roll out the dough to about ¼-inch (½ cm) thick. </step>
    <step num="7">Use snowflake cookie cutters to cut out shapes and transfer to the prepared baking sheets about 2 inches (5 cm) apart. Re-roll excess dough to cut out more shapes. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake for 10-12 minutes, until slightly golden around the edges . </step>
    <step num="9">Make the royal icing: Sift the powdered sugar into a large bowl. Add the vanilla and some of the water. Whisk until smooth, adding more water as needed to reach your desired consistency. </step>
    <step num="10">Transfer half of the icing to another bowl and add blue gel food coloring to one. Immediately transfer the icing to piping bags, or cover with plastic wrap. Do not leave the icing uncovered, as it will develop a film. If this happens, add a small amount of water and whisk to incorporate until the icing returns to your desired consistency. </step>
    <step num="11">Decorate the cookies with the royal icing and sprinkles. Let dry completely, at least 3-4 hours or overnight. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line 2 baking sheets with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a large bowl, cream together the sugar and coconut oil with an electric hand mixer until fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the vanilla and salt, and stir with a rubber spatula to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Sift the flour and baking powder into a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Gradually add the flour mixture to the coconut oil mixture and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Gradually add the non-dairy milk and stir until a crumbly dough forms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Using your hands, knead the dough into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">On a lightly floured surface, roll out the dough to about ¼-inch (½ cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Use snowflake cookie cutters to cut out shapes and transfer to the prepared baking sheets about 2 inches (5 cm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Re-roll excess dough to cut out more shapes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Bake for 10-12 minutes, until slightly golden around the edges . </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Make the royal icing: Sift the powdered sugar into a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add the vanilla and some of the water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Whisk until smooth, adding more water as needed to reach your desired consistency. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Transfer half of the icing to another bowl and add blue gel food coloring to one. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Immediately transfer the icing to piping bags, or cover with plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Do not leave the icing uncovered, as it will develop a film. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">If this happens, add a small amount of water and whisk to incorporate until the icing returns to your desired consistency. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Decorate the cookies with the royal icing and sprinkles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Let dry completely, at least 3-4 hours or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>