<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>One-Pan Whole Roasted Chicken &amp; Veggies Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/one-pan-whole-roasted-chicken-veggies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; medium yellow onion, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">6 ; medium carrots, cut on the bias into 1/2 inch (12MM) slices </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 package ; tuscan kale, about 1/2 bunch, stem removed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 tablespoons ; extra virgin olive oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; white wine, such as Pinot Grigio or Sauvignon Blanc ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 lb ; whole chicken, giblets removed, patted dry ; (1.5 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">8 sprigs ; fresh rosemary </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">8 sprigs ; fresh thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; lemon, halved </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">cast iron pan, 12 inch (30 cm) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">kitchen twine </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Healthy</category>
    <category num="4">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="5">Dinner</category>
    <category num="6">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="7">Date Night</category>
    <category num="8">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124665/hls24_1549920907.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124665/landscape_720/1549920907</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Arrange an oven rack in the center of the oven, then preheat to 425˚F (220˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Toss the onion, carrots, and kale in a 12-inch (30 cm) cast iron skillet with 2 tablespoons of olive oil, salt, and pepper until well coated. Pour the white wine over the vegetables. </step>
    <step num="2">Season the chicken all over with salt and pepper, then brush with the remaining tablespoon of olive oil. Stuff the rosemary, thyme, and lemon inside the cavity, tie the legs closed with kitchen twine, and tuck the wings underneath the bird. Place the chicken, breast-side up, on top of the vegetables in the skillet. </step>
    <step num="3">Roast the chicken for 1 hour, rotating the pan halfway through cooking. The chicken is done when it is golden brown, the skin is crispy, and an instant-read thermometer inserted into the thigh registers 165˚F (70˚C). Remove from the oven and let the chicken rest for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Carve the chicken, then plate alongside the vegetables. Pour the pan drippings over the top and serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="5">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Arrange an oven rack in the center of the oven, then preheat to 425˚F (220˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Toss the onion, carrots, and kale in a 12-inch (30 cm) cast iron skillet with 2 tablespoons of olive oil, salt, and pepper until well coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Pour the white wine over the vegetables. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Season the chicken all over with salt and pepper, then brush with the remaining tablespoon of olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Stuff the rosemary, thyme, and lemon inside the cavity, tie the legs closed with kitchen twine, and tuck the wings underneath the bird. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Place the chicken, breast-side up, on top of the vegetables in the skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Roast the chicken for 1 hour, rotating the pan halfway through cooking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">The chicken is done when it is golden brown, the skin is crispy, and an instant-read thermometer inserted into the thigh registers 165˚F (70˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Remove from the oven and let the chicken rest for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Carve the chicken, then plate alongside the vegetables. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Pour the pan drippings over the top and serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>