<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Potato Crust Breakfast Pizza Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/potato-crust-breakfast-pizza</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">30 oz ; frozen hash brown ; (850 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 teaspoons ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 teaspoons ; onion powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ½ teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; dried oregano </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">olive oil, for brushing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¾ cup ; shredded monterey jack cheese ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">6 oz ; breakfast sausage, cooked and drained ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">3 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">freshly ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 ; scallions, thinly sliced, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">hot sauce, to taste, optional </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="1">Date Night</category>
    <category num="2">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/131316/hls24_1556750492.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/131316/landscape_720/1556750492</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 500ºF (260ºC). </step>
    <step num="1">Make the crust: In a large microwave-safe bowl, microwave the hash browns on high power for 5-6 minutes, until you can separate the shredded potato pieces with your fingers but they still hold their shape. </step>
    <step num="2">Transfer the shredded potatoes to a clean dish towel set over a medium bowl. Wring the towel to squeeze any excess liquid from the potatoes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the drained potatoes to a large bowl with the eggs, garlic powder, onion powder, salt, and oregano and stir until everything is well incorporated. The mixture should look like mashed potatoes, with a few shredded potato pieces remaining. </step>
    <step num="4">Line a 12-inch (30 cm) round pizza pan with parchment paper. Transfer the potato mixture to the pan and shape it into a crust, pressing down so that it’s an even thickness with a lip around the outer edge. Brush the entire crust with olive oil. </step>
    <step num="5">Bake for 22-25 minutes, until the crust is beginning to brown and is firm to the touch. Remove from the oven. </step>
    <step num="6">Reduce the oven temperature to 325ºF (160ºC). </step>
    <step num="7">Add the toppings: Scatter the Monterey Jack cheese evenly over the crust. Top with the breakfast sausage. Carefully add the eggs, spacing evenly around the pizza. Season the eggs with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake the pizza for 10-12 minutes, until the egg whites are set and the yolks are still a bit runny. </step>
    <step num="9">Top with the scallions and hot sauce, if using, then slice into wedges. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 500ºF (260ºC). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Make the crust: In a large microwave-safe bowl, microwave the hash browns on high power for 5-6 minutes, until you can separate the shredded potato pieces with your fingers but they still hold their shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Transfer the shredded potatoes to a clean dish towel set over a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Wring the towel to squeeze any excess liquid from the potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the drained potatoes to a large bowl with the eggs, garlic powder, onion powder, salt, and oregano and stir until everything is well incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">The mixture should look like mashed potatoes, with a few shredded potato pieces remaining. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Line a 12-inch (30 cm) round pizza pan with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Transfer the potato mixture to the pan and shape it into a crust, pressing down so that it’s an even thickness with a lip around the outer edge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Brush the entire crust with olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Bake for 22-25 minutes, until the crust is beginning to brown and is firm to the touch. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Remove from the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Reduce the oven temperature to 325ºF (160ºC). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the toppings: Scatter the Monterey Jack cheese evenly over the crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Top with the breakfast sausage. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Carefully add the eggs, spacing evenly around the pizza. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Season the eggs with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Bake the pizza for 10-12 minutes, until the egg whites are set and the yolks are still a bit runny. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Top with the scallions and hot sauce, if using, then slice into wedges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>