<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Key Lime Pie With Toasted Marshmallow Meringue Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/key-lime-pie-with-toasted-marshmallow-meringue</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">10 ; graham crackers </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">7 tablespoons ; butter, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; brown sugar ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">6 ; eggs, separated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">lime zest, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">14 oz ; condensed milk, 1 can ; (395 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ pt ; vanilla ice cream ; (235 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ cup ; key lime juice ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; light corn syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Date Night</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/23905/low_1487096462.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/23905/mp4_720x1280/1487096462</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Place graham crackers in plastic bag and crush them into a fine crumb using a rolling pin. Alternatively, a food processor can be used to crush the crackers. </step>
    <step num="2">Pour the graham cracker crumbs into a medium bowl with the melted butter and brown sugar. Mix until the crumbs take on the character of a coarse, wet sand. </step>
    <step num="3">Pour the crumbs into a 9-inch (23 cm) pie dish. Press the crumb firmly into the dish, making sure to coat the bottom and sides of the dish evenly. Once the crust has been formed, place the pie dish into the refrigerator to firm up. </step>
    <step num="4">Separate 6 eggs. Working with the yolks (reserve the whites for later), add the zest of 1 lime and whisk, either by hand or with an electric mixer, for 2 minutes. Add the can of condensed milk and continue to whisk until mixture is smooth and has a pale yellow color. </step>
    <step num="5">Add in the ice cream and key lime juice. Continue to whisk for an additional 3-5 minutes. The filling should be smooth and airy when finished. </step>
    <step num="6">Pour the filling mixture into the refrigerated graham cracker crust and bake at 350˚F (180˚C) for 18-20 minutes, or until the edges of the crust begin to brown and the filling no longer jiggles when disturbed. </step>
    <step num="7">While the pie is baking, combine the reserved egg whites with corn syrup and about ¼ cup (50 grams) of the sugar and begin to whisk vigorously to form the meringue. Continue to add the sugar in small increments until all of it is incorporated. Continue to whisk until mixture thickens and stiff peaks form, about 7-10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Top the baked pie with the meringue. Using a rubber spatula, spread the meringue evenly over the top of the pie, making sure to cover all the visible areas of filling. Once covered, use the tip of the spatula to shape the meringue forming small peaks a valleys in the topping. </step>
    <step num="9">Bake at 350˚ (180˚C) for an additional 7-10 minutes to toast the meringue topping. Allow to cool completely for at least 1 hour before cutting. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Place graham crackers in plastic bag and crush them into a fine crumb using a rolling pin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Alternatively, a food processor can be used to crush the crackers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Pour the graham cracker crumbs into a medium bowl with the melted butter and brown sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Mix until the crumbs take on the character of a coarse, wet sand. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour the crumbs into a 9-inch (23 cm) pie dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Press the crumb firmly into the dish, making sure to coat the bottom and sides of the dish evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Once the crust has been formed, place the pie dish into the refrigerator to firm up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Separate 6 eggs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Working with the yolks (reserve the whites for later), add the zest of 1 lime and whisk, either by hand or with an electric mixer, for 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the can of condensed milk and continue to whisk until mixture is smooth and has a pale yellow color. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add in the ice cream and key lime juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Continue to whisk for an additional 3-5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">The filling should be smooth and airy when finished. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Pour the filling mixture into the refrigerated graham cracker crust and bake at 350˚F (180˚C) for 18-20 minutes, or until the edges of the crust begin to brown and the filling no longer jiggles when disturbed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">While the pie is baking, combine the reserved egg whites with corn syrup and about ¼ cup (50 grams) of the sugar and begin to whisk vigorously to form the meringue. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Continue to add the sugar in small increments until all of it is incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Continue to whisk until mixture thickens and stiff peaks form, about 7-10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Top the baked pie with the meringue. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Using a rubber spatula, spread the meringue evenly over the top of the pie, making sure to cover all the visible areas of filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Once covered, use the tip of the spatula to shape the meringue forming small peaks a valleys in the topping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Bake at 350˚ (180˚C) for an additional 7-10 minutes to toast the meringue topping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Allow to cool completely for at least 1 hour before cutting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>