<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Mini S’mores Eclair Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/mini-smores-eclair</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4.8 oz ; graham crackers, 1 envenlope ; (135 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; unsalted butter, cubed ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¾ cup ; flour ; (95 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 ; eggs, +1 for egg wash </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">14 oz ; marshmallow fluff ; (395 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">4 oz ; dark chocolate bar ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ cup ; heavy cream ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">mini marshmallow, for decorating </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/43898/low_1500401612.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/43898/mp4_720x1280/1500401612</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium saucepan, add the butter, water, and salt over medium heat. Allow all the butter to melt and bring the mixture to a boil. </step>
    <step num="1">As soon as the mixture begins to boil, reduce heat to medium-low and add in the flour and graham cracker crumbs. Using a wooden spoon, mix thoroughly to combine. </step>
    <step num="2">Continue stirring (about two minutes). The dough should form into a ball and easily pull away from the sided of the pan. Remove the mixture from heat and leave to cool for 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add in the eggs to the cooled dough, one at a time, being sure to fully incorporate each egg before adding the next. (The eggs will initially be difficult to incorporate into the dough - but continue stirring vigorously and they will eventually come together to form a smooth shiny dough) </step>
    <step num="4">Preheat oven to 425˚F (220˚C) </step>
    <step num="5">Once the dough comes together, transfer it to a piping bag and pipe onto a parchment-paper-lined baking sheet into 2-3 inch (5-7cm) logs. </step>
    <step num="6">Smooth out any peaks/tails caused by piping with a wet fingertip (this will ensure your eclairs cook evenly and maintain an even shape) </step>
    <step num="7">Brush the eclairs with beaten egg. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake in a preheated oven for 10 minutes at 425˚F. Then, without opening the oven, reduce heat to 350˚ (175˚C) and bake for an additional 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Remove eclairs from oven. Using the tip of a knife, cut a small “x” into the bottom of each eclair and transfer (“x” side up) to a cooling rack. (this will allow any excess steam/moisture to escape ensuring your eclairs maintain their shape). </step>
    <step num="10">Fill a piping bag fitted with a narrow tip with marshmallow fluff. </step>
    <step num="11">Just before serving, pipe the fluff into the cooled eclairs. </step>
    <step num="12">Break apart chocolate and add to a small microwave safe bowl. </step>
    <step num="13">To a separate, small microwave safe bowl, add the heavy cream. </step>
    <step num="14">Microwave the cream for one minute. Remove and immediately pour the hot cream over the chocolate pieces. Stir until the chocolate has melted and a nice ganache has formed. (if necessary place the bowl with chocolate and cream in the microwave for 10 second increments, stirring after each until smooth). </step>
    <step num="15">Dip the top side of the filled eclairs into the melted chocolate. </step>
    <step num="16">Sprinkle with additional graham cracker crumbs and top with mini marshmallows (if you have a kitchen torch you can “toast” the marshmallows to make them super cute). Best served immediately! </step>
    <step num="17">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium saucepan, add the butter, water, and salt over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Allow all the butter to melt and bring the mixture to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">As soon as the mixture begins to boil, reduce heat to medium-low and add in the flour and graham cracker crumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Using a wooden spoon, mix thoroughly to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Continue stirring (about two minutes). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">The dough should form into a ball and easily pull away from the sided of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove the mixture from heat and leave to cool for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add in the eggs to the cooled dough, one at a time, being sure to fully incorporate each egg before adding the next. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">(The eggs will initially be difficult to incorporate into the dough - but continue stirring vigorously and they will eventually come together to form a smooth shiny dough) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Preheat oven to 425˚F (220˚C) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Once the dough comes together, transfer it to a piping bag and pipe onto a parchment-paper-lined baking sheet into 2-3 inch (5-7cm) logs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Smooth out any peaks/tails caused by piping with a wet fingertip (this will ensure your eclairs cook evenly and maintain an even shape) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Brush the eclairs with beaten egg. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Bake in a preheated oven for 10 minutes at 425˚F. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Then, without opening the oven, reduce heat to 350˚ (175˚C) and bake for an additional 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove eclairs from oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Using the tip of a knife, cut a small “x” into the bottom of each eclair and transfer (“x” side up) to a cooling rack. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">(this will allow any excess steam/moisture to escape ensuring your eclairs maintain their shape). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Fill a piping bag fitted with a narrow tip with marshmallow fluff. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Just before serving, pipe the fluff into the cooled eclairs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Break apart chocolate and add to a small microwave safe bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">To a separate, small microwave safe bowl, add the heavy cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Microwave the cream for one minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Remove and immediately pour the hot cream over the chocolate pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Stir until the chocolate has melted and a nice ganache has formed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">(if necessary place the bowl with chocolate and cream in the microwave for 10 second increments, stirring after each until smooth). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Dip the top side of the filled eclairs into the melted chocolate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Sprinkle with additional graham cracker crumbs and top with mini marshmallows (if you have a kitchen torch you can “toast” the marshmallows to make them super cute). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Best served immediately! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>