<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Ham And Cheese Hash Brown Cubes Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/ham-and-cheese-hash-brown-cubes</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">15 slices ; cheddar cheese </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">15 slices ; ham </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">6 ; medium russet potatoes, or 3 large </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ½ teaspoons ; salt, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; flour ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">oil, for frying </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="3">Game Day</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98143/hls24_1528762775.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98143/landscape_720/1528762775</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">On a cutting board, place one slice of cheddar cheese, place the slice of ham on top of the cheddar. If the ham is not square, trim it to the same size as the slice of cheese. Scramble your leftover ham trimmings with onion, peppers, and eggs. Cut the ham and cheese into 4 equal squares. Repeat with the rest of the ham and cheese. </step>
    <step num="1">Stack the ham and cheese until you have 10 layers of ham and 10 layers of cheese. </step>
    <step num="2">On a cutting board, peel the potatoes. Shred the potatoes into a large bowl lines with a thin towel. </step>
    <step num="3">Once all of your potatoes are shredded, wrap the towel tightly and twist to squeeze out all of the water from the potatoes. Discard the potato water. </step>
    <step num="4">Place the shredded potatoes into a clean bowl, add 1 teaspoon of salt, pepper, flour, and egg. Mix thoroughly. </step>
    <step num="5">Wrap the potato mixture around the ham and cheese cube. Flatten each side to create a cube. Repeat with the rest of the cubes. </step>
    <step num="6">On a parchment paper-lined baking sheet place the hash brown cubes. Freeze for 2-3 hours or until solid. </step>
    <step num="7">Heat 4 inches (10 cm) of oil in a large pot until the temperature reaches 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="8">Fry each cube for 4 minutes until golden brown. Place on a cooling rack or drain on paper towel. Let cool for 5 minutes. Sprinkle with the rest of the salt. </step>
    <step num="9">Serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">On a cutting board, place one slice of cheddar cheese, place the slice of ham on top of the cheddar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">If the ham is not square, trim it to the same size as the slice of cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Scramble your leftover ham trimmings with onion, peppers, and eggs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cut the ham and cheese into 4 equal squares. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Repeat with the rest of the ham and cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Stack the ham and cheese until you have 10 layers of ham and 10 layers of cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">On a cutting board, peel the potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Shred the potatoes into a large bowl lines with a thin towel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Once all of your potatoes are shredded, wrap the towel tightly and twist to squeeze out all of the water from the potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Discard the potato water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place the shredded potatoes into a clean bowl, add 1 teaspoon of salt, pepper, flour, and egg. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Mix thoroughly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Wrap the potato mixture around the ham and cheese cube. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Flatten each side to create a cube. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Repeat with the rest of the cubes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">On a parchment paper-lined baking sheet place the hash brown cubes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Freeze for 2-3 hours or until solid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Heat 4 inches (10 cm) of oil in a large pot until the temperature reaches 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Fry each cube for 4 minutes until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Place on a cooling rack or drain on paper towel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Let cool for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Sprinkle with the rest of the salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>