<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chocolate Coconut Almond Balls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chocolate-coconut-almond-balls</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/7-mesmerizing-dessert-balls</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; desiccated coconut, unsweetened ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; icing sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">⅔ cup ; sweetened condensed milk ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">dark chocolate </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">almond </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Date Night</category>
    <category num="2">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/122992/hls24_1547760174.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/122992/landscape_720/1547760174</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>366.666</start_time>
    <end_time>407.0</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl mix together coconut, sugar, salt, vanilla, and condensed milk. If the mixture is too dry add additional milk until it all just comes together. </step>
    <step num="1">Roll the mixture into 1-inch (2.5 cm) balls and place on a wax paper lined baking sheet. Freeze for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Break apart chocolate bars and add to a microwave safe bowl. Microwave chocolate for 75 seconds, stopping every 30 seconds to check and stir. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove the coconut balls from the freezer and individually roll in melted chocolate to coat. Place back on a wax paper lined tray and sprinkle with additional coconut and top with an almond (optional). </step>
    <step num="4">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl mix together coconut, sugar, salt, vanilla, and condensed milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">If the mixture is too dry add additional milk until it all just comes together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Roll the mixture into 1-inch (2.5 cm) balls and place on a wax paper lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Freeze for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Break apart chocolate bars and add to a microwave safe bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Microwave chocolate for 75 seconds, stopping every 30 seconds to check and stir. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove the coconut balls from the freezer and individually roll in melted chocolate to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Place back on a wax paper lined tray and sprinkle with additional coconut and top with an almond (optional). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>