<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>3-ingredient Easy Creme Brulee Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/3-ingredient-creme-brulee</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ cup ; vanilla ice cream ; (70 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ; egg yolk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; sugar </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">French</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Date Night</category>
    <category num="5">Fusion</category>
    <category num="6">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/55826/low_1507769655.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/55826/mp4_720x1280/1507769655</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (160˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Scoop the ice cream in a microwave-safe bowl. Microwave the ice cream for 30 to 40 seconds or until completely melted. Allow to cool for 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the egg yolk into the melted ice cream and whisk well. </step>
    <step num="3">Pour the mixture into a ramekin. Place the ramekin in a pan. Pour hot water into the pan to come roughly halfway up the sides of the ramekin. </step>
    <step num="4">Bake for 40-50 minutes. The crème brûlée should be set, but still a little jiggly in the middle. Remove the ramekins from the roasting pan, allow to cool to room temperature, cover with plastic wrap and refrigerate for at least 2 hours, and up to 3 days. </step>
    <step num="5">Remove the crème brûlée from the refrigerator for at least 30 minutes before browning the sugar on top. </step>
    <step num="6">Sprinkle a tablespoon of sugar on top of each crème brûlée. Using a torch, melt the sugar to for a crispy top. If you don’t have a torch, you can broil the crème brûlée to melt the sugar. Keep an eye on it, to make sure you don’t over cook it. Allow the crème brûlée to sit for at least 5 minutes before serving. </step>
    <step num="7">You can also make various flavor by using different ice cream flavors. If you are using flavored ice cream, use 1 egg instead of 1 yolk. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (160˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Scoop the ice cream in a microwave-safe bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Microwave the ice cream for 30 to 40 seconds or until completely melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Allow to cool for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the egg yolk into the melted ice cream and whisk well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour the mixture into a ramekin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Place the ramekin in a pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Pour hot water into the pan to come roughly halfway up the sides of the ramekin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Bake for 40-50 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">The crème brûlée should be set, but still a little jiggly in the middle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Remove the ramekins from the roasting pan, allow to cool to room temperature, cover with plastic wrap and refrigerate for at least 2 hours, and up to 3 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove the crème brûlée from the refrigerator for at least 30 minutes before browning the sugar on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Sprinkle a tablespoon of sugar on top of each crème brûlée. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Using a torch, melt the sugar to for a crispy top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">If you don’t have a torch, you can broil the crème brûlée to melt the sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Keep an eye on it, to make sure you don’t over cook it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Allow the crème brûlée to sit for at least 5 minutes before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">You can also make various flavor by using different ice cream flavors. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">If you are using flavored ice cream, use 1 egg instead of 1 yolk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>