<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Deep-Fried Shrimp Onigiri Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/deep-fried-shrimp-onigiri</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; all-purpose flour, divided ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; cold water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">8 ; raw shrimps, peeled and deveined, tails left on </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">oil, for frying </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¾ cup ; dashi ; (180 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¼ cup ; soy sauce ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; mirin ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 ½ cups ; cooked rice, for serving ; (345 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; roasted seaweed strip, cut into 8 equal pieces </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Japanese</category>
    <category num="1">Seafood</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Date Night</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/48785/low_1503442279.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/48785/mp4_720x1280/1503442279</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Whisk the egg in a small bowl. Add ½ cup (60 g) of flour and the cold water and whisk to combine. Cover with plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the remaining flour to a shallow dish. Dredge each shrimp in the flour, shaking off any excess. </step>
    <step num="2">Heat the oil in a large pot until it reaches 350°F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="3">Dip the floured shrimp into the chilled batter. </step>
    <step num="4">Fry the shrimp until they float to the top and are golden brown in color. Use a slotted spoon to transfer the shrimp to a paper towel-lined plate to drain. </step>
    <step num="5">In a medium pan, combine the dashi, soy sauce, and mirin, and bring to a boil over high heat. Transfer to a small bowl. </step>
    <step num="6">To make the onigiri rice balls, first wet your palms with water and coat with a little bit of salt. </step>
    <step num="7">Take a handful of rice and make an indent in the middle. Dip a shrimp into the soy sauce mixture, then place in the center of the rice. Wrap the rice around the shrimp, creating a triangle shape. </step>
    <step num="8">Wrap a strip of seaweed around the rice ball. Repeat with remaining ingredients. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Whisk the egg in a small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add ½ cup (60 g) of flour and the cold water and whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cover with plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the remaining flour to a shallow dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Dredge each shrimp in the flour, shaking off any excess. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Heat the oil in a large pot until it reaches 350°F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Dip the floured shrimp into the chilled batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Fry the shrimp until they float to the top and are golden brown in color. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Use a slotted spoon to transfer the shrimp to a paper towel-lined plate to drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a medium pan, combine the dashi, soy sauce, and mirin, and bring to a boil over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Transfer to a small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">To make the onigiri rice balls, first wet your palms with water and coat with a little bit of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Take a handful of rice and make an indent in the middle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Dip a shrimp into the soy sauce mixture, then place in the center of the rice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Wrap the rice around the shrimp, creating a triangle shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Wrap a strip of seaweed around the rice ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Repeat with remaining ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>