<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Classic Meat lover's Calzone</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/classic-meat-lovers-calzones</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¾ cup ; warm water ; (180 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ teaspoons ; instant yeast, (1/2 packet) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 cups ; all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ½ teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 links ; Italian sausage, casings removed and sausage crumbled </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ ; yellow onion, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt, plus a pinch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; marinara sauce, plus more for dipping ; (130 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">8 slices ; deli ham </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">20 slices ; pepperoni </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 cup ; shredded mozzarella cheese ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ; large egg </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Italian</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Lunch</category>
    <category num="4">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/118284/hls24_1544033117.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/118284/landscape_720/1544033117</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the dough: In a medium bowl, combine the warm water, yeast, flour, and salt. Mix with a rubber spatula until well-combined and the dough comes together into a ball. </step>
    <step num="1">Lightly flour a clean surface, then turn the dough out and knead for 1-2 minutes to smooth and encourage gluten development. Shape the dough into a ball. </step>
    <step num="2">Drizzle the olive oil in a clean large bowl. Add the dough ball and turn to coat in the oil. Cover with a kitchen towel and let rise for 1 hour, or until doubled in size. </step>
    <step num="3">Preheat the oven to 425˚F (220˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="4">While the dough is rising, make the filling: Add the sausage to a medium nonstick pan over medium heat and cook until no longer pink, 5-6 minutes. Add the onion, salt, and pepper and continue to cook until the sausage is browned, about 5 minutes more. Remove from the heat and let cool. </step>
    <step num="5">After the dough has risen, turn it out onto a lightly floured surface. Divide the dough into 4 portions, then roll each into and round about ¼-inch (½ cm) thick. </step>
    <step num="6">Spread ¼ of the sauce over one half of each dough round, leaving a ½-inch (1 cm) border along the edge. Top each one with 2 slices of ham, 5 pepperoni, ¼ of the sausage and onion mixture, and ¼ cup (25 G) of mozzarella cheese. </step>
    <step num="7">Lightly beat the egg with a pinch of salt. Brush the egg wash on the border of the dough, fold the other half over, and press the edges together. Starting from one corner, fold the dough over itself in a twist. Tuck the other corner underneath. Transfer the calzones to the prepared baking sheet. Brush lightly with egg wash and score the tops with a knife to allow steam to escape. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake for 15-17 minutes, until golden brown. Let cool for 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Serve the calzones with marinara sauce for dipping, if desired. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the dough: In a medium bowl, combine the warm water, yeast, flour, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Mix with a rubber spatula until well-combined and the dough comes together into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Lightly flour a clean surface, then turn the dough out and knead for 1-2 minutes to smooth and encourage gluten development. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Shape the dough into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Drizzle the olive oil in a clean large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the dough ball and turn to coat in the oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cover with a kitchen towel and let rise for 1 hour, or until doubled in size. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Preheat the oven to 425˚F (220˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">While the dough is rising, make the filling: Add the sausage to a medium nonstick pan over medium heat and cook until no longer pink, 5-6 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the onion, salt, and pepper and continue to cook until the sausage is browned, about 5 minutes more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove from the heat and let cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">After the dough has risen, turn it out onto a lightly floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Divide the dough into 4 portions, then roll each into and round about ¼-inch (½ cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Spread ¼ of the sauce over one half of each dough round, leaving a ½-inch (1 cm) border along the edge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Top each one with 2 slices of ham, 5 pepperoni, ¼ of the sausage and onion mixture, and ¼ cup (25 G) of mozzarella cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Lightly beat the egg with a pinch of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Brush the egg wash on the border of the dough, fold the other half over, and press the edges together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Starting from one corner, fold the dough over itself in a twist. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Tuck the other corner underneath. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Transfer the calzones to the prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Brush lightly with egg wash and score the tops with a knife to allow steam to escape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Bake for 15-17 minutes, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Let cool for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Serve the calzones with marinara sauce for dipping, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>