<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Veggie Sushi 4 Ways Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/veggie-sushi-4-ways</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ½ tablespoons ; rice vinegar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¾ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 cups ; sushi rice, cooked ; (690 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; black rice, cooked ; (230 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 sheets ; roasted nori </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; sesame oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; shiitake mushroom, sliced ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; soy sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ teaspoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">8 leaves ; fresh spinach </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">4 sticks ; cucumber </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">4 sticks ; carrot </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">vegetable oil, for frying </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">½ cup ; all purpose flour ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">¼ teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">¾ cup ; ice water ; (180 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">1 ; medium sweet potato, cut into sticks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">2 slices ; avocado </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">4 slices ; avocado </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">4 sticks ; cucumber </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">4 sticks ; mango </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="25">4 strips ; teriyaki tofu, baked </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="26">4 sticks ; red bell pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="27">4 sticks ; carrot </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="28">wasabi </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="29">pickled ginger </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="30">soy sauce </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Japanese</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Healthy</category>
    <category num="3">Vegan</category>
    <category num="4">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="5">Dinner</category>
    <category num="6">Date Night</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/106781/hls24_1535403009.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/106781/landscape_720/1535403009</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a small pot over medium heat, add the rice vinegar, sugar, and salt and whisk to combine. Bring to a boil and continue whisking until the salt and sugar have dissolved. Remove the pot from the heat. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the cooked sushi rice to a large bowl and the cooked black rice to a separate medium bowl. Add ¾ of the rice vinegar mixture to the sushi rice and the remaining ¼ to the forbidden rice. Mix until the vinegar mixture is well distributed. </step>
    <step num="2">Make the shiitake veggie roll: Heat the sesame oil in a medium pan over medium heat. Once the oil is simmering, add the shiitake mushrooms, soy sauce, garlic powder, and pepper and cook for 6-8 minutes, until the mushrooms have released their juices and begin to crisp up. </step>
    <step num="3">Place 1 sheet of nori over a bamboo sushi mat. Scoop 1 cup (230 g) of sushi rice on top of the nori. Fill a small bowl with water to dip your fingers into--this will prevent them from getting sticky when handling the rice. Using your fingers, spread the rice in an even layer over the nori, leaving a 1-inch (2-cm) border at the top to seal the roll. </step>
    <step num="4">Over the bottom quarter of the nori, layer the spinach, cucumber, carrot, and shiitake mushrooms. Use your fingers to hold the vegetables in place while you begin to roll the nori. Squeeze the bamboo mat around the roll as you go to ensure a tight sushi roll. Transfer the sushi roll to a cutting board and cut it in half, then cut each half into quarters for a total of 8 sushi pieces. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the sweet potato tempura roll: Heat the vegetable oil in a medium pot until it reaches 375ºF (190ºC). </step>
    <step num="6">In a medium bowl, combine the flour, baking powder, salt, and pepper and mix well with a fork. Pour in the ice water and mix until incorporated--some lumps are okay. Drop the sweet potato sticks into the batter and toss with your fingers to ensure they are thoroughly coated. </step>
    <step num="7">Transfer a few of the sweet potato sticks at a time to a spider and carefully drop them into the hot oil. Cook for 3-4 minutes, until crispy, then transfer to a paper towel-lined plate. </step>
    <step num="8">Place 1 sheet of nori over a bamboo sushi mat. Scoop 1 cup (230 g) of sushi rice on top of the nori. Using your fingers, spread the rice in an even layer over the nori, leaving a 1-inch (2-cm) border at the top to seal the roll. </step>
    <step num="9">Over the bottom quarter of the nori, layer the sweet potato tempura and avocado. Use your fingers to hold the vegetables in place while you begin to roll the nori. Squeeze the bamboo mat around the roll as you go to ensure a tight sushi roll. Transfer the sushi roll to a cutting board and cut it in half, then cut each half into quarters for a total of 8 sushi pieces. </step>
    <step num="10">Make the avocado cucumber mango roll: Place 1 sheet of nori over a bamboo sushi mat. Scoop the forbidden rice on top of the nori. Using your fingers, spread the rice in an even layer over the nori, leaving a 1-inch (2-cm) border at the top to seal the roll. </step>
    <step num="11">Over the bottom quarter of the nori, layer the avocado, cucumber, and mango. Use your fingers to hold the filling in place while you begin to roll the nori. Squeeze the bamboo mat around the roll as you go to ensure a tight sushi roll. Transfer the sushi roll to a cutting board and cut it in half, then cut each half into quarters for a total of 8 sushi pieces. </step>
    <step num="12">Make the teriyaki tofu roll: Place 1 sheet of nori over a bamboo sushi mat. Scoop the remaining cup of sushi rice on top of the nori. Using your fingers, spread the rice in an even layer over the nori, leaving a 1-inch (2-cm) border at the top to seal the roll. </step>
    <step num="13">Over the bottom quarter of the roll, layer the teriyaki tofu, red bell pepper, and carrot. Use your fingers to hold the filling in place while you begin to roll the nori. Squeeze the bamboo mat around the roll as you go to ensure a tight sushi roll. Transfer the sushi roll to a cutting board and cut it in half, then cut each half into quarters for a total of 8 sushi pieces. </step>
    <step num="14">Serve the sushi with wasabi, pickled ginger, and soy sauce. </step>
    <step num="15">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a small pot over medium heat, add the rice vinegar, sugar, and salt and whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Bring to a boil and continue whisking until the salt and sugar have dissolved. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Remove the pot from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the cooked sushi rice to a large bowl and the cooked black rice to a separate medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add ¾ of the rice vinegar mixture to the sushi rice and the remaining ¼ to the forbidden rice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Mix until the vinegar mixture is well distributed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Make the shiitake veggie roll: Heat the sesame oil in a medium pan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Once the oil is simmering, add the shiitake mushrooms, soy sauce, garlic powder, and pepper and cook for 6-8 minutes, until the mushrooms have released their juices and begin to crisp up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Place 1 sheet of nori over a bamboo sushi mat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Scoop 1 cup (230 g) of sushi rice on top of the nori. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Fill a small bowl with water to dip your fingers into--this will prevent them from getting sticky when handling the rice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Using your fingers, spread the rice in an even layer over the nori, leaving a 1-inch (2-cm) border at the top to seal the roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Over the bottom quarter of the nori, layer the spinach, cucumber, carrot, and shiitake mushrooms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Use your fingers to hold the vegetables in place while you begin to roll the nori. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Squeeze the bamboo mat around the roll as you go to ensure a tight sushi roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Transfer the sushi roll to a cutting board and cut it in half, then cut each half into quarters for a total of 8 sushi pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Make the sweet potato tempura roll: Heat the vegetable oil in a medium pot until it reaches 375ºF (190ºC). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">In a medium bowl, combine the flour, baking powder, salt, and pepper and mix well with a fork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Pour in the ice water and mix until incorporated--some lumps are okay. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Drop the sweet potato sticks into the batter and toss with your fingers to ensure they are thoroughly coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Transfer a few of the sweet potato sticks at a time to a spider and carefully drop them into the hot oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Cook for 3-4 minutes, until crispy, then transfer to a paper towel-lined plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Place 1 sheet of nori over a bamboo sushi mat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Scoop 1 cup (230 g) of sushi rice on top of the nori. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Using your fingers, spread the rice in an even layer over the nori, leaving a 1-inch (2-cm) border at the top to seal the roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Over the bottom quarter of the nori, layer the sweet potato tempura and avocado. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Use your fingers to hold the vegetables in place while you begin to roll the nori. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Squeeze the bamboo mat around the roll as you go to ensure a tight sushi roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Transfer the sushi roll to a cutting board and cut it in half, then cut each half into quarters for a total of 8 sushi pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Make the avocado cucumber mango roll: Place 1 sheet of nori over a bamboo sushi mat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Scoop the forbidden rice on top of the nori. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Using your fingers, spread the rice in an even layer over the nori, leaving a 1-inch (2-cm) border at the top to seal the roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Over the bottom quarter of the nori, layer the avocado, cucumber, and mango. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Use your fingers to hold the filling in place while you begin to roll the nori. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Squeeze the bamboo mat around the roll as you go to ensure a tight sushi roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Transfer the sushi roll to a cutting board and cut it in half, then cut each half into quarters for a total of 8 sushi pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Make the teriyaki tofu roll: Place 1 sheet of nori over a bamboo sushi mat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="37">Scoop the remaining cup of sushi rice on top of the nori. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="38">Using your fingers, spread the rice in an even layer over the nori, leaving a 1-inch (2-cm) border at the top to seal the roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="39">Over the bottom quarter of the roll, layer the teriyaki tofu, red bell pepper, and carrot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="40">Use your fingers to hold the filling in place while you begin to roll the nori. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="41">Squeeze the bamboo mat around the roll as you go to ensure a tight sushi roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="42">Transfer the sushi roll to a cutting board and cut it in half, then cut each half into quarters for a total of 8 sushi pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="43">Serve the sushi with wasabi, pickled ginger, and soy sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="44">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>