<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Crispy Chicken Teriyaki Rice Balls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/crispy-chicken-teriyaki-rice-balls</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; boneless, skinless chicken breast ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">white pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ½ teaspoons ; cornstarch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; soy sauce ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 tablespoons ; brown sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; fresh ginger, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 tablespoon ; honey </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 teaspoon ; sesame oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 tablespoon ; mirin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 tablespoons ; cooking oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 cup ; bell pepper, julienned ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 cup ; carrot, julienned ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">4 cups ; short grain rice, cooked ; (800 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">3 ; eggs, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">2 cups ; panko breadcrumbs ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 cup ; scallion, thinly sliced ; (100 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Japanese</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98448/hls24_1528923855.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98448/landscape_720/1528923855</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large measuring cup, combine water and cornstarch. Stir until combined and add soy sauce, brown sugar, ginger, garlic, honey, sesame oil, and mirin. Mix well. </step>
    <step num="1">Season sliced chicken breast with salt and pepper, then pour ¼ cup (60 ml) of the sauce over the sliced chicken just until covered, and set aside. Mix the sauce with the sliced chicken, cover, and marinate in the refrigerator for at least 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large skillet over medium-high heat, pour the rest of the sauce and stir occasionally as it comes to a boil. Once boiling, reduce heat to low and simmer for 10 minutes, or until the sauce has thickened. Set aside in a bowl. </step>
    <step num="3">In the same skillet, add 1 tablespoon cooking oil and raise heat back to medium-high. Place sliced chicken pieces in the pan and cook for 3 minutes, flip, and cook an additional 3 minutes. Pour 1 tablespoon of the reduced sauce over the chicken and stir. Remove from the pan and set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the remaining cooking oil into the skillet and add the julienned vegetables. Season with salt and white pepper, and cook 3-4 minutes or until vegetables have softened. Add back the chicken and gradually add just enough sauce to coat the chicken and vegetables. </step>
    <step num="5">Take ⅓ cup (65 g) of cooked rice and flatten out on a piece of plastic wrap. Layer the cooked chicken and vegetables in the center of the rice and wrap the rice around the fillings. Form into a square shape and repeat with the remainder of the rice and filling. Chill rice balls in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Dip the rice ball in beaten eggs, then coat with panko. Shake off any excess bread crumbs. </step>
    <step num="7">Heat ½ inch (1 cm) oil in a skillet to 350˚F (180˚C) and fry for 3 minutes on each side or until golden and crispy. Move to a cooling rack, and season with salt. </step>
    <step num="8">Cut in half and serve with the remaining sauce for dipping. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large measuring cup, combine water and cornstarch. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Stir until combined and add soy sauce, brown sugar, ginger, garlic, honey, sesame oil, and mirin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Mix well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Season sliced chicken breast with salt and pepper, then pour ¼ cup (60 ml) of the sauce over the sliced chicken just until covered, and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Mix the sauce with the sliced chicken, cover, and marinate in the refrigerator for at least 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In a large skillet over medium-high heat, pour the rest of the sauce and stir occasionally as it comes to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Once boiling, reduce heat to low and simmer for 10 minutes, or until the sauce has thickened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Set aside in a bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">In the same skillet, add 1 tablespoon cooking oil and raise heat back to medium-high. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Place sliced chicken pieces in the pan and cook for 3 minutes, flip, and cook an additional 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Pour 1 tablespoon of the reduced sauce over the chicken and stir. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove from the pan and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the remaining cooking oil into the skillet and add the julienned vegetables. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Season with salt and white pepper, and cook 3-4 minutes or until vegetables have softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add back the chicken and gradually add just enough sauce to coat the chicken and vegetables. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Take ⅓ cup (65 g) of cooked rice and flatten out on a piece of plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Layer the cooked chicken and vegetables in the center of the rice and wrap the rice around the fillings. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Form into a square shape and repeat with the remainder of the rice and filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Chill rice balls in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Dip the rice ball in beaten eggs, then coat with panko. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Shake off any excess bread crumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Heat ½ inch (1 cm) oil in a skillet to 350˚F (180˚C) and fry for 3 minutes on each side or until golden and crispy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Move to a cooling rack, and season with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Cut in half and serve with the remaining sauce for dipping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>