<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>How To Make Perfect Chocolate Chip Cookies Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/tasty-101-ultimate-brown-butter-chocolate-chip-cookies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; bread flour ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¾ cup ; all-purpose flour ; (95 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 teaspoons ; kosher salt, or 1½ teaspoons table salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; unsalted butter, 2 sticks ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 tablespoons ; water, room temperature </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 cup ; dark brown sugar ; (220 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ cup ; white sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 teaspoons ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; espresso powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; large egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ; large egg yolk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ cup ; semi-sweet chocolate chips ; (85 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">5 oz ; dark chocolate, chopped ; (130 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="7">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="8">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/91719/hls24_1524866258.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/91719/landscape_720/1524866258</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium bowl, sift together the flours, salt, and baking soda. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">In a medium or large saucepan, add the butter and melt over medium heat. The larger the pan you use, the quicker the process will be! </step>
    <step num="2">Bring the butter to a boil, stirring frequently. As the water begins to boil out of the butter, the milk solids in the butter will separate, sink to the bottom, and begin to toast and brown. As this begins to happen, make sure to stir constantly so the butter browns evenly. It may become quite foamy, splatter a bit, and be difficult to see, so keep a close eye on it, removing from heat and continuing to stir if it starts to foam over. </step>
    <step num="3">Once the butter has turned a nice nutty brown, remove from the heat and pour into a large liquid measuring cup to stop the cooking. Allow it to cool down for a minute or two, give it a stir, and carefully add 2-3 tablespoons of water to the butter to bring it back up to 1 cup (240 ml) of liquid. </step>
    <step num="4">Set aside to cool to room temperature. To help speed this process up, you can place in the fridge for 10-15 minutes. You want to make sure the butter is still liquid when you’re adding it to the dough later on, so make sure to remove after 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">In a large bowl, add the sugars, vanilla, espresso powder, and cooled brown butter. Cream together with an electric hand mixer until light and fluffy, 1-2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the egg and yolk and beat until incorporated. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the dry ingredients, about ⅓ of the mixture at a time, and beat between additions until just incorporated. It’s okay for there to be a bit of unmixed flour on the edge of bowl, this will be incorporated in the next step. </step>
    <step num="8">Using a wooden spoon, fold the chocolate chips and chunks into the dough </step>
    <step num="9">Scoop the cookies onto a parchment paper-lined baking sheet in 3-tablespoon-sized mounds. </step>
    <step num="10">For optimal flavor, cover and refrigerate for 1 hour or, even better, overnight. </step>
    <step num="11">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="12">Evenly space the dough 3 inches (8 cm) apart from one another on a parchment paper-lined baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="13">Bake in a preheated oven for 12-14 minutes. </step>
    <step num="14">Let the cookies cool on the baking sheet for 2-3 minutes before transferring to a cooling rack to cool completely. </step>
    <step num="15">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium bowl, sift together the flours, salt, and baking soda. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a medium or large saucepan, add the butter and melt over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">The larger the pan you use, the quicker the process will be! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Bring the butter to a boil, stirring frequently. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">As the water begins to boil out of the butter, the milk solids in the butter will separate, sink to the bottom, and begin to toast and brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">As this begins to happen, make sure to stir constantly so the butter browns evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">It may become quite foamy, splatter a bit, and be difficult to see, so keep a close eye on it, removing from heat and continuing to stir if it starts to foam over. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Once the butter has turned a nice nutty brown, remove from the heat and pour into a large liquid measuring cup to stop the cooking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Allow it to cool down for a minute or two, give it a stir, and carefully add 2-3 tablespoons of water to the butter to bring it back up to 1 cup (240 ml) of liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Set aside to cool to room temperature. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">To help speed this process up, you can place in the fridge for 10-15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">You want to make sure the butter is still liquid when you’re adding it to the dough later on, so make sure to remove after 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">In a large bowl, add the sugars, vanilla, espresso powder, and cooled brown butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Cream together with an electric hand mixer until light and fluffy, 1-2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the egg and yolk and beat until incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the dry ingredients, about ⅓ of the mixture at a time, and beat between additions until just incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">It’s okay for there to be a bit of unmixed flour on the edge of bowl, this will be incorporated in the next step. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Using a wooden spoon, fold the chocolate chips and chunks into the dough </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Scoop the cookies onto a parchment paper-lined baking sheet in 3-tablespoon-sized mounds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">For optimal flavor, cover and refrigerate for 1 hour or, even better, overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Evenly space the dough 3 inches (8 cm) apart from one another on a parchment paper-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Bake in a preheated oven for 12-14 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Let the cookies cool on the baking sheet for 2-3 minutes before transferring to a cooling rack to cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>