<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Giant Stuffed Burger Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/giant-stuffed-burger</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; bacon ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 tablespoons ; salted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; large onion, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 lb ; ground beef ; (1 ½ kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 tablespoons ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">oil, for greasing pan </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 cups ; cheddar cheese, grated and divided ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 cups ; monterey jack cheese, grated and divided ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 cup ; fresh parsley, chopped, divided ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">lettuce, to serve </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">tomato, sliced, to serve </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">8 ; rolls, to serve </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Game Day</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/69401/hls24_1513799558.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/69401/landscape_720/1513799558</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">On a parchment paper-lined baking sheet, lay 5 of the bacon strips down back to back. Lifting up every other strip, fold about 1-inch (2 cm) the bacon back on itself. Lay another slice of bacon perpendicular to the strips and fold the flaps back over the horizontal strip of bacon. Repeat with the rest of the bacon until a tight weave has formed. </step>
    <step num="2">Bake for 30 minutes, or until desired crispiness has been reached. </step>
    <step num="3">In a 10-inch (25 cm) cast iron skillet heat the butter over medium-low heat. Add the onions and cook until a deep gold color, about 45 minutes. Remove from heat. </step>
    <step num="4">In a bowl, mix together the beef, garlic powder, paprika, salt and pepper. Divide the beef mixture in half. </step>
    <step num="5">On a piece of parchment paper spread half of the meat into a large circle about 10 inches (25 cm) long and 1 inch (2 cm) thick. Repeat with the other half of meat on a separate piece of parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="6">Sprinkle half of the cheddar and half of the Monterey Jack over one disk of ground beef, along with half of the parsley. Place the bacon lattice on top. </step>
    <step num="7">Sprinkle the rest of the cheddar and Monterey on top of the bacon lattice, along with the rest of the parsley. </step>
    <step num="8">Top with the caramelized onions. Place the other circle of meat on directly on top. Begin pinching together the meat patties making sure the fillings are not coming out, until a giant burger is formed. </step>
    <step num="9">Heat a greased 10 inch (25 cm) cast iron skillet over medium heat. Place the giant burger in the skillet carefully while peeling away the bottom piece of parchment. Cook for 5 minutes, until it is a deep brown color. </step>
    <step num="10">Using a large plate, place it over the skillet. While holding the plate in place flip the skillet so the burger falls onto to plate. Place the skillet back on the heat and slide the burger back into the pan so the cooked side is facing up now. Cook for another 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="11">Remove from heat and place skillet in the oven to finish cooking for 5 minutes </step>
    <step num="12">Remove from pan using spatulas and place on a cutting board for serving. </step>
    <step num="13">Cut into 8 or more pieces. Serve on a roll with lettuce and tomato. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">On a parchment paper-lined baking sheet, lay 5 of the bacon strips down back to back. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Lifting up every other strip, fold about 1-inch (2 cm) the bacon back on itself. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Lay another slice of bacon perpendicular to the strips and fold the flaps back over the horizontal strip of bacon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Repeat with the rest of the bacon until a tight weave has formed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Bake for 30 minutes, or until desired crispiness has been reached. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a 10-inch (25 cm) cast iron skillet heat the butter over medium-low heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the onions and cook until a deep gold color, about 45 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Remove from heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a bowl, mix together the beef, garlic powder, paprika, salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Divide the beef mixture in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">On a piece of parchment paper spread half of the meat into a large circle about 10 inches (25 cm) long and 1 inch (2 cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Repeat with the other half of meat on a separate piece of parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Sprinkle half of the cheddar and half of the Monterey Jack over one disk of ground beef, along with half of the parsley. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Place the bacon lattice on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Sprinkle the rest of the cheddar and Monterey on top of the bacon lattice, along with the rest of the parsley. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Top with the caramelized onions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Place the other circle of meat on directly on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Begin pinching together the meat patties making sure the fillings are not coming out, until a giant burger is formed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Heat a greased 10 inch (25 cm) cast iron skillet over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Place the giant burger in the skillet carefully while peeling away the bottom piece of parchment. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Cook for 5 minutes, until it is a deep brown color. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Using a large plate, place it over the skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">While holding the plate in place flip the skillet so the burger falls onto to plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Place the skillet back on the heat and slide the burger back into the pan so the cooked side is facing up now. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Cook for another 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Remove from heat and place skillet in the oven to finish cooking for 5 minutes </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Remove from pan using spatulas and place on a cutting board for serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Cut into 8 or more pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Serve on a roll with lettuce and tomato. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>