<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Bun Bo Xa Ot (Vietnamese Steak And Rice Noodle Salad) As Made By Diep Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/bun-bo-xa-ot-vietnamese-steak-and-rice-noodle-salad-as-made-by-diep</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; lemongrass ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ½ cups ; canola oil ; (600 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¾ cup ; garlic, minced ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; shallot, minced ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; red pepper flakes ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 tablespoons ; fish sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 tablespoons ; granulated sugar, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ cup ; water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¾ cup ; water ; (180 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">7 tablespoons ; granulated sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; garlic, smashed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">3 ½ tablespoons ; fish sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 tablespoon ; white distilled vinegar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 lb ; hanger steak, or bavette steak ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 tablespoon ; rice bran oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 teaspoon ; fish sauce salt, or kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">½ lb ; daikon radish, peeled and thinly sliced ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">½ lb ; carrot, peeled and thinly sliced ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 cup ; granulated sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">½ cup ; white distilled vinegar ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">¼ cup ; water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">1 tablespoon ; kosher salt, plus 1 teaspoon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">14 oz ; fine rice vermicelli noodles, cooked according to package instructions ; (420 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">1 small head ; red leaf lettuce, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">½ cup ; fresh thai basil, torn ; (20 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="25">½ cup ; fresh mint leaf, torn ; (20 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="26">½ cup ; store bought crispy fried shallots ; (70 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="27">½ cup ; roasted peanut ; (60 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vietnamese</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
    <category num="2">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/137448/hls24_1561661532.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/137448/landscape_720/1561661532</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the lemongrass chili oil: Chop the bottom 4 inches (10 cm) from the lemongrass stalks and discard the tops. Peel off any tough outer layers and discard, then thinly slice the remaining lemongrass. Process the sliced lemongrass in a food processor until very finely minced. You should have about 1 cup (130 g) total. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large enameled Dutch oven, heat the canola oil over high heat until it reaches 300°F (150°C). Add the garlic and lemongrass to the hot oil and cook until the garlic is golden brown and aromatic, about 10 minutes. Add the shallots. Reduce the heat to very low and add the red pepper flakes. Cook until extremely aromatic, about 2 minutes. Add the fish sauce, sugar, and water. Continue cooking for 2 hours, stirring occasionally to prevent the garlic from scorching at the bottom, until the oil has turned red. Remove the pot from the heat and let the chili oil cool, then transfer to an airtight container and refrigerate until ready to use, up to 3 weeks. </step>
    <step num="2">Make the pickles: Place the daikon and carrots in a deep bowl. </step>
    <step num="3">In a small pot, combine the sugar, vinegar, water, garlic and salt. Bring to a simmer over medium heat and stir until the sugar dissolves. </step>
    <step num="4">Pour the brine over the vegetables and let sit for at least 1 hour. The pickles can be stored in an airtight container in the refrigerator for up to 3 weeks. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the nuoc cham: In a small pot, bring the water and sugar to a simmer over medium heat. Add the garlic and stir until the sugar dissolves. Stir in the vinegar and fish sauce. Remove the pot from the heat and let the nuoc cham cool, then transfer to an airtight container and refrigerate until ready to use, up to 3 weeks. </step>
    <step num="6">Make the steak: Rub the steak with the rice bran oil and sprinkle salt on both sides. </step>
    <step num="7">Heat a large cast iron skillet over medium-high heat until smoking. Sear the steak in the hot skillet until the internal temperature reaches 130–135°F (54–57°C) for medium-rare, 6–10 minutes, turning the steak as needed to ensure even cooking. The timing of the steak will depend largely on the thickness of the meat. Remove the steak from the skillet and let rest for 10 minutes, then slice thinly against the grain. </step>
    <step num="8">To serve, add the rice noodles to a wide, shallow dish. Arrange the lettuce, basil, mint, pickles, fried shallots, and peanuts on top. Arrange the beef on top and spoon over some nuoc cham and lemongrass chili oil.". </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the lemongrass chili oil: Chop the bottom 4 inches (10 cm) from the lemongrass stalks and discard the tops. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Peel off any tough outer layers and discard, then thinly slice the remaining lemongrass. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Process the sliced lemongrass in a food processor until very finely minced. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">You should have about 1 cup (130 g) total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a large enameled Dutch oven, heat the canola oil over high heat until it reaches 300°F (150°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the garlic and lemongrass to the hot oil and cook until the garlic is golden brown and aromatic, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the shallots. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Reduce the heat to very low and add the red pepper flakes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Cook until extremely aromatic, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the fish sauce, sugar, and water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Continue cooking for 2 hours, stirring occasionally to prevent the garlic from scorching at the bottom, until the oil has turned red. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove the pot from the heat and let the chili oil cool, then transfer to an airtight container and refrigerate until ready to use, up to 3 weeks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Make the pickles: Place the daikon and carrots in a deep bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">In a small pot, combine the sugar, vinegar, water, garlic and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Bring to a simmer over medium heat and stir until the sugar dissolves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Pour the brine over the vegetables and let sit for at least 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">The pickles can be stored in an airtight container in the refrigerator for up to 3 weeks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Make the nuoc cham: In a small pot, bring the water and sugar to a simmer over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the garlic and stir until the sugar dissolves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Stir in the vinegar and fish sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Remove the pot from the heat and let the nuoc cham cool, then transfer to an airtight container and refrigerate until ready to use, up to 3 weeks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Make the steak: Rub the steak with the rice bran oil and sprinkle salt on both sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Heat a large cast iron skillet over medium-high heat until smoking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Sear the steak in the hot skillet until the internal temperature reaches 130–135°F (54–57°C) for medium-rare, 6–10 minutes, turning the steak as needed to ensure even cooking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">The timing of the steak will depend largely on the thickness of the meat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Remove the steak from the skillet and let rest for 10 minutes, then slice thinly against the grain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">To serve, add the rice noodles to a wide, shallow dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Arrange the lettuce, basil, mint, pickles, fried shallots, and peanuts on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Arrange the beef on top and spoon over some nuoc cham and lemongrass chili oil.". </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>