<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>The Best Vegan Vanilla Ice Cream Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/the-best-vegan-vanilla-ice-cream</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 cups ; cashews, ½ cup (65 g) if just making enough for the ice cream ; (390 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ¼ cups ; organic sugar ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">4 tablespoons ; cocoa butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 tablespoons ; coconut oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 cup ; coconut milk ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ; vanilla bean </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">ice cream maker </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegan</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105412/hls24_1534285182.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105412/landscape_720/1534285182</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Place the cashews in a large bowl. Add enough room-temperature water to cover the cashews. Cover the bowl with a kitchen towel and soak overnight. </step>
    <step num="1">Place the bowl of an ice cream machine in the freezer overnight. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the cashews and soaking water to a blender. Blend, starting on low speed and increasing to high until smooth and frothy, about 40 seconds. Strain into a large bowl through a fine-mesh sieve or cheesecloth. </step>
    <step num="3">Reserve 1 cup (240 ml) of cashew milk for the ice cream and store the rest in the refrigerator for up to a week for another use. </step>
    <step num="4">In a small saucepan over medium heat, combine the water and sugar and cook, stirring constantly, until the mixture is clear, about 2 minutes. Whisk in the cocoa butter, coconut oil, and salt. Remove the pan from the heat and set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">In a blender, combine the cashew milk and coconut milk. Blend on low speed. With the blender running, pour in the sugar mixture to emulsify. Continue until well-blended, about 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Pour the mixture into a large metal bowl and mix in the vanilla extract. Scrape in the seeds from the vanilla bean and whisk to combine. </step>
    <step num="7">Chill the base in the refrigerator for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="8">Add the chilled base to the ice cream maker and churn for 1 hour, or as long as the machine requires, until thick and creamy. </step>
    <step num="9">Transfer the ice cream to a loaf pan and freeze overnight. </step>
    <step num="10">Scoop and serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Place the cashews in a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add enough room-temperature water to cover the cashews. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cover the bowl with a kitchen towel and soak overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Place the bowl of an ice cream machine in the freezer overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the cashews and soaking water to a blender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Blend, starting on low speed and increasing to high until smooth and frothy, about 40 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Strain into a large bowl through a fine-mesh sieve or cheesecloth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Reserve 1 cup (240 ml) of cashew milk for the ice cream and store the rest in the refrigerator for up to a week for another use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">In a small saucepan over medium heat, combine the water and sugar and cook, stirring constantly, until the mixture is clear, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Whisk in the cocoa butter, coconut oil, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Remove the pan from the heat and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">In a blender, combine the cashew milk and coconut milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Blend on low speed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">With the blender running, pour in the sugar mixture to emulsify. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Continue until well-blended, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Pour the mixture into a large metal bowl and mix in the vanilla extract. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Scrape in the seeds from the vanilla bean and whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Chill the base in the refrigerator for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the chilled base to the ice cream maker and churn for 1 hour, or as long as the machine requires, until thick and creamy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Transfer the ice cream to a loaf pan and freeze overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Scoop and serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>