<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Stencil Cookies Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/stencil-cookies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 oz ; unsalted butter, room temperature ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; large egg, lightly beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 cups ; all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; cocoa powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">xacto knife, for cutting stencils </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">cheese cloth </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">butchers twine </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="1">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="2">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129678/hls24_1554939301.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129678/landscape_720/1554939301</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium bowl, cream the butter and sugar with a flexible spatula until smooth, about 1 minute. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the egg and vanilla and stir until well combined. </step>
    <step num="2">Place a fine-mesh sieve over the bowl and sift in the flour. Fold with the spatula until the flour is fully incorporated and the dough comes together. </step>
    <step num="3">Shape the dough into a disc, then cover with plastic wrap, and refrigerate until firm, at least 30 minutes to overnight. </step>
    <step num="4">Meanwhile Using thick paper and a craft knife, cut out a round stencil of your choosing. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">Cut a square from a double layer of cheesecloth. Place the cocoa powder in the center. Gather the edges, twist, and tie with kitchen string to create a sachet. </step>
    <step num="6">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="7">Lightly dust a clean surface with flour. Place chilled dough on work surface and lightly dust with flour. Roll the dough out to ¼-inch (6-mm) thick, lifting and turning the dough as you roll to keep it from sticking. Using a 2-inch (5-cm) round cookie cutter, cut out rounds of dough. Gather scraps of dough and reroll to cut out more rounds, lightly dusting the work surface with flour as needed. </step>
    <step num="8">Place the rounds on the prepared baking sheet, spacing 1 inch (2 ½ cm) apart. </step>
    <step num="9">Place the stencil over a dough round, making sure to press down, and gently dab with the cocoa powder sachet to cover completely. </step>
    <step num="10">Bake the cookies for 10 minutes, rotating baking sheet halfway through, until pale golden. Let cool for 5 minutes on the baking sheet, then transfer to a wire rack to cool completely. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium bowl, cream the butter and sugar with a flexible spatula until smooth, about 1 minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the egg and vanilla and stir until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Place a fine-mesh sieve over the bowl and sift in the flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Fold with the spatula until the flour is fully incorporated and the dough comes together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Shape the dough into a disc, then cover with plastic wrap, and refrigerate until firm, at least 30 minutes to overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Meanwhile Using thick paper and a craft knife, cut out a round stencil of your choosing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cut a square from a double layer of cheesecloth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Place the cocoa powder in the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Gather the edges, twist, and tie with kitchen string to create a sachet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Lightly dust a clean surface with flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Place chilled dough on work surface and lightly dust with flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Roll the dough out to ¼-inch (6-mm) thick, lifting and turning the dough as you roll to keep it from sticking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Using a 2-inch (5-cm) round cookie cutter, cut out rounds of dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Gather scraps of dough and reroll to cut out more rounds, lightly dusting the work surface with flour as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Place the rounds on the prepared baking sheet, spacing 1 inch (2 ½ cm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Place the stencil over a dough round, making sure to press down, and gently dab with the cocoa powder sachet to cover completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Bake the cookies for 10 minutes, rotating baking sheet halfway through, until pale golden. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Let cool for 5 minutes on the baking sheet, then transfer to a wire rack to cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>