<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Spaghetti Squash Nests Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/spaghetti-squash-nests</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; medium spaghetti squash, about 2 1/3 or 3 pounds (1.1 or 1.3 grams) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; grated parmesan cheese ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">olive oil, cooking spray </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 tablespoons ; fresh herb, such as chives, thyme, or parsley - minced </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Healthy</category>
    <category num="1">Breakfast</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124000/hls24_1548978643.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124000/landscape_720/1548978643</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">Using a fork, poke holes lengthwise around the center of the spaghetti squash. </step>
    <step num="2">Microwave for 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Cut the ends off of the squash, then slice in half lengthwise. Remove the seeds and pulp. </step>
    <step num="4">Place half of the squash flesh-side down in a microwave-safe dish with high sides. Pour ½ cup (120 ML) of water over the top of the squash and microwave on high for 3 minutes, or when a fork easily pulls the squash away from the skin in long strands that look like spaghetti. Repeat with second half— there will still be water left over from the first half. Cool the squash until it can be safely handled, about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Use a fork to remove all of the squash from the skin, breaking it up into small strands. You should have approximately 4 cups of squash (820 G). Transfer to a medium bowl and stir in the Parmesan cheese, salt, and pepper. </step>
    <step num="6">Divide the squash into 4 1-cup (205 G each cup) (2 portions and place on the prepared baking sheet. Shape into nests, creating a well large enough to fit an egg in the center of each. </step>
    <step num="7">Bake for 10 minutes, until the squash is starting to brown. Remove from the oven and let cool for 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Crack the eggs into a small bowl, 1 at a time, then pour into the wells of the squash nests. Season with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="9">Bake for 12-15 minutes, depending on your preferred doneness for the eggs. </step>
    <step num="10">Garnish each nest with fresh herbs and serve. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Using a fork, poke holes lengthwise around the center of the spaghetti squash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Microwave for 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Cut the ends off of the squash, then slice in half lengthwise. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Remove the seeds and pulp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Place half of the squash flesh-side down in a microwave-safe dish with high sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Pour ½ cup (120 ML) of water over the top of the squash and microwave on high for 3 minutes, or when a fork easily pulls the squash away from the skin in long strands that look like spaghetti. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Repeat with second half— there will still be water left over from the first half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Cool the squash until it can be safely handled, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Use a fork to remove all of the squash from the skin, breaking it up into small strands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">You should have approximately 4 cups of squash (820 G). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Transfer to a medium bowl and stir in the Parmesan cheese, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Divide the squash into 4 1-cup (205 G each cup) (2 portions and place on the prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Shape into nests, creating a well large enough to fit an egg in the center of each. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Bake for 10 minutes, until the squash is starting to brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Remove from the oven and let cool for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Crack the eggs into a small bowl, 1 at a time, then pour into the wells of the squash nests. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Bake for 12-15 minutes, depending on your preferred doneness for the eggs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Garnish each nest with fresh herbs and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>