<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Hearty Chicken Tortilla Soup Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/hearty-chicken-tortilla-soup</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">8 oz ; large white onion, roughly chopped ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">6 cloves ; garlic </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; jalapeño, seeded and roughly chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; chipotle pepper in adobo sauce, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; fresh cilantro, loosely packed ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 ; roma tomatoes, roughly chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 lb ; boneless, skinless chicken thighs ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; dried oregano </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 tablespoons ; olive oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">8 cups ; low sodium chicken stock ; (2 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">25 oz ; hominy, drained and rinsed ; (625 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 ; red bell peppers, seeded and chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">¼ cup ; lime juice ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">onion, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">fresh cilantro </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">avocado, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">cotija cheese, crumbled </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">tortilla strips </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">lime wedge </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Sides</category>
    <category num="2">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/132933/hls24_1557964477.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/132933/landscape_720/1557964477</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Add the onion, garlic, jalapeño, chipotle peppers, cilantro, and tomatoes to a food processor. Puree until well combined, with no large pieces remaining, about 2 minutes. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">Season the chicken thighs on both sides with salt and the oregano. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large pot, heat 1 tablespoon of olive oil over medium-high heat. Sear the chicken thighs for 4-5 minutes on each side, until golden brown. Transfer to a cutting board. Shred the chicken using 2 forks. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the remaining tablespoon of olive oil to the same pot if it appears dry. Pour the reserved puree into the pot. Cook over medium-high heat for 10 minutes, until the liquid has started to evaporate. Reduce the heat to medium and continue cooking until nearly all the moisture has been cooked out and the puree has reduced to a dark paste, stirring occasionally to prevent burning, about 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Pour in the chicken stock and stir, scraping the bottom of the pan to incorporate any browned bits. Increase the heat to medium-high. Stir in the shredded chicken and bring to a simmer. </step>
    <step num="5">Once the stock is simmering, stir in the hominy and bell pepper. Reduce the heat to medium and simmer for 5-10 minutes to allow the flavors to meld. Add the lime juice and season with salt to taste. </step>
    <step num="6">Serve the soup hot, with onion, cilantro, avocado, cotija cheese, tortilla strips, and lime wedges alongside for topping. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Add the onion, garlic, jalapeño, chipotle peppers, cilantro, and tomatoes to a food processor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Puree until well combined, with no large pieces remaining, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Season the chicken thighs on both sides with salt and the oregano. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a large pot, heat 1 tablespoon of olive oil over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Sear the chicken thighs for 4-5 minutes on each side, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Transfer to a cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Shred the chicken using 2 forks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the remaining tablespoon of olive oil to the same pot if it appears dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Pour the reserved puree into the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cook over medium-high heat for 10 minutes, until the liquid has started to evaporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Reduce the heat to medium and continue cooking until nearly all the moisture has been cooked out and the puree has reduced to a dark paste, stirring occasionally to prevent burning, about 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Pour in the chicken stock and stir, scraping the bottom of the pan to incorporate any browned bits. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Increase the heat to medium-high. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Stir in the shredded chicken and bring to a simmer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Once the stock is simmering, stir in the hominy and bell pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Reduce the heat to medium and simmer for 5-10 minutes to allow the flavors to meld. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the lime juice and season with salt to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Serve the soup hot, with onion, cilantro, avocado, cotija cheese, tortilla strips, and lime wedges alongside for topping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>