<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Silkiest Chocolate Tart Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/silkiest-chocolate-tart</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ cup ; unsalted butter, 1 stick, softened ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; powdered sugar ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; large egg, room temperature </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ½ cups ; all-purpose flour ; (185 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; cocoa powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">⅓ cup ; water ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ cup ; butter, 1 stick ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; instant coffee </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; dark chocolate, chopped ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">⅓ cup ; sugar ; (65 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 tablespoon ; vanilla </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">3 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">fresh raspberry, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">powdered sugar, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Date Night</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/99464/hls24_1529536075.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/99464/landscape_720/1529536075</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the tart dough: add the butter to a medium bowl and sift in the powdered sugar through a fine-mesh sieve. Using an electric hand mixer, beat until smooth. </step>
    <step num="1">Beat the egg and add half at a time to the butter mixture, beating well to incorporate between additions. </step>
    <step num="2">Sift in the flour and cocoa powder, and add the salt. Using a rubber spatula, mix the dough until the cocoa powder is evenly distributed. Wrap the dough in plastic wrap. </step>
    <step num="3">Chill in the refrigerator for at least 30 minutes, or overnight (if you chill the dough overnight, let it sit at room temperature for 15-30 minutes before rolling out). </step>
    <step num="4">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </step>
    <step num="5">Grease a 9-inch (23-cm) tart pan and roll out the chilled dough to an 11-inch (28-cm) circle. Roll the dough around the rolling pin, then unroll the dough over the pan. </step>
    <step num="6">Press the dough against the bottom and sides of the pan, then use the rolling pin to roll over the top of the pan, cutting off any excess dough (re-roll any excess dough and bake into cookies, if desired). Press the dough gently against the pan once more. Using a folk, prick some holes in the bottom of the crust so it doesn’t puff up. </step>
    <step num="7">Bake for 15 minutes, then remove the tart shell from the oven and reduce the temperature to 300˚F (150˚C) </step>
    <step num="8">Make the filling: in a medium saucepan, heat the pan over high heat. Combine the water and butter, and bring to a boil. Add the instant coffee and stir until dissolved. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the chocolate, sugar, and vanilla to a medium bowl and pour the hot butter mixture over. Whisk until the chocolate is melted and the mixture is glossy. </step>
    <step num="10">Add the eggs and whisk well to combine. Pour the filling into the par-baked shell. Bake for 12-15 minutes, or until chocolate is mostly set but the center jiggles slightly. </step>
    <step num="11">Cool the tart for at least 30 minutes, or until cool to touch. Garnish with raspberries and sift powdered sugar over the top. Slice and serve. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the tart dough: add the butter to a medium bowl and sift in the powdered sugar through a fine-mesh sieve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Using an electric hand mixer, beat until smooth </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Beat the egg and add half at a time to the butter mixture, beating well to incorporate between additions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Sift in the flour and cocoa powder, and add the salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Using a rubber spatula, mix the dough until the cocoa powder is evenly distributed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Wrap the dough in plastic wrap </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Chill in the refrigerator for at least 30 minutes, or overnight (if you chill the dough overnight, let it sit at room temperature for 15-30 minutes before rolling out). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Grease a 9-inch (23-cm) tart pan and roll out the chilled dough to an 11-inch (28-cm) circle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Roll the dough around the rolling pin, then unroll the dough over the pan </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Press the dough against the bottom and sides of the pan, then use the rolling pin to roll over the top of the pan, cutting off any excess dough (re-roll any excess dough and bake into cookies, if desired). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Press the dough gently against the pan once more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Using a folk, prick some holes in the bottom of the crust so it doesn’t puff up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Bake for 15 minutes, then remove the tart shell from the oven and reduce the temperature to 300˚F (150˚C) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Make the filling: in a medium saucepan, heat the pan over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Combine the water and butter, and bring to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the instant coffee and stir until dissolved. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Add the chocolate, sugar, and vanilla to a medium bowl and pour the hot butter mixture over. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Whisk until the chocolate is melted and the mixture is glossy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add the eggs and whisk well to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Pour the filling into the par-baked shell. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Bake for 12-15 minutes, or until chocolate is mostly set but the center jiggles slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Cool the tart for at least 30 minutes, or until cool to touch. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Garnish with raspberries and sift powdered sugar over the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Slice and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>