<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Larb As Made By Aria Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/larb-as-made-by-aria</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 ⅓ cups ; sticky rice, thai rice, divided ; (1.3 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">cold water, for soaking rice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">⅔ cup ; low sodium chicken broth ; (160 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 lb ; lean ground pork ; (910 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 ; large shallots, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 stalks ; lemongrass, green tops discarded and pale yellow stalks minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">⅓ cup ; galangal, 1 1/2 in (3 cm), peeled and finely grated ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">⅓ cup ; fish sauce, plus more to taste ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; fresh lime juice ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">3 ; thai bird chiles, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">4 ; scallions, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 ½ cups ; fresh mint leaf, loosely packed, chopped ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ½ cups ; fresh cilantro, leaves and soft stems, roughly chopped ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">red cabbage, or green cabbage, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">english cucumber, thinly sliced, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">bean sprout, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">lime wedge, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">large pot, with tight-fitting lid and steamer insert </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dinner</category>
    <category num="1">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/130645/hls24_1556041566.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/130645/landscape_720/1556041566</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Place 3 cups (690 G) Thai sticky rice in a medium bowl and cover with cold water by at least 1 inch (2 ½ cm). Cover with plastic wrap and soak overnight at room temperature. After the rice has soaked, drain and set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">Fill the large pot with 3 inches (7 cm) of water and bring to a steady simmer over medium-high heat. </step>
    <step num="2">Cut out a circle of parchment paper large enough to line the steamer insert and come 2 inches (5 cm) up the sides. </step>
    <step num="3">Place the parchment in the insert, add the rice, and spread in an even layer. Place the insert in the pot, cover with the lid, and steam until the rice is translucent and tender, 20-30 minutes. Turn off the heat, but keep the rice covered so it stays warm while you prepare the larb. </step>
    <step num="4">Toast the remaining ⅓ cup (75 G) rice in a small pan over medium-high heat, stirring constantly, until light golden brown, about 5 minutes. Immediately pour the rice into a small bowl and let cool completely. </step>
    <step num="5">Grind the toasted rice in a spice grinder or mortar and pestle until finely ground. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="6">Heat the chicken stock in a wok or large pan over medium heat. Once the stock is steaming, add the pork. Break up the meat with a wooden spoon and cook gently, stirring occasionally, until just cooked through and no longer pink, 8-10 minutes. Turn off the heat and stir in the garlic, shallots, lemongrass, and galangal. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the fish sauce, lime juice, chiles, scallions, mint, cilantro, and toasted rice to the pork mixture and stir to combine. Season with more fish sauce, if desired. </step>
    <step num="8">Serve the larb with the sticky rice, cabbage leaves, cucumbers, bean sprouts, and lime wedges. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Place 3 cups (690 G) Thai sticky rice in a medium bowl and cover with cold water by at least 1 inch (2 ½ cm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cover with plastic wrap and soak overnight at room temperature. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">After the rice has soaked, drain and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Fill the large pot with 3 inches (7 cm) of water and bring to a steady simmer over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Cut out a circle of parchment paper large enough to line the steamer insert and come 2 inches (5 cm) up the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Place the parchment in the insert, add the rice, and spread in an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Place the insert in the pot, cover with the lid, and steam until the rice is translucent and tender, 20-30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Turn off the heat, but keep the rice covered so it stays warm while you prepare the larb. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Toast the remaining ⅓ cup (75 G) rice in a small pan over medium-high heat, stirring constantly, until light golden brown, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Immediately pour the rice into a small bowl and let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Grind the toasted rice in a spice grinder or mortar and pestle until finely ground. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Heat the chicken stock in a wok or large pan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Once the stock is steaming, add the pork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Break up the meat with a wooden spoon and cook gently, stirring occasionally, until just cooked through and no longer pink, 8-10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Turn off the heat and stir in the garlic, shallots, lemongrass, and galangal. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the fish sauce, lime juice, chiles, scallions, mint, cilantro, and toasted rice to the pork mixture and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Season with more fish sauce, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Serve the larb with the sticky rice, cabbage leaves, cucumbers, bean sprouts, and lime wedges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>