<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Miso Butter-Seared Sea Bass With Roasted Vegetables Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/miso-butter-seared-sea-bass-with-roasted-vegetables</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 tablespoons ; unsalted grass-fed butter, softened </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 tablespoons ; white miso paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; ginger, grated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 cloves ; garlic, grated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; toasted sesame oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ lb ; baby potato, halved ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">freshly ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">3 tablespoons ; sunflower oil, neutral oil of choice, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">12 oz ; Chilean Sea Bass, skin on 1 in (2 1/2 cm) thick ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 ; baby bok choys, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 teaspoon ; toasted white sesame seeds, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
    <category num="2">Date Night</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
    <category num="4">Pescatarian</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/135020/hls24_1559674929.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/135020/landscape_720/1559674929</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). Line a baking sheet with a reusable baking mat or parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">In a small bowl, stir together the butter, miso, ginger, garlic, and sesame oil. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">Arrange the potatoes on the prepared baking sheet. Season with salt and pepper and drizzle with ½ tablespoon sunflower oil. Toss to coat. </step>
    <step num="3">Roast the potatoes until tender, 10-12 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">While the potatoes roast, sear the sea bass. Pat each fillet dry with a clean kitchen towel or paper towel and season on both sides with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="5">Heat 2 tablespoons of sunflower oil in a medium skillet over medium-high heat. Once the oil is nearly smoking, add the sea bass, skin-side down, and cook until the skin is crispy, 3-4 minutes. Flip and sear the other side until golden brown, about 3 minutes. Remove the fish from the pan. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove the potatoes from the oven, leaving the oven on. Move the potatoes to a quarter of the pan. Place the fish, skin-side down, on the other quarter and spread the bok choy on the empty half. Brush the miso butter over each fish fillet, then flip and brush more on the skin side. Drizzle the remaining ½ tablespoon sunflower oil over the bok choy and season with salt and pepper. Toss to coat. </step>
    <step num="7">Return the baking sheet to the oven and bake until the fish is completely opaque and just cooked through, 8-10 minutes. The internal temperature should reach 145°F (63°C). </step>
    <step num="8">Divide the fish, potatoes, and bok choy between 2 plates. Garnish with sesame seeds and serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line a baking sheet with a reusable baking mat or parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a small bowl, stir together the butter, miso, ginger, garlic, and sesame oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Arrange the potatoes on the prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Season with salt and pepper and drizzle with ½ tablespoon sunflower oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Roast the potatoes until tender, 10-12 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">While the potatoes roast, sear the sea bass. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Pat each fillet dry with a clean kitchen towel or paper towel and season on both sides with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Heat 2 tablespoons of sunflower oil in a medium skillet over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Once the oil is nearly smoking, add the sea bass, skin-side down, and cook until the skin is crispy, 3-4 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Flip and sear the other side until golden brown, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove the fish from the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove the potatoes from the oven, leaving the oven on. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Move the potatoes to a quarter of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Place the fish, skin-side down, on the other quarter and spread the bok choy on the empty half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Brush the miso butter over each fish fillet, then flip and brush more on the skin side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Drizzle the remaining ½ tablespoon sunflower oil over the bok choy and season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Return the baking sheet to the oven and bake until the fish is completely opaque and just cooked through, 8-10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">The internal temperature should reach 145°F (63°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Divide the fish, potatoes, and bok choy between 2 plates. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Garnish with sesame seeds and serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>