<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Dairy-Free Chocolate Coconut Espresso Panna Cotta Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/dairy-free-chocolate-coconut-espresso-panna-cotta</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/dairy-free-coconut-cream-panna-cotta</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">coconut oil, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ oz ; dark chocolate, chopped ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 cups ; coconut cream ; (600 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; organic cane sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; instant espresso </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; hot water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; agar agar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">shaved dark chocolate, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">espresso beans, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="3">Date Night</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117572/hls24_1543602966.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117572/landscape_720/1543602966</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>19.333</start_time>
    <end_time>79.716</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Grease 4 4-ounce (115 g) ramekins with coconut oil and set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">In a medium saucepan over medium-low heat, combine the dark chocolate, coconut cream, sugar, and instant espresso. Warm slowly, stirring occasionally, until the sugar is dissolved and the mixture is simmering. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the agar agar to the hot water and stir until there are no lumps and the agar agar is fully dissolved. </step>
    <step num="3">Pour the agar mixture into the warm coconut cream mixture and whisk to combine. Increase the heat to medium, bring to a gentle boil, and whisk continuously for 3 minutes, until thickened. Remove from the heat and immediately divide between the greased ramekins. </step>
    <step num="4">Refrigerate for at least 30 minutes. (The agar will set at room temperature, but chilling the panna cotta in the fridge will expedite the process.) </step>
    <step num="5">When ready to serve, use an offset spatula or butter knife to carefully work around the edges of the ramekins to loosen the panna cotta. Invert onto serving plates and garnish with shaved dark chocolate and espresso beans. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
    <step num="7">Nutrition - Calories: 387, Total fat: 31 grams, Sodium: 19 grams, Total carbs: 29 grams, Dietary fiber: 8 grams, Sugars: 21 grams, Protein: 3 grams </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Grease 4 4-ounce (115 g) ramekins with coconut oil and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a medium saucepan over medium-low heat, combine the dark chocolate, coconut cream, sugar, and instant espresso. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Warm slowly, stirring occasionally, until the sugar is dissolved and the mixture is simmering. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the agar agar to the hot water and stir until there are no lumps and the agar agar is fully dissolved. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour the agar mixture into the warm coconut cream mixture and whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Increase the heat to medium, bring to a gentle boil, and whisk continuously for 3 minutes, until thickened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove from the heat and immediately divide between the greased ramekins. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Refrigerate for at least 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">(The agar will set at room temperature, but chilling the panna cotta in the fridge will expedite the process.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">When ready to serve, use an offset spatula or butter knife to carefully work around the edges of the ramekins to loosen the panna cotta. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Invert onto serving plates and garnish with shaved dark chocolate and espresso beans. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Nutrition - Calories: 387, Total fat: 31 grams, Sodium: 19 grams, Total carbs: 29 grams, Dietary fiber: 8 grams, Sugars: 21 grams, Protein: 3 grams </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>