<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>High-Protein Sweet And Savory Crepes Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/high-protein-sweet-and-savory-crepes</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ cup ; yellow onion, thinly sliced ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ ; yellow bell pepper, seeded and diced into 1/4 in (6 mm) pieces </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; roma tomato, seeded and diced ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; zucchini, diced ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¾ cup ; japanese eggplant, about 1 small - diced ; (270 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 cloves ; garlic, unpeeled </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 tablespoons ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 teaspoons ; fresh thyme, plus more for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ teaspoon ; freshly ground black pepper, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; goat cheese, room temperature ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 cup ; whole milk ricotta cheese ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ cup ; strawberry, finely chopped, plus more for garnish, quartered ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">¼ cup ; blackberry, halved, plus more for garnish ; (35 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 teaspoon ; lemon zest </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 tablespoon ; honey, plus more for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">whipped cream, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">6 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 ½ cups ; unsweetened coconut milk, full-fat canned ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">½ cup ; coconut flour ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">1 tablespoon ; coconut oil, melted, plus more for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="4">Brunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/134661/hls24_1559324904.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/134661/landscape_720/1559324904</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">If making the savory filling, preheat the oven to 450°F (230°C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, toss together the onion, bell pepper, tomato, zucchini, eggplant, garlic, olive oil, thyme, salt, and pepper. Spread in an even layer on a large baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="2">Roast the vegetables until they are soft and caramelized, about 18 minutes, flipping halfway through. Set aside to cool. </step>
    <step num="3">When cool enough to handle, pick the garlic from the vegetables and remove the skin. Add to a large bowl and mash into a paste. Add the goat cheese and stir to combine, then add the vegetables and toss to coat. Season with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="4">Use immediately to fill the crepes, or store in an airtight container in the refrigerator for up to 3 days. </step>
    <step num="5">If making the sweet filling: In a small bowl, stir together the ricotta, strawberries, blackberries, lemon zest, and honey. </step>
    <step num="6">Use immediately to fill crepes, or store in an airtight container in the refrigerator up to 3 days. </step>
    <step num="7">Make the crepes: In a large bowl, combine the eggs, coconut milk, coconut flour, coconut oil, and salt. </step>
    <step num="8">Using an immersion blender, blend the ingredients to form a smooth batter, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed. </step>
    <step num="9">Preheat a 9-inch (22 cm) nonstick skillet or crepe pan over medium heat. Add just enough oil to coat the pan, about ½ teaspoon. Swirl the pan to coat evenly. </step>
    <step num="10">Add ½ cup batter to the hot pan and swirl the pan around again until the batter evenly coats the bottom all the way to the edges. Cook for 4-5 minutes, or until the bottom of the crepe is golden brown in spots and the top is completely cooked through with no raw batter on the surface. </step>
    <step num="11">Add ¼ cup of your preferred filling to the top left quarter of the crepe. Using a small spatula or spoon, evenly spread the filling over that section, leaving a ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) border along the outside edge.Fold the bottom half of the crepe over the top half, then fold the right (unfilled) side over the left side to form a triangle. Use a rubber spatula to gently transfer the crepe to a plate. Repeat with the remaining batter and filling. </step>
    <step num="12">Garnish the savory crepes with more thyme and the sweet crepes with whipped cream, quartered strawberries, blackberries, and honey. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">If making the savory filling, preheat the oven to 450°F (230°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a large bowl, toss together the onion, bell pepper, tomato, zucchini, eggplant, garlic, olive oil, thyme, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Spread in an even layer on a large baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Roast the vegetables until they are soft and caramelized, about 18 minutes, flipping halfway through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Set aside to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">When cool enough to handle, pick the garlic from the vegetables and remove the skin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add to a large bowl and mash into a paste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the goat cheese and stir to combine, then add the vegetables and toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Use immediately to fill the crepes, or store in an airtight container in the refrigerator for up to 3 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">If making the sweet filling: In a small bowl, stir together the ricotta, strawberries, blackberries, lemon zest, and honey. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Use immediately to fill crepes, or store in an airtight container in the refrigerator up to 3 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Make the crepes: In a large bowl, combine the eggs, coconut milk, coconut flour, coconut oil, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Using an immersion blender, blend the ingredients to form a smooth batter, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Preheat a 9-inch (22 cm) nonstick skillet or crepe pan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add just enough oil to coat the pan, about ½ teaspoon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Swirl the pan to coat evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Add ½ cup batter to the hot pan and swirl the pan around again until the batter evenly coats the bottom all the way to the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Cook for 4-5 minutes, or until the bottom of the crepe is golden brown in spots and the top is completely cooked through with no raw batter on the surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add ¼ cup of your preferred filling to the top left quarter of the crepe. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Using a small spatula or spoon, evenly spread the filling over that section, leaving a ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) border along the outside edge.Fold the bottom half of the crepe over the top half, then fold the right (unfilled) side over the left side to form a triangle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Use a rubber spatula to gently transfer the crepe to a plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Repeat with the remaining batter and filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Garnish the savory crepes with more thyme and the sweet crepes with whipped cream, quartered strawberries, blackberries, and honey. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>