<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Flower Pot 'Box' Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/flower-pot-box-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 package ; chocolate cake mix </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 package ; brownie mix </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">8 ; eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; vegetable oil ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 cups ; buttercream frosting, divided ; (460 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">30 drops ; yellow food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">11 drops ; red food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">4 drops ; brown food coloring </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/76421/hls24_1517594896.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/76421/landscape_720/1517594896</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 350°F (180°C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, combine cake mix, brownie mix, eggs, water, and vegetable oil, and whisk until batter is thick and smooth. </step>
    <step num="2">Line an 8x7-inch (20x17-cm) terra-cotta pot with foil, ensuring the sides are smooth as possible. Pour batter inside, leave 3 inches of space between the batter and the top of the pot. </step>
    <step num="3">Line a cupcake pan with green cupcake liners and fill each with about ¼ cup (32 g) of batter. </step>
    <step num="4">Put the terra-cotta pot and cupcake pan in the oven at the same time. Place a small pan or oven safe dish under the terra-cotta pot to catch any possible overflow of batter. </step>
    <step num="5">Bake cupcakes for 15 minutes. Bake cake for 45-60 minutes, or until a toothpick comes out clean. </step>
    <step num="6">In a medium bowl, combine 2 cups (455 g) buttercream frosting, 30 drops yellow food coloring, 10 drops red food coloring, and 4 drops brown food coloring to create a terra-cotta orange color. </step>
    <step num="7">In a separate bowl, combine 2 cups (455 g) of buttercream frosting and 1 drop of red food coloring to create a pale pink color. </step>
    <step num="8">Use the foil to lift the cake out of the terracotta pot, and carefully peel off the foil. Use an angled icing spatula to evenly ice the sides of the cake with the terra-cotta orange frosting. Use the spatula or icing scraper to remove excess icing and create a smooth finish. Add an inch (2cm) more of frosting to top rim of the cake, about 1-inch (2 cm) in thickness. Use the spatula or icing scraper to smooth the sides to create the rim of the pot. </step>
    <step num="9">Place a 2D piping tip inside a piping bag and fill it with the pale pink frosting. Twist the end of the piping bag and gently apply even pressure as you make a spiral design from the center out on each cupcake to create a rose. </step>
    <step num="10">Place two toothpicks in the center of the cake and use them to attach a cupcake to the center. Repeat around the rim of the cake with 4 more cupcakes spaced about 2 inches (5 cm) apart. Fold extra green cupcake liners into quarters and place one between each cupcake. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a large bowl, combine cake mix, brownie mix, eggs, water, and vegetable oil, and whisk until batter is thick and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Line an 8x7-inch (20x17-cm) terra-cotta pot with foil, ensuring the sides are smooth as possible. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Pour batter inside, leave 3 inches of space between the batter and the top of the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Line a cupcake pan with green cupcake liners and fill each with about ¼ cup (32 g) of batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Put the terra-cotta pot and cupcake pan in the oven at the same time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Place a small pan or oven safe dish under the terra-cotta pot to catch any possible overflow of batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Bake cupcakes for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Bake cake for 45-60 minutes, or until a toothpick comes out clean. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a medium bowl, combine 2 cups (455 g) buttercream frosting, 30 drops yellow food coloring, 10 drops red food coloring, and 4 drops brown food coloring to create a terra-cotta orange color. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a separate bowl, combine 2 cups (455 g) of buttercream frosting and 1 drop of red food coloring to create a pale pink color. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Use the foil to lift the cake out of the terracotta pot, and carefully peel off the foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Use an angled icing spatula to evenly ice the sides of the cake with the terra-cotta orange frosting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Use the spatula or icing scraper to remove excess icing and create a smooth finish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add an inch (2cm) more of frosting to top rim of the cake, about 1-inch (2 cm) in thickness. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Use the spatula or icing scraper to smooth the sides to create the rim of the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Place a 2D piping tip inside a piping bag and fill it with the pale pink frosting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Twist the end of the piping bag and gently apply even pressure as you make a spiral design from the center out on each cupcake to create a rose. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Place two toothpicks in the center of the cake and use them to attach a cupcake to the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Repeat around the rim of the cake with 4 more cupcakes spaced about 2 inches (5 cm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Fold extra green cupcake liners into quarters and place one between each cupcake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>