<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Classic Hummus By Alon Shaya Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/classic-hummus-as-made-by-alon-shaya</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ cups ; dried chickpeas ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 teaspoons ; baking soda, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 qt ; cold water, divided ; (2.8 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">7 cloves ; garlic, lightly crushed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; raw tahini ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; cumin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 tablespoons ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">3 tablespoons ; canola oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 tablespoons ; hot water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 tablespoons ; extra virgin olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">tahini sauce, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">3 tablespoons ; olive oil, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">¼ cup ; fresh parsley, lightly chopped (optional) ; (10 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">½ teaspoon ; aleppo-style pepper, optional </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Middle Eastern</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Vegan</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="5">Snacks</category>
    <category num="6">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97136/hls24_1528145864.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97136/landscape_720/1528145864</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, combine the dried chickpeas, ½ teaspoon baking soda, and 1½ quarts (1.4 L) of cold water water. Soak overnight. </step>
    <step num="1">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </step>
    <step num="2">Drain the chickpeas and transfer to a baking sheet. Sprinkle with 2 teaspoons of baking soda and spread evenly on the sheet. Bake for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Transfer baked chickpeas to colander and rinse under cold water. Massage to remove excess baking soda and begin to loosen the skins. </step>
    <step num="4">In a large pot over high heat, add the rinsed chickpeas, remaining 1½ quarts (1.4 L) of water, and remaining ½ teaspoon of baking soda. Bring to a boil, then reduce the heat to medium. </step>
    <step num="5">With a slotted spoon or small sieve, skim away any foam and loose skins that rise to the surface of the water and discard. This will ensure the hummus is extra creamy and smooth! Continue this process, regularly skimming off any loose skins, for about 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the garlic to the pot and continue to cook for another 25-30 minutes, until the chickpeas are very soft and easily fall apart. </step>
    <step num="7">Drain the chickpeas and let sit for a few minutes to let any extra moisture drain off. </step>
    <step num="8">Transfer the chickpeas to a food processor with the tahini, salt, cumin, and lemon juice. Process for 2-3 minutes, until the mixture is super smooth. </step>
    <step num="9">With the food processor still running, add the canola oil, hot water, and 2 tablespoons of olive oil. Continue to process for another 2-3 minutes. Don’t worry, you can’t over-process it! You want the hummus to be as smooth and creamy as possible. </step>
    <step num="10">To serve, spread the hummus in a wide, shallow bowl. If desired, top with tahini sauce, olive oil, and garnish with parsley and Aleppo-style pepper. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, combine the dried chickpeas, ½ teaspoon baking soda, and 1½ quarts (1.4 L) of cold water water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Soak overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Drain the chickpeas and transfer to a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Sprinkle with 2 teaspoons of baking soda and spread evenly on the sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Bake for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Transfer baked chickpeas to colander and rinse under cold water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Massage to remove excess baking soda and begin to loosen the skins. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">In a large pot over high heat, add the rinsed chickpeas, remaining 1½ quarts (1.4 L) of water, and remaining ½ teaspoon of baking soda. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Bring to a boil, then reduce the heat to medium. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">With a slotted spoon or small sieve, skim away any foam and loose skins that rise to the surface of the water and discard. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">This will ensure the hummus is extra creamy and smooth! Continue this process, regularly skimming off any loose skins, for about 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the garlic to the pot and continue to cook for another 25-30 minutes, until the chickpeas are very soft and easily fall apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Drain the chickpeas and let sit for a few minutes to let any extra moisture drain off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Transfer the chickpeas to a food processor with the tahini, salt, cumin, and lemon juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Process for 2-3 minutes, until the mixture is super smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">With the food processor still running, add the canola oil, hot water, and 2 tablespoons of olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Continue to process for another 2-3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Don’t worry, you can’t over-process it! You want the hummus to be as smooth and creamy as possible. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">To serve, spread the hummus in a wide, shallow bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">If desired, top with tahini sauce, olive oil, and garnish with parsley and Aleppo-style pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>