<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Easter Savory Pie (Pizza Rustica) Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/easter-savory-pie-pizza-rustica</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; warm water ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; olive oil ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; instant yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">5 ½ cups ; all-purpose flour ; (690 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">10 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">16 oz ; ricotta cheese ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 cup ; fresh parsley, chopped ; (35 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">4 oz ; grated pecorino romano ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">8 oz ; ham, boiled, cubed ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">8 oz ; pepperoni, cubed ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">8 oz ; provolone cheese, cubed ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">8 oz ; salami, hard, cubed ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">4 oz ; prosciutto, chopped ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 ½ cups ; bread crumbs ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 ; large egg, beaten </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Italian</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Lunch</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/86945/hls24_1522255744.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/86945/landscape_720/1522255744</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large mixing bowl, combine the warm water, sugar, olive oil, and instant yeast. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the flour and salt, and mix the dough together with a wooden spoon until it forms a ball. Then knead the dough for 1 minute, or until it feels smooth and springy. </step>
    <step num="2">Cover the dough in the bowl with a kitchen towel or plastic wrap. Let rise in a warm place for 2 hours. </step>
    <step num="3">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </step>
    <step num="4">In a large bowl, add 10 eggs, ricotta, parsley, and Pecorino Romano. Whisk the mixture until smooth. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the ham, pepperoni, provolone, hard salami, prosciutto, and bread crumbs. Fold in the cubed meats and cheeses. The texture should be thick and slightly wet. </step>
    <step num="6">Once the dough has doubled in size, dump it onto a floured surface, knead for 2 minutes, and shape it into a ball. Roll the dough out to a rough circle, about ¼-inch (½-cm) thick. </step>
    <step num="7">With a pizza cutter or knife, cut out a large disc that is 2 inches (5-cm) wider than a 9-inch (23-cm) springform pan or round baking dish. With the rest of the dough, cut thick strips about 9 inches (23-cm) long and 1 inch (2 cm) thick. </step>
    <step num="8">Transfer the dough disc into the springform pan or baking dish. Gently press the dough against the bottom and sides of the pan, allowing the excess to hang over the sides. </step>
    <step num="9">Pour the egg, cheese, and meat mixture into the pan. Pack the filling down and smooth the top with a spatula. </step>
    <step num="10">Weave the strips of dough on top to create a decorative pattern. Trim any excess dough, then fold and crimp the edges. Brush the top with egg wash. </step>
    <step num="11">Bake the pizza rustica for 2 hours, or until the filling is cooked through and the pizza dough has browned. </step>
    <step num="12">Let the the pizza rustica cool completely. Remove from the pan. Chill in the refrigerator overnight on a wire rack. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large mixing bowl, combine the warm water, sugar, olive oil, and instant yeast. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the flour and salt, and mix the dough together with a wooden spoon until it forms a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Then knead the dough for 1 minute, or until it feels smooth and springy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cover the dough in the bowl with a kitchen towel or plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Let rise in a warm place for 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a large bowl, add 10 eggs, ricotta, parsley, and Pecorino Romano. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Whisk the mixture until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the ham, pepperoni, provolone, hard salami, prosciutto, and bread crumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Fold in the cubed meats and cheeses. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">The texture should be thick and slightly wet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Once the dough has doubled in size, dump it onto a floured surface, knead for 2 minutes, and shape it into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Roll the dough out to a rough circle, about ¼-inch (½-cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">With a pizza cutter or knife, cut out a large disc that is 2 inches (5-cm) wider than a 9-inch (23-cm) springform pan or round baking dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">With the rest of the dough, cut thick strips about 9 inches (23-cm) long and 1 inch (2 cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Transfer the dough disc into the springform pan or baking dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Gently press the dough against the bottom and sides of the pan, allowing the excess to hang over the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Pour the egg, cheese, and meat mixture into the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Pack the filling down and smooth the top with a spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Weave the strips of dough on top to create a decorative pattern. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Trim any excess dough, then fold and crimp the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Brush the top with egg wash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Bake the pizza rustica for 2 hours, or until the filling is cooked through and the pizza dough has browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Let the the pizza rustica cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Remove from the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Chill in the refrigerator overnight on a wire rack. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>