<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Dairy-Free Strawberry Rhubarb Tart Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/dairy-free-strawberry-rhubarb-tart</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ cups ; whole wheat flour ; (195 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; almond flour ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; maple syrup ; (85 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; cold water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¾ cup ; coconut oil, cold ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 ½ cups ; strawberry, hulled and quartered, plus more sliced for garnish ; (525 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 cup ; rhubarb, diced, plus more sliced for garnish ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; coconut sugar ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ cup ; water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ; lemon, zested, plus more for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 tablespoons ; cornstarch, dissolved in 1½ tablespoons water </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Healthy</category>
    <category num="3">Vegan</category>
    <category num="4">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="5">Desserts</category>
    <category num="6">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/102521/hls24_1532033138.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/102521/landscape_720/1532033138</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the crust: Add the whole wheat flour, almond flour, baking powder, salt, maple syrup, water, and coconut oil to a food processor. Pulse until crumbly. </step>
    <step num="1">Transfer the dough to the prepared pie dish. Using a flat-bottomed measuring cup, press the dough against the bottom and sides of the dish. Using your fingers, form the edges of the crust, then press all the way around using the tines of a fork. Work quickly, as the heat from your hands will begin to melt the coconut oil and make the crust hard to work with. </step>
    <step num="2">Transfer the crust to the refrigerator to chill while you make the filling. </step>
    <step num="3">Make the filling: In a medium pot over medium heat, combine the quartered strawberries, diced rhubarb, coconut sugar, water, and lemon zest. Stir and bring to gentle boil. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the cornstarch slurry and stir. Simmer until the filling thickens, stirring occasionally, about 8 minutes. Remove the filling from the heat and set aside to cool slightly. </step>
    <step num="5">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). Grease a 9-inch (23 cm) pie dish. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove the crust from the refrigerator and poke holes in the bottom with a fork. Carefully pour the filling into the crust. </step>
    <step num="7">Decorate the top of the tart with sliced rhubarb and strawberries. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake for 30-40 minutes, or until the crust is golden brown. You can cover the edges of the crust with foil to prevent burning, then remove the foil for the last 10 minutes in the oven, if desired. </step>
    <step num="9">Let cool, then slice and serve. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the crust: Add the whole wheat flour, almond flour, baking powder, salt, maple syrup, water, and coconut oil to a food processor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pulse until crumbly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Transfer the dough to the prepared pie dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Using a flat-bottomed measuring cup, press the dough against the bottom and sides of the dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Using your fingers, form the edges of the crust, then press all the way around using the tines of a fork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Work quickly, as the heat from your hands will begin to melt the coconut oil and make the crust hard to work with </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Transfer the crust to the refrigerator to chill while you make the filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Make the filling: In a medium pot over medium heat, combine the quartered strawberries, diced rhubarb, coconut sugar, water, and lemon zest. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Stir and bring to gentle boil </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the cornstarch slurry and stir. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Simmer until the filling thickens, stirring occasionally, about 8 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove the filling from the heat and set aside to cool slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Grease a 9-inch (23 cm) pie dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove the crust from the refrigerator and poke holes in the bottom with a fork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Carefully pour the filling into the crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Decorate the top of the tart with sliced rhubarb and strawberries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Bake for 30-40 minutes, or until the crust is golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">You can cover the edges of the crust with foil to prevent burning, then remove the foil for the last 10 minutes in the oven, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Let cool, then slice and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>