<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Cookie Cutter Ice Cream Pops Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/cookie-cutter-ice-cream-pops</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">65 oz ; strawberry ice cream, softened ; (2 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 cups ; white chocolate chip ; (525 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; coconut oil ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">60 drops ; yellow food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">green sanding sugar, for sprinkling </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">pineapple cookie cutter, 3X5 in (7cmn X 12 cm) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">8 ; ice pop sticks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">metal skewer </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">offset spatula </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">BBQ</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/135185/hls24_1559773050.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/135185/landscape_720/1559773050</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">Scoop the softened ice cream onto the baking sheet, distributing evenly. Use a large offset spatula to spread the ice cream in an even layer. Cover the ice cream with a second piece of parchment paper. Freeze for at least 6 hours, up to overnight. Place another baking sheet in the freezer to chill. </step>
    <step num="2">Fill a bowl large enough to fit the cookie cutter with hot water. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove the empty chilled baking sheet from the freezer and line with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="4">Remove the ice cream from the freezer. Peel the top layer of the parchment paper off the ice cream. Working quickly, dip the cookie cutter in the hot water and press into the ice cream to cut out shapes. You may need to wiggle the cookie cutter around a little to get the shape to release. Use an offset spatula to transfer the shapes to the clean baking sheet. Return to the freezer. </step>
    <step num="5">Fill a medium bowl with very hot water. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove the ice cream pops from the freezer. Place a metal skewer into the hot water for 10 seconds. Working carefully and quickly, insert the skewer 3 inches (7 cm) into the base of a pineapple pop. Remove the skewer and immediately insert a popsicle stick into the space created by the skewer. Repeat with the remaining pops. </step>
    <step num="7">Return the pops to the freezer for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="8">While the pops set, make the magic shell. In a wide and shallow microwave-safe dish, combine the white chocolate chips and coconut oil. Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring between, until melted and smooth. </step>
    <step num="9">Continue stirring the magic shell until it cools down, about 3 minutes. Add the yellow food coloring, a few drops at a time, and stir until a pale, buttercup yellow color is achieved. </step>
    <step num="10">Remove the ice pops from the freezer. Pick up a pop by the stick and quickly dip the ice cream into the magic shell to coat completely. Sprinkle green sanding sugar over the top section of the pineapple to resemble the crown. Repeat with the remaining pops. </step>
    <step num="11">Return the pops to the freezer for 10 minutes to set and harden completely. Store in the freezer until ready to eat. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Scoop the softened ice cream onto the baking sheet, distributing evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Use a large offset spatula to spread the ice cream in an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cover the ice cream with a second piece of parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Freeze for at least 6 hours, up to overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Place another baking sheet in the freezer to chill. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Fill a bowl large enough to fit the cookie cutter with hot water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove the empty chilled baking sheet from the freezer and line with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Remove the ice cream from the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Peel the top layer of the parchment paper off the ice cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Working quickly, dip the cookie cutter in the hot water and press into the ice cream to cut out shapes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">You may need to wiggle the cookie cutter around a little to get the shape to release. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Use an offset spatula to transfer the shapes to the clean baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Return to the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Fill a medium bowl with very hot water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove the ice cream pops from the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Place a metal skewer into the hot water for 10 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Working carefully and quickly, insert the skewer 3 inches (7 cm) into the base of a pineapple pop. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Remove the skewer and immediately insert a popsicle stick into the space created by the skewer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Repeat with the remaining pops. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Return the pops to the freezer for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">While the pops set, make the magic shell. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">In a wide and shallow microwave-safe dish, combine the white chocolate chips and coconut oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring between, until melted and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Continue stirring the magic shell until it cools down, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Add the yellow food coloring, a few drops at a time, and stir until a pale, buttercup yellow color is achieved. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Remove the ice pops from the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Pick up a pop by the stick and quickly dip the ice cream into the magic shell to coat completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Sprinkle green sanding sugar over the top section of the pineapple to resemble the crown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Repeat with the remaining pops. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Return the pops to the freezer for 10 minutes to set and harden completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Store in the freezer until ready to eat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>