<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>GoT Cocktails: Pineapple, Blue Curaçao, And Rum Ice Zombie</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/ice-zombie</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">14 fl oz ; canned coconut milk, chilled ; (420 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; powdered sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">ice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; blue sanding sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; white sanding sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 fl oz ; pineapple juice, divided ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ½ oz ; white rum ; (45 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 fl oz ; blue curaçao ; (30 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Drinks</category>
    <category num="1">Happy Hour</category>
    <category num="2">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129055/hls24_1554398806.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129055/landscape_720/1554398806</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Carefully scoop the solid layer from the can of chilled coconut milk into a medium bowl. Blend with an electric hand mixer until fluffy. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the powdered sugar and continue mixing until fully incorporated, scraping down the bowl as needed. While mixer is still running, add in a splash of coconut milk from the can, and mix until cream is silky and just falls from a spoon. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">On a small plate, mix together the blue and white sugars. Pour 1 ounce pineapple juice into a small bowl. </step>
    <step num="3">Dip the rim of a highball glass into the pineapple juice, then in the sugar mixture. Fill glass with ice. </step>
    <step num="4">In a cocktail shaker filled with ice, combine the rum, blue curaçao, and remaining 1 ounce pineapple juice. Shake vigorously for 20 seconds. </step>
    <step num="5">Strain into the sugared highball glass and top with 2 tablespoons of the coconut whipped cream. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Carefully scoop the solid layer from the can of chilled coconut milk into a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Blend with an electric hand mixer until fluffy </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the powdered sugar and continue mixing until fully incorporated, scraping down the bowl as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">While mixer is still running, add in a splash of coconut milk from the can, and mix until cream is silky and just falls from a spoon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">On a small plate, mix together the blue and white sugars. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Pour 1 ounce pineapple juice into a small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Dip the rim of a highball glass into the pineapple juice, then in the sugar mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Fill glass with ice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a cocktail shaker filled with ice, combine the rum, blue curaçao, and remaining 1 ounce pineapple juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Shake vigorously for 20 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Strain into the sugared highball glass and top with 2 tablespoons of the coconut whipped cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>