<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Taiwanese Beef Noodle Soup Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/taiwanese-beef-noodle-soup</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 lb ; beef shank ; (905 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">6 ; scallions, halved crosswise, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">8 slices ; fresh ginger, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">6 pieces ; star anise, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; vegetable oil ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">6 cloves ; garlic </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 ; red chilis, halved lengthwise </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; medium white onion, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 piece ; rock sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">3 tablespoons ; spicy bean paste, or regular bean paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ cup ; dark soy sauce ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ cup ; rice wine ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ cup ; light soy sauce ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 ; medium tomatoes, quartered </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 teaspoon ; white pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">5 leaves ; bay leaf </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">2 bundles ; flour noodle </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">2 cups ; bok choy ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">scallion, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">fresh cilantro, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">red chili, finely diced </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Chinese</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Date Night</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/92228/hls24_1525287281.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/92228/landscape_720/1525287281</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Fill a large pot with about 6 quarts (5 ½ L) of water and add the beef shank, 3 scallions, 5 slices of ginger, and 3 pieces of star anise. Cover, bring to a boil over high heat, and cook for 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Remove the meat from the pot, rinse in cold water, and cut into thick slices. Discard the cooking liquid. </step>
    <step num="2">In a wok or large pan over medium-high heat, pour in the vegetable oil and add the remaining 3 scallions, 3 ginger slices, garlic, red chilies, remaining 3 pieces of star anise, onion, rock sugar, and spicy bean paste. Cook until the onions start to become translucent. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the sliced beef. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the dark soy sauce, for color, stir, then add the rice wine. </step>
    <step num="5">Pour in the light soy sauce, for flavor, then add the tomatoes. Stir fry for 8-10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Fill the same large pot about a quarter of the way with water and heat over medium-high heat. Add the stir-fried meat, vegetables, and cooking liquid. </step>
    <step num="7">Add more water until the meat is just covered, then add the white pepper, salt, and bay leaves. Cover and reduce the heat to low and simmer for at least 2 hours, until the meat becomes tender. Remove bay leaves and star anise before serving. </step>
    <step num="8">Bring a large pot of water to boil over high heat and cook the flour noodles according to the package instructions. Remove the noodles from the water. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the bok choy. Boil for 3 minutes, then remove. </step>
    <step num="10">To assemble the soup, place a generous amount of noodles in the bottom of a bowl. Then add bok choy, meat, and broth. Garnish with scallions, cilantro, and red chilies. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Fill a large pot with about 6 quarts (5 ½ L) of water and add the beef shank, 3 scallions, 5 slices of ginger, and 3 pieces of star anise. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cover, bring to a boil over high heat, and cook for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Remove the meat from the pot, rinse in cold water, and cut into thick slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Discard the cooking liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a wok or large pan over medium-high heat, pour in the vegetable oil and add the remaining 3 scallions, 3 ginger slices, garlic, red chilies, remaining 3 pieces of star anise, onion, rock sugar, and spicy bean paste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cook until the onions start to become translucent. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the sliced beef. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the dark soy sauce, for color, stir, then add the rice wine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Pour in the light soy sauce, for flavor, then add the tomatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Stir fry for 8-10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Fill the same large pot about a quarter of the way with water and heat over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the stir-fried meat, vegetables, and cooking liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add more water until the meat is just covered, then add the white pepper, salt, and bay leaves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Cover and reduce the heat to low and simmer for at least 2 hours, until the meat becomes tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove bay leaves and star anise before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Bring a large pot of water to boil over high heat and cook the flour noodles according to the package instructions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Remove the noodles from the water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Add the bok choy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Boil for 3 minutes, then remove. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">To assemble the soup, place a generous amount of noodles in the bottom of a bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Then add bok choy, meat, and broth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Garnish with scallions, cilantro, and red chilies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>