<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Matcha Green Tea Swiss Roll Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/matcha-green-tea-swiss-roll</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ¼ cups ; milk ; (300 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; cornstarch ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">⅓ cup ; white sugar ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; honey </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; heavy cream ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">⅓ cup ; white sugar ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 ; eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; matcha green tea powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 teaspoons ; honey </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; cake flour ; (25 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="4">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32078/low_1495125329.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32078/mp4_720x1280/1495125329</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Start with the filling. Pour the milk into a small saucepan, and sprinkle over the cornstarch, whisk until combined. </step>
    <step num="1">Next, add the honey and sugar stirring continuously over a low heat. When the milk mixture almost starts to boil it will thicken and get a bit lumpy, don't panic! Just keep stirring until it smooths out. Continue to stir the now thick milk mixture over the heat for an additional 1-2 minutes, to cook out the cornstarch flavor. </step>
    <step num="2">Take off the heat and pour into a bowl or shallow dish. Cover the mixture with cling wrap, pushing it all the way to the top of the custard to prevent a film from forming and chill this in the refrigerator until cold. </step>
    <step num="3">Next, make the cake by combining the sugar, honey, matcha powder, and eggs in a large bowl. Mix until it almost triples in size, is lighter in color, and becomes thick and fluffy. This will take about 7-10 minutes. If you dribble some of the batter on itself it should hold a "ribbon" shape for 4-5 seconds. </step>
    <step num="4">Once the batter has reached the correct consistency sift over the cake flour, and gently fold the flour in until all combined. </step>
    <step num="5">Heat your oven to 350˚F (175˚C) and butter your baking sheet. Place a piece of parchment paper (a few inches larger than your baking sheet) onto your baking sheet. Using a rubber scraper (or your hand) push out any bubbles. </step>
    <step num="6">Pour the batter into the prepared baking sheet and bake for 8-10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">NOTE: You'll know it's done when the cake is slightly risen, turning just a bit golden, and you can smell it. Also, if you gently press your fingertips on the surface of the cake, and no indentations are left, it's done. </step>
    <step num="8">In a clean bowl, whip the heavy cream with electric beaters until it is thick and pretty stiff, little peaks should form when you lift the beaters. </step>
    <step num="9">Grab your chilled custard from the fridge. Add one tsp of vanilla extract. Take the same beaters and whisk your custard, it will look funny at first, but after a few moments it will become nice and smooth. </step>
    <step num="10">Fold the whipped cream into the custard until they are combined. </step>
    <step num="11">Cool your cake for 2-3 minutes on the baking sheet. Lay a fresh sheet of parchment beside your cake and sprinkle it with powdered sugar. </step>
    <step num="12">Lift the cake with the sides of the parchment onto your table. Flip the cake onto the sugared parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="13">Remove parchment paper from the flipped cake. </step>
    <step num="14">Slather the filling onto your cake. </step>
    <step num="15">Roll it up, using the parchment to help. </step>
    <step num="16">Wrap the whole thing in cling wrap and chill for two hours before slicing. </step>
    <step num="17">Slice into pieces of your desired thickness and serve. </step>
    <step num="18">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Start with the filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pour the milk into a small saucepan, and sprinkle over the cornstarch, whisk until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Next, add the honey and sugar stirring continuously over a low heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">When the milk mixture almost starts to boil it will thicken and get a bit lumpy, don't panic! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Just keep stirring until it smooths out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Continue to stir the now thick milk mixture over the heat for an additional 1-2 minutes, to cook out the cornstarch flavor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Take off the heat and pour into a bowl or shallow dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cover the mixture with cling wrap, pushing it all the way to the top of the custard to prevent a film from forming and chill this in the refrigerator until cold. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Next, make the cake by combining the sugar, honey, matcha powder, and eggs in a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Mix until it almost triples in size, is lighter in color, and becomes thick and fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">This will take about 7-10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">If you dribble some of the batter on itself it should hold a "ribbon" shape for 4-5 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Once the batter has reached the correct consistency sift over the cake flour, and gently fold the flour in until all combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Heat your oven to 350˚F (175˚C) and butter your baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Place a piece of parchment paper (a few inches larger than your baking sheet) onto your baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Using a rubber scraper (or your hand) push out any bubbles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Pour the batter into the prepared baking sheet and bake for 8-10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">NOTE: You'll know it's done when the cake is slightly risen, turning just a bit golden, and you can smell it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Also, if you gently press your fingertips on the surface of the cake, and no indentations are left, it's done. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">In a clean bowl, whip the heavy cream with electric beaters until it is thick and pretty stiff, little peaks should form when you lift the beaters. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Grab your chilled custard from the fridge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Add one tsp of vanilla extract. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Take the same beaters and whisk your custard, it will look funny at first, but after a few moments it will become nice and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Fold the whipped cream into the custard until they are combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Cool your cake for 2-3 minutes on the baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Lay a fresh sheet of parchment beside your cake and sprinkle it with powdered sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Lift the cake with the sides of the parchment onto your table. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Flip the cake onto the sugared parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Remove parchment paper from the flipped cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Slather the filling onto your cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Roll it up, using the parchment to help. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Wrap the whole thing in cling wrap and chill for two hours before slicing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Slice into pieces of your desired thickness and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>