<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Crispy Cookie Bark Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/crispy-cookie-bark</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; all-purpose flour ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ teaspoon ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; unsalted butter ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; white sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; dark brown sugar ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ; egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">⅓ cup ; chocolate chips ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">24 oz ; semisweet baking chocolate ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">coarse sea salt </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="2">Snacks</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98654/hls24_1529011542.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98654/landscape_720/1529011542</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (160˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Make the cookies: in a medium bowl, whisk together the flour, baking soda, and salt. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">In a larger bowl, add the butter and sugars. Mix (either by hand or using an electric mixer) until smooth. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the egg, vanilla extract, and water to the butter mixture and mix until thoroughly incorporated. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the chocolate chips and dry ingredients, then use a spatula to gently fold them together, being careful not to overmix. </step>
    <step num="5">Using a small ice cream scoop or spoon, measure out 6 tablespoon-sized balls of dough and space them 2-3 inches (5-7 cm) apart on a prepared baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="6">Bake the cookies for 18 minutes. They should be thin with crispy edges when finished. </step>
    <step num="7">Remove the cookies from the oven and allow them to cool for 5 minutes on the baking sheet before transferring them to a wired cooling rack. Bake off the second half of the dough and allow all the cookies to reach room temperature before proceeding. </step>
    <step num="8">Once thoroughly cooled, place the baked cookies back in the oven, directly on the oven rack, and toast them at 325˚F (160˚C) for 7 minutes. This will completely dry out the cookies leaving them very crispy and brittle. </step>
    <step num="9">Carefully transfer all the toasted cookies to a parchment-lined baking sheet. Using the back of a heavy spoon or measuring cup, firmly smack the top of the cookies. Set the baking sheet of shattered cookies aside. </step>
    <step num="10">Make the bark: slowly melt 1 pound (455 g) of the baking chocolate either in a double boiler or in a glass bowl over just-simmering water. Allow the chocolate to melt undisturbed until about two-thirds of it has melted, then stir until it is completely smooth with no visible chunks. </step>
    <step num="11">Remove the chocolate from the heat and allow it to cool for 10 minutes before adding in the remaining chocolate. The residual heat will melt the solid chocolate. Mix until smooth. </step>
    <step num="12">Arrange the shattered cookie pieces in a layer on the baking sheet. Pour the melted chocolate over the pieces and use a spatula to quickly and evenly spread the chocolate across the tops of the cookie pieces. </step>
    <step num="13">Sprinkle with salt and any other desired toppings. Transfer the baking sheet to the refrigerator for at least 30 minutes for the chocolate to set. </step>
    <step num="14">Once the bark is set, remove the baking sheet from the refrigerator and cover the bark with parchment paper. Use something heavy (like a meat tenderizer) to break the bark into snack-sized pieces. </step>
    <step num="15">Serve the pieces immediately or store in the refrigerator until desired. </step>
    <step num="16">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (160˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Make the cookies: in a medium bowl, whisk together the flour, baking soda, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a larger bowl, add the butter and sugars. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Mix (either by hand or using an electric mixer) until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the egg, vanilla extract, and water to the butter mixture and mix until thoroughly incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the chocolate chips and dry ingredients, then use a spatula to gently fold them together, being careful not to overmix. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Using a small ice cream scoop or spoon, measure out 6 tablespoon-sized balls of dough and space them 2-3 inches (5-7 cm) apart on a prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Bake the cookies for 18 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">They should be thin with crispy edges when finished. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Remove the cookies from the oven and allow them to cool for 5 minutes on the baking sheet before transferring them to a wired cooling rack. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Bake off the second half of the dough and allow all the cookies to reach room temperature before proceeding. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Once thoroughly cooled, place the baked cookies back in the oven, directly on the oven rack, and toast them at 325˚F (160˚C) for 7 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">This will completely dry out the cookies leaving them very crispy and brittle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Carefully transfer all the toasted cookies to a parchment-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Using the back of a heavy spoon or measuring cup, firmly smack the top of the cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Set the baking sheet of shattered cookies aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Make the bark: slowly melt 1 pound (455 g) of the baking chocolate either in a double boiler or in a glass bowl over just-simmering water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Allow the chocolate to melt undisturbed until about two-thirds of it has melted, then stir until it is completely smooth with no visible chunks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Remove the chocolate from the heat and allow it to cool for 10 minutes before adding in the remaining chocolate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">The residual heat will melt the solid chocolate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Mix until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Arrange the shattered cookie pieces in a layer on the baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Pour the melted chocolate over the pieces and use a spatula to quickly and evenly spread the chocolate across the tops of the cookie pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Sprinkle with salt and any other desired toppings. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Transfer the baking sheet to the refrigerator for at least 30 minutes for the chocolate to set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Once the bark is set, remove the baking sheet from the refrigerator and cover the bark with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Use something heavy (like a meat tenderizer) to break the bark into snack-sized pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Serve the pieces immediately or store in the refrigerator until desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>