<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Hearty White Bean Stew Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/hearty-white-bean-stew</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; medium leek </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">5 oz ; pancetta ; (140 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 cups ; carrot, diced ; (220 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 stalks ; celery stalk, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">8 oz ; cremini mushroom, sliced ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">4 sprigs ; fresh thyme sprigs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">14.5 oz ; diced tomato ; (410 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">4 cups ; great northern beans, cooked or canned ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">6 cups ; low sodium vegetable broth ; (1.4 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">parmesan cheese, freshly grated, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">bread, crusty, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/114343/hls24_1541443999.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/114343/landscape_720/1541443999</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Trim the root end and the tough, dark green top of the leek and remove any thick outer layers. Cut the leek in half lengthwise, then slice into ¼-inch (6-mm) thick half moons. </step>
    <step num="1">Transfer to a bowl of water and shake around with your fingers to loosen any dirt or grit. Let the leeks sit in the water for a couple minutes to let any grit to sink to the bottom of the bowl. Carefully remove the cleaned leeks from the bowl, leaving the dirty water behind. </step>
    <step num="2">Heat the olive oil in a large, heavy-bottomed pot over medium heat. Add the pancetta and cook until crispy and most of the fat has rendered, about 8 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the leeks, carrots, celery, mushrooms, and garlic. Season with salt. Cook for 5-6 minutes, until the vegetables have released their juices and begin to soften. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the thyme leaves, tomatoes, beans, and vegetable stock. Stir to combine, then bring to a boil, cover, and cook, stirring occasionally, for 20 minutes until slightly reduced and hot throughout. Season with more salt, to taste. </step>
    <step num="5">Ladle into bowls and top with freshly grated Parmesan cheese. Serve with crusty bread. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
    <step num="7">NUTRITION: Calories: 338, Total fat:16 grams, Sodium: 291 mg, Total carbs: 37 grams, Dietary fiber: 11 grams, Sugars: 4 grams, Protein: 14 grams </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Trim the root end and the tough, dark green top of the leek and remove any thick outer layers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cut the leek in half lengthwise, then slice into ¼-inch (6-mm) thick half moons. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Transfer to a bowl of water and shake around with your fingers to loosen any dirt or grit. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Let the leeks sit in the water for a couple minutes to let any grit to sink to the bottom of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Carefully remove the cleaned leeks from the bowl, leaving the dirty water behind. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Heat the olive oil in a large, heavy-bottomed pot over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the pancetta and cook until crispy and most of the fat has rendered, about 8 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the leeks, carrots, celery, mushrooms, and garlic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Season with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Cook for 5-6 minutes, until the vegetables have released their juices and begin to soften. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the thyme leaves, tomatoes, beans, and vegetable stock. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Stir to combine, then bring to a boil, cover, and cook, stirring occasionally, for 20 minutes until slightly reduced and hot throughout. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Season with more salt, to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Ladle into bowls and top with freshly grated Parmesan cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Serve with crusty bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">NUTRITION: Calories: 338, Total fat:16 grams, Sodium: 291 mg, Total carbs: 37 grams, Dietary fiber: 11 grams, Sugars: 4 grams, Protein: 14 grams </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>