<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Roasted Delicata Squash And Farro Salad Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/roasted-delicata-squash-and-farro-salad</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; medium delicata squash, cleaned </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 tablespoons ; olive oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ½ teaspoons ; salt, plus a pinch, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; large fennel bulb </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ teaspoon ; smoked paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 bunch ; lacinato kale, woody stems removed, roughly chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">4 ½ cups ; farro, cooked ; (750 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; canned chickpea, drained and rinsed ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">⅓ cup ; creamy goat cheese, crumbled ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; apple cider vinegar ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; fresh lemon juice ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">3 tablespoons ; honey </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 tablespoon ; dijon mustard </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">4 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">½ cup ; extra virgin olive oil ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Healthy</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Lunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113290/hls24_1540506794.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113290/landscape_720/1540506794</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Prepare the delicata squash. Using a long, sharp knife, remove the ends of the squash, then cut in half lengthwise. Scoop out the seeds and pulp. Rinse and reserve the seeds. Lay each half of the squash down on its cut side and cut into ½-inch (1-cm) thick slices. </step>
    <step num="2">Place the squash in the 3 quart prep bowl along with 1 tablespoon of olive oil and 1 teaspoon of salt. Cover the bowl with the lid and shake to fully coat the squash. </step>
    <step num="3">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. Transfer the squash to the baking sheet, spread in a single layer, and roast for 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">While the squash is roasting, remove the fennel fronds and bottom end and thinly slice the bulb. Add to the bowl with 1 tablespoon of olive oil and ½ teaspoon of salt. Cover and shake well to coat. </step>
    <step num="5">After 20 minutes, remove the baking sheet with the squash from the oven and add the fennel, spreading evenly. Return to the oven for another 20 minutes, until the squash is tender and slightly browned and the fennel is tender and caramelized. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the delicata seeds to the 1½ quart prep bowl. Depending on how many seeds there are, add the remaining tablespoon of olive oil, a pinch of salt, and ½-1 teaspoon smoked paprika. Cover the bowl with the lid and shake to coat the seeds well. </step>
    <step num="7">Line a small baking sheet with parchment paper. Spread the seeds in a single layer and add to the oven for the last 10 minutes while the squash and fennel finish roasting, until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="8">Make the vinaigrette: In a small bowl, add the apple cider vinegar, lemon juice, honey, Dijon, and garlic. Whisk to combine, then season with salt and pepper. Slowly stream in the olive oil, whisking to emulsify. Season with more salt, if needed. </step>
    <step num="9">In a large bowl, assemble the salad. Add the kale, farro, and chickpeas, then the roasted delicata and fennel, and finally the goat cheese. Toss to combine. Top with the roasted squash seeds. </step>
    <step num="10">Add the salad to a serving bowl and drizzle with the vinaigrette. </step>
    <step num="11">Leftover salad will keep in the fridge for up to 4 days. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
    <step num="13">Nutrition (without dressing) per serving - Calories: 275, Total fat: 10 grams, Total carbs: 40 grams, Dietary fiber: 10 grams, Sugars: 8 grams, Protein: 11 grams </step>
    <step num="14">Nutrition – Apple Cider Vinaigrette per serving - Serving size: 2 tablespoons - Calories: 122, Total fat: 11 grams, Total carbs: 6 grams, Dietary fiber: 0 grams, Sugars: 5 grams, Protein: 0 grams </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Prepare the delicata squash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Using a long, sharp knife, remove the ends of the squash, then cut in half lengthwise. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Scoop out the seeds and pulp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Rinse and reserve the seeds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Lay each half of the squash down on its cut side and cut into ½-inch (1-cm) thick slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Place the squash in the 3 quart prep bowl along with 1 tablespoon of olive oil and 1 teaspoon of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cover the bowl with the lid and shake to fully coat the squash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Transfer the squash to the baking sheet, spread in a single layer, and roast for 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">While the squash is roasting, remove the fennel fronds and bottom end and thinly slice the bulb. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add to the bowl with 1 tablespoon of olive oil and ½ teaspoon of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cover and shake well to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">After 20 minutes, remove the baking sheet with the squash from the oven and add the fennel, spreading evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Return to the oven for another 20 minutes, until the squash is tender and slightly browned and the fennel is tender and caramelized. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the delicata seeds to the 1½ quart prep bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Depending on how many seeds there are, add the remaining tablespoon of olive oil, a pinch of salt, and ½-1 teaspoon smoked paprika. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cover the bowl with the lid and shake to coat the seeds well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Line a small baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Spread the seeds in a single layer and add to the oven for the last 10 minutes while the squash and fennel finish roasting, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Make the vinaigrette: In a small bowl, add the apple cider vinegar, lemon juice, honey, Dijon, and garlic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Whisk to combine, then season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Slowly stream in the olive oil, whisking to emulsify. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Season with more salt, if needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">In a large bowl, assemble the salad. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Add the kale, farro, and chickpeas, then the roasted delicata and fennel, and finally the goat cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Toss to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Top with the roasted squash seeds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Add the salad to a serving bowl and drizzle with the vinaigrette. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Leftover salad will keep in the fridge for up to 4 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Nutrition (without dressing) per serving - Calories: 275, Total fat: 10 grams, Total carbs: 40 grams, Dietary fiber: 10 grams, Sugars: 8 grams, Protein: 11 grams </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Nutrition – Apple Cider Vinaigrette per serving - Serving size: 2 tablespoons - Calories: 122, Total fat: 11 grams, Total carbs: 6 grams, Dietary fiber: 0 grams, Sugars: 5 grams, Protein: 0 grams </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>