<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Awesome Lemon Meringue Bars Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/awesome-lemon-meringue-bars</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ cups ; all-purpose flour ; (185 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; powdered sugar ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¾ cup ; unsalted butter, 1 1/2 sticks, cubed, room temperature ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; large egg yolk, reserve white for meringue </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 cup ; granulated sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ cup ; lemon juice ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; lemon zest </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ cup ; all-purpose flour ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; egg white </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">⅓ cup ; granulated sugar ; (65 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113171/hls24_1540416901.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113171/landscape_720/1540416901</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 325˚F (170˚C). Grease and line a 9-inch (23-cm) square baking dish with parchment paper and place on a baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="1">Make the crust: combine the flour, powdered sugar, salt, and butter in a medium bowl, and use your hands to mix until a crumbly dough forms. </step>
    <step num="2">Transfer the dough to the prepared pan, and use your hands to press it against the bottom and about 1 inch (2 cm) up the sides. Poke the bottom all over with a fork. </step>
    <step num="3">Bake for 20 minutes, until light golden brown. </step>
    <step num="4">While the crust is baking, make the lemon filling: In a large bowl, whisk together the eggs and egg yolk. Add the granulated sugar, lemon juice, zest, and a pinch of salt, and whisk to combine. Whisk in the flour until just combined. </step>
    <step num="5">When the crust is done baking, remove it from the oven. Pour the lemon filling over the crust and carefully return it to the oven for 25 minutes, until the filling no longer jiggles and the center is mostly set. </step>
    <step num="6">While the filling bakes, make the meringue: In a clean, dry medium bowl, use an electric hand mixer to beat the egg white until stiff peaks form. Add about half of the sugar, whip for 30 seconds, then add the rest of the sugar and whip until combined. </step>
    <step num="7">Transfer the meringue to a pastry bag fitted with a large tip or zip-top bag with a corner snipped off. </step>
    <step num="8">Pipe 9 evenly-spaced dollops of meringue on top of the lemon bars. </step>
    <step num="9">Return to the oven for 10-12 minutes, until the meringues are lightly browned. </step>
    <step num="10">Let cool completely, then refrigerate for 1-2 hours. </step>
    <step num="11">Slice into 9 bars. Serve chilled or at room temperature. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 325˚F (170˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Grease and line a 9-inch (23-cm) square baking dish with parchment paper and place on a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Make the crust: combine the flour, powdered sugar, salt, and butter in a medium bowl, and use your hands to mix until a crumbly dough forms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Transfer the dough to the prepared pan, and use your hands to press it against the bottom and about 1 inch (2 cm) up the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Poke the bottom all over with a fork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Bake for 20 minutes, until light golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">While the crust is baking, make the lemon filling: In a large bowl, whisk together the eggs and egg yolk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the granulated sugar, lemon juice, zest, and a pinch of salt, and whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Whisk in the flour until just combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">When the crust is done baking, remove it from the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Pour the lemon filling over the crust and carefully return it to the oven for 25 minutes, until the filling no longer jiggles and the center is mostly set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">While the filling bakes, make the meringue: In a clean, dry medium bowl, use an electric hand mixer to beat the egg white until stiff peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add about half of the sugar, whip for 30 seconds, then add the rest of the sugar and whip until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Transfer the meringue to a pastry bag fitted with a large tip or zip-top bag with a corner snipped off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Pipe 9 evenly-spaced dollops of meringue on top of the lemon bars. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Return to the oven for 10-12 minutes, until the meringues are lightly browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Let cool completely, then refrigerate for 1-2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Slice into 9 bars. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Serve chilled or at room temperature. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>