<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Vegan Apple Pie Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/vegan-apple-pie</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ½ cups ; all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (310 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; organic sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; vegan butter, cubed and chilled ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">6 tablespoons ; ice water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">7 ; granny smith apples </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; organic sugar, plus 1 teaspoon, divided ; (400 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; lemon, zested </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">5 tablespoons ; cornstarch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ ; lemon, juiced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 tablespoon ; coconut oil, melted, plus 1 teaspoon, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">4 teaspoons ; cinnamon, divided </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Vegan</category>
    <category num="4">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="5">Desserts</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/107899/hls24_1536095827.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/107899/landscape_720/1536095827</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the crust: In a large bowl, combine the flour, sugar, and salt. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the cubed butter, a bit at a time, and use a fork to work it into the flour with a fork until it breaks down to dime-sized pieces. </step>
    <step num="2">Gradually add the ice water and mix just until the dough can be pressed together. </step>
    <step num="3">Divide the dough in half and shape into discs. Wrap in plastic wrap and chill in the fridge for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="4">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="5">Make the filling: Peel and core apples, then thinly slice. Transfer to a large bowl and add 2 cups of sugar, the lemon zest, cornstarch, lemon juice, 1 teaspoon melted coconut oil, salt, and 3 teaspoons cinnamon. Toss until the apples are well-coated. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="6">On a lightly floured surface, roll out both of the discs of dough to about 1 inch (2 cm) thick. Transfer one round to a greased 8-inch (20-cm) pie dish and gently press against the bottom and sides. Trim the excess dough around the edges, then prick the bottom of the pie crust all over with a fork </step>
    <step num="7">Pour the apples into the bottom crust and cover with the top crust. Trim the excess dough around the edges, then crimp the top and bottom crusts together with a fork. Brush the top of the crust with the remaining tablespoon of melted coconut oil and sprinkle with the remaining teaspoon of sugar and cinnamon. Cut 4 vents in the top crust </step>
    <step num="8">Bake for 1 hour, until crust is starting to turn golden brown. </step>
    <step num="9">Let cool for 10 minutes, then slice and serve. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the crust: In a large bowl, combine the flour, sugar, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the cubed butter, a bit at a time, and use a fork to work it into the flour with a fork until it breaks down to dime-sized pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Gradually add the ice water and mix just until the dough can be pressed together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Divide the dough in half and shape into discs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Wrap in plastic wrap and chill in the fridge for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Make the filling: Peel and core apples, then thinly slice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Transfer to a large bowl and add 2 cups of sugar, the lemon zest, cornstarch, lemon juice, 1 teaspoon melted coconut oil, salt, and 3 teaspoons cinnamon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Toss until the apples are well-coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">On a lightly floured surface, roll out both of the discs of dough to about 1 inch (2 cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Transfer one round to a greased 8-inch (20-cm) pie dish and gently press against the bottom and sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Trim the excess dough around the edges, then prick the bottom of the pie crust all over with a fork </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Pour the apples into the bottom crust and cover with the top crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Trim the excess dough around the edges, then crimp the top and bottom crusts together with a fork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Brush the top of the crust with the remaining tablespoon of melted coconut oil and sprinkle with the remaining teaspoon of sugar and cinnamon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Cut 4 vents in the top crust </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Bake for 1 hour, until crust is starting to turn golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Let cool for 10 minutes, then slice and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>