<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Broccoli Cheddar Chicken Rollups Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/broccoli-cheddar-chicken-rollups</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 ½ cups ; broccoli, finely chopped, divided ; (525 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 cups ; shredded cheddar cheese ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; onion powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">8 oz ; cream cheese, 1 package, softened ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 ; chicken breasts </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">14 oz ; cheddar cracker, 1 package ; (390 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; all-purpose flour ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 ; eggs </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/84266/hls24_1520902008.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/84266/landscape_720/1520902008</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (165˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">In a small bowl, microwave 1½ cups (225 g) of broccoli for 1 minute. Add the cheddar cheese, garlic powder, onion powder, and cream cheese. Mix thoroughly, and set aside until ready to use. </step>
    <step num="2">On a cutting board, butterfly the chicken breasts with a knife. Cut through the chicken breast so you have 6 thinner chicken cutlets. Cover in plastic wrap, and tenderize by beating with a rolling pin or a heavy pan. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove the plastic wrap, and season with salt and pepper. Place a scoop of the broccoli cheddar mixture on top of a chicken cutlet, and spread until the chicken is covered. </step>
    <step num="4">Roll the chicken up starting from the tapered end. Use 2 toothpicks to keep the chicken tightly rolled. Repeat with the rest of the chicken. </step>
    <step num="5">In a plastic bag, crush the cheddar crackers until they have a coarse, sand-like texture. Pour the cracker crumbs into a large bowl. Add the rest of the minced broccoli. Stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="6">Put the flour into a medium bowl. </step>
    <step num="7">Whisk the eggs in another medium bowl. </step>
    <step num="8">Using tongs, place one of the pieces of chicken into the flour. Turn the chicken in the flour until it is fully coated, tap off any excess flour. Place the chicken in the egg, turn until the chicken is coated. Place the chicken in the broccoli cracker crumb mixture, turn until the chicken is fully coated. Repeat with the remaining chicken rolls. </step>
    <step num="9">Transfer the pieces of chicken to the prepared baking sheet. Bake for 40-45 minutes. </step>
    <step num="10">Let the chicken cool slightly, then remove the toothpicks. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (165˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a small bowl, microwave 1½ cups (225 g) of broccoli for 1 minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the cheddar cheese, garlic powder, onion powder, and cream cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Mix thoroughly, and set aside until ready to use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">On a cutting board, butterfly the chicken breasts with a knife. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cut through the chicken breast so you have 6 thinner chicken cutlets. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cover in plastic wrap, and tenderize by beating with a rolling pin or a heavy pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Remove the plastic wrap, and season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Place a scoop of the broccoli cheddar mixture on top of a chicken cutlet, and spread until the chicken is covered. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Roll the chicken up starting from the tapered end. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Use 2 toothpicks to keep the chicken tightly rolled. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Repeat with the rest of the chicken. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">In a plastic bag, crush the cheddar crackers until they have a coarse, sand-like texture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Pour the cracker crumbs into a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the rest of the minced broccoli. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Put the flour into a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Whisk the eggs in another medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Using tongs, place one of the pieces of chicken into the flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Turn the chicken in the flour until it is fully coated, tap off any excess flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Place the chicken in the egg, turn until the chicken is coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Place the chicken in the broccoli cracker crumb mixture, turn until the chicken is fully coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Repeat with the remaining chicken rolls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Transfer the pieces of chicken to the prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Bake for 40-45 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Let the chicken cool slightly, then remove the toothpicks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>