<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Spaghetti and Meatballs with Bone Marrow Sauce by Richard Blais Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/spaghetti-and-meatballs-with-bone-marrownara-sauce-by-richard-blais</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; yellow onion, diced ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; crushed red pepper flake </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; tomato paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">28 oz ; whole tomato, with juices, 1 can ; (795 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; red wine ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 cup ; whole milk ricotta cheese ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">8 oz ; ground pork ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">8 oz ; ground beef ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">3 tablespoons ; fresh basil, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 teaspoons ; fresh oregano, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 teaspoons ; fresh sage, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 tablespoon ; fresh rosemary, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 tablespoon ; fresh flat-leaf parsley, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">3 tablespoons ; extra virgin olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">¼ cup ; bone marrow, chopped ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">12 oz ; spaghetti, cooked ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">½ cup ; grated parmesan cheese ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 cup ; plain breadcrumbs, toasted ; (115 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Italian</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/33643/low_1496943252.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/33643/mp4_720x1280/1496943252</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large pot over medium heat, mix the onion, garlic, and red pepper flakes. Cook until the onions start begin to soften, about 3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Remove half of the onion/garlic mixture and place in a small bowl to cool. Set aside or refrigerate to cool completely. </step>
    <step num="2">To the pot with the remaining onions/garlic, add the tomato paste. Cook the tomato paste, about 2-3 minutes, stirring frequently, to caramelize the natural sugars in the paste. </step>
    <step num="3">Add red wine and canned tomatoes to the pot. Cook wine and tomatoes, stirring constantly, and scraping the bottom of the pan to make sure nothing burns, until the mixture comes to a low simmer. </step>
    <step num="4">Break apart the whole tomatoes using a wooden spoon or squeezing with tongs. Continue to cook over medium-high heat for about 5 minutes to give the alcohol in the wine a chance to evaporate. Add salt and pepper to taste. </step>
    <step num="5">Reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer, stirring occasionally, for about 20 minutes longer. </step>
    <step num="6">In a medium sized mixing bowl, stir the ricotta with the reserved (and cooled) onion-garlic mixture. Add the ground pork, ground beef, basil, oregano, sage, rosemary, parsley, salt, and pepper. Gently mix together first with a spoon then going in with your hands. </step>
    <step num="7">Shape the meat into ping-pong-sized balls and place on parchment lined baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="8">Place the meatballs in the fridge if you will not be cooking immediately or if they have warmed from handling (they will keep their shape better if kept cold before cooking!). </step>
    <step num="9">Heat oil in a large saute pan over medium-high heat. Working in batches, sear the meatballs lightly on all sides until they begin to brown. They will not be fully cooked at this point. </step>
    <step num="10">Transfer the seared meatballs (and any accumulated juices) to the marinara sauce. </step>
    <step num="11">Remove the bone marrow from the bone. Add to the meatballs and marinara sauce. </step>
    <step num="12">Cover and let simmer for an additional 20 minutes to finish cooking the meatballs and allow the bone marrow to render its fat. </step>
    <step num="13">Add cooked spaghetti to the finished sauce and toss to coat. </step>
    <step num="14">Serve garnished with toasted breadcrumbs and grated Parmesan cheese. </step>
    <step num="15">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large pot over medium heat, mix the onion, garlic, and red pepper flakes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cook until the onions start begin to soften, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Remove half of the onion/garlic mixture and place in a small bowl to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set aside or refrigerate to cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">To the pot with the remaining onions/garlic, add the tomato paste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cook the tomato paste, about 2-3 minutes, stirring frequently, to caramelize the natural sugars in the paste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add red wine and canned tomatoes to the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cook wine and tomatoes, stirring constantly, and scraping the bottom of the pan to make sure nothing burns, until the mixture comes to a low simmer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Break apart the whole tomatoes using a wooden spoon or squeezing with tongs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Continue to cook over medium-high heat for about 5 minutes to give the alcohol in the wine a chance to evaporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add salt and pepper to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer, stirring occasionally, for about 20 minutes longer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">In a medium sized mixing bowl, stir the ricotta with the reserved (and cooled) onion-garlic mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the ground pork, ground beef, basil, oregano, sage, rosemary, parsley, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Gently mix together first with a spoon then going in with your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Shape the meat into ping-pong-sized balls and place on parchment lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Place the meatballs in the fridge if you will not be cooking immediately or if they have warmed from handling (they will keep their shape better if kept cold before cooking!). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Heat oil in a large saute pan over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Working in batches, sear the meatballs lightly on all sides until they begin to brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">They will not be fully cooked at this point. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Transfer the seared meatballs (and any accumulated juices) to the marinara sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Remove the bone marrow from the bone. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add to the meatballs and marinara sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Cover and let simmer for an additional 20 minutes to finish cooking the meatballs and allow the bone marrow to render its fat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Add cooked spaghetti to the finished sauce and toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Serve garnished with toasted breadcrumbs and grated Parmesan cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>