<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Vegetarian Pad See Ew Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/vegetarian-pad-see-ew</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 tablespoons ; dark soy sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 tablespoons ; vegetarian mushroom oyster sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; light brown sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; thai bird chile powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">16 oz ; extra firm tofu, cut into 1 inch (2 cm) cubes ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 lb ; rice noodle, fresh wide ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 tablespoons ; canola oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">⅓ cup ; shallot ; (35 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 tablespoon ; water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">12 oz ; broccoli, Chinese broccoli, cut diagonally into 2 in (5 cm) pieces ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 ; large eggs, beaten </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Thai</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Healthy</category>
    <category num="3">Vegan</category>
    <category num="4">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="5">Dinner</category>
    <category num="6">Date Night</category>
    <category num="7">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/126647/hls24_1551999926.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/126647/landscape_720/1551999926</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a small bowl, whisk together the soy sauce, vegetarian oyster sauce, brown sugar, and chile powder. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the tofu to a medium bowl and drizzle with 1 tablespoon of the sauce. Gently toss to coat. Reserve the rest of the sauce. </step>
    <step num="2">Using your hands, break up the sheets of noodles into individual noodles. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">Heat 2 tablespoons of oil in a large nonstick wok or skillet over high heat, swirling the pan to coat. Working in batches, add the tofu to the pan in a single layer and cook for 1-2 minutes on each side, until browned. Flip and brown on the other side, 1-2 minutes more. Remove from the pan and set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the remaining tablespoon of canola oil to the pan. Add the shallot to the pan and cook until tender and lightly browned, about 2 minutes. Add the garlic and water and cook for 30 seconds, until fragrant. Add the Chinese broccoli and cook, tossing occasionally, until crispy and tender, 2-3 minutes. Add the reserved rice noodles, tofu, and sauce and toss to combine. Cook until the noodles are warmed through and coated in the sauce, 1-2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Push the noodles to one side of the pan and pour the eggs into the empty space. Cook for 30 seconds, stirring constantly, until the eggs are scrambled. Toss to incorporate the eggs into the rest of the dish. </step>
    <step num="6">Divide between 4 serving plates. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a small bowl, whisk together the soy sauce, vegetarian oyster sauce, brown sugar, and chile powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the tofu to a medium bowl and drizzle with 1 tablespoon of the sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Gently toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Reserve the rest of the sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Using your hands, break up the sheets of noodles into individual noodles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Heat 2 tablespoons of oil in a large nonstick wok or skillet over high heat, swirling the pan to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Working in batches, add the tofu to the pan in a single layer and cook for 1-2 minutes on each side, until browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Flip and brown on the other side, 1-2 minutes more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove from the pan and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the remaining tablespoon of canola oil to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the shallot to the pan and cook until tender and lightly browned, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the garlic and water and cook for 30 seconds, until fragrant. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the Chinese broccoli and cook, tossing occasionally, until crispy and tender, 2-3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add the reserved rice noodles, tofu, and sauce and toss to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cook until the noodles are warmed through and coated in the sauce, 1-2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Push the noodles to one side of the pan and pour the eggs into the empty space. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cook for 30 seconds, stirring constantly, until the eggs are scrambled. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Toss to incorporate the eggs into the rest of the dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Divide between 4 serving plates. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>