<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Trinidad Black Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/trinidad-black-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; seedless raisin ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; dried currant ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; prune, pitted ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; dried cherry ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ½ cups ; cherry brandy ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ cups ; dark rum ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; cinnamon stick </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; star anise </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ cup ; candied citrus peel, mixed ; (20 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ cup ; sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 tablespoons ; water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 teaspoon ; ground cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">¼ teaspoon ; nutmeg, freshly grated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">¼ teaspoon ; ground allspice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">2 teaspoons ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 cup ; unsalted butter, softened ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">1 cup ; dark brown sugar, packed ; (220 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">6 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">½ teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">½ teaspoon ; angostura bitters </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">½ cup ; sliced almond ; (35 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">½ cup ; cherry brandy ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">½ cup ; dark rum ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">¼ cup ; dry sherry ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/121122/hls24_1545433074.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/121122/landscape_720/1545433074</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the soaked spiced dried fruit: In a medium saucepan, combine the raisins, currants, prunes, cherries, cherry brandy, rum, cinnamon stick, and star anise. Cook over medium heat until just boiling, then remove from the heat and let steep for 1-2 hours. </step>
    <step num="1">About 20 minutes before making the cake batter, make the burnt sugar syrup: Add the sugar to a small nonstick saucepan over medium-high heat. Let the sugar deeply caramelize, turning almost black and smoking a bit. Reduce the heat to low and carefully pour in the water (it will steam) and stir vigorously to incorporate. Let the syrup remain in saucepan while it cools, about 15 mins. If it hardens too much before using, add a little more water and stir over low heat. </step>
    <step num="2">Remove the cinnamon stick and star anise from the soaked fruit mixture. Transfer to a food processor, add the candied citrus peel, and pulse into a chunky paste. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). Grease 2 8-inch or 1 10-inch (25 cm) round cake pans. </step>
    <step num="4">Make the cake batter: In a medium bowl, combine the flour, cinnamon, nutmeg, allspice, and baking powder. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">In a large bowl, cream the butter and brown sugar with an electric hand mixer. Once light and fluffy, beat in the eggs, 1 at a time. </step>
    <step num="6">With the mixer running, add ⅓ of the flour mixture then ½ of the fruit paste, then another ⅓ of the flour. Switch to a rubber spatula and fold in the remaining fruit paste and flour. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the burnt sugar syrup, vanilla, bitters, and sliced almonds. Fold quickly to incorporate so the syrup doesn’t harden. </step>
    <step num="8">Transfer the batter to the prepared baking pan(s). </step>
    <step num="9">Bake for 1 hour, then reduce the oven temperature to 250˚F (120˚C), and bake for 45 minutes more, until the cake is dark in color and a toothpick inserted in the center comes out clean. </step>
    <step num="10">While the cake is baking, make the soaking liquid: In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, combine the rum, cherry brandy, and sherry. </step>
    <step num="11">Let the cakes to cool for 5 minutes, then carefully run a knife around the edges of the pans. Slowly pour the soaking liquid over each of the cakes, a little at a time, allowing it to soak in. (Reserve about ¼ cup for serving) Let the cakes cool completely in the pans. </step>
    <step num="12">You can serve the cake immediately, but the flavor improves with time. Wrap the cooled cakes in plastic wrap and refrigerate for up to 2 months. Pour ½ cup of rum over the cake every 7 days to keep moist while storing. </step>
    <step num="13">Brush with more of the soaking liquid before slicing and serving. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the soaked spiced dried fruit: In a medium saucepan, combine the raisins, currants, prunes, cherries, cherry brandy, rum, cinnamon stick, and star anise. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cook over medium heat until just boiling, then remove from the heat and let steep for 1-2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">About 20 minutes before making the cake batter, make the burnt sugar syrup: Add the sugar to a small nonstick saucepan over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Let the sugar deeply caramelize, turning almost black and smoking a bit. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Reduce the heat to low and carefully pour in the water (it will steam) and stir vigorously to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Let the syrup remain in saucepan while it cools, about 15 mins. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">If it hardens too much before using, add a little more water and stir over low heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove the cinnamon stick and star anise from the soaked fruit mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Transfer to a food processor, add the candied citrus peel, and pulse into a chunky paste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Grease 2 8-inch or 1 10-inch (25 cm) round cake pans. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Make the cake batter: In a medium bowl, combine the flour, cinnamon, nutmeg, allspice, and baking powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">In a large bowl, cream the butter and brown sugar with an electric hand mixer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Once light and fluffy, beat in the eggs, 1 at a time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">With the mixer running, add ⅓ of the flour mixture then ½ of the fruit paste, then another ⅓ of the flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Switch to a rubber spatula and fold in the remaining fruit paste and flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the burnt sugar syrup, vanilla, bitters, and sliced almonds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Fold quickly to incorporate so the syrup doesn’t harden. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Transfer the batter to the prepared baking pan(s). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Bake for 1 hour, then reduce the oven temperature to 250˚F (120˚C), and bake for 45 minutes more, until the cake is dark in color and a toothpick inserted in the center comes out clean. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">While the cake is baking, make the soaking liquid: In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, combine the rum, cherry brandy, and sherry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Let the cakes to cool for 5 minutes, then carefully run a knife around the edges of the pans. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Slowly pour the soaking liquid over each of the cakes, a little at a time, allowing it to soak in. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">(Reserve about ¼ cup for serving) Let the cakes cool completely in the pans. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">You can serve the cake immediately, but the flavor improves with time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Wrap the cooled cakes in plastic wrap and refrigerate for up to 2 months. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Pour ½ cup of rum over the cake every 7 days to keep moist while storing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Brush with more of the soaking liquid before slicing and serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>