<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chocolate Cream Cheese Stuffed Monkey Bread Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chocolate-cream-cheese-stuffed-monkey-bread</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">32 oz ; biscuit dough, 2 16 oz containers, 16 big biscuits total ; (910 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">8 oz ; cream cheese ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">chocolate chips, we used dark chocolate </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; white sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 teaspoons ; cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ cup ; butter ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 cup ; brown sugar ; (220 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ cup ; walnuts, optional ; (50 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31860/low_1495124842.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31860/mp4_720x1280/1495124842</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (175˚C) </step>
    <step num="1">Cut biscuits in half and cube the cream cheese (32 pieces). </step>
    <step num="2">Flatten each biscuit and place one cube of cream cheese and a few chocolate chips in the center of each. Fold the biscuit dough around the cream cheese and chocolate and form into a ball. </step>
    <step num="3">In a large plastic bag combine white sugar and cinnamon. Add 6-8 dough balls to the bag, seal the bag, and shake until well coated. Repeat for the remainder of the stuffed dough pieces. </step>
    <step num="4">In a microwave safe bowl add brown sugar and butter. Microwave on high for 70 seconds - stopping halfway to stir. Remove from microwave and stir until it reaches a caramel consistency. </step>
    <step num="5">In a greased bundt pan, sprinkle half of the walnuts, half the dough pieces, and drizzle half the caramel glaze. Repeat with remaining walnuts, dough, and glaze. </step>
    <step num="6">Bake for 30-35 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Remove from oven and turn upside down onto a plate to cool for 10 minutes before lifting off the pan (this way the warm glaze runs back through and fully coats all the bread) </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (175˚C) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cut biscuits in half and cube the cream cheese (32 pieces). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Flatten each biscuit and place one cube of cream cheese and a few chocolate chips in the center of each. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Fold the biscuit dough around the cream cheese and chocolate and form into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a large plastic bag combine white sugar and cinnamon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add 6-8 dough balls to the bag, seal the bag, and shake until well coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Repeat for the remainder of the stuffed dough pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a microwave safe bowl add brown sugar and butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Microwave on high for 70 seconds - stopping halfway to stir. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove from microwave and stir until it reaches a caramel consistency. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a greased bundt pan, sprinkle half of the walnuts, half the dough pieces, and drizzle half the caramel glaze. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Repeat with remaining walnuts, dough, and glaze. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Bake for 30-35 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove from oven and turn upside down onto a plate to cool for 10 minutes before lifting off the pan (this way the warm glaze runs back through and fully coats all the bread) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>