<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Hazelnut-Crusted Pear &amp; Brie Tart Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/hazelnut-crusted-pear-brie-tart</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; skin-on hazelnuts ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; buckwheat flour ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 large sprig ; fresh rosemary </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">4 tablespoons ; maple syrup, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 pinch ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; unsalted butter, 1/2 stick, cubed and chilled ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 tablespoons ; orange marmalade </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">4 oz ; brie cheese, thinly sliced ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">4 ; pears, cored and very thinly sliced </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117575/hls24_1543603070.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117575/landscape_720/1543603070</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Spread the hazelnuts on a baking sheet and toast for about 8 minutes, until fragrant and browned. Let cool, then remove the skins by gently rubbing with a kitchen towel. </step>
    <step num="2">Increase the oven temperature to 400˚F (200˚C). </step>
    <step num="3">In a food processor, combine the buckwheat flour, hazelnuts, rosemary leaves, 3 tablespoons of maple syrup, and the salt. Pulse until the hazelnuts break down and the mixture resembles a coarse meal. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the butter and pulse to combine, until no large chunks of butter remain. </step>
    <step num="5">Press the crust into a 10-inch (25-cm) tart pan. Poke holes all over the bottom of the crust with a fork. </step>
    <step num="6">Bake the crust for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Reduce the oven temperature to 375˚F (190˚C). </step>
    <step num="8">Spread the orange marmalade over the bottom of the warm crust. Arrange the brie slices evenly over the marmalade. </step>
    <step num="9">Shingle the pear slices neatly around the outside edge of the tart, packing them close together. Add a second layer around the outside edge, on top of the first layer. There should be a circle left in the center of the tart. Begin tucking pear slices horizontally, skin-side up, around the edge of the inner circle. Work toward the center, using smaller slices as the circle gets smaller (the thinner the better here, they will bend and not break!). Once you get to the very middle, tuck a few small slices into the center to fill in. </step>
    <step num="10">Using a pastry brush, lightly brush the remaining tablespoon of maple syrup over the pear slices. </step>
    <step num="11">Bake for 40 minutes, until the pears have softened. </step>
    <step num="12">Let cool for 10 minutes before slicing. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
    <step num="14">Nutrition - Calories: 226, Total fat: 13 grams, Sodium: 106 mg, Total carbohydrates: 25 grams, Dietary fiber: 4 grams, Sugars: 13 grams, Protein: 5 grams </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Spread the hazelnuts on a baking sheet and toast for about 8 minutes, until fragrant and browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Let cool, then remove the skins by gently rubbing with a kitchen towel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Increase the oven temperature to 400˚F (200˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a food processor, combine the buckwheat flour, hazelnuts, rosemary leaves, 3 tablespoons of maple syrup, and the salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pulse until the hazelnuts break down and the mixture resembles a coarse meal. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the butter and pulse to combine, until no large chunks of butter remain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Press the crust into a 10-inch (25-cm) tart pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Poke holes all over the bottom of the crust with a fork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Bake the crust for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Reduce the oven temperature to 375˚F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Spread the orange marmalade over the bottom of the warm crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Arrange the brie slices evenly over the marmalade. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Shingle the pear slices neatly around the outside edge of the tart, packing them close together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add a second layer around the outside edge, on top of the first layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">There should be a circle left in the center of the tart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Begin tucking pear slices horizontally, skin-side up, around the edge of the inner circle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Work toward the center, using smaller slices as the circle gets smaller (the thinner the better here, they will bend and not break!). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Once you get to the very middle, tuck a few small slices into the center to fill in. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Using a pastry brush, lightly brush the remaining tablespoon of maple syrup over the pear slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Bake for 40 minutes, until the pears have softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Let cool for 10 minutes before slicing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Nutrition - Calories: 226, Total fat: 13 grams, Sodium: 106 mg, Total carbohydrates: 25 grams, Dietary fiber: 4 grams, Sugars: 13 grams, Protein: 5 grams </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>