<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Hong Kong Style Egg Tarts Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/hong-kong-style-egg-tarts</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 ; eggs, beaten, reserve 2 tablespoons for your pastry dough </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¾ cup ; water, hot ; (180 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">6 tablespoons ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">⅛ teaspoon ; salt, pinch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; evaporated milk ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">vanilla extract, a dash, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; cake flour, plus extra for dusting ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 stick ; unsalted butter, room temperature ; 115 g </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ cup ; powdered sugar ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 tablespoons ; egg, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">⅛ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">vanilla extract, a dash, optional </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Chinese</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31853/low_1495124858.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31853/mp4_720x1280/1495124858</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 400˚F / 200˚C. </step>
    <step num="1">For the pastry, in a large bowl, sift flour, sugar, and salt. Then add softened butter. Bring the mixture together with your hands, careful not to knead the pastry dough too much or you will make the pastry tough. </step>
    <step num="2">Whisk the egg yolks and add the 2 tablespoons of beaten yolk to the flour mixture. Bring together until smooth. If the dough is too sticky, coating your hands with flour will help. Cover with plastic wrap and then refrigerate for 30 minutes, or until the dough is firm. </step>
    <step num="3">To make the custard filling, melt sugar and salt with hot water. Mix until dissolved then let cool. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the rest of the beaten egg yolk. Stir in sugar water and also evaporated milk (if adding vanilla, add now). Stir and combine everything well. </step>
    <step num="5">Strain the filling to ensure no lumps. Chill in the refrigerator. </step>
    <step num="6">Take the dough out and divide into 16 equal portions. Spray the tart pan with a light coating of oil. Take one portion of your dough and roll it into a ball and place in your tart shell. Press the shell into the pan with your fingers. Try to make the wrapper uniform in thickness and avoid a thick bottom. Repeat to finish all. </step>
    <step num="7">Pour the custard filling into the shells until it is about 80% full. Bake for 15 to 20 minutes until the surface becomes golden brown and a toothpick can stand in the egg tart. </step>
    <step num="8">Cool down for several minutes and then take the egg tarts out of the pan. Serve while still warm. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 400˚F / 200˚C. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">For the pastry, in a large bowl, sift flour, sugar, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Then add softened butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Bring the mixture together with your hands, careful not to knead the pastry dough too much or you will make the pastry tough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Whisk the egg yolks and add the 2 tablespoons of beaten yolk to the flour mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Bring together until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">If the dough is too sticky, coating your hands with flour will help. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cover with plastic wrap and then refrigerate for 30 minutes, or until the dough is firm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">To make the custard filling, melt sugar and salt with hot water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Mix until dissolved then let cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the rest of the beaten egg yolk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Stir in sugar water and also evaporated milk (if adding vanilla, add now). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Stir and combine everything well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Strain the filling to ensure no lumps. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Chill in the refrigerator. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Take the dough out and divide into 16 equal portions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Spray the tart pan with a light coating of oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Take one portion of your dough and roll it into a ball and place in your tart shell. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Press the shell into the pan with your fingers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Try to make the wrapper uniform in thickness and avoid a thick bottom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Repeat to finish all. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Pour the custard filling into the shells until it is about 80% full. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Bake for 15 to 20 minutes until the surface becomes golden brown and a toothpick can stand in the egg tart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Cool down for several minutes and then take the egg tarts out of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Serve while still warm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>