<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Dumplings As Made By Yidi Li Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/dumplings-as-made-by-yidi-li</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; bread flour, plus more for dusting ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; water, room temperature ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ lb ; ground pork ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; green onion, sliced ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; large egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ teaspoon ; ground five spice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ teaspoon ; ground suchuan pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 tablespoon ; fresh ginger, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 tablespoon ; soy sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ tablespoon ; sesame oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">7 oz ; raw shrimp, chopped ; (195 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">¾ cup ; wood ear mushrooms, minced ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">3 cups ; napa cabbage, minced ; (300 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Chinese</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124320/hls24_1549413162.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124320/landscape_720/1549413162</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the dough: Combine the flour and salt in a medium bowl. Gradually pour in the water, stirring with chopsticks to incorporate. Once the dough comes together in a ball, knead in the bowl for 5-8 minutes, until smooth. Cover with a damp towel and let rest in the bowl for 30 minutes </step>
    <step num="1">Make the filling: In a medium bowl, combine the pork, green onion, egg, salt, five spice, Sichuan pepper, ginger, soy sauce, and sesame oil. Using chopsticks, mix until well combined. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the shrimp, wood ear mushrooms, and Napa cabbage. Mix well. </step>
    <step num="3">On a lightly floured surface, turn out the dough and knead a few times. Stretch the dough into a 1-inch (2.5 cm) thick ring, then cut to make a rope. </step>
    <step num="4">Divide the dough into 2-ounce (55 G) pieces, turning the rope 90 degrees after each cut to make triangle shapes. Lightly flour the dough portions. </step>
    <step num="5">Working 1 at a time, pat each dough portion into a flat circle, then, using a small rolling pin, roll out into a thin circle. </step>
    <step num="6">Add 1 tablespoon of the filling to the center of a dumpling wrapper. Fold the wrapper in half. Using your fingertips, make pleats to seal the dumpling. Press the edges firmly to fully seal the dumpling. Repeat with the remaining wrappers and filling. </step>
    <step num="7">Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil. Add the dumplings and cook for 10 minutes, or until the filling is cooked through </step>
    <step num="8">Serve immediately with dipping sauce. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the dough: Combine the flour and salt in a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Gradually pour in the water, stirring with chopsticks to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Once the dough comes together in a ball, knead in the bowl for 5-8 minutes, until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cover with a damp towel and let rest in the bowl for 30 minutes </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Make the filling: In a medium bowl, combine the pork, green onion, egg, salt, five spice, Sichuan pepper, ginger, soy sauce, and sesame oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Using chopsticks, mix until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the shrimp, wood ear mushrooms, and Napa cabbage. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Mix well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">On a lightly floured surface, turn out the dough and knead a few times. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Stretch the dough into a 1-inch (2.5 cm) thick ring, then cut to make a rope. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Divide the dough into 2-ounce (55 G) pieces, turning the rope 90 degrees after each cut to make triangle shapes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Lightly flour the dough portions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Working 1 at a time, pat each dough portion into a flat circle, then, using a small rolling pin, roll out into a thin circle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add 1 tablespoon of the filling to the center of a dumpling wrapper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Fold the wrapper in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Using your fingertips, make pleats to seal the dumpling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Press the edges firmly to fully seal the dumpling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Repeat with the remaining wrappers and filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add the dumplings and cook for 10 minutes, or until the filling is cooked through </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Serve immediately with dipping sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>