<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Mother’s Day Edible Bouquet Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/mothers-day-edible-bouquet</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; white chocolate chip ; (175 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; coconut oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">15 ; strawberries </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 cups ; store-bought vanilla frosting, divided ; (230 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">purple gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">orange gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">red gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">6 ; chocolate cupcakes, in green cupcake liners </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">10 ; mini chocolate cupcakes, in pastel pink, yellow, and purple cupcake liners </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; gumdrop ; (180 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">3 ; piping bags </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">large closed star piping tip </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">small closed star piping tip </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ; medium flower pot, or decorative watering can </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">green flower foam, or styrofoam </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">4 ; parchment papers, roughly 10-inch x 10-inch (25 cm x 25 cm) squares </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">12 ; bamboo skewers, 10 inch (25 cm) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">bamboo skewer, 6 inch (15 cm) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="2">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/132365/hls24_1557513701.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/132365/landscape_720/1557513701</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">In a medium bowl, combine the white chocolate chips and coconut oil. Microwave on medium power in 30-second intervals, stirring between, until melted and smooth. </step>
    <step num="2">Dip the strawberries in melted white chocolate, then place on the prepared baking sheet. Let set at room temperature for at least 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="3">Divide the frosting evenly between 3 small bowls. Use gel food coloring to color each bowl of frosting pastel purple, orange, and pink. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the purple frosting to a piping bag fitted with a large closed star piping tip. Starting in center, pipe the frosting on a standard cupcake, spiraling from the center out toward the edge. Frost 2 more cupcakes with purple frosting. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the orange frosting a piping bag fitted with a small closed star piping tip. Starting in the center of a mini cupcake, pipe a small star. Repeat, working your way outward, until the top is filled. Repeat with remaining mini cupcakes. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the pink frosting to a piping bag fitted with a large closed star piping tip. Starting in the center and working outward, pipe the frosting onto the remaining 3 standard cupcakes. </step>
    <step num="7">Chill the cupcakes for 20 minutes, or until ready to assemble. </step>
    <step num="8">Prepare the flower pot by nestling the flower foam inside in multiple pieces. Lightly crumple sheets of parchment in your hands, then uncrumple and stuff into the areas around the foam so the ends stick up and out of the flower pot. </step>
    <step num="9">To assemble the bouquet, slide a gumdrop about 1 inch (2.5 cm) down each skewer; this will keep the cupcakes and strawberries from sliding down. Slide a large cupcake onto a skewer. Press the bottom end of the skewer through the foam so the cupcake is upright. Use varying lengths of skewers, trimming as needed and add more skewered cupcakes and strawberries until the bouquet is full. (You may have leftover strawberries.) Add more paper as needed. Note: Keep the larger cupcakes mostly upright in the container. Save the smaller, less heavy cupcakes and strawberries for decorating the sides. </step>
    <step num="10">Store in the refrigerator until ready to eat. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a medium bowl, combine the white chocolate chips and coconut oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Microwave on medium power in 30-second intervals, stirring between, until melted and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Dip the strawberries in melted white chocolate, then place on the prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Let set at room temperature for at least 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Divide the frosting evenly between 3 small bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Use gel food coloring to color each bowl of frosting pastel purple, orange, and pink. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the purple frosting to a piping bag fitted with a large closed star piping tip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Starting in center, pipe the frosting on a standard cupcake, spiraling from the center out toward the edge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Frost 2 more cupcakes with purple frosting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the orange frosting a piping bag fitted with a small closed star piping tip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Starting in the center of a mini cupcake, pipe a small star. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Repeat, working your way outward, until the top is filled. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Repeat with remaining mini cupcakes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add the pink frosting to a piping bag fitted with a large closed star piping tip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Starting in the center and working outward, pipe the frosting onto the remaining 3 standard cupcakes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Chill the cupcakes for 20 minutes, or until ready to assemble. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Prepare the flower pot by nestling the flower foam inside in multiple pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Lightly crumple sheets of parchment in your hands, then uncrumple and stuff into the areas around the foam so the ends stick up and out of the flower pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">To assemble the bouquet, slide a gumdrop about 1 inch (2.5 cm) down each skewer; this will keep the cupcakes and strawberries from sliding down. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Slide a large cupcake onto a skewer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Press the bottom end of the skewer through the foam so the cupcake is upright. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Use varying lengths of skewers, trimming as needed and add more skewered cupcakes and strawberries until the bouquet is full. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">(You may have leftover strawberries.) Add more paper as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Note: Keep the larger cupcakes mostly upright in the container. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Save the smaller, less heavy cupcakes and strawberries for decorating the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Store in the refrigerator until ready to eat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>