<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>How to Make the Best Sugar Cookies Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/sugar-cookies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">24 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, softened </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ cups ; granulated sugar ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 tablespoons ; cream cheese, softened </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; large egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 ; large egg yolks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; McCormick vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; McCormick almond extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">3 ½ cups ; all purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (440 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 teaspoons ; cream of tartar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">4 cups ; powdered sugar ; (480 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">gel food coloring, of your choice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">water, as needed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">¼ cup ; pasteurized egg white </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117767/hls24_1543621734.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117767/landscape_720/1543621734</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the cookie dough: In a large bowl, cream together the butter, sugar, and cream cheese with an electric hand mixer on high speed for about 5 minutes, until fluffy and the sugar is mostly dissolved. Scrape down the bowl as needed to evenly beat the mixture. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the egg, egg yolks, vanilla, and almond extract and mix well, scraping down the sides of the bowl. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the salt, then sift the flour, baking powder, and cream of tartar into the bowl and fold to incorporate some of the flour. Then beat on low speed, just until incorporated and the dough comes together. </step>
    <step num="3">Shape the dough into a flat disc and wrap tightly in plastic wrap. Chill in the refrigerator for at least 2 hours, or up to 3-4 days. </step>
    <step num="4">When ready to bake the cookies, preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="5">Remove the dough from the fridge and let sit at room temperature for a few minutes to soften slightly. </step>
    <step num="6">On a lightly floured surface, roll out the cookie dough with a rolling pin to ¼-inch (6mm) thick. </step>
    <step num="7">Dip cookie cutters of your choice in some extra flour and cut out shapes from the dough. Gather any excess dough into a ball and chill in the fridge to firm, then re-roll and cut out more cookies. Place the cookies on the prepared baking sheet and chill for at least 20 minutes to ensure they hold their shapes. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake the cookies for 10-12 minutes, or until the edges just barely start to turn golden brown. Cool completely on a wire rack before decorating with royal icing or frosting. </step>
    <step num="9">To make the royal icing, sift the powdered sugar into a large bowl and add the salt. On one side of the bowl, add the vanilla and egg whites. </step>
    <step num="10">Where you added the liquids, begin whisking the powdered sugar into the liquids, gathering a bit more as you whisk to prevent lumps from forming, until all of the powdered sugar is incorporated. Add food coloring, if desired, and whisk to incorporate. You can divide the icing into smaller bowls to make more than one color. At this point, the icing should be a good consistency for piping borders. If you’d like the frosting to be looser to flood or dip your cookies, add a few tablespoons of water, 1 tablespoon at a time, until it reaches your desired consistency. </step>
    <step num="11">Decorate the cookies as desired. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the cookie dough: In a large bowl, cream together the butter, sugar, and cream cheese with an electric hand mixer on high speed for about 5 minutes, until fluffy and the sugar is mostly dissolved. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Scrape down the bowl as needed to evenly beat the mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the egg, egg yolks, vanilla, and almond extract and mix well, scraping down the sides of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the salt, then sift the flour, baking powder, and cream of tartar into the bowl and fold to incorporate some of the flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Then beat on low speed, just until incorporated and the dough comes together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Shape the dough into a flat disc and wrap tightly in plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Chill in the refrigerator for at least 2 hours, or up to 3-4 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">When ready to bake the cookies, preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove the dough from the fridge and let sit at room temperature for a few minutes to soften slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">On a lightly floured surface, roll out the cookie dough with a rolling pin to ¼-inch (6mm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Dip cookie cutters of your choice in some extra flour and cut out shapes from the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Gather any excess dough into a ball and chill in the fridge to firm, then re-roll and cut out more cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Place the cookies on the prepared baking sheet and chill for at least 20 minutes to ensure they hold their shapes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Bake the cookies for 10-12 minutes, or until the edges just barely start to turn golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cool completely on a wire rack before decorating with royal icing or frosting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">To make the royal icing, sift the powdered sugar into a large bowl and add the salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">On one side of the bowl, add the vanilla and egg whites. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Where you added the liquids, begin whisking the powdered sugar into the liquids, gathering a bit more as you whisk to prevent lumps from forming, until all of the powdered sugar is incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add food coloring, if desired, and whisk to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">You can divide the icing into smaller bowls to make more than one color. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">At this point, the icing should be a good consistency for piping borders. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">If you’d like the frosting to be looser to flood or dip your cookies, add a few tablespoons of water, 1 tablespoon at a time, until it reaches your desired consistency. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Decorate the cookies as desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>