<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Low-Carb Steak Salad With Dijon Vinaigrette Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/low-carb-steak-salad-with-dijon-vinaigrette</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ ; medium red onion, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">10.5 oz ; cherry tomato, 1 package ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 tablespoons ; olive oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 teaspoons ; shallot, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; dijon mustard </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ teaspoon ; worcestershire sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; honey </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 tablespoons ; extra virgin olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; red wine vinegar ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1.25 lb ; boneless new york strip steak, about 1¼ inches (3 cm) thick ; (570 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 head ; red leaf lettuce, washed, dried, and cut into ½-inch (1.25 cm) pieces </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ cup ; walnuts, toasted, chopped ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">¼ cup ; gorgonzola cheese, crumbled ; (30 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dinner</category>
    <category num="1">Date Night</category>
    <category num="2">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/123304/hls24_1548199368.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/123304/landscape_720/1548199368</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 425˚F (220˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">Spread the sliced onion on half of the baking sheet and arrange tomatoes on the other half. Drizzle each side with 1 tablespoon olive oil and season with salt and pepper. Toss to coat. </step>
    <step num="2">Roast in the oven for 10-15 minutes, or until the onion is caramelized and the tomatoes are browned in spots and just beginning to burst. Remove from oven and let cool. </step>
    <step num="3">In a small bowl, whisk together the shallot, Dijon mustard, Worcestershire sauce, honey, extra-virgin olive oil, red wine vinegar, salt, and pepper. Refrigerate until ready to use. </step>
    <step num="4">Liberally season the steak all over with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="5">Heat a cast-iron skillet over medium-high heat. Add the remaining tablespoon of olive oil to the hot skillet. When the oil is smoking, add the steak to the pan. Sear for 5 minutes, or until a deep golden brown crust forms. Flip the steak and cook another 5 minutes on the other side. Sear the sides of the steak until golden brown, another 3-4 minutes total. </step>
    <step num="6">Transfer the pan with the steak to the preheated oven for about 5 minutes, or until an instant-read thermometer inserted into the center of the steak reads 125-130˚F (51-54˚C) for medium-rare. Remove the steak from the oven and let rest for 10 minutes before slicing. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the lettuce to a large bowl. Add the roasted tomatoes, roasted onion, walnuts, Gorgonzola, and sliced steak. Toss well. Divide the salad between serving bowl and drizzle over the dressing. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 425˚F (220˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Spread the sliced onion on half of the baking sheet and arrange tomatoes on the other half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Drizzle each side with 1 tablespoon olive oil and season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Roast in the oven for 10-15 minutes, or until the onion is caramelized and the tomatoes are browned in spots and just beginning to burst. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove from oven and let cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a small bowl, whisk together the shallot, Dijon mustard, Worcestershire sauce, honey, extra-virgin olive oil, red wine vinegar, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Refrigerate until ready to use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Liberally season the steak all over with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Heat a cast-iron skillet over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the remaining tablespoon of olive oil to the hot skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">When the oil is smoking, add the steak to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Sear for 5 minutes, or until a deep golden brown crust forms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Flip the steak and cook another 5 minutes on the other side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Sear the sides of the steak until golden brown, another 3-4 minutes total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Transfer the pan with the steak to the preheated oven for about 5 minutes, or until an instant-read thermometer inserted into the center of the steak reads 125-130˚F (51-54˚C) for medium-rare. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Remove the steak from the oven and let rest for 10 minutes before slicing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the lettuce to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add the roasted tomatoes, roasted onion, walnuts, Gorgonzola, and sliced steak. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Toss well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Divide the salad between serving bowl and drizzle over the dressing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>