<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Cheddar, Sausage, And Egg Breakfast Casserole</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/cheddar-sausage-and-egg-breakfast-bake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; breakfast sausage, casings removed, crumbled ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">8 ; scallions, chopped, white\light green parts and dark green parts divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; red bell pepper, seeded and diced, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">8 cups ; fresh spinach, packed ; (320 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 teaspoons ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 cups ; whole milk ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">nonstick cooking spray, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">8 cups ; day-old country white bread ; (280 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 cups ; shredded cheddar cheese, divided ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ cup ; chicken stock ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ cup ; heavy cream ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="2">Brunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/127171/hls24_1552501724.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/127171/landscape_720/1552501724</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Add the breakfast sausage to a large nonstick skillet over medium heat. Cook, breaking up with a spatula until no longer pink, 7-8 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the white and light green scallions, ½ of the bell pepper, and ½ of the spinach. Sauté for 2 minutes, until the spinach is wilted, then add the rest of the spinach and continue cooking until wilted. Remove the pan from the heat and let cool. </step>
    <step num="2">In a medium bowl, whisk together the eggs, salt, and garlic powder. Add the milk and whisk to incorporate. </step>
    <step num="3">Grease a 9 (22 cm) x 13-inch (33 cm) glass baking dish with nonstick spray. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the cubed bread to the baking dish. If you don’t have day-old bread, spread the cubed bread on a baking sheet and dry out in a 300˚F (150˚C) oven for 15-20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Sprinkle 1 cup (100 G) of shredded cheese over the bread, then evenly spread the sausage mixture on top. Pour the egg mixture over the sausage mixture. Cover the baking dish with plastic wrap and refrigerate for at least 1 hour, or overnight. </step>
    <step num="6">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </step>
    <step num="7">In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, combine the chicken stock and heavy cream. </step>
    <step num="8">Pour over the chilled bake. Sprinkle the remaining cup of cheese and remaining bell pepper over the top. </step>
    <step num="9">Cover with foil and bake for 45 minutes, then uncover and bake for another 15-20 minutes, until the custard is set and the cheese is golden brown. Remove from oven and let cool for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="10">Garnish with the dark green scallions, then slice and serve. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Add the breakfast sausage to a large nonstick skillet over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cook, breaking up with a spatula until no longer pink, 7-8 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the white and light green scallions, ½ of the bell pepper, and ½ of the spinach. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Sauté for 2 minutes, until the spinach is wilted, then add the rest of the spinach and continue cooking until wilted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Remove the pan from the heat and let cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In a medium bowl, whisk together the eggs, salt, and garlic powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the milk and whisk to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Grease a 9 (22 cm) x 13-inch (33 cm) glass baking dish with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the cubed bread to the baking dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">If you don’t have day-old bread, spread the cubed bread on a baking sheet and dry out in a 300˚F (150˚C) oven for 15-20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Sprinkle 1 cup (100 G) of shredded cheese over the bread, then evenly spread the sausage mixture on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Pour the egg mixture over the sausage mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cover the baking dish with plastic wrap and refrigerate for at least 1 hour, or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, combine the chicken stock and heavy cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Pour over the chilled bake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Sprinkle the remaining cup of cheese and remaining bell pepper over the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cover with foil and bake for 45 minutes, then uncover and bake for another 15-20 minutes, until the custard is set and the cheese is golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Remove from oven and let cool for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Garnish with the dark green scallions, then slice and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>