<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Vegan Black Rice Sushi Rolls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/vegan-black-rice-sushi-rolls</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">⅓ cup ; organic tempeh, cut into thin strips ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">⅓ cup ; soy sauce ; (80 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; medium carrot, grated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ head ; purple cabbage, grated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 sheets ; toasted nori </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">black rice, cooked according to package directions, and cooled </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; avocado, thinly sliced lengthwise ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">⅓ cup ; english cucumber, seeded, cut into thin strips ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">⅓ cup ; cashews, coarsely chopped ; (45 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">water, for sealing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">3 tablespoons ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¼ cup ; lime juice ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">3 tablespoons ; maple syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 teaspoons ; white miso paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 teaspoons ; black sesame seeds </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 teaspoon ; fresh ginger, grated, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">bamboo sushi mat, optional </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Vegan</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Lunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/130682/hls24_1556066591.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/130682/landscape_720/1556066591</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium bowl, pour the soy sauce over the tempeh. Set aside to marinate for at least 25 minutes. While the tempeh marinates, prepare the rest of the ingredients. </step>
    <step num="1">Heat a medium nonstick pan over medium-high heat. Add the marinated tempeh strips. Cook for 1-2 minutes on each side, until golden brown and lightly charred. Remove from the pan and set aside to cool. </step>
    <step num="2">In a medium bowl, toss together the carrot and cabbage. </step>
    <step num="3">Build the sushi rolls: Lay a sheet of toasted nori, shiny side down, on the bamboo mat or clean work surface. Pat about ¼ of the rice evenly over the nori, leaving about a ½ inch (1 ¼ cm) of space at the top. Layer a few slices of avocado over the rice toward the bottom of the nori sheet. Top with a few pieces of cucumber, some of the carrot-cabbage mixture, a couple of pieces of tempeh, and about 1 tablespoon of chopped cashews. </step>
    <step num="4">To close the sushi roll, brush a bit of water across the empty edge of the nori. Using both hands, roll the filled end of the nori sheet over onto itself, carefully tucking all of the ingredients inside. Continue rolling until the nori sheet covers the rice and seal with the damp edge. Repeat with remaining nori sheets and fillings. </step>
    <step num="5">With a sharp knife, cut each roll into 6-8 pieces, depending on preference. Pro tip: If you wet the knife before slicing, it will cut through the nori more cleanly. But be careful! </step>
    <step num="6">Make the sesame miso sauce: In a small bowl, combine the olive oil, lime juice, maple syrup, miso, sesame seeds, and ginger, if using. Whisk to combine. </step>
    <step num="7">Serve the sushi rolls with the sauce for dipping. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium bowl, pour the soy sauce over the tempeh. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Set aside to marinate for at least 25 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">While the tempeh marinates, prepare the rest of the ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Heat a medium nonstick pan over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the marinated tempeh strips. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cook for 1-2 minutes on each side, until golden brown and lightly charred. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove from the pan and set aside to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a medium bowl, toss together the carrot and cabbage. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Build the sushi rolls: Lay a sheet of toasted nori, shiny side down, on the bamboo mat or clean work surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Pat about ¼ of the rice evenly over the nori, leaving about a ½ inch (1 ¼ cm) of space at the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Layer a few slices of avocado over the rice toward the bottom of the nori sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Top with a few pieces of cucumber, some of the carrot-cabbage mixture, a couple of pieces of tempeh, and about 1 tablespoon of chopped cashews. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">To close the sushi roll, brush a bit of water across the empty edge of the nori. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Using both hands, roll the filled end of the nori sheet over onto itself, carefully tucking all of the ingredients inside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Continue rolling until the nori sheet covers the rice and seal with the damp edge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Repeat with remaining nori sheets and fillings. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">With a sharp knife, cut each roll into 6-8 pieces, depending on preference. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Pro tip: If you wet the knife before slicing, it will cut through the nori more cleanly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">But be careful! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Make the sesame miso sauce: In a small bowl, combine the olive oil, lime juice, maple syrup, miso, sesame seeds, and ginger, if using. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Serve the sushi rolls with the sauce for dipping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>