<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Steak With Garlic Butter Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/steak-with-garlic-butter</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; thick rib eye steak, 1 inch (2 cm) thick ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 tablespoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; freshly ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">4 tablespoons ; canola oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 tablespoons ; butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 sprigs ; fresh thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 bunches ; fresh rosemary </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 cloves ; garlic, crushed </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Date Night</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31932/low_1495124939.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31932/mp4_720x1280/1495124939</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 250°F (120°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Season the steak evenly with the salt and pepper on all sides. </step>
    <step num="2">Place the steak on a wire rack on top of a baking sheet. Bake for 35 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Heat the canola oil in a skillet or stainless steel pan over high heat until smoking. Sear the steak on one side for 30 seconds, then flip. </step>
    <step num="4">Immediately, add the butter, thyme, rosemary, and garlic, swirling the pan to melt the butter quickly. </step>
    <step num="5">Place the herbs and garlic on top of the steak, and push the steak toward the top of the pan. Tilt the pan toward you to pool the butter near the bottom. Using a spoon, continuously scoop the butter over the top of the steak for about 30–45 seconds. </step>
    <step num="6">This helps not only flavor the steak, but also helps cook the steak faster. If you prefer your steak medium or medium-well, cook your steak longer. </step>
    <step num="7">To test the doneness of your steak, lightly press the tip of your left index finger to the tip of your left thumb. The fleshy area below the thumb should feel how rare steak feels pressing the surface of the steak. For medium-rare steak, touch your middle finger to your thumb and press the area below your thumb. For medium, touch your fourth finger to your thumb. For well done, touch your pinky to your thumb. </step>
    <step num="8">Rest the steak for 10 minutes on a cutting board. Slice, then serve! </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 250°F (120°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Season the steak evenly with the salt and pepper on all sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Place the steak on a wire rack on top of a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Bake for 35 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Heat the canola oil in a skillet or stainless steel pan over high heat until smoking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Sear the steak on one side for 30 seconds, then flip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Immediately, add the butter, thyme, rosemary, and garlic, swirling the pan to melt the butter quickly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Place the herbs and garlic on top of the steak, and push the steak toward the top of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Tilt the pan toward you to pool the butter near the bottom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Using a spoon, continuously scoop the butter over the top of the steak for about 30–45 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">This helps not only flavor the steak, but also helps cook the steak faster. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">If you prefer your steak medium or medium-well, cook your steak longer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">To test the doneness of your steak, lightly press the tip of your left index finger to the tip of your left thumb. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">The fleshy area below the thumb should feel how rare steak feels pressing the surface of the steak. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">For medium-rare steak, touch your middle finger to your thumb and press the area below your thumb. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">For medium, touch your fourth finger to your thumb. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">For well done, touch your pinky to your thumb. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Rest the steak for 10 minutes on a cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Slice, then serve! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>