<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Mirror Glaze Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/mirror-glaze</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/3-part-mirror-glaze-cake</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ¼ cups ; water ; (300 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ cups ; sugar ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">14 oz ; sweetened condensed milk, 1 can ; (395 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">15 ; gelatin sheets </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">26 oz ; white chocolate, chopped, over 30% cocoa butter ; (735 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">gel food coloring, of choice </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Date Night</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="3">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32151/low_1495125336.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32151/mp4_720x1280/1495125336</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>24.11</start_time>
    <end_time>73.6</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Boil the water, sugar, and condensed milk in a pot for 1 minute, then remove from heat. </step>
    <step num="1">Bloom the gelatin sheets in 8 cups (2 liters) of cold water for 5 minutes, then wring the gelatin sheets of excess water and mix into the sugar mixture. </step>
    <step num="2">Pour the liquid over the chocolate, letting it sit for 2-3 minutes to allow the chocolate to soften. </step>
    <step num="3">Using an immersion blender, carefully blend the chocolate and the liquid, making sure that you are not blending in air bubbles by lifting up the blender too high. It’s okay to go slow, just make sure it’s all blended with as little bubbles as possible, which will show up in the final product. </step>
    <step num="4">Sieve the mix into a large jug or vertical container to remove any excess bubbles. If there are still bubbles, continue to sieve back and forth. A trick to remove air bubbles from the surface is to manually pop them with a toothpick or to press cling film into the surface and remove the bubbles. </step>
    <step num="5">Separate the glaze into different containers and color them to your desire. </step>
    <step num="6">We used red and white for this cake. Blend the coloring with the glaze until the color is distributed evenly, then cover each container with the cling film, pressing the film into the glaze to ensure that there is no skin when you are ready to use the glaze. </step>
    <step num="7">When you are ready to use the glaze, make sure each one is around 90-96°F, then pour the colored glazes back into one container. Swirl them if you’d like, then glaze your cake! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Boil the water, sugar, and condensed milk in a pot for 1 minute, then remove from heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Bloom the gelatin sheets in 8 cups (2 liters) of cold water for 5 minutes, then wring the gelatin sheets of excess water and mix into the sugar mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Pour the liquid over the chocolate, letting it sit for 2-3 minutes to allow the chocolate to soften. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Using an immersion blender, carefully blend the chocolate and the liquid, making sure that you are not blending in air bubbles by lifting up the blender too high. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">It’s okay to go slow, just make sure it’s all blended with as little bubbles as possible, which will show up in the final product. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Sieve the mix into a large jug or vertical container to remove any excess bubbles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">If there are still bubbles, continue to sieve back and forth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">A trick to remove air bubbles from the surface is to manually pop them with a toothpick or to press cling film into the surface and remove the bubbles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Separate the glaze into different containers and color them to your desire. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">We used red and white for this cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Blend the coloring with the glaze until the color is distributed evenly, then cover each container with the cling film, pressing the film into the glaze to ensure that there is no skin when you are ready to use the glaze. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">When you are ready to use the glaze, make sure each one is around 90-96°F, then pour the colored glazes back into one container. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Swirl them if you’d like, then glaze your cake! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>