<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Fajita Chicken And Rice Dinner Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/fajita-chicken-and-rice-dinner</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¼ cup ; extra virgin olive oil, Private Selection Italian ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 tablespoons ; lime juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; agave nectar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">4 teaspoons ; kosher salt, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; dried oregano </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 teaspoons ; chili powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 teaspoons ; ground cumin, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 lb ; boneless, skinless chicken thighs ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ; small yellow onion, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ; medium green bell pepper, seeded and sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; medium yellow bell pepper, seeded and sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ; medium red bell pepper, seeded and sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 cup ; white long grain rice, rinsed ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ½ cups ; chicken stock ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">Lime wedges, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">fresh cilantro, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dinner</category>
    <category num="1">Date Night</category>
    <category num="2">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/123625/hls24_1548369837.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/123625/landscape_720/1548369837</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a shallow dish or medium bowl, whisk together the olive oil, lime juice, agave, 1 teaspoon of salt, the oregano, chili powder, and 2 teaspoons of cumin. Add the chicken and toss to coat well. Cover with plastic wrap and marinate in the refrigerator for at least 30 minutes, up to 4 hours. </step>
    <step num="1">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </step>
    <step num="2">Remove the chicken from the marinade and place in a large oven-safe pot over medium-high heat, being careful not to overcrowd the pot. Cook for 3 minutes, or until golden brown, then flip and repeat on the other side. Remove the chicken from the pot and set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the onion and bell peppers to the pot. Cook for 2-3 minutes, or until starting to soften. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the rice and chicken stock. Season with the remaining teaspoon of cumin, the pepper, and remaining 2 teaspoons of salt. Bring to a boil, then return the chicken thighs to the pot. </step>
    <step num="5">Cover with a lid and transfer to the oven until the rice is tender, about 45 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Garnish with a squeeze of lime juice and cilantro. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a shallow dish or medium bowl, whisk together the olive oil, lime juice, agave, 1 teaspoon of salt, the oregano, chili powder, and 2 teaspoons of cumin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the chicken and toss to coat well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cover with plastic wrap and marinate in the refrigerator for at least 30 minutes, up to 4 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Remove the chicken from the marinade and place in a large oven-safe pot over medium-high heat, being careful not to overcrowd the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cook for 3 minutes, or until golden brown, then flip and repeat on the other side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove the chicken from the pot and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the onion and bell peppers to the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Cook for 2-3 minutes, or until starting to soften. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the rice and chicken stock. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Season with the remaining teaspoon of cumin, the pepper, and remaining 2 teaspoons of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Bring to a boil, then return the chicken thighs to the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cover with a lid and transfer to the oven until the rice is tender, about 45 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Garnish with a squeeze of lime juice and cilantro. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>