<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Instant Energy Ginger Citrus Spritz Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/instant-energy-ginger-citrus-spritz</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ cup ; sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; cold water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; fresh ginger, 3 in (7 cm) peeled and finely grated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ½ cups ; orange juice, freshly squeezed ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 bottle ; prosecco </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¾ cup ; orange liqueur, such as aperol ; (180 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">12 oz ; club soda ; (355 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; navel orange, sliced into rounds </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Drinks</category>
    <category num="1">Happy Hour</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129790/hls24_1555016887.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129790/landscape_720/1555016887</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the ginger simple syrup: In a small saucepan over medium heat, combine the sugar, water, and ginger. Bring to a low boil, then reduce the heat to low and simmer for 5 minutes, until the sugar is fully dissolved and the ginger is fragrant. Remove from heat and let cool for 5-10 minutes. Strain through a fine-mesh sieve (you should have ⅓ cup (80 ml) syrup). </step>
    <step num="1">Fill a 10-cup pitcher halfway with ice. Pour in the ginger simple syrup, orange juice, and prosecco and stir to combine. Top with the bitter orange liqueur and club soda. Fill the pitcher with the orange slices. Serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="2">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the ginger simple syrup: In a small saucepan over medium heat, combine the sugar, water, and ginger. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Bring to a low boil, then reduce the heat to low and simmer for 5 minutes, until the sugar is fully dissolved and the ginger is fragrant. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Remove from heat and let cool for 5-10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Strain through a fine-mesh sieve (you should have ⅓ cup (80 ml) syrup). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Fill a 10-cup pitcher halfway with ice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour in the ginger simple syrup, orange juice, and prosecco and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Top with the bitter orange liqueur and club soda. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Fill the pitcher with the orange slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>