<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Holiday Vegetable Wellington Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/holiday-vegetable-wellington</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 cups ; butternut squash, small diced ; (615 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">olive oil, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">freshly ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">14 oz ; red kidney bean, rinsed and drained ; (255 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; chestnut, shelled, roasted and halved ; (145 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; medium shallot, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">8 oz ; cremini mushroom, cleaned and finely chopped ; (220 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 tablespoon ; dried thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">4 cloves ; garlic, minced, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">18 oz ; frozen spinach, defrosted and squeezed dry of excess liquid ; (540 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">lemon juice, of 1/2 lemon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">lemon zest, of 1/2 lemon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">½ teaspoon ; ground nutmeg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 ; small white onion, small diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 ; medium carrot, small diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">2 tablespoons ; fresh sage, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 tablespoon ; balsamic vinegar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">2 tablespoons ; dijon mustard </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">2 cups ; white bread, torn loosely packed ; (70 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">¼ cup ; vegetable stock ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">16 oz ; puff pastry ; (490 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">6 ; red peppers, whole roasted, cut to lay flat and dried of any excess liquid </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">1 ; large egg, beaten </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Date Night</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/120887/hls24_1545348706.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/120887/landscape_720/1545348706</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). </step>
    <step num="1">On a baking sheet, drizzle the butternut squash with olive oil, then season with salt and pepper. Toss to coat, then spread in an even layer. Roast for 20 minutes, stirring halfway, until the squash is tender and golden brown. Remove from the oven and set aside to cool. </step>
    <step num="2">On another baking sheet, spread out the kidney beans and chestnuts. Bake for 10 minutes, or until the excess moisture has released and the beans begin to crack down the middle. Remove from the oven and set aside to cool. </step>
    <step num="3">Prepare the duxelle (mushroom mixture): In a large pan over medium heat, melt the butter. Once the butter begins to foam, add the shallot, mushrooms, thyme, and salt. Stir to combine and cook for 10-15 minutes, or until the liquid evaporates from the mushrooms and they begin to turn golden brown. Transfer the duxelle to a bowl and set aside to cool. </step>
    <step num="4">Return the pan to the stove (no need to clean), and heat a drizzle of oil over medium heat. Add 2 cloves of minced garlic and the frozen spinach. Break the spinach up with a wooden spoon and sauté for 2 minutes, or until the garlic is toasted and the spinach is warmed through. Add the lemon juice, lemon zest, nutmeg, salt, and pepper. Transfer to a bowl and set aside to cool. </step>
    <step num="5">Return the same pan back to the stove over medium-high heat and add a drizzle of oil. When the oil is hot, add the onion, carrot, salt, and pepper. Sauté for 5 minutes, or until the vegetables are softened and beginning to turn golden brown. Add the remaining 2 cloves of garlic and the sage and sauté for 1 minute more, or until the garlic is just fragrant. Add the balsamic vinegar, Dijon mustard, and bread. Stir until the bread is well-coated, then remove from the heat and let cool slightly. </step>
    <step num="6">Transfer the bread mixture to a food processor. Add in the roasted kidney beans and chestnuts and vegetable stock. Pulse a few times, until just combined. (The mixture should be an even consistency but still have texture to it. It should stick together when pressed in your palm). Transfer the bread mixture to a large bowl. Gently stir in the roasted butternut squash and season with more salt and pepper to taste. </step>
    <step num="7">Increase the oven temperature to 425°F (220°C) and line a large baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="8">On a lightly floured surface, roll each piece of puff pastry into rectangle slightly smaller than the prepared baking sheet. Transfer 1 piece of the pastry to the baking sheet and set the other piece aside. </step>
    <step num="9">Assemble the Wellington: Spread the cooled duxelle lengthwise down the middle of the puff pastry on the baking sheet, creating a rectangle the size that you want your wellington to be. Make sure to leave about a 2-inch border at both ends of the pastry. (You will be removing all excess dough and using it for decorations.) </step>
    <step num="10">Next, arrange half of the bell peppers over the duxelle. Make sure they lay flat, only overlap on the edges, and completely cover the mushrooms. </step>
    <step num="11">Top the bell pepper layer with the roasted squash and bread mixture by using your hands to pack the mixture into a loaf, making sure it doesn’t go over the edges of the peppers. </step>
    <step num="12">Layer the remaining roasted peppers evenly over the bread mixture. </step>
    <step num="13">Top the peppers with the spinach mixture. (This will be a bit messy, but it’s okay, it’s part of the process!) </step>
    <step num="14">Gently roll the second piece of pastry over the spinach layer, creating a blanket over all of the vegetable layers. Press the pastry gently around the filling to create a log shape. Trim the pastry so that there is about a 1-inch (2.5 cm) border around the log. </step>
    <step num="15">Fold the bottom layer of the pastry over the top layer and seal the dough together with a decorative crimp. Cut decorative shapes from the dough scraps and arrange over the log. Using a paring knife, cut a few vents into your wellington to allow steam to escape. You can hide the vents along the edges of your decorations. </step>
    <step num="16">Generously brush the top and sides of the wellington with the beaten egg. </step>
    <step num="17">Bake for 30 minutes, or until the pastry is golden brown and crispy. </step>
    <step num="18">Let rest for 15 minutes before slicing and serving. </step>
    <step num="19">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">On a baking sheet, drizzle the butternut squash with olive oil, then season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Toss to coat, then spread in an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Roast for 20 minutes, stirring halfway, until the squash is tender and golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Remove from the oven and set aside to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">On another baking sheet, spread out the kidney beans and chestnuts. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Bake for 10 minutes, or until the excess moisture has released and the beans begin to crack down the middle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove from the oven and set aside to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Prepare the duxelle (mushroom mixture): In a large pan over medium heat, melt the butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Once the butter begins to foam, add the shallot, mushrooms, thyme, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Stir to combine and cook for 10-15 minutes, or until the liquid evaporates from the mushrooms and they begin to turn golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Transfer the duxelle to a bowl and set aside to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Return the pan to the stove (no need to clean), and heat a drizzle of oil over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add 2 cloves of minced garlic and the frozen spinach. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Break the spinach up with a wooden spoon and sauté for 2 minutes, or until the garlic is toasted and the spinach is warmed through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the lemon juice, lemon zest, nutmeg, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Transfer to a bowl and set aside to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Return the same pan back to the stove over medium-high heat and add a drizzle of oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">When the oil is hot, add the onion, carrot, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Sauté for 5 minutes, or until the vegetables are softened and beginning to turn golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Add the remaining 2 cloves of garlic and the sage and sauté for 1 minute more, or until the garlic is just fragrant. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Add the balsamic vinegar, Dijon mustard, and bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Stir until the bread is well-coated, then remove from the heat and let cool slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Transfer the bread mixture to a food processor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Add in the roasted kidney beans and chestnuts and vegetable stock. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Pulse a few times, until just combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">(The mixture should be an even consistency but still have texture to it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">It should stick together when pressed in your palm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Transfer the bread mixture to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Gently stir in the roasted butternut squash and season with more salt and pepper to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Increase the oven temperature to 425°F (220°C) and line a large baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">On a lightly floured surface, roll each piece of puff pastry into rectangle slightly smaller than the prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Transfer 1 piece of the pastry to the baking sheet and set the other piece aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Assemble the Wellington: Spread the cooled duxelle lengthwise down the middle of the puff pastry on the baking sheet, creating a rectangle the size that you want your wellington to be. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Make sure to leave about a 2-inch border at both ends of the pastry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">(You will be removing all excess dough and using it for decorations.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Next, arrange half of the bell peppers over the duxelle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="37">Make sure they lay flat, only overlap on the edges, and completely cover the mushrooms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="38">Top the bell pepper layer with the roasted squash and bread mixture by using your hands to pack the mixture into a loaf, making sure it doesn’t go over the edges of the peppers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="39">Layer the remaining roasted peppers evenly over the bread mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="40">Top the peppers with the spinach mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="41">(This will be a bit messy, but it’s okay, it’s part of the process!) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="42">Gently roll the second piece of pastry over the spinach layer, creating a blanket over all of the vegetable layers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="43">Press the pastry gently around the filling to create a log shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="44">Trim the pastry so that there is about a 1-inch (2.5 cm) border around the log. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="45">Fold the bottom layer of the pastry over the top layer and seal the dough together with a decorative crimp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="46">Cut decorative shapes from the dough scraps and arrange over the log. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="47">Using a paring knife, cut a few vents into your wellington to allow steam to escape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="48">You can hide the vents along the edges of your decorations. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="49">Generously brush the top and sides of the wellington with the beaten egg. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="50">Bake for 30 minutes, or until the pastry is golden brown and crispy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="51">Let rest for 15 minutes before slicing and serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="52">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>