<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Fruity Cereal Donuts Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/fruity-cereal-donuts</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">nonstick cooking spray, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; fruit flavored rice cereal ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¾ cup ; milk ; (180 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 ¼ cups ; powdered sugar, sifted ; (270 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 ½ cups ; all purpose flour ; (310 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; fruit flavored rice cereal, finely crushed ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ½ teaspoons ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ teaspoon ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; granulated sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ cup ; vegetable oil ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 cup ; milk ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 ½ cups ; fruit flavored rice cereal ; (45 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">2 ; donut pans, 6 count </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/133566/hls24_1558483252.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/133566/landscape_720/1558483252</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 425˚F (220˚C). Grease the donut pans with nonstick spray. </step>
    <step num="1">In a medium bowl, combine the cereal and milk for the glaze. Set aside to soak while you make the donuts, about 20 minutes. Strain into a clean bowl, pressing on the cereal to extract as much milk as possible. </step>
    <step num="2">Make the donuts: In a medium bowl, combine the flour, crushed cereal, baking powder, baking soda, and salt. Stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="3">In a large bowl, whisk together the sugar, vegetable oil, eggs, milk, and vanilla. Add the dry ingredients and whisk until there are no lumps. </step>
    <step num="4">Transfer the batter to a piping bag or zip-top bag with a corner cut off. Pipe the batter into the prepared donut pans. Leave about ¼ inch (6 ml) from the rim, so they don’t overflow. </step>
    <step num="5">Bake for 9-10 minutes, until the donuts are just beginning to turn golden brown around the edges and a toothpick inserted in the center comes out clean. Let cool in the pan for 5 minutes, then transfer to a wire rack to continue cooling for about 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Make the glaze: In a medium bowl, combine the powdered sugar and ¼ cup of the cereal milk. Whisk until smooth. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the cereal for topping to a shallow dish. </step>
    <step num="8">Once cooled, dip the tops of the donuts into the glaze, then into the cereal. Set on a wire rack set over a baking pan to dry for at least 20 minutes, until the glaze is no longer shiny. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 425˚F (220˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Grease the donut pans with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a medium bowl, combine the cereal and milk for the glaze. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set aside to soak while you make the donuts, about 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Strain into a clean bowl, pressing on the cereal to extract as much milk as possible. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Make the donuts: In a medium bowl, combine the flour, crushed cereal, baking powder, baking soda, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a large bowl, whisk together the sugar, vegetable oil, eggs, milk, and vanilla. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the dry ingredients and whisk until there are no lumps. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Transfer the batter to a piping bag or zip-top bag with a corner cut off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Pipe the batter into the prepared donut pans. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Leave about ¼ inch (6 ml) from the rim, so they don’t overflow. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Bake for 9-10 minutes, until the donuts are just beginning to turn golden brown around the edges and a toothpick inserted in the center comes out clean. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Let cool in the pan for 5 minutes, then transfer to a wire rack to continue cooling for about 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Make the glaze: In a medium bowl, combine the powdered sugar and ¼ cup of the cereal milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Whisk until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the cereal for topping to a shallow dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Once cooled, dip the tops of the donuts into the glaze, then into the cereal. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Set on a wire rack set over a baking pan to dry for at least 20 minutes, until the glaze is no longer shiny. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>