<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>16-Layer No-Bake S’mores Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/16-layer-no-bake-smores-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ½ cups ; semi-sweet chocolate chips ; (435 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 cups ; heavy cream, hot ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 cups ; marshmallow fluff, divided ; (255 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 tablespoons ; milk, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">29 ; graham crackers, plus 2 graham crackers, crumbled, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; chocolate bar, chopped, for deoration </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/90013/hls24_1524071950.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/90013/landscape_720/1524071950</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large heatproof bowl, pour the hot heavy cream over the semisweet chocolate chips. Let stand for 30 seconds, then whisk together for 1 minute, or until thick and smooth. </step>
    <step num="1">Place 1 cup (85 g) of marshmallow fluff in a medium heatproof bowl and place the remaining fluff into a separate medium heatproof bowl. Add a tablespoon of milk to the bowl with 1 cup (85 g) of fluff and the remaining 2 tablespoons milk to the bowl with the remaining fluff. </step>
    <step num="2">Microwave each bowl of fluff for 15 seconds. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove the bowls from the microwave and use a fork to stir the milk into the fluff until it is thick and smooth. Cover the bowl with less fluff and store in the fridge – it will be used later for decoration. </step>
    <step num="4">Line a 5x8-inch (13x20cm) loaf pan with parchment paper and place a row of graham crackers on the bottom of the pan. Pour a thin layer of the marshmallow fluff over the graham crackers and use a spoon or spatula to spread the mixture evenly. Place another row of graham crackers on top of the fluff, then pour a thin layer of the chocolate ganache over the crackers and use a spoon or spatula to spread an even layer. Repeat three more times. </step>
    <step num="5">Cover and chill in the fridge overnight. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove the cake and reserved marshmallow fluff from the fridge. Use the parchment to lift the cake out of the loaf pan. Microwave the leftover marshmallow fluff mixture for 15 seconds, then use a spatula to spread the fluff over the cake in an even layer. </step>
    <step num="7">Optional: use a small kitchen torch to gently toast the marshmallow topping. Sprinkle crumbled graham cracker and chocolate chunks over the top of the cake. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large heatproof bowl, pour the hot heavy cream over the semisweet chocolate chips. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Let stand for 30 seconds, then whisk together for 1 minute, or until thick and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Place 1 cup (85 g) of marshmallow fluff in a medium heatproof bowl and place the remaining fluff into a separate medium heatproof bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add a tablespoon of milk to the bowl with 1 cup (85 g) of fluff and the remaining 2 tablespoons milk to the bowl with the remaining fluff. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Microwave each bowl of fluff for 15 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Remove the bowls from the microwave and use a fork to stir the milk into the fluff until it is thick and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cover the bowl with less fluff and store in the fridge – it will be used later for decoration. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Line a 5x8-inch (13x20cm) loaf pan with parchment paper and place a row of graham crackers on the bottom of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Pour a thin layer of the marshmallow fluff over the graham crackers and use a spoon or spatula to spread the mixture evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Place another row of graham crackers on top of the fluff, then pour a thin layer of the chocolate ganache over the crackers and use a spoon or spatula to spread an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Repeat three more times. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cover and chill in the fridge overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove the cake and reserved marshmallow fluff from the fridge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Use the parchment to lift the cake out of the loaf pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Microwave the leftover marshmallow fluff mixture for 15 seconds, then use a spatula to spread the fluff over the cake in an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Optional: use a small kitchen torch to gently toast the marshmallow topping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Sprinkle crumbled graham cracker and chocolate chunks over the top of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>