<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Sticky Bun Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/sticky-bun-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">24 oz ; cream cheese, 3 packages ; (675 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; powdered sugar ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; milk ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 teaspoons ; vanilla extract, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">35 slices ; white bread </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 sticks ; butter, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; granulated sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 teaspoons ; cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 cup ; brown sugar, packed ; (220 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; honey ; (85 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 cup ; pecan ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">vanilla ice cream, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/83921/hls24_1520635232.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/83921/landscape_720/1520635232</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (165˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, add the cream cheese, powdered sugar, milk, and 1 teaspoon of vanilla. Mix with a whisk or hand mixer until smooth. Set aside until ready to use. </step>
    <step num="2">On a cutting board, cut the crusts off the bread. Lay out 5 pieces of bread so they are slightly overlapping, then press the overlapping edges together to adhere. Repeat with the rest of the bread, you will have 7 strips of 5 pieces of bread. </step>
    <step num="3">In a small bowl, melt ¾ cups of butter. Add the granulated sugar and cinnamon and stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="4">Brush the cinnamon butter mixture on one of the strips of bread. </step>
    <step num="5">Spread the cream cheese filling on the strip of bread. Repeat with the rest of the strips of bread. </step>
    <step num="6">Roll up one of the strips of bread, take that roll and roll it on to another strip of bread. Repeat until all of the strips have been rolled up into one large roll. </step>
    <step num="7">In a small saucepan over medium heat, mix together the remaining ¾ cup (170 g) butter, brown sugar, salt, remaining teaspoon vanilla, and honey until melted. Remove from heat. </step>
    <step num="8">Pour ⅔ of the caramel mixture into an 8-inch (20 cm) round cake pan. Sprinkle the pecans on top of the caramel. Place the bread roll inside the pan on top of the caramel. Pour the rest of the caramel over the top of the roll. </step>
    <step num="9">Bake for 40 minutes, until the top is crisp. </step>
    <step num="10">Place a large plate over the top of the cake pan. Using oven mitts, invert the roll onto the plate, and remove the cake pan. </step>
    <step num="11">Let cool for about 10 minutes before slicing. </step>
    <step num="12">Serve immediately, with vanilla ice cream if desired! </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (165˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a large bowl, add the cream cheese, powdered sugar, milk, and 1 teaspoon of vanilla. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Mix with a whisk or hand mixer until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set aside until ready to use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">On a cutting board, cut the crusts off the bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Lay out 5 pieces of bread so they are slightly overlapping, then press the overlapping edges together to adhere. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Repeat with the rest of the bread, you will have 7 strips of 5 pieces of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a small bowl, melt ¾ cups of butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the granulated sugar and cinnamon and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Brush the cinnamon butter mixture on one of the strips of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Spread the cream cheese filling on the strip of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Repeat with the rest of the strips of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Roll up one of the strips of bread, take that roll and roll it on to another strip of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Repeat until all of the strips have been rolled up into one large roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">In a small saucepan over medium heat, mix together the remaining ¾ cup (170 g) butter, brown sugar, salt, remaining teaspoon vanilla, and honey until melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove from heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Pour ⅔ of the caramel mixture into an 8-inch (20 cm) round cake pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Sprinkle the pecans on top of the caramel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Place the bread roll inside the pan on top of the caramel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Pour the rest of the caramel over the top of the roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Bake for 40 minutes, until the top is crisp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Place a large plate over the top of the cake pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Using oven mitts, invert the roll onto the plate, and remove the cake pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Let cool for about 10 minutes before slicing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Serve immediately, with vanilla ice cream if desired! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>