<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Peppermint Mocha Cannoli Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/peppermint-mocha-cannoli</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; flour ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; instant espresso powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; cold butter, cubed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; egg, separated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ cup ; dry white wine ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 cups ; whole milk ricotta cheese ; (500 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">⅓ cup ; powdered sugar ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 tablespoons ; cocoa powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¾ teaspoon ; instant espresso powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">candy cane, or peppermints, crushed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">dark chocolate, for melting </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">oil, for frying </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">cannoli forms, available at most specialty kitchen stores or online </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Fusion</category>
    <category num="6">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32217/low_1495125482.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32217/mp4_720x1280/1495125482</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Separate egg white and egg yolk into two small bowls. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, whisk together flour, sugar, salt, and 1 teaspoon instant espresso powder. Add the butter and work into the flour mixture with your fingertips until it reaches a sandy consistency. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the egg yolk, vanilla extract, and white wine. Mix together first with a wooden spoon, then finish by kneading it out on a lightly floured surface with your hands until the dough comes together and becomes smooth. Form into a ball and cover with plastic wrap. Refrigerate dough for 30 minutes to an hour. </step>
    <step num="3">Form into a ball and cover with plastic wrap. Refrigerate dough for 30 minutes to an hour. </step>
    <step num="4">To make the filling: in a medium bowl whisk together the ricotta cheese, powdered sugar, cocoa powder, and ¾ teaspoon instant espresso powder. Refrigerate until ready to pipe. If the ricotta is especially wet, first remove excess moisture by patting it down with paper towels. </step>
    <step num="5">Remove the chilled dough and divide in half. Roll out to as thin as possible on a lightly floured surface. Using a small bowl, cookie cutter, or jar lid, cut into circles (re-rolling the circles and re-cutting if necessary to reach desired thinness). Wrap dough around a lightly greased cannoli form and seal with egg white. </step>
    <step num="6">Heat oil to 350˚F (175˚C) and carefully lower the cannoli forms into the hot oil. Fry until golden on all sides. Remove from oil and set on paper towel to drain and cool. </step>
    <step num="7">Using a small bowl, cookie cutter, or jar lid, cut into circles (re-rolling the circles and re-cutting if necessary to reach desired thinness). </step>
    <step num="8">Remove the cooled pastry and dip ends in melted chocolate and roll in crushed candy canes. Place on wax paper to set. </step>
    <step num="9">Wrap dough around a lightly greased cannoli form and seal with egg white. </step>
    <step num="10">Before serving, pipe the ricotta mixture into the cannoli. Dust with powdered sugar. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Separate egg white and egg yolk into two small bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a large bowl, whisk together flour, sugar, salt, and 1 teaspoon instant espresso powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the butter and work into the flour mixture with your fingertips until it reaches a sandy consistency. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the egg yolk, vanilla extract, and white wine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Mix together first with a wooden spoon, then finish by kneading it out on a lightly floured surface with your hands until the dough comes together and becomes smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Form into a ball and cover with plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Refrigerate dough for 30 minutes to an hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Form into a ball and cover with plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Refrigerate dough for 30 minutes to an hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">To make the filling: in a medium bowl whisk together the ricotta cheese, powdered sugar, cocoa powder, and ¾ teaspoon instant espresso powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Refrigerate until ready to pipe. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">If the ricotta is especially wet, first remove excess moisture by patting it down with paper towels. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove the chilled dough and divide in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Roll out to as thin as possible on a lightly floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Using a small bowl, cookie cutter, or jar lid, cut into circles (re-rolling the circles and re-cutting if necessary to reach desired thinness). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Wrap dough around a lightly greased cannoli form and seal with egg white. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Heat oil to 350˚F (175˚C) and carefully lower the cannoli forms into the hot oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Fry until golden on all sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Remove from oil and set on paper towel to drain and cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Using a small bowl, cookie cutter, or jar lid, cut into circles (re-rolling the circles and re-cutting if necessary to reach desired thinness). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Remove the cooled pastry and dip ends in melted chocolate and roll in crushed candy canes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Place on wax paper to set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Wrap dough around a lightly greased cannoli form and seal with egg white. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Before serving, pipe the ricotta mixture into the cannoli. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Dust with powdered sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>