<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Gourmet 4-Ingredient Chocolate Mousse</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/gourmet-4-ingredient-chocolate-mousse</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">5 oz ; dark chocolate, chopped ; (140 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 ; large eggs, separated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; sugar, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">whipped cream </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">cocoa powder </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124548/hls24_1549651394.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124548/landscape_720/1549651394</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Fold a kitchen towel and set in the bottom of a large skillet. Fill with water and bring to a gentle simmer over medium heat. </step>
    <step num="1">Place the chocolate in a small heatproof bowl. Set in the pan of simmering water and stir until the chocolate is completely melted, 3-5 minutes. Carefully remove the bowl from the water and set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">Combine the egg whites and 1 tablespoon of sugar in a medium heatproof bowl. Set in the pan of simmering water and stir until the mixture reaches 140˚F (60˚C). Carefully remove the bowl from the water. </step>
    <step num="3">Using an electric hand mixer, beat the egg white mixture until soft peaks form. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">Set a medium heatproof bowl in the pan of simmering water. In the bowl, combine the egg yolks, water, and remaining tablespoon of sugar. Beat with an electric hand mixer until foamy and the temperature reaches 160-170˚F (70-75˚C). Carefully remove the bowl from the water. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the melted chocolate to the yolk mixture and mix with a rubber spatula until well combined. </step>
    <step num="6">Add a scoop of the egg white mixture and stir to combine. Add rest of the egg white mixture and fold to incorporate. </step>
    <step num="7">Divide the mixture between 4 serving cups. Chill in the refrigerator for at least 1 hour, or until set. </step>
    <step num="8">Top with whipped cream and cocoa powder, if desired. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Fold a kitchen towel and set in the bottom of a large skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Fill with water and bring to a gentle simmer over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Place the chocolate in a small heatproof bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set in the pan of simmering water and stir until the chocolate is completely melted, 3-5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Carefully remove the bowl from the water and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Combine the egg whites and 1 tablespoon of sugar in a medium heatproof bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Set in the pan of simmering water and stir until the mixture reaches 140˚F (60˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Carefully remove the bowl from the water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Using an electric hand mixer, beat the egg white mixture until soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Set a medium heatproof bowl in the pan of simmering water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">In the bowl, combine the egg yolks, water, and remaining tablespoon of sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Beat with an electric hand mixer until foamy and the temperature reaches 160-170˚F (70-75˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Carefully remove the bowl from the water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add the melted chocolate to the yolk mixture and mix with a rubber spatula until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add a scoop of the egg white mixture and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add rest of the egg white mixture and fold to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Divide the mixture between 4 serving cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Chill in the refrigerator for at least 1 hour, or until set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Top with whipped cream and cocoa powder, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>