<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Thanksgiving Leftover Sweet Potato Waffles Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/thanksgiving-leftover-sweet-potato-waffles</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; whole wheat </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 ; eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; milk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¼ cup ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; maple syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ½ cups ; mashed sweet potato </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; cranberry sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¼ cup ; orange juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ cup ; raw pecans </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">3 tablespoons ; maple syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">¼ cup ; water </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/116196/hls24_1542737070.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/116196/landscape_720/1542737070</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the waffles: In a medium bowl, whisk together the flour, baking powder, cinnamon, and salt. </step>
    <step num="1">In a separate large bowl, whisk together eggs, milk, olive oil, maple syrup, vanilla, and sweet potato until smooth. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the dry ingredients to the wet ingredients and stir with a rubber spatula until just combined, making sure not to overmix the batter. </step>
    <step num="3">Heat a waffle iron and grease with oil. </step>
    <step num="4">Scoop enough batter to fill your waffle iron into the center. Close the iron and cook for 5-6 minutes, until the waffle is golden brown and cooked all the way through. Remove the waffle and repeat with the remaining batter. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the cranberry syrup: Add the cranberry sauce and orange juice to a blender and blend until smooth. The syrup should be thin enough to drizzle, but not liquidy. Add more orange juice as needed to reach the right consistency. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="6">Make the pecan topping: In a small saucepan, combine the apple, pecans, maple syrup, and water. Cook over medium-high heat until the syrup starts to glaze the pecans and the apples soften, about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Serve the waffles warm with the pecan topping, cranberry syrup, and a few pieces of goat cheese, if desired. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the waffles: In a medium bowl, whisk together the flour, baking powder, cinnamon, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a separate large bowl, whisk together eggs, milk, olive oil, maple syrup, vanilla, and sweet potato until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the dry ingredients to the wet ingredients and stir with a rubber spatula until just combined, making sure not to overmix the batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Heat a waffle iron and grease with oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Scoop enough batter to fill your waffle iron into the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Close the iron and cook for 5-6 minutes, until the waffle is golden brown and cooked all the way through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove the waffle and repeat with the remaining batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Make the cranberry syrup: Add the cranberry sauce and orange juice to a blender and blend until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">The syrup should be thin enough to drizzle, but not liquidy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add more orange juice as needed to reach the right consistency. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Make the pecan topping: In a small saucepan, combine the apple, pecans, maple syrup, and water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cook over medium-high heat until the syrup starts to glaze the pecans and the apples soften, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Serve the waffles warm with the pecan topping, cranberry syrup, and a few pieces of goat cheese, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>