<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Potato Chip–Coated Onion Rings Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/potato-chip-coated-onion-rings</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">vegetable oil, for frying </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ; large onions, Vidalia onion, roots trimmed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">5 oz ; potato chips, original ; (140 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">5 oz ; potato chips, sour cream and onion ; (140 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">5 oz ; potato chips, BBQ ; (140 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; all-purpose flour ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; buttermilk ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; freshly ground black pepper, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">fresh parsley, for garnish, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">dipping sauce, of choice, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Game Day</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Snacks</category>
    <category num="6">Appetizers</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/127375/hls24_1552668100.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/127375/landscape_720/1552668100</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Add enough oil to a large Dutch oven or heavy-bottomed pot to come about halfway up the sides. Heat the oil until it reaches 375˚F (190˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Slice the onions ¾-inch (19 cm) thick and separate into individual rings. </step>
    <step num="2">Place the original potato chips in a resealable plastic bag and crush into crumbs. Transfer to a shallow bowl and repeat with the sour cream and onion and BBQ chips, adding each flavor to a separate bowl. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the flour and eggs to 2 more shallow bowls. To the eggs, add the buttermilk and a pinch of salt and pepper and beat to combine. Add 1 teaspoon salt and 1 teaspoon pepper to the flour and mix to combine. </step>
    <step num="4">With one hand, dredge an onion ring in the flour mixture and gently shake off any excess. With the other hand, dip the onion ring in the egg mixture and let any excess drip off. Dip once more in the flour, then the egg. Dip the onion ring in 1 of the 3 chip flavors, ensuring that the ring is coated thoroughly. Set on a baking sheet and repeat with the remaining onion rings, coating about ⅓ of the rings in each chip flavor. </step>
    <step num="5">Working in batches, fry the onion rings in the hot oil for 2-3 minutes, until golden brown. Watch carefully, as the onion rings will cook quickly. Transfer to a wire rack to drain. </step>
    <step num="6">Sprinkle the onion rings with parsley and serve with your favorite dipping sauces. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Add enough oil to a large Dutch oven or heavy-bottomed pot to come about halfway up the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Heat the oil until it reaches 375˚F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Slice the onions ¾-inch (19 cm) thick and separate into individual rings. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Place the original potato chips in a resealable plastic bag and crush into crumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Transfer to a shallow bowl and repeat with the sour cream and onion and BBQ chips, adding each flavor to a separate bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the flour and eggs to 2 more shallow bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">To the eggs, add the buttermilk and a pinch of salt and pepper and beat to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add 1 teaspoon salt and 1 teaspoon pepper to the flour and mix to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">With one hand, dredge an onion ring in the flour mixture and gently shake off any excess. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">With the other hand, dip the onion ring in the egg mixture and let any excess drip off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Dip once more in the flour, then the egg. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Dip the onion ring in 1 of the 3 chip flavors, ensuring that the ring is coated thoroughly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Set on a baking sheet and repeat with the remaining onion rings, coating about ⅓ of the rings in each chip flavor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Working in batches, fry the onion rings in the hot oil for 2-3 minutes, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Watch carefully, as the onion rings will cook quickly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Transfer to a wire rack to drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Sprinkle the onion rings with parsley and serve with your favorite dipping sauces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>