<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Sweet Sesame Dumplings (Tangyuan) Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/sweet-sesame-dumplings-tangyuan</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; black sesame seeds, toasted, ground ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; powdered sugar ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ½ tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 cups ; glutinous rice flour, plus more for dusting ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; warm water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 tablespoons ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; osmanthus, dried flower </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Chinese</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124270/hls24_1549391669.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124270/landscape_720/1549391669</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the filling: In a medium bowl, combine the ground black sesame seeds, powdered sugar and melted butter. Mix until well combined. Roll 1 tablespoon scoops of the mixture into balls. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">Make the dough: Add the rice flour to a medium bowl. Gradually add the water and mix with your hands until the dough comes together. </step>
    <step num="2">On a lightly floured surface, turn out the dough. Shape into a ball and cut in half. Roll the dough into 2 logs, then cut into about 16 2-3-ounce (55G -85G) portions. </step>
    <step num="3">Flatten a dough portion in your palm and add a sesame ball to the center. Encase the filling with the dough and roll into a ball. Repeat with the remaining ingredients. </step>
    <step num="4">Bring a large pot of water to boil. Add the sugar and osmanthus flower. Drop the dumplings into the boiling water. Gently stir so they don’t stick to the bottom of the pot. Cook until the dumplings float to the surface, then remove from the pot. </step>
    <step num="5">Serve the dumplings in a bowl with the cooking liquid. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the filling: In a medium bowl, combine the ground black sesame seeds, powdered sugar and melted butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Mix until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Roll 1 tablespoon scoops of the mixture into balls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Make the dough: Add the rice flour to a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Gradually add the water and mix with your hands until the dough comes together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">On a lightly floured surface, turn out the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Shape into a ball and cut in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Roll the dough into 2 logs, then cut into about 16 2-3-ounce (55G -85G) portions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Flatten a dough portion in your palm and add a sesame ball to the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Encase the filling with the dough and roll into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Repeat with the remaining ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Bring a large pot of water to boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the sugar and osmanthus flower. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Drop the dumplings into the boiling water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Gently stir so they don’t stick to the bottom of the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Cook until the dumplings float to the surface, then remove from the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Serve the dumplings in a bowl with the cooking liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>