<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chocolate Mousse Cheesecake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chocolate-mousse-cheesecake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">20 ; chocolate sandwich cookies </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; brown sugar ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">7 tablespoons ; butter, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">32 oz ; cream cheese, softened ; (900 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 oz ; semi-sweet chocolate chips ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; cocoa powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ½ cups ; sugar ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 teaspoons ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">4 ; eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ½ cups ; heavy cream ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; powdered sugar ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">16 oz ; chocolate chips ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 cups ; heavy cream, hot ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Date Night</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/25338/low_1488475947.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/25338/mp4_720x1280/1488475947</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 300˚F (150˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Place cookies in plastic bag and crush them into a fine crumb using a rolling pin. Alternatively, a food processor can be used to crush the cookies. </step>
    <step num="2">Pour the cookie crumbs into a medium bowl with the melted butter and brown sugar. Mix until the crumbs take on the character of a coarse, wet sand. </step>
    <step num="3">Pour the crumbs into a 9-inch (23 cm) spring pan. Press the crumb firmly into the pan, making sure to coat the bottom evenly. </step>
    <step num="4">Once the crust has been formed, place it in the refrigerator to firm up. </step>
    <step num="5">Add cream cheese, melted chocolate, cocoa powder, and sugar to a large bowl and whisk, either by hand or with an electric mixer, until all the ingredients are incorporated. </step>
    <step num="6">NOTE: If mixing by hand, it is recommended to microwave the cream cheese slightly before whisking in order to soften it up. </step>
    <step num="7">Add vanilla extract and eggs, and continue to whisk until mixture is smooth and glossy. </step>
    <step num="8">In a separate bowl, combine heavy cream and powdered sugar. Whisk until the cream develops a mousse-y texture and soft peaks form. </step>
    <step num="9">Adding a small amount at a time, carefully fold in the whipped cream into the cream cheese batter, being careful not to let the air out of the fluffy mixture. Fold just until incorporated. </step>
    <step num="10">Once combined, pour the batter over the prepared cookie crust inside the springform pan. Use a spatula to smooth out the top. Give the pan a slight jiggle to release any large air bubbles that may be trapped in the batter. </step>
    <step num="11">Place the filled pan on top of a sheet of aluminium foil and fold the foil up the sides on the outside of the pan. Then place the wrapped pan into a larger baking pan or dish lined with 2 paper towels at the bottom. </step>
    <step num="12">NOTE: The aluminium foil will keep water from seeping into the bottom of the pan and the paper towels ensure that the heat is distributed evenly along the bottom of the pan. </step>
    <step num="13">Fill the larger pan with about 1 inch (2 ½ cm) of hot water. </step>
    <step num="14">Bake at 300˚F (150˚C) for 60-70 minutes--checking every 15-20 minutes to add more hot water to the larger dish, as necessary. </step>
    <step num="15">Once out of the oven, immediately run a small sharp knife around the outside of the cheesecake to release it from the pan. Allow the cheesecake to cool completely before removing it from the pan. </step>
    <step num="16">Prepare the ganache by combining chocolate chips with hot cream. Stir until chocolate is completely melted and ganache is smooth and glossy. </step>
    <step num="17">Pour ganache evenly over the cooled cheesecake. </step>
    <step num="18">Refrigerate the ganache covered cake for 30 minutes before cutting and serving. </step>
    <step num="19">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 300˚F (150˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Place cookies in plastic bag and crush them into a fine crumb using a rolling pin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Alternatively, a food processor can be used to crush the cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Pour the cookie crumbs into a medium bowl with the melted butter and brown sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Mix until the crumbs take on the character of a coarse, wet sand. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour the crumbs into a 9-inch (23 cm) spring pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Press the crumb firmly into the pan, making sure to coat the bottom evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Once the crust has been formed, place it in the refrigerator to firm up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add cream cheese, melted chocolate, cocoa powder, and sugar to a large bowl and whisk, either by hand or with an electric mixer, until all the ingredients are incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">NOTE: If mixing by hand, it is recommended to microwave the cream cheese slightly before whisking in order to soften it up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add vanilla extract and eggs, and continue to whisk until mixture is smooth and glossy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">In a separate bowl, combine heavy cream and powdered sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Whisk until the cream develops a mousse-y texture and soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Adding a small amount at a time, carefully fold in the whipped cream into the cream cheese batter, being careful not to let the air out of the fluffy mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Fold just until incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Once combined, pour the batter over the prepared cookie crust inside the springform pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Use a spatula to smooth out the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Give the pan a slight jiggle to release any large air bubbles that may be trapped in the batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Place the filled pan on top of a sheet of aluminium foil and fold the foil up the sides on the outside of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Then place the wrapped pan into a larger baking pan or dish lined with 2 paper towels at the bottom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">NOTE: The aluminium foil will keep water from seeping into the bottom of the pan and the paper towels ensure that the heat is distributed evenly along the bottom of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Fill the larger pan with about 1 inch (2 ½ cm) of hot water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Bake at 300˚F (150˚C) for 60-70 minutes--checking every 15-20 minutes to add more hot water to the larger dish, as necessary. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Once out of the oven, immediately run a small sharp knife around the outside of the cheesecake to release it from the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Allow the cheesecake to cool completely before removing it from the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Prepare the ganache by combining chocolate chips with hot cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Stir until chocolate is completely melted and ganache is smooth and glossy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Pour ganache evenly over the cooled cheesecake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Refrigerate the ganache covered cake for 30 minutes before cutting and serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>