<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Sweet Corn And Blueberry Swirl Ice Cream Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/sweet-corn-and-blueberry-swirl-ice-cream</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ears ; corn, shucked </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 cups ; heavy cream, divided ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; blueberry ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; granulated sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">14 oz ; condensed milk, 1 can, chilled ; (395 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105051/hls24_1533936577.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105051/landscape_720/1533936577</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Remove the corn kernels from the cob with a knife. Then, carefully break the cobs in half with your hands. </step>
    <step num="1">Place the corn kernels in a food processor. Pulse several times until coarsely chopped. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the chopped kernels, cobs, 1½ cups (360 ml) of cream, and the salt to a large saucepan. Stir to ensure the ingredients are well combined. Cover and cook over low heat for 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove the cream and corn mixture from the heat and chill in the refrigerator for at least 2 hours. </step>
    <step num="4">Combine the blueberries, sugar, and lemon juice in a medium bowl. Let sit at room temperature for 10 minutes, or until the berries appear juicy and vibrant, stirring occasionally. </step>
    <step num="5">Transfer the berry mixture to a food processor or blender and puree. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove the corn cobs from the chilled cream mixture. Pour the remaining corn cream through a sieve into a large bowl. Use the back of a spoon or spatula to press the solids to extract any remaining liquid. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the remaining heavy cream. Using an electric hand mixer, whip the cream mixture until soft peaks form. Fold in the condensed milk with a rubber spatula. </step>
    <step num="8">Pour half of the cream mixture into a 9x5-inch (23x13-cm) loaf pan. Top with half of the blueberry puree and use a knife to swirl it into the cream. </step>
    <step num="9">Top with the remaining cream and puree, then swirl the puree with a knife again. </step>
    <step num="10">Freeze for 3-4 hours before serving. If the ice cream is too solid to scoop, let sit at room temperature for 10-15 minutes before scooping. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Remove the corn kernels from the cob with a knife. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Then, carefully break the cobs in half with your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Place the corn kernels in a food processor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Pulse several times until coarsely chopped. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the chopped kernels, cobs, 1½ cups (360 ml) of cream, and the salt to a large saucepan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Stir to ensure the ingredients are well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cover and cook over low heat for 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove the cream and corn mixture from the heat and chill in the refrigerator for at least 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Combine the blueberries, sugar, and lemon juice in a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Let sit at room temperature for 10 minutes, or until the berries appear juicy and vibrant, stirring occasionally. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Transfer the berry mixture to a food processor or blender and puree. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove the corn cobs from the chilled cream mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Pour the remaining corn cream through a sieve into a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Use the back of a spoon or spatula to press the solids to extract any remaining liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the remaining heavy cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Using an electric hand mixer, whip the cream mixture until soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Fold in the condensed milk with a rubber spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Pour half of the cream mixture into a 9x5-inch (23x13-cm) loaf pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Top with half of the blueberry puree and use a knife to swirl it into the cream </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Top with the remaining cream and puree, then swirl the puree with a knife again. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Freeze for 3-4 hours before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">If the ice cream is too solid to scoop, let sit at room temperature for 10-15 minutes before scooping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>