<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>French Pepper Steak (Steak Au Poivre) Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/french-pepper-steak-steak-au-poivre</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">14 oz ; new york strip steak, or other steak of good quality </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; coarsely ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; vegetable oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; butter, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; cream ; (236 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">⅓ cup ; brandy or cognac ; (80 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 tablespoon ; dijon mustard </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">French</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Date Night</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/26653/low_1489683961.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/26653/mp4_720x1280/1489683961</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Liberally season steak with salt and coarsely ground black pepper, being sure to generously coat the entire surface of the meat. Using your hands, press the seasoning into the meat create an even coating. </step>
    <step num="1">Heat vegetable oil and 1 tablespoon of butter in a large skillet over medium-high heat until just smoking. Add the steak to the pan and sear on one side for 4 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Turn and sear the other side for another 4 minutes, for medium-rare. If steak has a fat-cap, be sure to sear it as well for 30 seconds to a minute. Once cooked to desired doneness, transfer steak to a cutting board to rest. </step>
    <step num="3">Reduce heat to medium and add brandy. Allow brandy to cook down for about 1 minute while using a whisk to scrape off any browned bits leftover in the bottom of the pan. </step>
    <step num="4">Once brandy has reduced by half, add cream and continue to whisk until combined. Add dijon mustard and butter and continue to cook until mixture begins to reduce and thicken, about 5-7 minutes. The final pan sauce should have a rich consistency and coat the back of a spoon. Reduce heat to low and reserve. </step>
    <step num="5">Once rested, slice steak into ½-inch (1.5cm) pieces. Pour cream sauce over the top and serve. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Liberally season steak with salt and coarsely ground black pepper, being sure to generously coat the entire surface of the meat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Using your hands, press the seasoning into the meat create an even coating. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Heat vegetable oil and 1 tablespoon of butter in a large skillet over medium-high heat until just smoking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the steak to the pan and sear on one side for 4 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Turn and sear the other side for another 4 minutes, for medium-rare. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">If steak has a fat-cap, be sure to sear it as well for 30 seconds to a minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Once cooked to desired doneness, transfer steak to a cutting board to rest. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Reduce heat to medium and add brandy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Allow brandy to cook down for about 1 minute while using a whisk to scrape off any browned bits leftover in the bottom of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Once brandy has reduced by half, add cream and continue to whisk until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add dijon mustard and butter and continue to cook until mixture begins to reduce and thicken, about 5-7 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">The final pan sauce should have a rich consistency and coat the back of a spoon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Reduce heat to low and reserve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Once rested, slice steak into ½-inch (1.5cm) pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Pour cream sauce over the top and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>