<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Magic Chocolate Ball Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/magic-chocolate-ball</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">8 oz ; milk chocolate, chopped or in chips ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ; brownies, prepared as desired </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">assorted berries, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">ice cream, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">8 oz ; dark chocolate, chopped ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; heavy cream ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">6-inch fillable ornament, 6-inch (15 cm) available at craft and baking stores or online </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Date Night</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/49963/low_1504030513.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/49963/mp4_720x1280/1504030513</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Melt the milk chocolate in the microwave in 20-second intervals, stirring until smooth. </step>
    <step num="1">Open the fillable ornament and coat the inside with a lightly oiled paper towel. Pour the melted chocolate into one of the halves. Close the ornament, rotating the ball so that the chocolate evenly coats the entire surface. Continue slowly rotating for 5 minutes. You may have to shake it a bit to get the chocolate to fill any holes. Place the ball in the freezer, then flip it after 2 minutes. Continue to flip it every few minutes, 2-3 more times. The chocolate should be set by then. Freeze for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Remove the ball from the freezer. Carefully open the ornament and remove the ball. Work quickly and avoid touching the ball for too long with your warm hands. If you want to be extra careful, immediately after unmolding, place the ball back in the freezer for a few minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Dip or run a flat-bottomed bowl in boiling water, then dry the entire bowl. Invert the bowl onto a flat surface, then place one side of the frozen chocolate ball on the hot bowl. </step>
    <step num="4">Twist back and forth with a gentle motion, making sure that you’re not applying too much pressure to the ball, as it is very fragile. Use a paper towel to help insulate the ball from your warm fingers. You may have to reheat and wipe off the bowl a few times as it will cool down a bit. Place the ball back in the freezer. </step>
    <step num="5">On a large plate, stack the brownies on top of each other, then surround them with berries. Place a scoop of ice cream on top of the brownies, then slowly place the chocolate ball on top. To cover up any holes or imperfections along the seam where the ball touches the plate, surround the base of the ball with more berries. </step>
    <step num="6">Microwave the dark chocolate with the heavy cream in 20-second intervals until smooth and glossy. </step>
    <step num="7">Pour the chocolate sauce over the ball in a circular motion. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Melt the milk chocolate in the microwave in 20-second intervals, stirring until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Open the fillable ornament and coat the inside with a lightly oiled paper towel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Pour the melted chocolate into one of the halves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Close the ornament, rotating the ball so that the chocolate evenly coats the entire surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Continue slowly rotating for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">You may have to shake it a bit to get the chocolate to fill any holes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Place the ball in the freezer, then flip it after 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Continue to flip it every few minutes, 2-3 more times. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">The chocolate should be set by then. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Freeze for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Remove the ball from the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Carefully open the ornament and remove the ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Work quickly and avoid touching the ball for too long with your warm hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">If you want to be extra careful, immediately after unmolding, place the ball back in the freezer for a few minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Dip or run a flat-bottomed bowl in boiling water, then dry the entire bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Invert the bowl onto a flat surface, then place one side of the frozen chocolate ball on the hot bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Twist back and forth with a gentle motion, making sure that you’re not applying too much pressure to the ball, as it is very fragile. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Use a paper towel to help insulate the ball from your warm fingers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">You may have to reheat and wipe off the bowl a few times as it will cool down a bit. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Place the ball back in the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">On a large plate, stack the brownies on top of each other, then surround them with berries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Place a scoop of ice cream on top of the brownies, then slowly place the chocolate ball on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">To cover up any holes or imperfections along the seam where the ball touches the plate, surround the base of the ball with more berries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Microwave the dark chocolate with the heavy cream in 20-second intervals until smooth and glossy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Pour the chocolate sauce over the ball in a circular motion. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>