<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>How To Make Handmade Pasta Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/fresh-pasta-dough</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 pinch ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">6 ; large egg yolks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; extra virgin olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 cups ; '00' grade pasta flour, plus more for dusting ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 pinch ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">5 ; large egg yolks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 tablespoon ; extra virgin olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; semolina flour ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 cup ; all-purpose flour, or '00' flour ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 pinch ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">6 ; large egg yolks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 tablespoon ; extra virgin olive oil </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Italian</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/103440/hls24_1532738104.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/103440/landscape_720/1532738104</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">On a clean, sturdy work surface, turn out your chosen flour(s) and salt and make a large well in the middle with your hands. </step>
    <step num="1">Whisk the eggs, egg yolks, and olive oil together in a medium bowl until combined, then pour the mixture into the well. </step>
    <step num="2">Using the same fork, whisk the eggs, slowly incorporating more and more flour into the eggs by moving your fork along the edges of the well. </step>
    <step num="3">Once almost all of the flour is incorporated, start bringing the dough together with your hands. (The dough should be malleable, but not sticky--add more flour if the dough is sticking too much to your hands or the surface. Alternatively, if it’s too dry and tough, whisk another egg with 1 tablespoon of water and use your hand to sprinkle some of the mixture over the dough, continuing to do so until the dough is easier to knead.) </step>
    <step num="4">Knead the dough for 7-10 minutes, until the dough is smooth and elastic. When you poke the dough, it should spring back. </step>
    <step num="5">Wrap the dough in plastic wrap and let rest at room temperature for 30 minutes to an hour, or until the dough does not spring back when poked. </step>
    <step num="6">Unwrap the dough and cut into 8 equal pieces so that it’s easier to work with. Take 1 piece and wrap the rest in the plastic wrap so that they don’t dry out. </step>
    <step num="7">Lightly flour your work surface, and begin rolling out the piece of dough into one long piece. Then, fold the top third down, and the bottom third over that, like a letter. Rotate the dough 90˚ and roll the piece back into a long shape. This helps form a more even rectangular shape and makes the dough a little bit easier to work with. </step>
    <step num="8">Continue rolling out the dough until it is very thin. When you lift the dough, you should be able to see your hands through it. </step>
    <step num="9">Fold the top and bottom of the rectangle to meet in the middle, then fold over again--this will make the dough easier to cut. Cut the dough to your ideal shape. Loosen or unravel the cut dough immediately, so it doesn’t stick, sprinkle with a bit of extra flour, or semolina, if using. Let the pasta sit out for about 30 minutes to dry out slightly. </step>
    <step num="10">Bring a large pot of heavily salted water to a boil. Add the pasta and stir to ensure it doesn’t clump. Cook for 2-3 minutes, or 30 seconds to 1 minute after the pasta comes to the surface (fresh pasta will cook much faster than dried pasta!) </step>
    <step num="11">Take out a noodle and taste for doneness. Once cooked to your liking, remove the pasta from the water, being sure to save at least 1 cup (240 ML) of the pasta cooking water. </step>
    <step num="12">Add the cooked pasta into your preferred sauce and stir to coat, adding some of the reserved pasta water if needed to add a bit of body and silkiness to the sauce. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">On a clean, sturdy work surface, turn out your chosen flour(s) and salt and make a large well in the middle with your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Whisk the eggs, egg yolks, and olive oil together in a medium bowl until combined, then pour the mixture into the well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Using the same fork, whisk the eggs, slowly incorporating more and more flour into the eggs by moving your fork along the edges of the well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Once almost all of the flour is incorporated, start bringing the dough together with your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">(The dough should be malleable, but not sticky--add more flour if the dough is sticking too much to your hands or the surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Alternatively, if it’s too dry and tough, whisk another egg with 1 tablespoon of water and use your hand to sprinkle some of the mixture over the dough, continuing to do so until the dough is easier to knead.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Knead the dough for 7-10 minutes, until the dough is smooth and elastic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">When you poke the dough, it should spring back. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Wrap the dough in plastic wrap and let rest at room temperature for 30 minutes to an hour, or until the dough does not spring back when poked. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Unwrap the dough and cut into 8 equal pieces so that it’s easier to work with. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Take 1 piece and wrap the rest in the plastic wrap so that they don’t dry out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Lightly flour your work surface, and begin rolling out the piece of dough into one long piece. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Then, fold the top third down, and the bottom third over that, like a letter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Rotate the dough 90˚ and roll the piece back into a long shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">This helps form a more even rectangular shape and makes the dough a little bit easier to work with. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Continue rolling out the dough until it is very thin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">When you lift the dough, you should be able to see your hands through it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Fold the top and bottom of the rectangle to meet in the middle, then fold over again--this will make the dough easier to cut. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Cut the dough to your ideal shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Loosen or unravel the cut dough immediately, so it doesn’t stick, sprinkle with a bit of extra flour, or semolina, if using. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Let the pasta sit out for about 30 minutes to dry out slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Bring a large pot of heavily salted water to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add the pasta and stir to ensure it doesn’t clump. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Cook for 2-3 minutes, or 30 seconds to 1 minute after the pasta comes to the surface (fresh pasta will cook much faster than dried pasta!) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Take out a noodle and taste for doneness. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Once cooked to your liking, remove the pasta from the water, being sure to save at least 1 cup (240 ML) of the pasta cooking water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Add the cooked pasta into your preferred sauce and stir to coat, adding some of the reserved pasta water if needed to add a bit of body and silkiness to the sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>