<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Lardy Cake Monkey Bread Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/lardy-cake-monkey-bread</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 ⅛ cups ; white bread flour, plus more for kneading ; (500 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 teaspoons ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, at room temperature. substitute with lard ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">⅞ cup ; milk, warm ; (200 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 ½ teaspoons ; active dry yeast ; (10 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 ; large eggs, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; raisin ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">⅞ cup ; strong black tea, hot ; (200 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ cup ; cream cheese ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ cup ; caster sugar, for coating ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">⅜ cup ; icing sugar ; (65 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ cup ; cream cheese ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 tablespoons ; milk </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">British</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Brunch</category>
    <category num="4">Desserts</category>
    <category num="5">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="6">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32207/low_1495125450.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32207/mp4_720x1280/1495125450</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, combine bread flour, sugar, and butter. Use your hands to mix, until the mixture is the texture of breadcrumbs. </step>
    <step num="1">In a small jar, stir together the milk, yeast, and eggs. Pour three quarters of the liquid mixture on top of the dry ingredients and mix together. Add liquid, a tablespoon at a time, until the mixture forms a soft dough. </step>
    <step num="2">Turn the mixture out onto a large, floured surface and knead for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Form the dough into a ball and place it in a clean mixing bowl covered with cling film. Set in a warm, dry place and let it rise for one hour. </step>
    <step num="4">Combine the raisins and the hot tea in a small bowl and let the mixture sit for 45 minutes, then drain the raisins. </step>
    <step num="5">When the dough has risen, divide it into 16 equal sized pieces. Flatten each piece into a disk about 8cm in diameter, and place a teaspoon of cream cheese and a teaspoon of raisins in the centre. Form the disk into a ball, with the sultanas and cream cheese in the centre. </step>
    <step num="6">Roll each ball in caster sugar, to coat. Place stuffed balls of dough into a cast iron skillet or round baking dish and cover with cling film. Set in a warm, dry place and let it rise for one hour. </step>
    <step num="7">Bake in a 350°F/180°C fan oven/gas mark 6 for 45 to 50 minutes, until the bread is cooked through and golden on top. </step>
    <step num="8">While the bread cooks, make the glaze. Stir together icing sugar, cream cheese, and milk to combine. If the mixture is too dry, add more milk a tablespoon at a time. </step>
    <step num="9">Drizzle it all over the monkey bread. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, combine bread flour, sugar, and butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Use your hands to mix, until the mixture is the texture of breadcrumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a small jar, stir together the milk, yeast, and eggs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Pour three quarters of the liquid mixture on top of the dry ingredients and mix together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add liquid, a tablespoon at a time, until the mixture forms a soft dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Turn the mixture out onto a large, floured surface and knead for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Form the dough into a ball and place it in a clean mixing bowl covered with cling film. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Set in a warm, dry place and let it rise for one hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Combine the raisins and the hot tea in a small bowl and let the mixture sit for 45 minutes, then drain the raisins. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">When the dough has risen, divide it into 16 equal sized pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Flatten each piece into a disk about 8cm in diameter, and place a teaspoon of cream cheese and a teaspoon of raisins in the centre. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Form the disk into a ball, with the sultanas and cream cheese in the centre. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Roll each ball in caster sugar, to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Place stuffed balls of dough into a cast iron skillet or round baking dish and cover with cling film. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Set in a warm, dry place and let it rise for one hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Bake in a 350°F/180°C fan oven/gas mark 6 for 45 to 50 minutes, until the bread is cooked through and golden on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">While the bread cooks, make the glaze. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Stir together icing sugar, cream cheese, and milk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">If the mixture is too dry, add more milk a tablespoon at a time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Drizzle it all over the monkey bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>