<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Churro Ice Cream Bowls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/churro-ice-cream-bowls</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¼ cup ; butter ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 tablespoons ; brown sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; water ; (235 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; flour ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; vanilla </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">4 ; eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">cooking spray </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">oil, for frying </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">cinnamon sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">ice cream </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">hot fudge, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">caramel sauce, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ; piping bag, with a small star tip </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 ; muffin tin, 6 to 12 cups </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Mexican</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="7">Fusion</category>
    <category num="8">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31948/low_1495124889.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31948/mp4_720x1280/1495124889</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a 1.5-quart saucepan over medium-high heat, add butter, brown sugar, salt, and water, and bring to a boil. </step>
    <step num="1">As soon as the butter has fully melted and the mixture begins to boil, reduce the heat to medium-low and add in flour. Using a wooden spoon, stir until the dough comes together to form a ball (about 1 minute). </step>
    <step num="2">Remove from heat and let cool for 5 minutes before proceeding to the next step (to prevent accidentally cooking the eggs). </step>
    <step num="3">Mix in the vanilla extract and add in the eggs, one at a time, being sure to fully incorporate each egg before adding the next. </step>
    <step num="4">Once all the eggs are incorporated, transfer it to a piping bag with a small star tip. </step>
    <step num="5">Invert a muffin tin and spray thoroughly with nonstick cooking spray. Pipe the dough around the inverted cups in spirals to form the bowls. Immediately transfer the tray to the freezer and freeze until solid (about 3 hours or overnight). </step>
    <step num="6">Heat oil in a deep pot to 350˚F (175˚C). Remove the muffin tin from the freezer and flex it to release the churro bowls (you may need to also use a butter knife under the bottom edge to initially release them). Return any extras to the freezer while you wait to fry. </step>
    <step num="7">Fry them in batches, until nicely browned, no more than 3 minutes at a time. Be sure to carefully turn them so they fry evenly. </step>
    <step num="8">Once desired color is reached, remove them from the oil to a paper towel-lined plate. Dab off any excess oil then roll them in cinnamon sugar. </step>
    <step num="9">Fill with your favorite ice cream and toppings. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a 1.5-quart saucepan over medium-high heat, add butter, brown sugar, salt, and water, and bring to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">As soon as the butter has fully melted and the mixture begins to boil, reduce the heat to medium-low and add in flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Using a wooden spoon, stir until the dough comes together to form a ball (about 1 minute). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Remove from heat and let cool for 5 minutes before proceeding to the next step (to prevent accidentally cooking the eggs). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Mix in the vanilla extract and add in the eggs, one at a time, being sure to fully incorporate each egg before adding the next. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Once all the eggs are incorporated, transfer it to a piping bag with a small star tip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Invert a muffin tin and spray thoroughly with nonstick cooking spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Pipe the dough around the inverted cups in spirals to form the bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Immediately transfer the tray to the freezer and freeze until solid (about 3 hours or overnight). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Heat oil in a deep pot to 350˚F (175˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Remove the muffin tin from the freezer and flex it to release the churro bowls (you may need to also use a butter knife under the bottom edge to initially release them). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Return any extras to the freezer while you wait to fry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Fry them in batches, until nicely browned, no more than 3 minutes at a time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Be sure to carefully turn them so they fry evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Once desired color is reached, remove them from the oil to a paper towel-lined plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Dab off any excess oil then roll them in cinnamon sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Fill with your favorite ice cream and toppings. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>