<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>How To Make Homemade Sourdough Bread Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/how-to-make-homemade-sourdough-bread</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; warm water ; (470 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ¼ teaspoons ; active dry yeast, 1 packet </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 ½ cups ; flour ; (440 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 cups ; flour ; (500 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 teaspoons ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ¼ cups ; water ; (295 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; starter, stir before using ; (260 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Sides</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/29845/low_1492809315.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/29845/mp4_720x1280/1492809315</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a glass bowl, add water and yeast. Mix the yeast into the water and let it sit for a couple minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Add in the rest of the ingredients for the starter. Mix well until everything is fully incorporated. </step>
    <step num="2">Wrap the bowl with clear wrap, making sure not to tightly seal the bowl. Let the starter breathe a little and keep it in a dark place at room temperature. Stir every 12 hours until making the dough. The starter will rise and shrink each day and you should see bubbles, letting you know that the yeast is being activated! </step>
    <step num="3">On day 5, combine all ingredients into a bowl, and knead for 10 minutes on low if using a machine; if kneading by hand, knead for 20 minutes until dough is stretchy yet doesn’t stick to your hands. </step>
    <step num="4">While the dough is kneading, store your starter for future use. Your starter will last forever as long as you maintain and care for it. It can stay in the fridge and be fed once a week with a teaspoon of sugar. To replenish your starter, simply add 1 cup of flour (125g) and ½ cup of water (120ml), mix, and place it back in the fridge. Leave it out overnight to get to room temperature before preparing the dough. </step>
    <step num="5">Place kneaded dough into a large floured bowl with a towel over the top, then sprinkle flour and let it rise for 12 hours. </step>
    <step num="6">Place risen dough onto a floured board and knead for a few minutes. Place it into a floured proofing basket or a medium bowl, sprinkle flour and let it rise for another 4 hours. </step>
    <step num="7">Preheat oven to 480°F (250°C). </step>
    <step num="8">Flip the dough onto a parchment paper, and transfer the dough and paper into a large cast-iron dutch oven. </step>
    <step num="9">Score the top of the bread. </step>
    <step num="10">Place the lid on top and bake for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="11">Take the lid off and bake for another 15 minutes or until the crust is golden brown. </step>
    <step num="12">Transfer onto a cooling rack and let it rest for an hour. Knock the bottom of the bread to listen for a hollow knock. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a glass bowl, add water and yeast. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Mix the yeast into the water and let it sit for a couple minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add in the rest of the ingredients for the starter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Mix well until everything is fully incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Wrap the bowl with clear wrap, making sure not to tightly seal the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Let the starter breathe a little and keep it in a dark place at room temperature. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Stir every 12 hours until making the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">The starter will rise and shrink each day and you should see bubbles, letting you know that the yeast is being activated! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">On day 5, combine all ingredients into a bowl, and knead for 10 minutes on low if using a machine; if kneading by hand, knead for 20 minutes until dough is stretchy yet doesn’t stick to your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">While the dough is kneading, store your starter for future use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Your starter will last forever as long as you maintain and care for it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">It can stay in the fridge and be fed once a week with a teaspoon of sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">To replenish your starter, simply add 1 cup of flour (125g) and ½ cup of water (120ml), mix, and place it back in the fridge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Leave it out overnight to get to room temperature before preparing the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Place kneaded dough into a large floured bowl with a towel over the top, then sprinkle flour and let it rise for 12 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Place risen dough onto a floured board and knead for a few minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Place it into a floured proofing basket or a medium bowl, sprinkle flour and let it rise for another 4 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Preheat oven to 480°F (250°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Flip the dough onto a parchment paper, and transfer the dough and paper into a large cast-iron dutch oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Score the top of the bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Place the lid on top and bake for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Take the lid off and bake for another 15 minutes or until the crust is golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Transfer onto a cooling rack and let it rest for an hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Knock the bottom of the bread to listen for a hollow knock. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>