<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Paprika-Spiced Chicken With Lemon Yogurt And Crispy Potatoes Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/paprika-spiced-chicken-with-lemon-yogurt-and-crispy-potatoes</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">6 oz ; boneless, skinless chicken breast, 4 pieces, pounded to 1/2 inch (1 cm) thickness ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 teaspoons ; smoked sweet paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">fine sea salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">freshly ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">5 tablespoons ; olive oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 teaspoons ; dijon mustard, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 clove ; garlic, grated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; lemon, zested, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 lb ; fingerling potato, halved ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¾ cup ; whole milk greek yogurt ; (185 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 tablespoons ; fresh parsley, chopped, extra to garnish, to taste </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
    <category num="2">Date Night</category>
    <category num="3">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/76288/hls24_1517533692.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/76288/landscape_720/1517533692</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Season the chicken breasts with paprika, salt, and pepper. Place in a shallow dish and add 2 tablespoons of the oil, 1 teaspoon of the mustard, the garlic, and half the lemon zest. </step>
    <step num="2">Toss until the chicken breasts are fully coated, then cover the dish and marinate at least 30 minutes, up to overnight. </step>
    <step num="3">On a baking sheet, toss the potato halves with 1 tablespoon of the olive oil. Season with salt and pepper and roast until tender and golden, 25 to 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Heat 1 tablespoon of oil in a large skillet over medium-high. Remove the chicken breasts from the marinade, and working in two batches, cook until golden brown on one side, 6 to 8 minutes. Flip each breast and continue to cook until the chicken is cooked through, 2 to 4 minutes longer. Transfer to a serving platter and repeat with the remaining oil and breasts. </step>
    <step num="5">In a small bowl, stir together the yogurt with the remaining 1 teaspoon mustard, lemon zest, salt, pepper and the parsley. </step>
    <step num="6">Serve the chicken with the yogurt and potato wedges. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Season the chicken breasts with paprika, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Place in a shallow dish and add 2 tablespoons of the oil, 1 teaspoon of the mustard, the garlic, and half the lemon zest. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Toss until the chicken breasts are fully coated, then cover the dish and marinate at least 30 minutes, up to overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">On a baking sheet, toss the potato halves with 1 tablespoon of the olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Season with salt and pepper and roast until tender and golden, 25 to 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Heat 1 tablespoon of oil in a large skillet over medium-high. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove the chicken breasts from the marinade, and working in two batches, cook until golden brown on one side, 6 to 8 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Flip each breast and continue to cook until the chicken is cooked through, 2 to 4 minutes longer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Transfer to a serving platter and repeat with the remaining oil and breasts. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a small bowl, stir together the yogurt with the remaining 1 teaspoon mustard, lemon zest, salt, pepper and the parsley. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Serve the chicken with the yogurt and potato wedges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>