<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Curry Sticky Rice Stuffed With Short Rib By Chef JJ Johnson Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/curry-sticky-rice-stuffed-with-short-rib-by-chef-jj-johnson</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 cups ; sticky rice, uncooked ; (600 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">warm water, for soaking </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 cups ; unsweetened coconut milk, canned ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ½ tablespoons ; curry powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; lime zest, about 2 limes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 lb ; boneless short ribs, cut into 3 inch (7 1/2 cm) pieces ; (910 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 tablespoons ; canola oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ; jalepeno, seeded and roughly chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 ; bay leaves </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 sprigs ; fresh thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">5 sprigs ; fresh parsley </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">⅔ cup ; dry red wine ; (160 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 ½ cups ; beef stock ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">⅓ cup ; orange juice, freshly squeezed ; (80 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">2 ; cinnamon sticks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">1 tablespoon ; sesame seeds </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">lime wedge, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Indian</category>
    <category num="1">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="2">Lunch</category>
    <category num="3">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/119686/hls24_1544752794.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/119686/landscape_720/1544752794</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Add the rice to a large nonreactive bowl that holds at least double the volume of the rice. Cover the rice by 2-3 inches (5- 7 ½ cm) with warm water and soak for 2 hours. </step>
    <step num="1">Drain the rice and transfer to a steamer basket lined with cheesecloth. Set the steamer basket over a large pot with several inches of boiling water. </step>
    <step num="2">Cover and steam the rice for 30 minutes, or until shiny and tender. Be careful that the pot doesn’t run dry during steaming; add more water if necessary. </step>
    <step num="3">While the rice steams, pour the coconut milk into a large heavy pot over medium heat and bring to a simmer. Make sure it does not boil. </step>
    <step num="4">Once the coconut milk is simmering, add the sugar, curry powder, lime zest, and salt, and whisk to completely dissolve the sugar and salt in the hot coconut milk. </step>
    <step num="5">When the sticky rice is done, turn it out into a large dish and use a wooden spoon to mix in the coconut milk mixture. Let stand, covered, for 30 minutes-1 hour to allow the flavors to melt. </step>
    <step num="6">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </step>
    <step num="7">Season the short ribs all over with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="8">Heat the canola oil in a large Dutch oven over high heat. Working in batches, sear the short ribs on all sides until golden brown, 5-6 minutes. Remove from the pot and set aside. </step>
    <step num="9">To the Dutch oven, add the jalapeño, bay leaves, thyme, and parsley, and cook until fragrant, 1-2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="10">Deglaze the pan with the red wine, scraping any browned bits from the bottom of the pot, then add the beef stock and orange juice. </step>
    <step num="11">Return the short ribs back to the pan. Cover and braise in the oven for 3 hours, until the meat pulls apart easily with a fork. Set aside to cool slightly, then shred the short ribs with 2 forks. </step>
    <step num="12">Using a 3-inch square mold, add a scoop of rice to the mold and spread in an even layer. Scoop in a layer of short rib, then cover with more rice. Garnish with sesame seeds. Unmold the rice and repeat with the remaining ingredients. </step>
    <step num="13">Serve with lime wedges. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Add the rice to a large nonreactive bowl that holds at least double the volume of the rice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cover the rice by 2-3 inches (5- 7 ½ cm) with warm water and soak for 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Drain the rice and transfer to a steamer basket lined with cheesecloth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set the steamer basket over a large pot with several inches of boiling water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Cover and steam the rice for 30 minutes, or until shiny and tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Be careful that the pot doesn’t run dry during steaming; add more water if necessary. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">While the rice steams, pour the coconut milk into a large heavy pot over medium heat and bring to a simmer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Make sure it does not boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Once the coconut milk is simmering, add the sugar, curry powder, lime zest, and salt, and whisk to completely dissolve the sugar and salt in the hot coconut milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">When the sticky rice is done, turn it out into a large dish and use a wooden spoon to mix in the coconut milk mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Let stand, covered, for 30 minutes-1 hour to allow the flavors to melt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Season the short ribs all over with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Heat the canola oil in a large Dutch oven over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Working in batches, sear the short ribs on all sides until golden brown, 5-6 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove from the pot and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">To the Dutch oven, add the jalapeño, bay leaves, thyme, and parsley, and cook until fragrant, 1-2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Deglaze the pan with the red wine, scraping any browned bits from the bottom of the pot, then add the beef stock and orange juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Return the short ribs back to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Cover and braise in the oven for 3 hours, until the meat pulls apart easily with a fork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Set aside to cool slightly, then shred the short ribs with 2 forks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Using a 3-inch square mold, add a scoop of rice to the mold and spread in an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Scoop in a layer of short rib, then cover with more rice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Garnish with sesame seeds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Unmold the rice and repeat with the remaining ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Serve with lime wedges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>