<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Easy Weeknight Instant Pot Lasagna</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/instant-pot-lasagna</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ lb ; ground beef ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ; medium white onion, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">4 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 teaspoons ; dried oregano </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ teaspoon ; red pepper flakes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; marinara sauce ; (520 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; whole milk ricotta cheese ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ½ cups ; low-moisture mozzarella, divided ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¾ cup ; grated parmesan cheese, divided ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; fresh parsley, minced, loosely packed ; (35 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ; large egg, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 teaspoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">10 ; lasagna noodles, uncooked </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 cup ; water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">instant pot </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">springform pan, 7 inch (17 cm) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Italian</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Date Night</category>
    <category num="4">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/125214/hls24_1550626077.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/125214/landscape_720/1550626077</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Set the Instant-Pot to sauté. Add the ground beef and cook for 5-6 minutes, until no longer pink. Add the onion, garlic, salt, oregano, and red pepper flakes and cook for 3-4 minutes more, until the onions are translucent. Add the tomato sauce and stir to combine, then carefully remove the insert from the Instant-Pot. Let cool for 5 minutes, then transfer the tomato sauce to a bowl and wash and dry the insert. </step>
    <step num="1">In a medium bowl, combine the ricotta, 1 cup (100 G) of mozzarella, ½ cup (55 G) of Parmesan, the parsley, and egg. Mix well. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the olive oil to a 7-inch (17 cm) springform pan and brush in an even layer over the bottom. </step>
    <step num="3">Arrange a layer of lasagna noodles on the bottom of the pan, breaking the noodles to fit if necessary. Top with a layer of sauce, then half of the ricotta mixture. Add another layer of noodles, sauce, and the rest of the ricotta. Finish with the remaining noodles and sauce. Cover the pan tightly with foil. </step>
    <step num="4">Return the insert to the Instant-Pot and pour in the water. Place pan with the lasagna on a steamer rack trivet and carefully lower into the pot. Cover with the lid and twist to lock. Turn the steam valve to “sealing”. Set to high pressure and cook for 24 minutes (it will take about 5 minutes to heat and pressurize). </step>
    <step num="5">Once the cook time is finished, vent naturally for 15 minutes, then turn the quick release steam valve to “venting” and when the float valve has fully dropped, open the pressure cooker and carefully lift out the lasagna. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove the foil and sprinkle top of the lasagna with the remaining ½ cup (50 G) mozzarella and ¼ cup (25 G) Parmesan. </step>
    <step num="7">Turn the broiler to high. Broil the lasagna for 2-4 minutes, until the cheese on top is melted and golden brown. </step>
    <step num="8">Let the lasagna cool for 10 minutes, then place on a serving plate and carefully release the springform. Slice and serve. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Set the Instant-Pot to sauté. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the ground beef and cook for 5-6 minutes, until no longer pink. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the onion, garlic, salt, oregano, and red pepper flakes and cook for 3-4 minutes more, until the onions are translucent. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the tomato sauce and stir to combine, then carefully remove the insert from the Instant-Pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Let cool for 5 minutes, then transfer the tomato sauce to a bowl and wash and dry the insert. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In a medium bowl, combine the ricotta, 1 cup (100 G) of mozzarella, ½ cup (55 G) of Parmesan, the parsley, and egg. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Mix well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the olive oil to a 7-inch (17 cm) springform pan and brush in an even layer over the bottom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Arrange a layer of lasagna noodles on the bottom of the pan, breaking the noodles to fit if necessary. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Top with a layer of sauce, then half of the ricotta mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add another layer of noodles, sauce, and the rest of the ricotta. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Finish with the remaining noodles and sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cover the pan tightly with foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Return the insert to the Instant-Pot and pour in the water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Place pan with the lasagna on a steamer rack trivet and carefully lower into the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cover with the lid and twist to lock. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Turn the steam valve to “sealing”. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Set to high pressure and cook for 24 minutes (it will take about 5 minutes to heat and pressurize). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Once the cook time is finished, vent naturally for 15 minutes, then turn the quick release steam valve to “venting” and when the float valve has fully dropped, open the pressure cooker and carefully lift out the lasagna. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Remove the foil and sprinkle top of the lasagna with the remaining ½ cup (50 G) mozzarella and ¼ cup (25 G) Parmesan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Turn the broiler to high. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Broil the lasagna for 2-4 minutes, until the cheese on top is melted and golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Let the lasagna cool for 10 minutes, then place on a serving plate and carefully release the springform. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Slice and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>