<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Berry-Stuffed French Toast For Two Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/berry-stuffed-french-toast-for-two</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; raspberry ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; blackberry ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; maple syrup, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; black raspberry liqueur </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 oz ; cream cheese, softened ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 slices ; brioche bread </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; whole milk ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; large egg, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 tablespoons ; black raspberry liqueur </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 tablespoons ; butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ cup ; heavy cream ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 tablespoon ; maple syrup </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">French</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="3">Brunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98222/hls24_1528824955.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98222/landscape_720/1528824955</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the filling: Add the raspberries, blackberries, black raspberry liqueur, and 1 tablespoon of maple syrup to a large bowl. Stir and let sit for 10 minutes for the berries to macerate. </step>
    <step num="1">In a medium bowl, mix together the cream cheese and remaining tablespoon of maple syrup until smooth. </step>
    <step num="2">Spread the filling evenly over the 4 slices of bread. Arrange some of the berries on 2 slices of the bread and top with the other slices of bread. Press to seal the pieces together. </step>
    <step num="3">In a shallow dish, whisk together the milk, egg, black raspberry liqueur, and salt. </step>
    <step num="4">Melt the butter on a griddle or in a large skillet over medium heat. Quickly dip both sides of the bread pockets in the milk mixture, then transfer to the pan and fry on each side for about 3 minutes, until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="5">In a large bowl, beat the heavy cream until soft peaks form. Add the maple syrup and continue beating until the cream holds medium peaks. </step>
    <step num="6">Serve the stuffed French toast with a dollop of maple whipped cream and a scoop of macerated berries with their soaking liquid. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the filling: Add the raspberries, blackberries, black raspberry liqueur, and 1 tablespoon of maple syrup to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Stir and let sit for 10 minutes for the berries to macerate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a medium bowl, mix together the cream cheese and remaining tablespoon of maple syrup until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Spread the filling evenly over the 4 slices of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Arrange some of the berries on 2 slices of the bread and top with the other slices of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Press to seal the pieces together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a shallow dish, whisk together the milk, egg, black raspberry liqueur, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Melt the butter on a griddle or in a large skillet over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Quickly dip both sides of the bread pockets in the milk mixture, then transfer to the pan and fry on each side for about 3 minutes, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a large bowl, beat the heavy cream until soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the maple syrup and continue beating until the cream holds medium peaks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Serve the stuffed French toast with a dollop of maple whipped cream and a scoop of macerated berries with their soaking liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>