<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>How To Make Vegan Kimchi Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/how-to-make-kimchi</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 lb ; green cabbage, savoy or napa ; (910 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; coarse salt ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">4 ; green onions </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; ginger, 2-inch (5 cm) piece </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">6 cloves ; garlic </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; daikon radish ; (4 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; white rice ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; water, plus more as needed ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 tablespoons ; soy sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 tablespoon ; vegan sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 tablespoon ; gochugaru </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Korean</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Healthy</category>
    <category num="3">Vegan</category>
    <category num="4">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="5">Sides</category>
    <category num="6">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/104112/hls24_1533243731.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/104112/landscape_720/1533243731</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Cut the head of cabbage in half lengthwise and slice off the ends. Quarter lengthwise, then slice crosswise into 2-inch (5 cm) pieces. </step>
    <step num="1">Place the cabbage and salt in a large bowl. Using your hands, massage the salt into the cabbage until it starts to soften a bit. Cover with a kitchen towel and let stand for 1-2 hours. Rinse the cabbage thoroughly under cold water, then let drain in a colander. </step>
    <step num="2">Meanwhile, chop the green onions into 1-inch (2 cm) pieces. </step>
    <step num="3">Peel the ginger and garlic. </step>
    <step num="4">Cut the daikon radish into matchsticks. </step>
    <step num="5">Combine the rice, water, garlic, ginger, and soy sauce in a mason jar or medium bowl. Use an immersion blender or standing blender to make a smooth paste. Mix in the sugar and gochugaru, starting with 1 tablespoon for a mild flavor and up to 5 tablespoons to make it spicier. </step>
    <step num="6">Gently squeeze any remaining water from the cabbage and transfer to a large bowl, along with the green onions and daikon. Toss to combine. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the seasoning paste to the bowl. Wearing gloves if you’d like to protect your hands from stings, stains, and smells, gently massage the paste into the vegetables until they are thoroughly coated. </step>
    <step num="8">Pack the kimchi into a large jar, pressing down until the seasoning paste rises to cover the vegetables and leaving at least 1 inch (2 ½ cm) of space at the top. Seal the jar with the lid. </step>
    <step num="9">Eat the kimchi right away or, to ferment, let the jar stand in a dark place at room temperature for 2-14 days. You may see bubbles inside and liquid may seep out of the jar; to be safe, place a bowl or plate under the jar to catch any overflow. Check the kimchi once a day. When it reaches your desired flavor, transfer the jar to the refrigerator. Eat right away, or let sit for another week or 2 for the flavors to deepen. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Cut the head of cabbage in half lengthwise and slice off the ends. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Quarter lengthwise, then slice crosswise into 2-inch (5 cm) pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Place the cabbage and salt in a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Using your hands, massage the salt into the cabbage until it starts to soften a bit. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Cover with a kitchen towel and let stand for 1-2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Rinse the cabbage thoroughly under cold water, then let drain in a colander. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Meanwhile, chop the green onions into 1-inch (2 cm) pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Peel the ginger and garlic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Cut the daikon radish into matchsticks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Combine the rice, water, garlic, ginger, and soy sauce in a mason jar or medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Use an immersion blender or standing blender to make a smooth paste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Mix in the sugar and gochugaru, starting with 1 tablespoon for a mild flavor and up to 5 tablespoons to make it spicier. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Gently squeeze any remaining water from the cabbage and transfer to a large bowl, along with the green onions and daikon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Toss to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add the seasoning paste to the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Wearing gloves if you’d like to protect your hands from stings, stains, and smells, gently massage the paste into the vegetables until they are thoroughly coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Pack the kimchi into a large jar, pressing down until the seasoning paste rises to cover the vegetables and leaving at least 1 inch (2 ½ cm) of space at the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Seal the jar with the lid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Eat the kimchi right away or, to ferment, let the jar stand in a dark place at room temperature for 2-14 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">You may see bubbles inside and liquid may seep out of the jar; to be safe, place a bowl or plate under the jar to catch any overflow. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Check the kimchi once a day. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">When it reaches your desired flavor, transfer the jar to the refrigerator. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Eat right away, or let sit for another week or 2 for the flavors to deepen. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>