<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Carne Asada TacosWay by Gabriel Barajas (aka Mr. TacosWay) Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/carne-asada-tacos-way-with-gabriel-barajas-aka-mr-tacosway</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; ball tip sirloin ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 tablespoons ; vegetable oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; taco seasoning </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">16 ; corn tortillas </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ cups ; shredded monterey jack cheese ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; white onion, diced ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ cup ; fresh cilantro, chopped ; (20 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">4 ; avocados </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">3 ; serrano peppers </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 tablespoon ; fresh cilantro </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">3 cloves ; garlic </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ tablespoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ cup ; water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 cup ; dried red chili ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">4 ; stewed tomatilloes, plus 2 cups (480 ml) stewing liquid </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 ; stewed tomato, plus ½ cup (120 ml) stewing liquid </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">2 cloves ; garlic </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">¼ cup ; salt ; (60 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Mexican</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Lunch</category>
    <category num="4">Game Day</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/93859/hls24_1526084879.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/93859/landscape_720/1526084879</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">To make the guacamole, add the avocados, serrano peppers, cilantro, garlic, salt, and a bit of water to a blender. Blend until smooth, adding water as needed to thin it down. Transfer to a bowl and set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">To make the red sauce, add the dried chilies, stewed tomatillos in 2 cups (480 ml) of their stewing liquid, stewed tomato in ½ cup (120 ml) of its stewing liquid, garlic, and bit of salt in a blender. Blend until everything is well incorporated, adding more salt to taste. </step>
    <step num="2">Mix 1 teaspoon of salt into 1 tablespoon of taco seasoning and rub the seasoning onto both sides of the steak. </step>
    <step num="3">Cut the steak into thin strips, then cut into small pieces. </step>
    <step num="4">Add 1 tablespoon of oil to a large griddle or cast iron pan over high heat. Once the oil is hot, add the steak and cook for 6-8 minutes or until the steak has browned on all sides. Move to the side of the griddle to keep warm. </step>
    <step num="5">Reduce the heat to medium/medium-high and add a bit more oil to the griddle. Place the tortillas on the griddle and top with a generous amount of cheese. On half of the tortillas, add some of the cooked steak, diced onion, cilantro, red sauce, and guacamole. </step>
    <step num="6">Place the other tortilla (cheese-side down) on top of the fillings. Serve. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">To make the guacamole, add the avocados, serrano peppers, cilantro, garlic, salt, and a bit of water to a blender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Blend until smooth, adding water as needed to thin it down. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Transfer to a bowl and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">To make the red sauce, add the dried chilies, stewed tomatillos in 2 cups (480 ml) of their stewing liquid, stewed tomato in ½ cup (120 ml) of its stewing liquid, garlic, and bit of salt in a blender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Blend until everything is well incorporated, adding more salt to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Mix 1 teaspoon of salt into 1 tablespoon of taco seasoning and rub the seasoning onto both sides of the steak. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cut the steak into thin strips, then cut into small pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add 1 tablespoon of oil to a large griddle or cast iron pan over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Once the oil is hot, add the steak and cook for 6-8 minutes or until the steak has browned on all sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Move to the side of the griddle to keep warm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Reduce the heat to medium/medium-high and add a bit more oil to the griddle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place the tortillas on the griddle and top with a generous amount of cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">On half of the tortillas, add some of the cooked steak, diced onion, cilantro, red sauce, and guacamole. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Place the other tortilla (cheese-side down) on top of the fillings. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>