<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Kaiserschmarren By Wolfgang Puck Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/kaiserschmarren-by-wolfgang-puck</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">8 ; large eggs, separated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; dark raisins ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">vanilla bean </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">6 tablespoons ; rum </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 cups ; crème fraîche ; (480 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 tablespoons ; all-purpose flour </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">kosher salt, pinch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ teaspoon ; cream of tartar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ½ cups ; granulated sugar ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">4 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, at room temperature, for brushing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">sugar, for coating </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ½ lb ; strawberry, small strawberries hulled or hulled and halved large berries, 4 cups total ; (630 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ ; vanilla bean, or 1/2 teaspoon vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">¼ cup ; orange juice ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">¼ cup ; granulated sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 tablespoon ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">star anise, whole, as desired </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">1 cup ; confectioners sugar, for serving ; (120 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">German</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32279/low_1495125504.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32279/mp4_720x1280/1495125504</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Position a rack in the center of the oven. Preheat the oven to 425°F (220°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Separate egg yolk and egg whites into 2 bowls. </step>
    <step num="2">Meanwhile, put the raisins and rum in a small bowl and steep for about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Put the crème fraîche, ½ cup sugar (100 G), egg yolks, raisins, and 1 tablespoon of the rum in a mixing bowl. Whisk until blended. Stir in the flour. </step>
    <step num="4">Put the egg whites in a large, clean mixing bowl. Add the cream of tartar and salt. With a hand-held electric mixer on medium speed, beat until thick and foamy. Then, still beating, gradually add 1 cup (200 G) of sugar. Continue beating until soft peaks form when the beaters are lifted out. </step>
    <step num="5">Drop a large scoop of the meringue onto the egg yolk batter. With a flexible rubber spatula, gently fold the whites into the batter to lighten it. Scoop the remaining meringue over the batter and gently fold it in. </step>
    <step num="6">Coat a medium ovenproof skillet with the butter. Sprinkle in sugar and shake and rotate to coat the butter. Tap out any excess. </step>
    <step num="7">Gently scrape the batter into the prepared skillet. Smooth the top. Bake in the preheated oven until puffed, golden brown on top, and springy to a gentle touch at its center, 10 to 12 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">While the batter bakes, in a nonreactive skillet stir together the berries, lemon juice, ¼ cup (50 G) sugar, orange juice and zest, vanilla, and star anise. Cook over medium-low heat, stirring to help the sugar dissolve and mashing a few of the berries to help thicken the sauce. </step>
    <step num="9">Divide the compote among serving plates. With a large serving spoon, scoop up large dollops of the Kaiserschmarren, distributing them evenly on top of the compote. Dust generously with confectioners sugar. Serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Position a rack in the center of the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Preheat the oven to 425°F (220°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Separate egg yolk and egg whites into 2 bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Meanwhile, put the raisins and rum in a small bowl and steep for about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Put the crème fraîche, ½ cup sugar (100 G), egg yolks, raisins, and 1 tablespoon of the rum in a mixing bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Whisk until blended. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Stir in the flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Put the egg whites in a large, clean mixing bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the cream of tartar and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">With a hand-held electric mixer on medium speed, beat until thick and foamy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Then, still beating, gradually add 1 cup (200 G) of sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Continue beating until soft peaks form when the beaters are lifted out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Drop a large scoop of the meringue onto the egg yolk batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">With a flexible rubber spatula, gently fold the whites into the batter to lighten it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Scoop the remaining meringue over the batter and gently fold it in. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Coat a medium ovenproof skillet with the butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Sprinkle in sugar and shake and rotate to coat the butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Tap out any excess. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Gently scrape the batter into the prepared skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Smooth the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Bake in the preheated oven until puffed, golden brown on top, and springy to a gentle touch at its center, 10 to 12 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">While the batter bakes, in a nonreactive skillet stir together the berries, lemon juice, ¼ cup (50 G) sugar, orange juice and zest, vanilla, and star anise. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Cook over medium-low heat, stirring to help the sugar dissolve and mashing a few of the berries to help thicken the sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Divide the compote among serving plates. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">With a large serving spoon, scoop up large dollops of the Kaiserschmarren, distributing them evenly on top of the compote. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Dust generously with confectioners sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>