<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Festive Stuffed Acorn Squash Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/festive-stuffed-acorn-squash</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ; acorn squashes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; olive oil, plus more for brushing and drizzling </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¾ cup ; wild rice, uncooked and rinsed ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ¼ cups ; vegetable broth, plus 2 tablespoons, divided ; (300 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; chili powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ teaspoon ; ground cumin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ½ teaspoons ; maple syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">5 oz ; cremini mushroom, quartered and sliced ; (140 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">5 oz ; shiitake mushroom, quartered and sliced ; (140 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ ; medium onion, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 teaspoon ; fresh rosemary, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 teaspoon ; fresh thyme, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">¼ cup ; white wine ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">2 cups ; kale, chopped ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">2 tablespoons ; pomegranate seeds </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Vegan</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Dinner</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/115839/hls24_1542396256.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/115839/landscape_720/1542396256</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Place the acorn squash stem-side up on a cutting board and cut in half. Scoop out the seeds and pulp, and transfer to a bowl. Separate the seeds from the pulp. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">Set the squash halves cut-side up on a baking sheet. Brush with olive oil and sprinkle with salt and pepper. Bake for 40 minutes, or until almost cooked through. </step>
    <step num="3">In a small pot, combine the wild rice and 1¼ cups (300 ml) vegetable broth, and bring to a boil. Once boiling, cover and reduce the heat to low. Simmer for 45 minutes, or until the liquid is absorbed and the rice is tender. </step>
    <step num="4">Rinse the squash seeds and dry on a dish towel (some residual moisture is okay). Transfer to a small bowl and add the chili powder, cumin, salt, and maple syrup. Mix until well-coated. </step>
    <step num="5">Remove the squash from the oven and move to one side of the baking sheet. Using parchment paper, make a tray for the squash seeds. Spread the squash seeds on the tray. </step>
    <step num="6">Bake for 15 minutes, stirring halfway through, until the squash is completely tender and the seeds are crispy. </step>
    <step num="7">Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat. Once the oil begins to shimmer, add the mushrooms and cook for 6-8 minutes, until they’ve released a good amount of liquid. </step>
    <step num="8">Add the onion and cook for 3-4 minutes, until semi-translucent. Add a drizzle of olive oil and the garlic, rosemary, and thyme, and cook for 3-4 minutes, until fragrant. Deglaze the pan with the white wine and cook until most of the liquid has evaporated. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the kale, salt, and pepper, and cook until the kale wilts and reduces in volume by about ¼. Add the remaining 2 tablespoons of vegetable broth and cook until kale is almost completely wilted and most of the liquid has evaporated. Stir in the wild rice and remove from the heat. </step>
    <step num="10">Fill each squash half with the mushroom mixture and garnish with the squash seeds and pomegranate seeds. (Save leftover squash seeds for snacking!) </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Place the acorn squash stem-side up on a cutting board and cut in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Scoop out the seeds and pulp, and transfer to a bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Separate the seeds from the pulp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Set the squash halves cut-side up on a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Brush with olive oil and sprinkle with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Bake for 40 minutes, or until almost cooked through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">In a small pot, combine the wild rice and 1¼ cups (300 ml) vegetable broth, and bring to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Once boiling, cover and reduce the heat to low. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Simmer for 45 minutes, or until the liquid is absorbed and the rice is tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Rinse the squash seeds and dry on a dish towel (some residual moisture is okay). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Transfer to a small bowl and add the chili powder, cumin, salt, and maple syrup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Mix until well-coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove the squash from the oven and move to one side of the baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Using parchment paper, make a tray for the squash seeds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Spread the squash seeds on the tray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Bake for 15 minutes, stirring halfway through, until the squash is completely tender and the seeds are crispy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Once the oil begins to shimmer, add the mushrooms and cook for 6-8 minutes, until they’ve released a good amount of liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Add the onion and cook for 3-4 minutes, until semi-translucent. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Add a drizzle of olive oil and the garlic, rosemary, and thyme, and cook for 3-4 minutes, until fragrant. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Deglaze the pan with the white wine and cook until most of the liquid has evaporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Add the kale, salt, and pepper, and cook until the kale wilts and reduces in volume by about ¼. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Add the remaining 2 tablespoons of vegetable broth and cook until kale is almost completely wilted and most of the liquid has evaporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Stir in the wild rice and remove from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Fill each squash half with the mushroom mixture and garnish with the squash seeds and pomegranate seeds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">(Save leftover squash seeds for snacking!) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>