<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Jewish Strawberry Jam And Chocolate Chip Mandelbrot As Made By Danielle Warren Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/jewish-strawberry-jam-and-chocolate-chip-mandelbrot-as-made-by-danielle-warren</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (375 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¾ cup ; granulated sugar ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 teaspoons ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; corn oil ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 cup ; strawberry jam, smooth, plus more for serving (optional) ; (325 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ cup ; semi-sweet chocolate chips, (optional) ; (90 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">cinnamon sugar, for topping </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/118231/hls24_1543972100.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/118231/landscape_720/1543972100</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, whisk together the flour, sugar, and baking powder. Add the corn oil, vanilla, and eggs, and stir with a rubber spatula until the dough starts to come together. Use your hands to finish mixing the dough until well combined and thick. </step>
    <step num="2">If making strawberry mandelbrot, wet your hands with water and shape half of the dough into a rough oval on the prepared baking sheets. Pinch the edges of the dough up to create a well. Spread the strawberry jam in the center of the dough. Flatten the remaining dough and place on top of the strawberry jam. Leave a bit of extra dough in the bowl to fill in the cracks. </step>
    <step num="3">If making chocolate chip mandelbrot, fold the chocolate chips into the dough. Wet your hands with water and shape the dough into a rough oval on the prepared baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="4">Bake the mandelbrot for 25-35 minutes, or until the edges are golden brown. </step>
    <step num="5">Let cool for 10 minutes, then transfer to a cutting board. Top with cinnamon sugar, if desired, then slice into 1-inch-wide pieces. </step>
    <step num="6">Serve with additional strawberry jam, whipped cream, coffee, or ice cream, if desired. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a large bowl, whisk together the flour, sugar, and baking powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the corn oil, vanilla, and eggs, and stir with a rubber spatula until the dough starts to come together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Use your hands to finish mixing the dough until well combined and thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">If making strawberry mandelbrot, wet your hands with water and shape half of the dough into a rough oval on the prepared baking sheets. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Pinch the edges of the dough up to create a well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Spread the strawberry jam in the center of the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Flatten the remaining dough and place on top of the strawberry jam. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Leave a bit of extra dough in the bowl to fill in the cracks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">If making chocolate chip mandelbrot, fold the chocolate chips into the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Wet your hands with water and shape the dough into a rough oval on the prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Bake the mandelbrot for 25-35 minutes, or until the edges are golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Let cool for 10 minutes, then transfer to a cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Top with cinnamon sugar, if desired, then slice into 1-inch-wide pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Serve with additional strawberry jam, whipped cream, coffee, or ice cream, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>