<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Easy Homemade Potato Gnocchi Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/easy-homemade-potato-gnocchi</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 ; medium russet potatoes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 teaspoon ; salt, plus more for the water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ½ cups ; all-purpose flour, extra to dust ; (190 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 tablespoons ; butter, for pan frying </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">sage leaves </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Lunch</category>
    <category num="6">Date Night</category>
    <category num="7">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="8">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/24412/low_1487698681.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/24412/mp4_720x1280/1487698681</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Add the potatoes to a large pot of cool salted water. Bring the water to a boil and cook for 20-25 minutes, or until a fork can easily pierce a potato. Drain the potatoes and set aside until cool enough to handle but still warm. </step>
    <step num="1">Using a peeler or your fingers, remove the skin from the potatoes. In a medium bowl, mash the potatoes until all lumps are gone. Add the salt and pepper and mix well. Make a well in the center of the potatoes and crack an egg into it. Whisk the eggs briefly. Then, using your hands, gently mix it into the potatoes until evenly distributed. </step>
    <step num="2">Put 1 cups of flour onto a clean surface and turn out the potato dough onto it, keeping the remaining ½ cup close by in case you need it. Working quickly and carefully, knead the dough, only incorporating as much flour as you need along the way until the dough loses stickiness and becomes more solid. Slice the dough into 4 parts. Roll out 1 part into a long rope, about 1 inch wide, cutting in half and working with 1 half at a time if the rope is becoming too long. Slice the rope into ½-inch squares and set aside on a lightly floured surface. Repeat with the remaining dough. </step>
    <step num="3">If desired, place a fork on your work surface and slide each gnocchi square from the base of the fork prongs to the top so they make a decorative shape. </step>
    <step num="4">Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil and add the gnocchi in batches, stirring gently once or twice to ensure they are not sticking. Boil until they float to the surface; after another 15-30 seconds in the water, remove. </step>
    <step num="5">In a pan over medium heat, melt butter and add the sage. Add the gnocchi and toss until lightly golden. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Add the potatoes to a large pot of cool salted water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Bring the water to a boil and cook for 20-25 minutes, or until a fork can easily pierce a potato. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Drain the potatoes and set aside until cool enough to handle but still warm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Using a peeler or your fingers, remove the skin from the potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a medium bowl, mash the potatoes until all lumps are gone. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the salt and pepper and mix well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Make a well in the center of the potatoes and crack an egg into it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Whisk the eggs briefly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Then, using your hands, gently mix it into the potatoes until evenly distributed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Put 1 cups of flour onto a clean surface and turn out the potato dough onto it, keeping the remaining ½ cup close by in case you need it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Working quickly and carefully, knead the dough, only incorporating as much flour as you need along the way until the dough loses stickiness and becomes more solid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Slice the dough into 4 parts. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Roll out 1 part into a long rope, about 1 inch wide, cutting in half and working with 1 half at a time if the rope is becoming too long. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Slice the rope into ½-inch squares and set aside on a lightly floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Repeat with the remaining dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">If desired, place a fork on your work surface and slide each gnocchi square from the base of the fork prongs to the top so they make a decorative shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil and add the gnocchi in batches, stirring gently once or twice to ensure they are not sticking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Boil until they float to the surface; after another 15-30 seconds in the water, remove. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">In a pan over medium heat, melt butter and add the sage. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add the gnocchi and toss until lightly golden. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>