<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Salmon Poke Bowl Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/salmon-poke-bowl</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; sushi rice ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; water, plus more for rinsing ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 tablespoons ; rice vinegar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ½ teaspoons ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">8 oz ; wild-caught, sushi-grade salmon fillet ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 tablespoons ; soy sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 tablespoons ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ ; avocado, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ ; cucumber, halved lengthwise and thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 tablespoons ; pickled ginger </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ; green onion, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">5 small sheets ; nori </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">¼ teaspoon ; toasted sesame seeds </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">¼ teaspoon ; black sesame seeds </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Seafood</category>
    <category num="2">Healthy</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Date Night</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97042/hls24_1528132507.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97042/landscape_720/1528132507</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Add the rice to a fine mesh strainer and submerge in a bowl filled with water. Shake the rice a few times to remove excess starch. </step>
    <step num="1">Transfer the rice to a medium pot and add 1 cup (240 ml) of water. Cover the pot and bring to a boil over medium-high heat. Once boiling, reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer for 10 minutes. Remove the pan from the heat and let stand for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Remove the lid and fluff the rice with a fork or rice paddle. Transfer the rice to a large bowl. </step>
    <step num="3">Mix together the rice vinegar, sugar, and salt and pour over the rice while still hot. Gently fold the rice to incorporate. Cover and set aside until ready to assemble the bowl. </step>
    <step num="4">Using a very sharp knife, gently slice the salmon fillet into ½-inch (1 cm) cubes. It may be easier to slice if you place the salmon in the freezer for a few minutes to help it firm up. </step>
    <step num="5">Just before assembly, place the salmon in a bowl and season with the soy sauce and lemon juice. </step>
    <step num="6">To assemble, place a few spoonfuls of rice into a medium bowl (use any leftover rice for another poke bowl or sushi). Top the rice with the seasoned salmon, avocado, cucumber, ginger, green onions, nori sheets, toasted sesame seeds, and black sesame seeds. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Add the rice to a fine mesh strainer and submerge in a bowl filled with water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Shake the rice a few times to remove excess starch. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Transfer the rice to a medium pot and add 1 cup (240 ml) of water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cover the pot and bring to a boil over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Once boiling, reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Remove the pan from the heat and let stand for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove the lid and fluff the rice with a fork or rice paddle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Transfer the rice to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Mix together the rice vinegar, sugar, and salt and pour over the rice while still hot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Gently fold the rice to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Cover and set aside until ready to assemble the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Using a very sharp knife, gently slice the salmon fillet into ½-inch (1 cm) cubes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">It may be easier to slice if you place the salmon in the freezer for a few minutes to help it firm up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Just before assembly, place the salmon in a bowl and season with the soy sauce and lemon juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">To assemble, place a few spoonfuls of rice into a medium bowl (use any leftover rice for another poke bowl or sushi). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Top the rice with the seasoned salmon, avocado, cucumber, ginger, green onions, nori sheets, toasted sesame seeds, and black sesame seeds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>