<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Truffle Shrimp Ravioli Pasta By Estrella Sunset &amp; Sweetfin Poké's Chef Dakota Weiss Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/truffle-shrimp-ravioli-by-estrella-sunset-sweetfin-poke-s-chef-dakota-weiss</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 cups ; 00 pasta flour ; (500 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; milk ; (70 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">10 yolks ; egg yolk ; 200 g </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ½ tablespoons ; extra virgin olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ lb ; shrimp, peeled and deveined ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 tablespoons ; cream cheese </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 tablespoons ; ricotta cheese </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; black truffle butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 tablespoon ; black truffle oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 tablespoons ; fresh chives, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 ; lemon, zested </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ; lemon, juiced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">6 oz ; hazelnuts, toasted ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">6 oz ; panko breadcrumbs ; (180 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">3 oz ; brown butter ; (85 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 tablespoon ; butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">¼ cup ; chicken stock ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">2 tablespoons ; shallot, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">1 tablespoon ; fresh chives, minced </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Italian</category>
    <category num="1">Seafood</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Date Night</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/24333/low_1487374126.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/24333/mp4_720x1280/1487374126</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the pasta by adding flour and a pinch of salt to the bowl of a food processor, pulse a few times. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the egg yolks, milk, and olive oil. </step>
    <step num="2">Run the food processor, adding additional milk or flour if the mixture is too wet or dry. Once it to starts to clump together and becomes a dough, let it get “worked” in the food processor for about 10 turns. </step>
    <step num="3">Take your pasta to a floured table surface and knead it with your hands until you start to get a shiny, smooth surface. Wrap in plastic and set it aside to rest, about 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Add all of the truffle shrimp mousse ingredients to a cleaned food processor and run until very smooth. </step>
    <step num="5">Transfer to piping bag and set aside in the refrigerator. </step>
    <step num="6">Begin rolling out the pasta dough by cutting off about an eighth of the dough ball and flattening with a rolling pin, until it forms a long rectangle about ¼ inch (6 mm) in thickness and is no wider than your pasta machine. </step>
    <step num="7">Run the dough strip through your pasta machine from the machine’s widest setting a few times until smooth. </step>
    <step num="8">Start rolling the dough through the settings, towards the most narrow, skipping no settings in between, rolling the dough through each setting twice. </step>
    <step num="9">NOTE: Cut the dough strip into smaller pieces if it becomes too long and unmanageable. Store finished strips under a damp cloth to keep pasta from drying out. </step>
    <step num="10">Use a circular cutter about 3 inches (7 cm) in diameter to cut ravioli. </step>
    <step num="11">Pipe about 1 tablespoon onto each circle (the amount will vary depending on the exact size of your circles). Egg wash the perimeter and join sides of the circle to form a half circle. Gently pinch dough together to seal ravioli. </step>
    <step num="12">Place prepared ravioli on a floured surface to prevent sticking, covered with a lightly moistened towel. </step>
    <step num="13">Egg wash the perimeter and join sides of the circle to form a half circle. Gently pinch dough together to seal ravioli. </step>
    <step num="14">Heat butter for the bread crumbs in a saucepan until milk solids begin to brown and it starts to smell nutty, then remove from heat. </step>
    <step num="15">Puree all bread crumb ingredients with the browned butter in food processor until it reaches a coarse sand-like texture. </step>
    <step num="16">Return bread crumbs to saucepan and toast until golden. Stir often to prevent burning. </step>
    <step num="17">Cook ravioli in salted boiling water 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="18">NOTE: Submerge in ice bath if not serving immediately. </step>
    <step num="19">For the glace, melt butter in saucepan. Add chicken stock and whisk together until simmering. Add shallots and chives and then immediately add ravioli. Continuously move the ravioli to warm and coat the with the glace, about 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="20">Serve topped with toasted hazelnut bread crumbs. </step>
    <step num="21">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the pasta by adding flour and a pinch of salt to the bowl of a food processor, pulse a few times. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the egg yolks, milk, and olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Run the food processor, adding additional milk or flour if the mixture is too wet or dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Once it to starts to clump together and becomes a dough, let it get “worked” in the food processor for about 10 turns. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Take your pasta to a floured table surface and knead it with your hands until you start to get a shiny, smooth surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Wrap in plastic and set it aside to rest, about 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add all of the truffle shrimp mousse ingredients to a cleaned food processor and run until very smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Transfer to piping bag and set aside in the refrigerator. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Begin rolling out the pasta dough by cutting off about an eighth of the dough ball and flattening with a rolling pin, until it forms a long rectangle about ¼ inch (6 mm) in thickness and is no wider than your pasta machine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Run the dough strip through your pasta machine from the machine’s widest setting a few times until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Start rolling the dough through the settings, towards the most narrow, skipping no settings in between, rolling the dough through each setting twice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">NOTE: Cut the dough strip into smaller pieces if it becomes too long and unmanageable. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Store finished strips under a damp cloth to keep pasta from drying out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Use a circular cutter about 3 inches (7 cm) in diameter to cut ravioli. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Pipe about 1 tablespoon onto each circle (the amount will vary depending on the exact size of your circles). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Egg wash the perimeter and join sides of the circle to form a half circle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Gently pinch dough together to seal ravioli. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Place prepared ravioli on a floured surface to prevent sticking, covered with a lightly moistened towel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Egg wash the perimeter and join sides of the circle to form a half circle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Gently pinch dough together to seal ravioli. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Heat butter for the bread crumbs in a saucepan until milk solids begin to brown and it starts to smell nutty, then remove from heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Puree all bread crumb ingredients with the browned butter in food processor until it reaches a coarse sand-like texture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Return bread crumbs to saucepan and toast until golden. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Stir often to prevent burning. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Cook ravioli in salted boiling water 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">NOTE: Submerge in ice bath if not serving immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">For the glace, melt butter in saucepan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Add chicken stock and whisk together until simmering. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Add shallots and chives and then immediately add ravioli. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Continuously move the ravioli to warm and coat the with the glace, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Serve topped with toasted hazelnut bread crumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>