<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>The Easiest Way To Make Great BBQ Ribs Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/the-easiest-way-to-make-great-bbbq-ribs</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; ketchup ; (480 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; brown sugar ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; molasses ; (85 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; apple cider vinegar ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; worcestershire sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 teaspoons ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 teaspoons ; smoked paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ cup ; dark brown sugar ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">3 tablespoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 teaspoons ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ½ tablespoons ; cumin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 ½ tablespoons ; onion powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ½ tablespoons ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 ½ tablespoons ; cayenne </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">2 teaspoons ; ground mustard </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 ½ tablespoons ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">4 lb ; baby back ribs ; (2 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">4 cups ; wood chips ; (355 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">BBQ</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Game Day</category>
    <category num="5">BBQ</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/136740/hls24_1561061384.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/136740/landscape_720/1561061384</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the smoke bombs: Add the wood chips to a bowl and cover with water. Let soak for 1 hour, then drain. Place 1 cup of the damp wood chips on a piece of aluminum foil and fold into a packet. Poke multiple holes in the top with a toothpick or fork. Repeat with the remaining wood chips, creating 4 packets total. </step>
    <step num="1">Make the sauce: Add the ketchup, brown sugar, molasses, apple cider vinegar, Worcestershire, salt, pepper, and smoked paprika to a small pot over medium heat, whisking to combine. Once the sauce begins to boil, reduce heat to low and simmer for 15 minutes. Remove from the heat and let cool to room temperature. </step>
    <step num="2">Make the rub: In a medium bowl, whisk together the brown sugar, salt, pepper, cumin, onion powder, paprika, cayenne, ground mustard, and garlic powder. </step>
    <step num="3">On a large cutting board, pat the ribs dry with paper towels. If necessary, remove the membrane on the bone-side of the ribs by using a paring knife to gently loosen and pulling it up in one sheet. </step>
    <step num="4">Generously season the ribs all over with the dry rub. </step>
    <step num="5">Wrap the ribs in aluminum foil until completely covered. </step>
    <step num="6">Preheat the grill to 300°F (150°C) with the lid closed. </step>
    <step num="7">Place the foil-wrapped ribs over indirect heat and close the lid. Cook for 2½ hours, until the meat is tender and starting to pull away from the bone, flipping every 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Remove the ribs from the grill and let rest for 10 minutes. Meanwhile, carefully remove the grates and place the smoke bombs over the flames. Close the lid and let smoke build up for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Unwrap the ribs and discard the foil. </step>
    <step num="10">Baste one side of the ribs with the sauce and place directly on the grill, sauce side down. Baste the other side, now facing up. Continue to flip and baste every 5 minutes for 15 minutes total. </step>
    <step num="11">Remove the ribs from the grill and serve with extra barbecue sauce. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the smoke bombs: Add the wood chips to a bowl and cover with water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Let soak for 1 hour, then drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Place 1 cup of the damp wood chips on a piece of aluminum foil and fold into a packet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Poke multiple holes in the top with a toothpick or fork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Repeat with the remaining wood chips, creating 4 packets total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Make the sauce: Add the ketchup, brown sugar, molasses, apple cider vinegar, Worcestershire, salt, pepper, and smoked paprika to a small pot over medium heat, whisking to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Once the sauce begins to boil, reduce heat to low and simmer for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove from the heat and let cool to room temperature. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Make the rub: In a medium bowl, whisk together the brown sugar, salt, pepper, cumin, onion powder, paprika, cayenne, ground mustard, and garlic powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">On a large cutting board, pat the ribs dry with paper towels. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">If necessary, remove the membrane on the bone-side of the ribs by using a paring knife to gently loosen and pulling it up in one sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Generously season the ribs all over with the dry rub. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Wrap the ribs in aluminum foil until completely covered. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Preheat the grill to 300°F (150°C) with the lid closed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Place the foil-wrapped ribs over indirect heat and close the lid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cook for 2½ hours, until the meat is tender and starting to pull away from the bone, flipping every 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Remove the ribs from the grill and let rest for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Meanwhile, carefully remove the grates and place the smoke bombs over the flames. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Close the lid and let smoke build up for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Unwrap the ribs and discard the foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Baste one side of the ribs with the sauce and place directly on the grill, sauce side down. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Baste the other side, now facing up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Continue to flip and baste every 5 minutes for 15 minutes total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Remove the ribs from the grill and serve with extra barbecue sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>