<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Fudgy Hidden Veggie Brownies</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/eggplant-brownies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; eggplant, peeled and cut into large pieces </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">8 oz ; semisweet chocolate chip, divided, plus more to taste ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 oz ; unsweetened chocolate, chopped ; (45 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">6 tablespoons ; maple syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 cup ; superfine almond flour ; (95 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; dutch processed cocoa powder ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/116793/hls24_1543272288.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/116793/landscape_720/1543272288</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Peel the eggplant, then cut in half lengthwise. Scoop out the seeds, then chop into large pieces. Transfer to a steamer basket set over a large pot of simmering water, cover, and steam for 20 minutes, until the eggplant is very soft. </step>
    <step num="2">Transfer the hot eggplant to the bowl of the food processor with 4 ounces (110 g) of semisweet chocolate chips, the unsweetened chocolate, maple syrup, and vanilla extract. The heat from the eggplant will melt the chocolate. Blend on high speed for 2-3 minutes, until very smooth, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed. </step>
    <step num="3">In a medium bowl, beat the eggs, then add the almond flour, cocoa powder, and salt, and whisk to combine. Add the eggplant chocolate mixture and fold with a rubber spatula to combine. Fold in the remaining semisweet chocolate chips. </step>
    <step num="4">Transfer the batter to a greased 8-inch (20-cm) square baking dish and smooth the top. Top with more chocolate chips, if desired. </step>
    <step num="5">Bake for 35 minutes, until a toothpick inserted in the center of the brownies comes out clean. </step>
    <step num="6">Let cool for 20 minutes before slicing. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Peel the eggplant, then cut in half lengthwise. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Scoop out the seeds, then chop into large pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Transfer to a steamer basket set over a large pot of simmering water, cover, and steam for 20 minutes, until the eggplant is very soft. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Transfer the hot eggplant to the bowl of the food processor with 4 ounces (110 g) of semisweet chocolate chips, the unsweetened chocolate, maple syrup, and vanilla extract. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">The heat from the eggplant will melt the chocolate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Blend on high speed for 2-3 minutes, until very smooth, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a medium bowl, beat the eggs, then add the almond flour, cocoa powder, and salt, and whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the eggplant chocolate mixture and fold with a rubber spatula to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Fold in the remaining semisweet chocolate chips. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Transfer the batter to a greased 8-inch (20-cm) square baking dish and smooth the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Top with more chocolate chips, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Bake for 35 minutes, until a toothpick inserted in the center of the brownies comes out clean. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Let cool for 20 minutes before slicing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>