<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Salvadoran Pupusas As Made By Curly And His Abuelita Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/salvadoran-pupusas-as-made-by-curly-and-his-abuelita</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ head ; green cabbage, cored and shredded </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ; small white onion, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ; medium carrots, grated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">4 cups ; boiling water ; (960 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; distilled white vinegar ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; dried oregano </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; vegetable oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 lb ; boneless pork shoulder, cut into 1-inch (2-cm) cubes ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; medium tomato, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ ; green bell pepper, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 ; small white onion, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">4 cups ; masa harina ; (450 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 teaspoons ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">3 cups ; cold water ; (720 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 cup ; grated mozzarella cheese ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">1 cup ; refried bean, cooked ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 tablespoon ; vegetable oil, for frying </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Latin American</category>
    <category num="1">Sides</category>
    <category num="2">Game Day</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/110702/hls24_1538153157.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/110702/landscape_720/1538153157</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the curtido: In a large bowl, combine the cabbage, onion, and carrots. Pour the boiling water over the vegetables and toss. Let sit for 10 minutes, then drain. </step>
    <step num="1">In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, combine the vinegar, oregano, and salt. Pour over the slaw and toss to coat. Once thoroughly mixed, transfer the curtido any any leftover liquid in the bowl to an airtight jar or container. </step>
    <step num="2">Chill for at least 20 minutes in the refrigerator, or chill overnight for best results. </step>
    <step num="3">Make the chicharrón: Heat the vegetable oil in a large pan over medium-high heat. Add the pork shoulder and salt. Cook for 15 minutes without disturbing. If the pork is browning too quickly, reduce the heat to medium. Turn the pork over and let cook on the other side for 10 minutes more, or until crispy and golden brown. </step>
    <step num="4">Transfer the pork to a food processor and add the tomato, green bell pepper, and onion. Pulse until a thick paste forms. The mixture should not be watery. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the pupusa dough: In a large bowl, whisk together the masa harina and salt, then add the water. Use your hands to mix until the dough comes together with a clay-like texture. </step>
    <step num="6">Fill a small bowl with water and a bit of oil and set near your work station. You’ll wet your fingers with the mixture as you work to keep the dough from sticking to your hands. </step>
    <step num="7">Take a golf ball-sized portion of dough and roll into a ball, then flatten into an even round. </step>
    <step num="8">Fill the dough round with ½ tablespoon chicharrón paste, 1 teaspoon refried beans, and 1 teaspoon mozzarella cheese. Fold the dough over the filling until it’s completely sealed. Then, pat out the ball between your hands until flat. If the pupusa cracks, patch it with a bit of dough and a little oil. Repeat with the remaining ingredients. </step>
    <step num="9">Heat a large pan or griddle over medium heat. Brush with vegetable oil, then place 2-3 pupusas on the pan and cook for 2-4 minutes, or until the bottoms are golden brown. Flip and cook on the other side for 2-4 minutes more, until golden brown and warmed through. Repeat with the remaining pupusas. </step>
    <step num="10">Serve the pupusas with curtido. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the curtido: In a large bowl, combine the cabbage, onion, and carrots. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pour the boiling water over the vegetables and toss. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Let sit for 10 minutes, then drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, combine the vinegar, oregano, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour over the slaw and toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Once thoroughly mixed, transfer the curtido any any leftover liquid in the bowl to an airtight jar or container. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Chill for at least 20 minutes in the refrigerator, or chill overnight for best results. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Make the chicharrón: Heat the vegetable oil in a large pan over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the pork shoulder and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Cook for 15 minutes without disturbing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">If the pork is browning too quickly, reduce the heat to medium. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Turn the pork over and let cook on the other side for 10 minutes more, or until crispy and golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Transfer the pork to a food processor and add the tomato, green bell pepper, and onion. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Pulse until a thick paste forms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">The mixture should not be watery. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Make the pupusa dough: In a large bowl, whisk together the masa harina and salt, then add the water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Use your hands to mix until the dough comes together with a clay-like texture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Fill a small bowl with water and a bit of oil and set near your work station. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">You’ll wet your fingers with the mixture as you work to keep the dough from sticking to your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Take a golf ball-sized portion of dough and roll into a ball, then flatten into an even round. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Fill the dough round with ½ tablespoon chicharrón paste, 1 teaspoon refried beans, and 1 teaspoon mozzarella cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Fold the dough over the filling until it’s completely sealed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Then, pat out the ball between your hands until flat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">If the pupusa cracks, patch it with a bit of dough and a little oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Repeat with the remaining ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Heat a large pan or griddle over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Brush with vegetable oil, then place 2-3 pupusas on the pan and cook for 2-4 minutes, or until the bottoms are golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Flip and cook on the other side for 2-4 minutes more, until golden brown and warmed through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Repeat with the remaining pupusas. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Serve the pupusas with curtido. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>