<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Homemade Dutch Oven Bread Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/homemade-dutch-oven-bread</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; lukewarm water, between 90˚-110˚F (30˚-40˚C) ; (470 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 envelope ; active dry yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">4 cups ; all-purpose flour, lightly packed and leveled off, plus more for dusting ; (600 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ½ teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">French</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="4">Vegan</category>
    <category num="5">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="6">Brunch</category>
    <category num="7">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="8">Fusion</category>
    <category num="9">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/22703/low_1485976591.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/22703/mp4_720x1280/1485976591</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Stir yeast packet into water and allow yeast to bloom. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, mix flour and salt by hand. Once incorporated, create a small well in the middle and pour in the water/yeast mixture. </step>
    <step num="2">Mix by hand, wetting your working hand before mixing so the dough doesn’t stick to your fingers. The water and flour should come together and a form rough dough that pulls away from the sides of the bowl. </step>
    <step num="3">NOTE: If the dough is too sticky, add more flour in small increments, about 1 tablespoon at a time. If the dough is too dry, add more water, 1 tablespoon at a time. </step>
    <step num="4">Once the dough has come together, cover it and let it rise until it doubles in size (about 1 and a half to 2 hours). </step>
    <step num="5">Uncover the dough and give it a few pokes with your finger. If the dough has risen properly it should indent under the pressure of your fingers and slowly deflate. </step>
    <step num="6">Using your hand or a rubber spatula fold the dough. Starting from the rim of the bowl, work the dough loose from the sides and fold it up and towards the center of the bowl. Turn the bowl 90 degrees, and repeat until all the dough has been pulled from the sides and folded towards the center. </step>
    <step num="7">Once finished, cover and allow the dough to continue to rise for another 1.5-2 hours. </step>
    <step num="8">Once the dough has doubled in size again, gently remove it from the bowl onto a lightly floured surface. </step>
    <step num="9">Sprinkle a small amount of flour on top of the dough. Using your hands, begin to shape the loaf. Fold the dough under itself several times to form a ball, then claps together the seams of dough underneath. </step>
    <step num="10">Place the dough seam-side down in a clean bowl that has been coated with olive oil and flour. </step>
    <step num="11">Cover and let rise for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="12">Meanwhile, take a 6-quart (6 liters) dutch oven (or heavy cooking pot with oven-safe lid) and place it inside the oven. Preheat the oven to 450˚F (230˚C) and allow it to heat up with the pot inside for 45 minutes. </step>
    <step num="13">Remove the pot from the oven and place it on a trivet or heat-safe surface. (Be careful! It’ll be VERY HOT.) </step>
    <step num="14">Turn the proofed dough over onto a lightly floured surface and carefully place it inside of the pot. </step>
    <step num="15">Cover with the lid and return the pot to the oven. </step>
    <step num="16">Bake at 450˚F (230˚C) for 45 minutes, removing the lid for the last 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="17">Remove bread from pot and allow to cool for 10 minutes before cutting. </step>
    <step num="18">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Stir yeast packet into water and allow yeast to bloom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a large bowl, mix flour and salt by hand. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Once incorporated, create a small well in the middle and pour in the water/yeast mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Mix by hand, wetting your working hand before mixing so the dough doesn’t stick to your fingers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">The water and flour should come together and a form rough dough that pulls away from the sides of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">NOTE: If the dough is too sticky, add more flour in small increments, about 1 tablespoon at a time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">If the dough is too dry, add more water, 1 tablespoon at a time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Once the dough has come together, cover it and let it rise until it doubles in size (about 1 and a half to 2 hours). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Uncover the dough and give it a few pokes with your finger. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">If the dough has risen properly it should indent under the pressure of your fingers and slowly deflate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Using your hand or a rubber spatula fold the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Starting from the rim of the bowl, work the dough loose from the sides and fold it up and towards the center of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Turn the bowl 90 degrees, and repeat until all the dough has been pulled from the sides and folded towards the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Once finished, cover and allow the dough to continue to rise for another 1.5-2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Once the dough has doubled in size again, gently remove it from the bowl onto a lightly floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Sprinkle a small amount of flour on top of the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Using your hands, begin to shape the loaf. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Fold the dough under itself several times to form a ball, then claps together the seams of dough underneath. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Place the dough seam-side down in a clean bowl that has been coated with olive oil and flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Cover and let rise for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Meanwhile, take a 6-quart (6 liters) dutch oven (or heavy cooking pot with oven-safe lid) and place it inside the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Preheat the oven to 450˚F (230˚C) and allow it to heat up with the pot inside for 45 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Remove the pot from the oven and place it on a trivet or heat-safe surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">(Be careful! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">It’ll be VERY HOT.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Turn the proofed dough over onto a lightly floured surface and carefully place it inside of the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Cover with the lid and return the pot to the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Bake at 450˚F (230˚C) for 45 minutes, removing the lid for the last 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Remove bread from pot and allow to cool for 10 minutes before cutting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>