<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Ackee And Saltfish With Bammy As Made By Karamo And Jason Brown Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/ackee-and-saltfish-with-bammy-as-made-by-karamo-and-jason-brown</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 lb ; cassava, peeled and grate ; (90 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 can ; coconut milk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; canola oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ lb ; boneless saltfish, salted codfish ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">12 cups ; cold water, divided ; (3 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">8 cups ; water, divided ; (2 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 tablespoons ; canola oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ; large yellow onion, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ; medium red bell pepper, seeded and sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; medium green bell pepper, seeded and sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ; medium tomato, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">4 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ ; scotch bonnet pepper, seeded and finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 tablespoon ; fresh thyme leaf </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">1 can ; ackee, drained and rinsed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">2 ; scallions, finely chopped </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="1">Caribbean</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/135311/hls24_1559856714.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/135311/landscape_720/1559856714</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the bammy: Add the cassava to a food processor and pulse until finely shredded. Transfer to a clean towel and squeeze to extract excess liquid until the cassava is fully dry. </step>
    <step num="1">Transfer to a medium bowl and break up the cassava. Sprinkle in the salt and stir to distribute. </step>
    <step num="2">Heat an 8-inch (20 cm) skillet over medium-low heat. Carefully pour half of the cassava into the pan. Use a silicone spatula to pat the cassava into a disc. Cook the bammy for about 6-8 minutes on each side, until light golden brown.. </step>
    <step num="3">Transfer the bammy to a shallow dish filled with the coconut milk and let soak for 1 minute. Do not let soak too long, or the bammy will fall apart. </step>
    <step num="4">Add 1 tablespoon of canola oil to the skillet and carefully transfer the bammy back to the pan. Fry for another 5 minutes on each side, until light golden brown. Repeat with the remaining cassava. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the ackee and saltfish: Rinse the salted cod in a bowl with 4 cups (960 ml) of cold water. Drain and repeat twice more. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the rinsed cod to a small saucepan with 4 cups (960 ml) of water. Bring to a boil and cook for 15 minutes. Drain and repeat once more. </step>
    <step num="7">Transfer the fish to a medium bowl. Use 2 forks or your hands to flake the fish into chunks. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="8">Heat the canola oil in a large skillet over medium heat. Once shimmering, add the onion, red and green bell pepper, tomato, garlic, scotch bonnet, thyme, pepper, and salt. Sauté, stirring occasionally, for 8-10 minutes, until slightly softened. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the ackee, flaked saltfish, and scallions and carefully fold in to the vegetables. Sauté for 4-5 minutes more, until warmed through. Season to taste with more salt if needed. </step>
    <step num="10">Slice the warm bammies into quarters, then serve with the ackee and saltfish. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the bammy: Add the cassava to a food processor and pulse until finely shredded. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Transfer to a clean towel and squeeze to extract excess liquid until the cassava is fully dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Transfer to a medium bowl and break up the cassava. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Sprinkle in the salt and stir to distribute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Heat an 8-inch (20 cm) skillet over medium-low heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Carefully pour half of the cassava into the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Use a silicone spatula to pat the cassava into a disc. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cook the bammy for about 6-8 minutes on each side, until light golden brown.. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Transfer the bammy to a shallow dish filled with the coconut milk and let soak for 1 minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Do not let soak too long, or the bammy will fall apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add 1 tablespoon of canola oil to the skillet and carefully transfer the bammy back to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Fry for another 5 minutes on each side, until light golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Repeat with the remaining cassava. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Make the ackee and saltfish: Rinse the salted cod in a bowl with 4 cups (960 ml) of cold water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Drain and repeat twice more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the rinsed cod to a small saucepan with 4 cups (960 ml) of water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Bring to a boil and cook for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Drain and repeat once more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Transfer the fish to a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Use 2 forks or your hands to flake the fish into chunks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Heat the canola oil in a large skillet over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Once shimmering, add the onion, red and green bell pepper, tomato, garlic, scotch bonnet, thyme, pepper, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Sauté, stirring occasionally, for 8-10 minutes, until slightly softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Add the ackee, flaked saltfish, and scallions and carefully fold in to the vegetables. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Sauté for 4-5 minutes more, until warmed through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Season to taste with more salt if needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Slice the warm bammies into quarters, then serve with the ackee and saltfish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>