<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Mangú Con Los Tres Golpes Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/mangu-con-los-tres-golpes</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; red onion, sliced into rings </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; vinegar ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">6 ; plantains </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">5 cups ; water ; (1 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 cups ; canola oil, divided ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">12 slices ; dominican frying cheese, queso de freir </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; flour ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">18 slices ; dominican salami, salami frito </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">6 tablespoons ; butter, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">6 ; eggs, fried, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ; avocado, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Latin American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Breakfast</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/81490/hls24_1519773876.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/81490/landscape_720/1519773876</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Place the sliced onions in a medium bowl with a heavy pinch of salt and vinegar. Let soak while preparing the other ingredients, about 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="1">Peel the plantains and cut into quarters. Place the plantains in a large pot with enough water to cover them by 1 inch (2 cm). Add salt to taste. Bring the plantains to a boil over high heat and cook until they are very tender, about 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Meanwhile, in a medium skillet, heat the canola oil to 350°F (180°C) over high heat. </step>
    <step num="3">Coat each slice of Dominican frying cheese in flour, and then place the slices in 1¾ cups (420 ML) canola oil and fry until both sides are golden brown, about 3 minutes. Remove from skillet and transfer to a paper towel-lined plate. </step>
    <step num="4">Add another tablespoon of oil to the skillet and fry the salami until brown and crispy on both sides, 4 minutes. Remove from the skillet, transfer to a paper towel-lined plate. </step>
    <step num="5">Wipe out the skillet, and add another tablespoon of oil to the pan. Pour in the onions and their soaking liquid. Sauté until the onions are soft and bright pink, about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Once the plantains are tender, scoop them out from the water and place in a separate large bowl, and keep the starchy boiling liquid warm on the stove. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the butter and about 1 cup (240 ml) of the hot starchy plantain liquid. Mash the cooked plantains together until it is creamy and smooth. Add more liquid as needed. </step>
    <step num="8">Serve the mangú with the fried cheese, fried salami, avocado, and fried eggs. Garnish with pickled onions. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Place the sliced onions in a medium bowl with a heavy pinch of salt and vinegar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Let soak while preparing the other ingredients, about 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Peel the plantains and cut into quarters. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Place the plantains in a large pot with enough water to cover them by 1 inch (2 cm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add salt to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Bring the plantains to a boil over high heat and cook until they are very tender, about 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Meanwhile, in a medium skillet, heat the canola oil to 350°F (180°C) over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Coat each slice of Dominican frying cheese in flour, and then place the slices in 1¾ cups (420 ML) canola oil and fry until both sides are golden brown, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Remove from skillet and transfer to a paper towel-lined plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add another tablespoon of oil to the skillet and fry the salami until brown and crispy on both sides, 4 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Remove from the skillet, transfer to a paper towel-lined plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Wipe out the skillet, and add another tablespoon of oil to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Pour in the onions and their soaking liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Sauté until the onions are soft and bright pink, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Once the plantains are tender, scoop them out from the water and place in a separate large bowl, and keep the starchy boiling liquid warm on the stove. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the butter and about 1 cup (240 ml) of the hot starchy plantain liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Mash the cooked plantains together until it is creamy and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Add more liquid as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Serve the mangú with the fried cheese, fried salami, avocado, and fried eggs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Garnish with pickled onions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>