<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Sloppy Joe Egg Rolls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/sloppy-joe-egg-rolls</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 qt ; vegetable oil, plus 1 tablespoon ; (2.8 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 lb ; lean ground beef ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 teaspoons ; salt, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 teaspoons ; pepper, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ; white onion, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; green bell pepper, seeded and diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; dried oregano </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 tablespoon ; brown sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">4 cloves ; garlic, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 tablespoons ; worcestershire sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ cup ; ketchup ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 cups ; tomato sauce ; (520 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">20 ; egg roll wrappers </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ; egg, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 cup ; cheese dip, for serving ; (260 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Chinese</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="4">Game Day</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105335/hls24_1534277828.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105335/landscape_720/1534277828</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Heat 3 quarts (2.8 L) of oil in a large pot until it reaches 350°F (180°C). Set a wire rack over a baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="1">Heat the remaining tablespoon of vegetable oil in a large cast-iron skillet over high heat. Add the ground beef, 1 teaspoon of salt, and 1 teaspoon of pepper, and cook for 10 minutes, or until browned. Remove the beef from the pan, leaving the drippings behind, and set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">In the same pan, cook the onion for 5 minutes, or until softened. </step>
    <step num="3">Push the onions to one side of the pan, and add the green pepper to the other side. Cook for 5 minutes, or until softened. </step>
    <step num="4">Return the ground beef to the pan. Add the remaining teaspoon of salt, remaining teaspoon of pepper, the oregano, brown sugar, garlic, Worcestershire sauce, and ketchup, and stir to combine. Add the tomato sauce and stir well. </step>
    <step num="5">Lay an egg roll wrapper on a clean surface. Brush a ½ inch (1 cm) border all around with egg wash. </step>
    <step num="6">Place two tablespoon filling of sloppy joe filling in the center of the egg roll wrapper. Fold one corner of the wrapper over the filling. Fold the sides over the folded corner. Continue rolling to seal the egg roll. Repeat with the rest of the wrappers and filling. </step>
    <step num="7">Fry the egg rolls, about 2 at a time, for about 2 minutes on each side, until evenly golden brown. Set the fried egg rolls on the wire rack to drain, and let cool for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Serve warm with cheese dip. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Heat 3 quarts (2.8 L) of oil in a large pot until it reaches 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Set a wire rack over a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Heat the remaining tablespoon of vegetable oil in a large cast-iron skillet over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the ground beef, 1 teaspoon of salt, and 1 teaspoon of pepper, and cook for 10 minutes, or until browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Remove the beef from the pan, leaving the drippings behind, and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In the same pan, cook the onion for 5 minutes, or until softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Push the onions to one side of the pan, and add the green pepper to the other side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cook for 5 minutes, or until softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Return the ground beef to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the remaining teaspoon of salt, remaining teaspoon of pepper, the oregano, brown sugar, garlic, Worcestershire sauce, and ketchup, and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the tomato sauce and stir well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Lay an egg roll wrapper on a clean surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Brush a ½ inch (1 cm) border all around with egg wash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Place two tablespoon filling of sloppy joe filling in the center of the egg roll wrapper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Fold one corner of the wrapper over the filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Fold the sides over the folded corner. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Continue rolling to seal the egg roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Repeat with the rest of the wrappers and filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Fry the egg rolls, about 2 at a time, for about 2 minutes on each side, until evenly golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Set the fried egg rolls on the wire rack to drain, and let cool for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Serve warm with cheese dip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>