<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Deep-Fried Turkey Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/deep-fried-turkey</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; salt ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 lb ; brown sugar ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">6 qt ; boiling water ; (5.5 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 lb ; ice ; (1.3 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 qt ; cold water, enough water to cover turkey entirely ; (3.8 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">13 lb ; turkey, no larger than 15 lb (6.8 kg) ; (5.9 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">4 ½ gal ; peanut oil ; (17 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">oven mitts, or rotisserie grade oven mitts </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">propane burner, with sturdy stand that will hold your large pot </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">deep fry thermometer </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">30 qt ; large pot ; (28 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">basket, or hook or stainless steel kitchen utensil with wide bottom, long handle and looped top </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">s hook with handle </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="4">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="5">Dinner</category>
    <category num="6">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32228/low_1495125485.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32228/mp4_720x1280/1495125485</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">DISCLAIMER: Deep frying a turkey can be dangerous if not done properly. </step>
    <step num="1">Determine the amount of oil you will need before you start. This turkey and pot required 4 ½ gallons (17 liter) of peanut oil, you may need more or less. </step>
    <step num="2">To determine the correct amount, place the turkey in the pot you will be using to fry. Fill it with water until it has just covered your turkey, that water level should also be at least 5 inches (13 cm) below the rim of your pot. Remove the turkey and see where the water levels off, this is the amount of oil you will need to fry the turkey. If the oil level is NOT 5 inches (13 cm) below the rim of your pot, use a taller pot. If too much oil is used, it will spill over when the turkey is lowered and cause a fire. If you like, as a precaution, turn off the propane burner before you add the turkey to the hot oil. </step>
    <step num="3">In a large pot, container or cooler with a lid, combine salt, brown sugar and boiling water to make the brine. </step>
    <step num="4">Once the salt and brown sugar have dissolved, cool down with ice. </step>
    <step num="5">Place your turkey into the brine mixture, add more cold water to cover your turkey entirely. Weight down the turkey with something heavy and cover. </step>
    <step num="6">Place the turkey in a cool place or refrigerator and let it brine for 8-16 hours. </step>
    <step num="7">Remove the turkey from the brine, discard the brine. Pat dry the turkey. Make sure it’s entirely dry inside and out, border on very dry. </step>
    <step num="8">Let it sit at room temp for 30 minutes prior to frying. </step>
    <step num="9">While the turkey is coming to room temp, prepare your deep frying pot. The pot should be large enough to hold the turkey, oil and have enough room to contain the oil once it starts bubbling (recommend 30 quart/ 28-liter pot). </step>
    <step num="10">NOTE: Make sure the deep frying pot is clean and dry, any moisture in the pot will make the oil pop when it starts heating up. </step>
    <step num="11">Pour the peanut oil into the pot. You should have enough oil to just cover the turkey. Set over high heat on an outside propane burner. Bring the temperature of the oil to 350°F (180°C). </step>
    <step num="12">While the oil is heating up, prepare your turkey to submerge into the oil. </step>
    <step num="13">If you are using a turkey deep frying kit, use all the equipment provided (i.e. hook/basket, s-hook, retrieval handle). If not, take a stainless steel kitchen utensil with a wide bottom, long handle and looped top. Take the kitchen utensil and push the handle through the neck of the turkey. You want the wide part of the utensil to rest inside the turkey cavity. Take an s-hook with a handle attachment and loop it through the loop part of the kitchen utensil. </step>
    <step num="14">Wipe down the turkey again to make sure there is no moisture. Turkey is ready. </step>
    <step num="15">Once the temperature of the oil has reached 350°F (180°C), slowly and gently lower the turkey into the oil. SLOWLY AND GENTLY. </step>
    <step num="16">Fry the turkey for 3 minutes per pound (455 grams). For a 15 lb (6.8 kg) turkey, this will take 45 minutes. Make sure the oil temp is maintained at 350°F (180°C). </step>
    <step num="17">After 45 minutes, turn off your propane burner and then gently remove the turkey from the oil. </step>
    <step num="18">Place the turkey on a large baking sheet or carving board and check the temperature. Right out of the fryer, the breast meat should be at 150°F (65°C) and will reach 160°F (70°C) due to carry over cooking. </step>
    <step num="19">Let the turkey rest for 30 minutes before carving. </step>
    <step num="20">NOTE: Oil will be hot for a few hours after frying. Do not touch or dispose of until fully cooled. </step>
    <step num="21">Carve as desired. </step>
    <step num="22">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">DISCLAIMER: Deep frying a turkey can be dangerous if not done properly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Determine the amount of oil you will need before you start. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">This turkey and pot required 4 ½ gallons (17 liter) of peanut oil, you may need more or less. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">To determine the correct amount, place the turkey in the pot you will be using to fry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Fill it with water until it has just covered your turkey, that water level should also be at least 5 inches (13 cm) below the rim of your pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Remove the turkey and see where the water levels off, this is the amount of oil you will need to fry the turkey. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">If the oil level is NOT 5 inches (13 cm) below the rim of your pot, use a taller pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">If too much oil is used, it will spill over when the turkey is lowered and cause a fire. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">If you like, as a precaution, turn off the propane burner before you add the turkey to the hot oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a large pot, container or cooler with a lid, combine salt, brown sugar and boiling water to make the brine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Once the salt and brown sugar have dissolved, cool down with ice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place your turkey into the brine mixture, add more cold water to cover your turkey entirely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Weight down the turkey with something heavy and cover. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Place the turkey in a cool place or refrigerator and let it brine for 8-16 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove the turkey from the brine, discard the brine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Pat dry the turkey. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Make sure it’s entirely dry inside and out, border on very dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Let it sit at room temp for 30 minutes prior to frying. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">While the turkey is coming to room temp, prepare your deep frying pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">The pot should be large enough to hold the turkey, oil and have enough room to contain the oil once it starts bubbling (recommend 30 quart/ 28-liter pot). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">NOTE: Make sure the deep frying pot is clean and dry, any moisture in the pot will make the oil pop when it starts heating up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Pour the peanut oil into the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">You should have enough oil to just cover the turkey. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Set over high heat on an outside propane burner. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Bring the temperature of the oil to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">While the oil is heating up, prepare your turkey to submerge into the oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">If you are using a turkey deep frying kit, use all the equipment provided (i.e. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">hook/basket, s-hook, retrieval handle). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">If not, take a stainless steel kitchen utensil with a wide bottom, long handle and looped top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Take the kitchen utensil and push the handle through the neck of the turkey. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">You want the wide part of the utensil to rest inside the turkey cavity. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Take an s-hook with a handle attachment and loop it through the loop part of the kitchen utensil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Wipe down the turkey again to make sure there is no moisture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Turkey is ready. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Once the temperature of the oil has reached 350°F (180°C), slowly and gently lower the turkey into the oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">SLOWLY AND GENTLY. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Fry the turkey for 3 minutes per pound (455 grams). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="37">For a 15 lb (6.8 kg) turkey, this will take 45 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="38">Make sure the oil temp is maintained at 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="39">After 45 minutes, turn off your propane burner and then gently remove the turkey from the oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="40">Place the turkey on a large baking sheet or carving board and check the temperature. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="41">Right out of the fryer, the breast meat should be at 150°F (65°C) and will reach 160°F (70°C) due to carry over cooking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="42">Let the turkey rest for 30 minutes before carving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="43">NOTE: Oil will be hot for a few hours after frying. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="44">Do not touch or dispose of until fully cooled. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="45">Carve as desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="46">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>