<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>How To Make Vegan Pho Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/how-to-make-vegan-pho</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">20 ; dried shiitake mushrooms </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 ; medium white onions, tops and bottoms cut off peeled halved crosswise </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; large daikon radish, peeled and cut into 1-inch (2 1/4 cm) thick rounds </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; ginger, 6 inches (15 cm) peeled, sliced into coins </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 cups ; oyster mushroom, sliced into 2-inch (5 cm) pieces ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">12 cups ; water ; (2.8 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ; cinnamon stick, or piece of cassia bark </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; clove </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">5 ; cardamom pods </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">5 ; star anises </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 teaspoon ; coriander seed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 teaspoon ; fennel seeds </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">14 oz ; soft tofu, 1 package drained and sliced into 1 inch (2 cm) pieces or fried tofu, sliced ; (400 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">rice stick noodle, cooked </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">red onion, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">bean sprout, washed well </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">chili pepper, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">lime wedge </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">fresh cilantro leaves </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vietnamese</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Healthy</category>
    <category num="4">Vegan</category>
    <category num="5">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="6">Dinner</category>
    <category num="7">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="8">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/106739/hls24_1535392627.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/106739/landscape_720/1535392627</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Add the dried shiitake mushrooms to a medium bowl and pour in enough water to cover. Cover with a dish towel and let hydrate for 8 hours, then rinse and drain the mushrooms 2-3 times. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large pan over medium heat, dry sear the onions until caramelized on both sides, 10-15 minutes. Transfer to a bowl and repeat with the daikon radish and ginger. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">Heat the oil in the pan. Add the oyster mushrooms and sauté until browned and caramelized, 6-8 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the caramelized onions, daikon, ginger, oyster mushrooms, and soaked shiitake mushrooms to a large stock pot. Add the water and bring to a boil over high heat. Reduce the heat to low heat and cover. Simmer for at least 1 hour, or up to 8 hours. The longer it cooks, the stronger the flavor of the broth will be. Season with salt to taste. </step>
    <step num="4">About 30 minutes before serving, combine the cinnamon stick, cloves, cardamom, star anise, coriander, and fennel in a fine-mesh sieve. Lower into the pot, resting the sieve on the edge, then cover and simmer for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Remove the spices and add the tofu to heat through, 10-15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove the pot from the heat. Remove the onions, daikon, and ginger from the pot. (Slice and add them back to the soup, if desired.) </step>
    <step num="7">Add the noodles to serving bowls and ladle in the broth, mushrooms, and tofu. </step>
    <step num="8">Garnish with red onion, bean sprouts, chili peppers, a squeeze of lime, and cilantro. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Add the dried shiitake mushrooms to a medium bowl and pour in enough water to cover. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cover with a dish towel and let hydrate for 8 hours, then rinse and drain the mushrooms 2-3 times. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a large pan over medium heat, dry sear the onions until caramelized on both sides, 10-15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Transfer to a bowl and repeat with the daikon radish and ginger. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Heat the oil in the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the oyster mushrooms and sauté until browned and caramelized, 6-8 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the caramelized onions, daikon, ginger, oyster mushrooms, and soaked shiitake mushrooms to a large stock pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the water and bring to a boil over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Reduce the heat to low heat and cover. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Simmer for at least 1 hour, or up to 8 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">The longer it cooks, the stronger the flavor of the broth will be. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Season with salt to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">About 30 minutes before serving, combine the cinnamon stick, cloves, cardamom, star anise, coriander, and fennel in a fine-mesh sieve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Lower into the pot, resting the sieve on the edge, then cover and simmer for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Remove the spices and add the tofu to heat through, 10-15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Remove the pot from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Remove the onions, daikon, and ginger from the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">(Slice and add them back to the soup, if desired.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Add the noodles to serving bowls and ladle in the broth, mushrooms, and tofu. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Garnish with red onion, bean sprouts, chili peppers, a squeeze of lime, and cilantro. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>