<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Show-Stopping Beef Wellington Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/show-stopping-beef-wellington</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 lb ; center-cut beef tenderloin ; (1 ½ kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; canola oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; english mustard ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 ; shallots, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 lb ; cremini mushroom, minced ; (910 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">5 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ lb ; prosciutto, thinly sliced, or ham ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 sheet ; puff pastry </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 ; eggs, beaten </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">British</category>
    <category num="2">French</category>
    <category num="3">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="4">Dinner</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Fusion</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/61937/low_1510687871.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/61937/mp4_720x1280/1510687871</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 400°F (200°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Let the beef tenderloin come to room temperature. Season with kosher salt and pepper on all sides. </step>
    <step num="2">Add canola oil to a large pan on high heat. Once the oil is hot, add the tenderloin. Without moving the tenderloin, cook until a dark brown crust forms, about 3 minutes. Repeat searing on all sides, including the tenderloin ends. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove the tenderloin from the pan and transfer to a cutting board or wire rack and remove ties. </step>
    <step num="4">Brush the mustard on all sides of the meat while it’s still warm. Let the meat rest for while making the duxelle (mushrooms cooked and reduced until dry). </step>
    <step num="5">To the same pan, add the butter, mushrooms, minced shallot, and minced garlic over medium heat. Cook, stirring occasionally, until all the liquid evaporates and the mushroom mixture becomes a thick, dry-like paste. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove the mushrooms from the pan and let cool completely. </step>
    <step num="7">Place a large layer of overlapping sheets of plastic wrap on your work surface that is twice the length and width of the tenderloin. </step>
    <step num="8">Lay overlapping strips of prosciutto on the plastic into an even square layer. </step>
    <step num="9">Spread a layer of the mushrooms evenly over the prosciutto. </step>
    <step num="10">Tightly and evenly wrap the tenderloin with the prosciutto, using the plastic wrap to wrap it even tighter and seal ends. Tie the ends of the plastic wrap together to hold the Wellington’s shape. Place in the refrigerator for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="11">Place a new layer of plastic wrap on the work surface and lay a sheet of puff pastry over it. Unwrap the prosciutto-wrapped beef tenderloin onto the puff pastry, wrapping until the ends meet. Cut off any extra puff pastry, making sure there is no overlap. </step>
    <step num="12">Wrap the puff pastry in plastic wrap, tying the ends together to form a log shape. Place in the refrigerator for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="13">Place the beef Wellington on a greased, parchment paper-lined baking sheet. Brush the surface with the beaten eggs. With a fork, score a decorative design onto the surface of the puff pastry. </step>
    <step num="14">Decorate with additional pastry (optional). Sprinkle with kosher salt. </step>
    <step num="15">Bake for 40 minutes or until the puff pastry is a dark golden brown and the internal temperature of the beef is 135°F (57°C) for medium-rare. </step>
    <step num="16">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 400°F (200°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Let the beef tenderloin come to room temperature. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Season with kosher salt and pepper on all sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add canola oil to a large pan on high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Once the oil is hot, add the tenderloin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Without moving the tenderloin, cook until a dark brown crust forms, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Repeat searing on all sides, including the tenderloin ends. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove the tenderloin from the pan and transfer to a cutting board or wire rack and remove ties. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Brush the mustard on all sides of the meat while it’s still warm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Let the meat rest for while making the duxelle (mushrooms cooked and reduced until dry). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">To the same pan, add the butter, mushrooms, minced shallot, and minced garlic over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cook, stirring occasionally, until all the liquid evaporates and the mushroom mixture becomes a thick, dry-like paste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove the mushrooms from the pan and let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Place a large layer of overlapping sheets of plastic wrap on your work surface that is twice the length and width of the tenderloin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Lay overlapping strips of prosciutto on the plastic into an even square layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Spread a layer of the mushrooms evenly over the prosciutto. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Tightly and evenly wrap the tenderloin with the prosciutto, using the plastic wrap to wrap it even tighter and seal ends. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Tie the ends of the plastic wrap together to hold the Wellington’s shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Place in the refrigerator for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Place a new layer of plastic wrap on the work surface and lay a sheet of puff pastry over it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Unwrap the prosciutto-wrapped beef tenderloin onto the puff pastry, wrapping until the ends meet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Cut off any extra puff pastry, making sure there is no overlap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Wrap the puff pastry in plastic wrap, tying the ends together to form a log shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Place in the refrigerator for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Place the beef Wellington on a greased, parchment paper-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Brush the surface with the beaten eggs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">With a fork, score a decorative design onto the surface of the puff pastry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Decorate with additional pastry (optional). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Sprinkle with kosher salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Bake for 40 minutes or until the puff pastry is a dark golden brown and the internal temperature of the beef is 135°F (57°C) for medium-rare. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>