<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Dark Chocolate Rice Cereal Treat Hearts Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/dark-chocolate-rice-cereal-treat-hearts</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, plus more for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">5 oz ; mini marshmallows ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 cups ; crispy rice cereal ; (90 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">12 oz ; dark chocolate, chopped ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">red sanding sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">valentines sprinkles </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Date Night</category>
    <category num="2">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124769/hls24_1550019711.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124769/landscape_720/1550019711</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Melt the butter in a large saucepan over medium heat. Add the marshmallows and stir constantly until smooth and melted. Add the rice cereal and stir until well coated. </step>
    <step num="1">Transfer the mixture to a buttered 8-inch (20 cm) square baking pan and press into an even layer. Set aside to cool, about 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="2">Once the rice cereal treats have cooled, use a heart-shaped cookie cutter to cut out shapes from the treats. </step>
    <step num="3">In a microwave-safe bowl, microwave the dark chocolate in 30-second intervals, stirring between, until melted and smooth. </step>
    <step num="4">Line a baking sheet with wax paper. Dip half of each heart in the melted chocolate, then set on the baking sheet. Immediately, while the chocolate is still is warm, sprinkle the chocolate side with red sanding sugar and Valentine’s sprinkles. Let cool until the chocolate hardens completely, 1-2 hours. </step>
    <step num="5">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Melt the butter in a large saucepan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the marshmallows and stir constantly until smooth and melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the rice cereal and stir until well coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Transfer the mixture to a buttered 8-inch (20 cm) square baking pan and press into an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Set aside to cool, about 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Once the rice cereal treats have cooled, use a heart-shaped cookie cutter to cut out shapes from the treats. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a microwave-safe bowl, microwave the dark chocolate in 30-second intervals, stirring between, until melted and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Line a baking sheet with wax paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Dip half of each heart in the melted chocolate, then set on the baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Immediately, while the chocolate is still is warm, sprinkle the chocolate side with red sanding sugar and Valentine’s sprinkles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Let cool until the chocolate hardens completely, 1-2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>