<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Grilled Swineapple Dogs Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/grilled-swineapple-dogs</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 teaspoons ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; chili powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; onion powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ ; pineapple, cut into 12 thin spears </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">24 slices ; bacon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">12 ; pork hot dogs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">12 ; hot dog buns </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">BBQ sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">red onion, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">jalapeño, minced </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="2">Lunch</category>
    <category num="3">Game Day</category>
    <category num="4">BBQ</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/35019/low_1498583551.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/35019/mp4_720x1280/1498583551</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat a grill or grill plate to medium-low heat. </step>
    <step num="1">Sprinkle the paprika, garlic powder, chili powder, onion powder black pepper, and salt over the pineapple spears in a bowl. Mix until they are completely coated. </step>
    <step num="2">Lay a slice of bacon at a slight diagonal angle on your work surface. Lay a second slice above it making sure they slightly overlapped in the middle. </step>
    <step num="3">Place one hot dog and one thin pineapple spear near the bottom part of the first slice of bacon. Tuck the end of the bacon around the hot dog and pineapple and roll across the counter until they are completely encased. Use toothpicks if needed to get a tight seal. </step>
    <step num="4">Place the hot dogs on the grill and cook gently until the bacon is crispy and the pineapple and hot dog are heated through, about 40 minutes. Flip halfway through. </step>
    <step num="5">Place into hot dog buns, top with barbecue sauce, minced red onion, and minced jalapeño (optional). </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat a grill or grill plate to medium-low heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Sprinkle the paprika, garlic powder, chili powder, onion powder black pepper, and salt over the pineapple spears in a bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Mix until they are completely coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Lay a slice of bacon at a slight diagonal angle on your work surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Lay a second slice above it making sure they slightly overlapped in the middle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Place one hot dog and one thin pineapple spear near the bottom part of the first slice of bacon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Tuck the end of the bacon around the hot dog and pineapple and roll across the counter until they are completely encased. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Use toothpicks if needed to get a tight seal. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Place the hot dogs on the grill and cook gently until the bacon is crispy and the pineapple and hot dog are heated through, about 40 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Flip halfway through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place into hot dog buns, top with barbecue sauce, minced red onion, and minced jalapeño (optional). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>