<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Peanut Butter Banana Poke Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/peanut-butter-banana-poke-cake</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/easy-poke-cake-4-ways</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; freshly made yellow cake, prepared from scratch or using a packaged mix </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 ; bananas, 2 mashed and 2 sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ½ cups ; creamy peanut butter, melted ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">14 oz ; can of sweetened condensed milk ; (400 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">8 oz ; frozen whipped topping, thawed ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ cup ; roasted peanuts, chopped ; (65 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32540/low_1495477504.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32540/mp4_720x1280/1495477504</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>81.5</start_time>
    <end_time>108.0</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Using the back of a wooden spoon, poke at least 3 rows of 4 holes in the cooked cake, making 12 holes total. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, mix 2 mashed bananas, 1 cup of the melted peanut butter, and the sweetened condensed milk; if needed, add extra milk to loosen the mixture. Pour the mixture over the cake and let it settle into the holes for about 10 minutes. Some of the mixture will stay on top, which is okay. </step>
    <step num="2">Spread the whipped topping evenly over the cake. Place sliced bananas on the topping, drizzle the remaining ½ cup of melted peanut butter on top, and sprinkle with the roasted peanuts. Chill the cake for at least 3 hours or up to overnight. </step>
    <step num="3">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Using the back of a wooden spoon, poke at least 3 rows of 4 holes in the cooked cake, making 12 holes total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a large bowl, mix 2 mashed bananas, 1 cup of the melted peanut butter, and the sweetened condensed milk; if needed, add extra milk to loosen the mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Pour the mixture over the cake and let it settle into the holes for about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Some of the mixture will stay on top, which is okay. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Spread the whipped topping evenly over the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Place sliced bananas on the topping, drizzle the remaining ½ cup of melted peanut butter on top, and sprinkle with the roasted peanuts. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Chill the cake for at least 3 hours or up to overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>