<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Giant Edible Cookie Bowl Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/giant-edible-cookie-bowl</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; store-bought cookie dough ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; all-purpose flour ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">nonstick cooking spray </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; semisweet chocolate chip ; (175 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; coconut oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 scoops ; vanilla ice cream </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">4 scoops ; chocolate ice cream </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; banana, quartered </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">6 ; strawberries, sliced vertically </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; whipped cream ; (30 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Date Night</category>
    <category num="6">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="7">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="8">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/84368/hls24_1520965503.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/84368/landscape_720/1520965503</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (160˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Place cookie dough in a medium bowl and add the flour. Mix until the flour is incorporated. The extra flour will help keep the cookie from running off of the bowl. </step>
    <step num="2">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper, and wrap an ovenproof bowl in foil. Spray with nonstick spray and press the cookie dough onto the bowl until it is completely covered. </step>
    <step num="3">Bake for 25 minutes, or until golden brown. Remove from oven and cool for 30 minutes with the bowl facing down. Once it has cooled, flip over, remove the ovenproof bowl, and allow the cookie to finish cooling. </step>
    <step num="4">Meanwhile, microwave the chocolate chips with the coconut oil for 1 minute, stirring every 20 seconds, until the chocolate has fully melted. </step>
    <step num="5">Pour the melted chocolate into the cookie bowl and spread it around until the inside of the bowl is fully covered, pouring the excess chocolate out. Freeze for 20 minutes, or until the chocolate has fully hardened. </step>
    <step num="6">Fill with vanilla and chocolate ice cream, banana, strawberries, and whipped cream. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (160˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Place cookie dough in a medium bowl and add the flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Mix until the flour is incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">The extra flour will help keep the cookie from running off of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper, and wrap an ovenproof bowl in foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Spray with nonstick spray and press the cookie dough onto the bowl until it is completely covered. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Bake for 25 minutes, or until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove from oven and cool for 30 minutes with the bowl facing down. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Once it has cooled, flip over, remove the ovenproof bowl, and allow the cookie to finish cooling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Meanwhile, microwave the chocolate chips with the coconut oil for 1 minute, stirring every 20 seconds, until the chocolate has fully melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Pour the melted chocolate into the cookie bowl and spread it around until the inside of the bowl is fully covered, pouring the excess chocolate out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Freeze for 20 minutes, or until the chocolate has fully hardened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Fill with vanilla and chocolate ice cream, banana, strawberries, and whipped cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>