<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Lamb Biryani Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/lamb-biryani</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; basmati rice ; (400 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 cups ; water, plus 3 tbsp, divided ; (720 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; medium white onion, chopped, plus 2 thinly sliced, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">5 tablespoons ; slivered almonds, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 cloves ; garlic, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; ginger, 1 inch (2 cm) peeled and coarsely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">6 tablespoons ; vegetable oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 tablespoons ; golden raisin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ½ lb ; boneless lamb shoulder, cut into chunks ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ¼ teaspoons ; salt, plus an additional 1 1/2 tbsp, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; plain yogurt ; (245 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 teaspoon ; saffron thread </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 tablespoons ; milk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ; cinnamon stick, 1 inch (2 cm) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">5 ; cloves </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">½ teaspoon ; black peppercorn </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">½ teaspoon ; cardamom seeds, removed from pods </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">1 teaspoon ; coriander seeds </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 teaspoon ; cumin seeds </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">1 teaspoon ; nutmeg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">¼ teaspoon ; cayenne pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">½ ; lemon, juiced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, cut into 8 pieces </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">3 ; eggs, hard boiled, peeled and halved, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">3 tablespoons ; fresh cilantro, chopped, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Indian</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105798/hls24_1534551907.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105798/landscape_720/1534551907</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Soak the rice in 2 cups (480 ml) of water for about 2 hours. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the chopped onion, 2 tablespoons slivered almonds, garlic, ginger, and 3 tablespoons of water to a food processor. Blend into a paste. </step>
    <step num="2">Heat the oil in a large nonstick pan over medium heat. Add the sliced onions and fry until browned and crisp, about 10 minutes. Remove from the pan with a slotted spoon and drain on paper towels. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the raisins to the pan. Stir until they become plump, about 2 minutes, then remove and drain on paper towels. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the lamb to the pan, in batches if necessary, and brown on all sides, about 5 minutes. Transfer the browned meat to a bowl and set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">Reduce the heat to medium. Add the onion paste to the pan. Cook, stirring constantly, until the paste turns light brown. If it sticks to the bottom of the pan, add a bit of water and keep stirring. </step>
    <step num="6">Return the meat and any accumulated juices to the pan. Add 1¼ teaspoons of salt, the yogurt, and 1 cup (240 ml) of water. Cover, reduce the heat to low, and simmer for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the saffron threads to a small bowl with the milk and set aside. </step>
    <step num="8">Bring a large pot of water to boil and add 1½ tablespoons of salt. Drain the rice and add to pot. Boil for 5 minutes, then immediately drain and rinse. </step>
    <step num="9">In a spice grinder or mortar and pestle, finely grind the cinnamon stick, cloves, peppercorns, cardamon, coriander, and cumin. </step>
    <step num="10">Add the spices to the meat, along with the nutmeg and cayenne. Cover and continue cooking until the meat is tender, about 10 minutes. If there is too much sauce, increase the heat to high, uncover, and stir to evaporate some of the liquid (there should about 1 cup (240 g) of sauce left in the meat). </step>
    <step num="11">Preheat the oven to 300˚F (150˚C). </step>
    <step num="12">In a large Dutch oven or deep casserole dish, layer half of the rice, the meat with its sauce, and the rest of the rice. Squeeze the lemon juice over rice. </step>
    <step num="13">Using the end of a wooden spoon, poke holes all the way through the layers. Spoon a bit of the saffron and milk into each hole. </step>
    <step num="14">Distribute the butter over the rice and sprinkle over most of the fried onions, reserving some for garnish. Cover the dish with foil, then top with a lid. </step>
    <step num="15">Bake for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="16">Remove the biriyani from the oven and set aside for at least 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="17">Garnish with the eggs, raisins, remaining 3 tablespoons of slivered almonds, reserved fried onions, and cilantro. </step>
    <step num="18">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Soak the rice in 2 cups (480 ml) of water for about 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the chopped onion, 2 tablespoons slivered almonds, garlic, ginger, and 3 tablespoons of water to a food processor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Blend into a paste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Heat the oil in a large nonstick pan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the sliced onions and fry until browned and crisp, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Remove from the pan with a slotted spoon and drain on paper towels. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the raisins to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Stir until they become plump, about 2 minutes, then remove and drain on paper towels. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the lamb to the pan, in batches if necessary, and brown on all sides, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Transfer the browned meat to a bowl and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Reduce the heat to medium. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the onion paste to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cook, stirring constantly, until the paste turns light brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">If it sticks to the bottom of the pan, add a bit of water and keep stirring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Return the meat and any accumulated juices to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add 1¼ teaspoons of salt, the yogurt, and 1 cup (240 ml) of water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Cover, reduce the heat to low, and simmer for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Add the saffron threads to a small bowl with the milk and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Bring a large pot of water to boil and add 1½ tablespoons of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Drain the rice and add to pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Boil for 5 minutes, then immediately drain and rinse. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">In a spice grinder or mortar and pestle, finely grind the cinnamon stick, cloves, peppercorns, cardamon, coriander, and cumin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add the spices to the meat, along with the nutmeg and cayenne. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Cover and continue cooking until the meat is tender, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">If there is too much sauce, increase the heat to high, uncover, and stir to evaporate some of the liquid (there should about 1 cup (240 g) of sauce left in the meat). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Preheat the oven to 300˚F (150˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">In a large Dutch oven or deep casserole dish, layer half of the rice, the meat with its sauce, and the rest of the rice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Squeeze the lemon juice over rice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Using the end of a wooden spoon, poke holes all the way through the layers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Spoon a bit of the saffron and milk into each hole. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Distribute the butter over the rice and sprinkle over most of the fried onions, reserving some for garnish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Cover the dish with foil, then top with a lid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Bake for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Remove the biriyani from the oven and set aside for at least 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Garnish with the eggs, raisins, remaining 3 tablespoons of slivered almonds, reserved fried onions, and cilantro. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>