<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Pepperoni Pizza Ring Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/pepperoni-pizza-ring</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ cups ; warm water ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ teaspoons ; active dry yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 ½ cups ; flour ; (440 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; grated parmesan cheese ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 teaspoons ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 tablespoons ; olive oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 tablespoons ; cornmeal </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">8 slices ; pepperoni, deli style </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">8 slices ; provolone cheese, deli style </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">3 cups ; tomato sauce, divided ; (780 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">3 cups ; shredded mozzarella cheese ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 tablespoons ; olive oil </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Game Day</category>
    <category num="6">Fusion</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/65776/hls24_1512432558.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/65776/landscape_720/1512432558</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a liquid measuring cup, sprinkle the yeast over the warm water. Set aside for 5 minutes to bloom. </step>
    <step num="2">In a bowl, add 3 cups (375 g) of the flour, Parmesan, baking powder, salt, and sugar and stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="3">Add 2 tablespoons of the olive oil and stir to combine. Pour the yeast water over the flour mixture and stir until the dough forms into a ball. </step>
    <step num="4">Use ¼ cup (30 g) of flour for dusting the surface. Scrape the dough out of the bowl onto your floured surface. Knead the dough for about 10 minutes until the dough is tight. You may need to sprinkle a little flour while you're kneading if the dough is too sticky. Form the dough into a ball. </step>
    <step num="5">Pour 1 tablespoon of olive oil in a bowl. Place the dough in the bowl. 7. Cover, let rise for 1 hour in a warm area, or until the dough has doubled in size. </step>
    <step num="6">Flour the surface. Flip bowl over surface and let the dough fall out of the bowl. Divide the dough into 3 equal balls. </step>
    <step num="7">Begin forming the dough into a circle about ½-inch (1 cm) thick and 8 inches (20 cm) wide, making sure the middle of the circle is not too thin. Repeat with the other 2 balls of dough. </step>
    <step num="8">Sprinkle the cornmeal on a baking sheet. Place dough on the baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="9">Place 4 slices of pepperoni on the dough in the center. Place 4 slices of the provolone over the pepperoni. Spread half of the tomato sauce around the edge of the dough. Sprinkle 1½ cups (150 g) of mozzarella over the sauce around the edge of the circle. </step>
    <step num="10">Place the second circle of dough over the first and tuck the edges underneath the first layer of dough. Repeat with the pepperoni, provolone, tomato sauce, and mozzarella. Place the third layer of dough over the second. Tuck the edges underneath. </step>
    <step num="11">With a knife make one vertical cut in the center of the pizza, making sure you cut through all of the layers. Make another horizontal cut, then 2 diagonal cuts so you have 8 triangles to fold over. Begin folding back each layer, creating an opening in the center. Repeat 7 more times. </step>
    <step num="12">Brush the ring with olive oil and bake for 40 minutes. Cover with foil and continue to bake for 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="13">Place a bowl filled with the rest of the tomato sauce in the center of the ring. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a liquid measuring cup, sprinkle the yeast over the warm water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Set aside for 5 minutes to bloom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a bowl, add 3 cups (375 g) of the flour, Parmesan, baking powder, salt, and sugar and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add 2 tablespoons of the olive oil and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour the yeast water over the flour mixture and stir until the dough forms into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Use ¼ cup (30 g) of flour for dusting the surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Scrape the dough out of the bowl onto your floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Knead the dough for about 10 minutes until the dough is tight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">You may need to sprinkle a little flour while you're kneading if the dough is too sticky. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Form the dough into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Pour 1 tablespoon of olive oil in a bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Place the dough in the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">7. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Cover, let rise for 1 hour in a warm area, or until the dough has doubled in size. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Flour the surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Flip bowl over surface and let the dough fall out of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Divide the dough into 3 equal balls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Begin forming the dough into a circle about ½-inch (1 cm) thick and 8 inches (20 cm) wide, making sure the middle of the circle is not too thin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Repeat with the other 2 balls of dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Sprinkle the cornmeal on a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Place dough on the baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Place 4 slices of pepperoni on the dough in the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Place 4 slices of the provolone over the pepperoni. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Spread half of the tomato sauce around the edge of the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Sprinkle 1½ cups (150 g) of mozzarella over the sauce around the edge of the circle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Place the second circle of dough over the first and tuck the edges underneath the first layer of dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Repeat with the pepperoni, provolone, tomato sauce, and mozzarella. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Place the third layer of dough over the second. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Tuck the edges underneath. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">With a knife make one vertical cut in the center of the pizza, making sure you cut through all of the layers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Make another horizontal cut, then 2 diagonal cuts so you have 8 triangles to fold over. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Begin folding back each layer, creating an opening in the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Repeat 7 more times. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Brush the ring with olive oil and bake for 40 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Cover with foil and continue to bake for 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Place a bowl filled with the rest of the tomato sauce in the center of the ring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="37">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>