<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Macchiato Macarons Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/macchiato-macarons</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 ; large egg whites, room temperature </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; granulated sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ¾ cups ; powdered sugar ; (210 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; superfine almond flour, if unable to find “superfine” it is recommended that you pulse the almond flour in a food processor first ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; instant espresso powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ cup ; butter, room temperature ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; powdered sugar, sifted ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 teaspoons ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">cocoa powder, optional </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="4">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/39415/low_1498730816.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/39415/mp4_720x1280/1498730816</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Line a large baking tray with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">In a medium mixing bowl, beat the egg whites with an electric hand mixer on medium speed until soft peaks form. Add ⅓ of the granulated sugar and with mixer on high, continue to beat until egg whites are stiff peaks. Add another ⅓ of the sugar and beat again until egg whites are back to stiff peaks. Repeat with last ⅓ of sugar, beating until whites are shiny and fluffy. </step>
    <step num="2">Using a fine mesh strainer, sift together the almond flour, confectioners sugar, and espresso powder into the bowl with the egg whites. Discard any large pieces that remain in the strainer. </step>
    <step num="3">With a rubber scraper, fold the mixture into the egg whites, about 35-45 strokes, or until the batter falls on itself but a slight peak remains (Do not overmix or batter will be too thin and runny). </step>
    <step num="4">Fill a piping bag fitted with a round tip. Pipe batter onto prepared baking tray into 1 ½ inch (4 cm) disks. </step>
    <step num="5">Lift and drop the baking tray onto a hard surface 2-3 times to smooth out the batter and knock out any air bubbles. Allow cookies to rest at room temperature for one hour, until a skin forms on the surface of the cookies. </step>
    <step num="6">Preheat oven to 285˚F (140˚C) </step>
    <step num="7">To make the filling, beat the butter, confectioners sugar and vanilla extract until light and fluffy. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="8">After about one hour, gently brush the top a cookie with your finger to check that a skin has formed. The batter should not stick to your finger, if it does, allow to set for an additional 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Bake cookies in preheated oven for 15 minutes, or until the cookies peel away from the parchment when lifted. </step>
    <step num="10">Allow the cookie shells to cool completely. </step>
    <step num="11">Pipe the buttercream frosting onto the bottom side of a cooled shell and sandwich together with a similarly sized cookie. </step>
    <step num="12">Dust with optional cocoa powder and serve. *Store in an airtight container in the refrigerator. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Line a large baking tray with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a medium mixing bowl, beat the egg whites with an electric hand mixer on medium speed until soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add ⅓ of the granulated sugar and with mixer on high, continue to beat until egg whites are stiff peaks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add another ⅓ of the sugar and beat again until egg whites are back to stiff peaks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Repeat with last ⅓ of sugar, beating until whites are shiny and fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Using a fine mesh strainer, sift together the almond flour, confectioners sugar, and espresso powder into the bowl with the egg whites. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Discard any large pieces that remain in the strainer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">With a rubber scraper, fold the mixture into the egg whites, about 35-45 strokes, or until the batter falls on itself but a slight peak remains (Do not overmix or batter will be too thin and runny). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Fill a piping bag fitted with a round tip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Pipe batter onto prepared baking tray into 1 ½ inch (4 cm) disks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Lift and drop the baking tray onto a hard surface 2-3 times to smooth out the batter and knock out any air bubbles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Allow cookies to rest at room temperature for one hour, until a skin forms on the surface of the cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Preheat oven to 285˚F (140˚C) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">To make the filling, beat the butter, confectioners sugar and vanilla extract until light and fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">After about one hour, gently brush the top a cookie with your finger to check that a skin has formed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">The batter should not stick to your finger, if it does, allow to set for an additional 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Bake cookies in preheated oven for 15 minutes, or until the cookies peel away from the parchment when lifted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Allow the cookie shells to cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Pipe the buttercream frosting onto the bottom side of a cooled shell and sandwich together with a similarly sized cookie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Dust with optional cocoa powder and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">*Store in an airtight container in the refrigerator. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>