<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Quick Pickled Veggies Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/quick-pickled-veggies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 cups ; vegetable scraps, such red onions cabbage carrots cucumbers radishes beetsjalapeño peppers cauliflower and string beans ; (545 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; apple cider vinegar ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 teaspoons ; black peppercorn </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; red pepper flakes, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 ; bay leaves </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 teaspoons ; yellow mustard seeds </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 tablespoons ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">3 large cloves ; garlic, smashed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 cups ; ice ; (475 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; jar, 1 quart (1 liter) with a tight-fitting lid </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Sides</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129584/hls24_1554916184.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129584/landscape_720/1554916184</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Prepare your jar(s). Wash with hot, soapy water and dry completely before proceeding. </step>
    <step num="1">Cut the vegetable scraps into bite-size pieces, if necessary. Fill the jar with the vegetable pieces, leaving about ½ inch of space at the top. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large pot, combine the vinegar, salt, peppercorns, red pepper flakes (if using), bay leaves, garlic, mustard seeds, and sugar. Bring to a boil over high heat, and stir until the sugar and salt are completely dissolved. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the ice to the pot and stir until melted, to cool the pickling liquid. </step>
    <step num="4">Pour the cooled pickling liquid over the vegetables to cover completely. Cover the jars with a tight-fitting lid and shake to distribute the spices. </step>
    <step num="5">The pickles will keep in the refrigerator for up to 1 month. Serve with sandwiches, tacos, salads, or as desired. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Prepare your jar(s). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Wash with hot, soapy water and dry completely before proceeding. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cut the vegetable scraps into bite-size pieces, if necessary. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Fill the jar with the vegetable pieces, leaving about ½ inch of space at the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a large pot, combine the vinegar, salt, peppercorns, red pepper flakes (if using), bay leaves, garlic, mustard seeds, and sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Bring to a boil over high heat, and stir until the sugar and salt are completely dissolved. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the ice to the pot and stir until melted, to cool the pickling liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Pour the cooled pickling liquid over the vegetables to cover completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Cover the jars with a tight-fitting lid and shake to distribute the spices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">The pickles will keep in the refrigerator for up to 1 month. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Serve with sandwiches, tacos, salads, or as desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>