<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>The Ultimate Tomato Sauce Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/the-ultimate-tomato-sauce</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">28 oz ; canned whole tomatoes, 2 cans ; (790 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">8 cloves ; garlic </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; olive oil ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ; large onion, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 oz ; anchovies, 1 tin or jar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; red pepper flakes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; tomato paste ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ cup ; dry red wine ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 cup ; water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 lb ; spaghetti, or paste of choice, dry ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ; parmesan cheese, for grating </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Italian</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/104084/hls24_1533235347.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/104084/landscape_720/1533235347</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Add the tomatoes to a deep, large bowl. Using your hands, crush the tomatoes until no large pieces remain, just a coarse tomato puree. </step>
    <step num="1">Peel the garlic cloves and finely chop. </step>
    <step num="2">Heat the olive oil and butter in a large pot over medium heat. Add the onion and garlic and season with salt and pepper. Cook, stirring occasionally, until the onion is softened but not browned, about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the anchovies and the oil they are packed in. Cook, stirring occasionally, until dissolved into the oil, about 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the red pepper flakes and stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the tomato paste and cook until it turns a dark, brick-red color, about 4 minutes (this caramelizes the sugars in the tomato, which will give a really great flavor and take the edge off that raw tomato-y taste). </step>
    <step num="6">Add the wine and cook for about 1 minute, just to burn off the alcohol. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the tomatoes and stir everything together, making sure to scrape the bottom of the pot to get all those good bits. Add water and bring it to a boil. </step>
    <step num="8">Reduce the heat to medium-low and cook the sauce for 1½–2 hours at a very low simmer; there should just be a few bubbles here and there. If medium-low is too high (every stove is different), reduce the heat to low. Stir every 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Ladle out about 2 cups of sauce: This is what is known as your "extra sauce." You'll serve it alongside the pasta or freeze it for later. </step>
    <step num="10">To serve, cook the spaghetti in a large pot of salted boiling water. </step>
    <step num="11">Drain the pasta and add it to the sauce. Serve it right out of the pot, or transfer to a serving bowl. Top with grated Parmesan cheese. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Add the tomatoes to a deep, large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Using your hands, crush the tomatoes until no large pieces remain, just a coarse tomato puree. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Peel the garlic cloves and finely chop. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Heat the olive oil and butter in a large pot over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the onion and garlic and season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cook, stirring occasionally, until the onion is softened but not browned, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the anchovies and the oil they are packed in. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cook, stirring occasionally, until dissolved into the oil, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the red pepper flakes and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the tomato paste and cook until it turns a dark, brick-red color, about 4 minutes (this caramelizes the sugars in the tomato, which will give a really great flavor and take the edge off that raw tomato-y taste). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the wine and cook for about 1 minute, just to burn off the alcohol. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the tomatoes and stir everything together, making sure to scrape the bottom of the pot to get all those good bits. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add water and bring it to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Reduce the heat to medium-low and cook the sauce for 1½–2 hours at a very low simmer; there should just be a few bubbles here and there. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">If medium-low is too high (every stove is different), reduce the heat to low. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Stir every 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Ladle out about 2 cups of sauce: This is what is known as your "extra sauce." You'll serve it alongside the pasta or freeze it for later. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">To serve, cook the spaghetti in a large pot of salted boiling water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Drain the pasta and add it to the sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Serve it right out of the pot, or transfer to a serving bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Top with grated Parmesan cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>