<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>One-Pot Chicken, Chard, And Couscous Dinner Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/one-pot-chicken-chard-and-couscous-dinner</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 ; skin-on chicken leg quarters </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; kosher salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">10 cloves ; garlic, minced, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; fresh thyme leaf, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; fresh rosemary, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; fresh oregano, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">4 tablespoons ; olive oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 bunches ; rainbow swiss chard </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; cinnamon stick </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">4 ; whole cloves </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 teaspoons ; mustard seed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 teaspoon ; whole allspice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 ; bay leaves, crushed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 teaspoon ; whole black peppercorn </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">2 teaspoons ; coriander seed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">½ teaspoon ; red pepper flakes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 cup ; white wine vinegar ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">½ cup ; water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">1 ; large yellow onion, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">¼ cup ; lemon juice ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">2 cups ; israeli couscous ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">3 cups ; chicken stock ; (720 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">2 tablespoons ; caper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="25">crumbled feta cheese, fresh, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="26">fresh parsley, chopped, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
    <category num="2">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="3">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/123614/hls24_1548366013.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/123614/landscape_720/1548366013</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, season the chicken legs with salt, pepper, 5 cloves of minced garlic, the thyme, rosemary, oregano, and 2 tablespoons of olive oil. Toss to fully coat the chicken, then cover with plastic wrap and marinate in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Prepare the Swiss chard. Cut out the thick stems. Stack the leaves, roll up, then thinly slice into ribbons. Slice the roll in half. Transfer to a bowl and set aside. Slice the chard stems on the bias. Transfer to a medium glass or nonreactive metal bowl and set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large skillet, combine the sugar, 1 tablespoon of salt, the cinnamon stick, cloves, mustard seeds, allspice, bay leaves, peppercorns, coriander seeds, and red pepper flakes. Add the white wine vinegar and water, and stir well. Heat the pan over high heat, bring to a boil, and cook for 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Place a strainer over the bowl of sliced chard stems. Pour the boiling pickling liquid over the stems and discard the solids. Let the stems pickle until the liquid has cooled and the stems have softened, about 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Wipe out the skillet, then heat over medium-high heat with the remaining 2 tablespoons of olive oil until the oil is shimmering. Sear the chicken, skin-side down, until the skin is dark golden brown, 5-7 minutes. Flip and cook on the other side for another 5-7 minutes. Transfer to a plate and set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the onion, remaining 5 cloves of minced garlic, salt, and pepper. Cook, stirring, until the onion is softened and golden brown, about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the lemon juice, Swiss chard leaves, and couscous. Cook until the greens wilt, about 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the chicken stock and bring to a boil. Sprinkle in the capers and return the chicken to the pan, submerging in the cooking liquid. Cover, reduce the heat to low, and simmer for about 15 minutes, until the couscous has puffed up and become tender. Remove the pan from the heat. </step>
    <step num="8">Serve with the pickled chard stems, feta cheese, and parsley. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, season the chicken legs with salt, pepper, 5 cloves of minced garlic, the thyme, rosemary, oregano, and 2 tablespoons of olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Toss to fully coat the chicken, then cover with plastic wrap and marinate in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Prepare the Swiss chard. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cut out the thick stems. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Stack the leaves, roll up, then thinly slice into ribbons. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Slice the roll in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Transfer to a bowl and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Slice the chard stems on the bias. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Transfer to a medium glass or nonreactive metal bowl and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a large skillet, combine the sugar, 1 tablespoon of salt, the cinnamon stick, cloves, mustard seeds, allspice, bay leaves, peppercorns, coriander seeds, and red pepper flakes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the white wine vinegar and water, and stir well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Heat the pan over high heat, bring to a boil, and cook for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Place a strainer over the bowl of sliced chard stems. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Pour the boiling pickling liquid over the stems and discard the solids. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Let the stems pickle until the liquid has cooled and the stems have softened, about 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Wipe out the skillet, then heat over medium-high heat with the remaining 2 tablespoons of olive oil until the oil is shimmering. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Sear the chicken, skin-side down, until the skin is dark golden brown, 5-7 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Flip and cook on the other side for another 5-7 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Transfer to a plate and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add the onion, remaining 5 cloves of minced garlic, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Cook, stirring, until the onion is softened and golden brown, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Add the lemon juice, Swiss chard leaves, and couscous. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Cook until the greens wilt, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Add the chicken stock and bring to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Sprinkle in the capers and return the chicken to the pan, submerging in the cooking liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Cover, reduce the heat to low, and simmer for about 15 minutes, until the couscous has puffed up and become tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Remove the pan from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Serve with the pickled chard stems, feta cheese, and parsley. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>