<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Stuffed Steak Rolls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/stuffed-steak-rolls</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 tablespoons ; canola oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 tablespoons ; garlic, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ; sweet onions, like Vidalia, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 cups ; mushrooms, thinly sliced ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ tablespoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ tablespoon ; freshly ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 lb ; flank steak ; (900 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">4 oz ; baby spinach, 1 package ; (113 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">9 slices ; provolone cheese </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Healthy</category>
    <category num="3">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="4">Dinner</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32178/low_1495125381.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32178/mp4_720x1280/1495125381</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 350°F (177°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Heat one tablespoon of the oil in a pan over medium-high heat. Combine the garlic, onions, mushrooms, salt, and pepper in the pan and cook until almost all of the moisture has evaporated and the onions are caramelizing, 15–20 minutes. Remove from heat and set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">Lay the flank steak on a cutting board. Add salt and pepper on both sides, to taste. </step>
    <step num="3">Spoon the mushroom and onion mixture on top, spreading it evenly across the steak. Sprinkle the spinach on top, followed by the slices of provolone. Press down lightly to compress the spinach. </step>
    <step num="4">Starting at the bottom of the flank steak, roll it up tightly, making sure the grain of the meat is running horizontally. Use six toothpicks to secure the steak roll. Slice the steak roll into six equal rolls. </step>
    <step num="5">Heat the remaining oil in a pan over high heat. Sear the steak rolls on one side for one to two minutes, then flip. Sear the second side for about one minute, then bake for 10–15 minutes, until medium rare. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove the toothpicks, then serve! </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 350°F (177°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Heat one tablespoon of the oil in a pan over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Combine the garlic, onions, mushrooms, salt, and pepper in the pan and cook until almost all of the moisture has evaporated and the onions are caramelizing, 15–20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Remove from heat and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Lay the flank steak on a cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add salt and pepper on both sides, to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Spoon the mushroom and onion mixture on top, spreading it evenly across the steak. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Sprinkle the spinach on top, followed by the slices of provolone. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Press down lightly to compress the spinach. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Starting at the bottom of the flank steak, roll it up tightly, making sure the grain of the meat is running horizontally. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Use six toothpicks to secure the steak roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Slice the steak roll into six equal rolls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Heat the remaining oil in a pan over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Sear the steak rolls on one side for one to two minutes, then flip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Sear the second side for about one minute, then bake for 10–15 minutes, until medium rare. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove the toothpicks, then serve! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>