<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>100-Layer Lasagna Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/100-layer-lasagna</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 stick ; butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; flour ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">8 cups ; milk ; (2 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 teaspoons ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ teaspoon ; nutmeg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; olive oil ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 cups ; onion, finely chopped ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 cups ; carrot, finely chopped ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 cups ; celery, finely chopped ; (450 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">6 lb ; ground beef, 80% lean 20% fat ; (2.5 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">115 oz ; tomato sauce, 4 cans ; (3.5 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ cup ; tomato paste ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">4 cups ; chicken stock ; (960 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 tablespoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">½ tablespoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">110 ; no-boil flat lasagna noodles </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">2 cups ; grated parmesan cheese ; (220 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 cup ; fresh chives, finely chopped ; (40 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Fusion</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/89658/hls24_1523902408.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/89658/landscape_720/1523902408</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Lay down about 6 feet (1.8 meters) of tinfoil on a flat surface. Place place 4 clusters of 2 lasagna noodles towards the left half of the foil sheet, leaving about a ½-inch (1 cm) gap in between each cluster. </step>
    <step num="1">Fold the right half of foil over the noodles, pressing flat. To help you see where the noodles are, run your finger along the edges of the noodles to create a rough outline in the foil. </step>
    <step num="2">Fold the top and bottom flaps of foil over, creasing and pressing flat. </step>
    <step num="3">Flip the foil sheet onto the table so that it’s now standing, then arrange into a square box, using the 4 groups of noodles as a visual guide. Fold and crease over any excess foil to join the ends together, then set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">In a large pot, melt the butter over medium heat. </step>
    <step num="5">Whisk in the flour, cooking until the mixture reaches a light golden color. </step>
    <step num="6">Slowly drizzle in the milk and bring to a boil, whisking constantly until smooth. Mix in salt, pepper, and nutmeg. Bring to a boil. </step>
    <step num="7">Transfer the béchamel to a large bowl and press plastic wrap onto the surface of the sauce to prevent a skin from forming. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="8">Heat oil in a very large pot over high heat. Once the oil begins to shimmer, add the onions, carrots, and celery and cook until the vegetables have started to sweat but aren’t browning. </step>
    <step num="9">Add in the ground beef and use a wooden spoon or spatula to break up the meat into small pieces. </step>
    <step num="10">Cook the beef, stirring occasionally, until half of the liquid has evaporated. </step>
    <step num="11">Add in the tomato sauce, tomato paste, chicken stock, salt, and pepper, stirring to combine evenly and breaking up any last lumps. </step>
    <step num="12">Turn down the heat to low, and simmer, covered, for about 2 hours. </step>
    <step num="13">Preheat oven to 350°F (180°C). </step>
    <step num="14">To assemble, line a greased 9x9-inch (23x23-cm) square baking pan with 2 sheets of foil that extend over the sides. </step>
    <step num="15">Spread a thin layer of béchamel on the lined baking pan and top with 2 lasagna noodles. Spread a thin layer of meat sauce evenly across the noodles, followed by a thin layer of béchamel. Repeat the layering process, following the order of: 2 noodles, meat sauce, and béchamel. Alternate the direction of the lasagna sheets after every layer. </step>
    <step num="16">After 50 layers, place the foil box over the lasagna, helping it stay upright and stable. </step>
    <step num="17">Continue with the layering process until the 99th layer. </step>
    <step num="18">Sprinkle Parmesan on top, then cover the whole lasagna with foil. </step>
    <step num="19">Bake for about 1½ hours, uncovering the foil halfway, until the top is a deep golden brown. </step>
    <step num="20">Cool for at least 2 hours, then carefully lift out the lasagna with the foil sleeves onto a large cutting board. </step>
    <step num="21">Peel away the foil walls, then sprinkle the top of the lasagna generously with chives. </step>
    <step num="22">Cut and serve. </step>
    <step num="23">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Lay down about 6 feet (1.8 meters) of tinfoil on a flat surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Place place 4 clusters of 2 lasagna noodles towards the left half of the foil sheet, leaving about a ½-inch (1 cm) gap in between each cluster. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Fold the right half of foil over the noodles, pressing flat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">To help you see where the noodles are, run your finger along the edges of the noodles to create a rough outline in the foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Fold the top and bottom flaps of foil over, creasing and pressing flat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Flip the foil sheet onto the table so that it’s now standing, then arrange into a square box, using the 4 groups of noodles as a visual guide. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Fold and crease over any excess foil to join the ends together, then set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a large pot, melt the butter over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Whisk in the flour, cooking until the mixture reaches a light golden color. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Slowly drizzle in the milk and bring to a boil, whisking constantly until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Mix in salt, pepper, and nutmeg. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Bring to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Transfer the béchamel to a large bowl and press plastic wrap onto the surface of the sauce to prevent a skin from forming. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Heat oil in a very large pot over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Once the oil begins to shimmer, add the onions, carrots, and celery and cook until the vegetables have started to sweat but aren’t browning. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add in the ground beef and use a wooden spoon or spatula to break up the meat into small pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cook the beef, stirring occasionally, until half of the liquid has evaporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add in the tomato sauce, tomato paste, chicken stock, salt, and pepper, stirring to combine evenly and breaking up any last lumps. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Turn down the heat to low, and simmer, covered, for about 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Preheat oven to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">To assemble, line a greased 9x9-inch (23x23-cm) square baking pan with 2 sheets of foil that extend over the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Spread a thin layer of béchamel on the lined baking pan and top with 2 lasagna noodles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Spread a thin layer of meat sauce evenly across the noodles, followed by a thin layer of béchamel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Repeat the layering process, following the order of: 2 noodles, meat sauce, and béchamel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Alternate the direction of the lasagna sheets after every layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">After 50 layers, place the foil box over the lasagna, helping it stay upright and stable. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Continue with the layering process until the 99th layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Sprinkle Parmesan on top, then cover the whole lasagna with foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Bake for about 1½ hours, uncovering the foil halfway, until the top is a deep golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Cool for at least 2 hours, then carefully lift out the lasagna with the foil sleeves onto a large cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Peel away the foil walls, then sprinkle the top of the lasagna generously with chives. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Cut and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>