<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Herbed Flatbread (Focaccia) 4 Ways Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/herbed-flatbread-focaccia-4-ways</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ cups ; warm water ; (355 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 pack ; active dry yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">4 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (500 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ teaspoon ; dried thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ teaspoon ; fresh rosemary </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">8 oz ; mixed tomato, to taste ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">fresh rosemary, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">caramelized onion, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">8 oz ; mixed olive, to taste ; (135 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">parmesan cheese, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">mozzarella cheese, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">gorgonzola cheese, to taste </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="5">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="6">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="7">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="8">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/27853/low_1490804574.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/27853/mp4_720x1280/1490804574</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Stir yeast packet into water and allow yeast to bloom. (A light foam should appear on top of the water after about 5 minutes. This means the yeast is alive and active.) </step>
    <step num="1">Add olive oil to water and mix. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large bowl, mix flour, salt, pepper, and herbs together. </step>
    <step num="3">Once incorporated, create a small well in the middle and pour in the water/yeast/oil mixture. </step>
    <step num="4">Mix by hand, wetting your working hand before mixing so the dough doesn’t stick to your fingers. The water and flour should come together and form a rough dough that pulls away from the sides of the bowl. </step>
    <step num="5">NOTE: If the dough is too sticky, add more flour in small increments, about 1 tablespoon at a time. If the dough is too dry, add more water, 1 tablespoon at a time. </step>
    <step num="6">Once the dough begins to come together, turn it out onto a lightly floured work surface and knead the dough until it forms a smooth ball. </step>
    <step num="7">Coat the bowl the dough was initially mixed in with about a tablespoon of olive oil and place the dough ball inside. Give it a few turns to coat the dough in the oil. </step>
    <step num="8">Cover and let the dough rise until it doubles in size about 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="9">While the dough rises, prepare a large baking sheet by generously coating it with olive oil. </step>
    <step num="10">Once the dough has risen, turn it out onto the prepared baking sheet and flatten it out into a large rectangle. </step>
    <step num="11">Using a knife or dough scraper, cut the dough into 4 evenly sized rectangles. </step>
    <step num="12">Press the rectangles flat and arrange them with each one pressed into a corner of the baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="13">Cover and let the dough rest for 20 to 30 minutes. Preheat the oven to 450˚F (230˚C) while the dough is resting. </step>
    <step num="14">Depending on the temperature of your kitchen and activeness of the yeast, the 4 rectangles should have risen to be about an 1-inch (2 ½ cm) thick. </step>
    <step num="15">Using your fingers, poke the the dough all over--creating small dimples across the surface. </step>
    <step num="16">Generously coat the tops of the dough rectangles one last time with olive oil (some oil will pool inside of the divots we made with our fingers. That’s ok!) Use a basting brush to ensure all of the dough gets covered with olive oil. </step>
    <step num="17">Top the dough rectangles with your choice of toppings. (We did four different combinations, including tomatoes with fresh rosemary, caramelized onions and parmesan cheese, mixed olive with gorgonzola cheese, and 3-cheese using parmesan, mozzarella, and gorgonzola.) </step>
    <step num="18">Once finished with the toppings, liberally sprinkle the breads with a coarse salt. </step>
    <step num="19">Bake at 450˚F (230˚C) for 20-25 minutes until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="20">Allow the bread to cool for 10 minutes before cutting into equal pieces. </step>
    <step num="21">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Stir yeast packet into water and allow yeast to bloom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">(A light foam should appear on top of the water after about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">This means the yeast is alive and active.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add olive oil to water and mix. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a large bowl, mix flour, salt, pepper, and herbs together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Once incorporated, create a small well in the middle and pour in the water/yeast/oil mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Mix by hand, wetting your working hand before mixing so the dough doesn’t stick to your fingers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">The water and flour should come together and form a rough dough that pulls away from the sides of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">NOTE: If the dough is too sticky, add more flour in small increments, about 1 tablespoon at a time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">If the dough is too dry, add more water, 1 tablespoon at a time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Once the dough begins to come together, turn it out onto a lightly floured work surface and knead the dough until it forms a smooth ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Coat the bowl the dough was initially mixed in with about a tablespoon of olive oil and place the dough ball inside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Give it a few turns to coat the dough in the oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Cover and let the dough rise until it doubles in size about 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">While the dough rises, prepare a large baking sheet by generously coating it with olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Once the dough has risen, turn it out onto the prepared baking sheet and flatten it out into a large rectangle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Using a knife or dough scraper, cut the dough into 4 evenly sized rectangles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Press the rectangles flat and arrange them with each one pressed into a corner of the baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Cover and let the dough rest for 20 to 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Preheat the oven to 450˚F (230˚C) while the dough is resting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Depending on the temperature of your kitchen and activeness of the yeast, the 4 rectangles should have risen to be about an 1-inch (2 ½ cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Using your fingers, poke the the dough all over--creating small dimples across the surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Generously coat the tops of the dough rectangles one last time with olive oil (some oil will pool inside of the divots we made with our fingers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">That’s ok!) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Use a basting brush to ensure all of the dough gets covered with olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Top the dough rectangles with your choice of toppings. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">(We did four different combinations, including tomatoes with fresh rosemary, caramelized onions and parmesan cheese, mixed olive with gorgonzola cheese, and 3-cheese using parmesan, mozzarella, and gorgonzola.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Once finished with the toppings, liberally sprinkle the breads with a coarse salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Bake at 450˚F (230˚C) for 20-25 minutes until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Allow the bread to cool for 10 minutes before cutting into equal pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>