<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Classic Coq Au Vin Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/classic-coq-au-vin</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 lb ; skin-on chicken leg quarter ; (1.8 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 sprigs ; fresh thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 ; bay leaves </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ bunch ; fresh parsley stems </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 cups ; red burgundy wine, or any dry red wine ; (720 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; bacon, cubed ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">3 ; large carrots, peeled and minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ; large white onion, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ lb ; cremini mushroom, sliced ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ lb ; cremini mushroom, quartered ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">5 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 tablespoons ; tomato paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 tablespoons ; all-purpose flour </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">¼ cup ; brandy ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">2 tablespoons ; extra virgin olive oil, plus more as needed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">8 oz ; pearl onion, peeled ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">1 pinch ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">¼ cup ; fresh parsley, chopped, for garnish ; (10 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">1 ; baguette, sliced, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">French</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113318/hls24_1540513305.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113318/landscape_720/1540513305</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, season the chicken with salt and pepper. Toss until well coated. </step>
    <step num="1">Tie the thyme sprigs, bay leaves, and parsley stems together with kitchen twine to make a bouquet garni. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the bouquet garni to the bowl with the chicken. Pour the wine over the chicken. Cover with plastic wrap and refrigerate for at least 2 hours or, even better, overnight. </step>
    <step num="3">In a large Dutch oven, cook the bacon over medium-low heat until the fat has rendered and the bacon is crisp, 15 minutes. Using a slotted spoon, transfer the bacon to a paper towel-lined plate, leaving any excess fat in the pot. </step>
    <step num="4">Remove the chicken from the marinade, reserving the liquid, and place on a paper towel-lined sheet pan. Pat the chicken with more paper towels until completely dry. </step>
    <step num="5">Heat the bacon fat over medium heat until nearly smoking. Working in batches, add the chicken legs skin-side down in a single layer and cook until well browned, 5 minutes per side. Remove the chicken from the pot and set aside. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the carrots, onion, sliced mushrooms, and garlic to the pot. Cook until the vegetables are softened and lightly browned, about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Stir in the tomato paste and cook for 3 minutes, until darkened and fragrant. Then, sprinkle in the flour and cook for another minute, until incorporated. </step>
    <step num="8">Pour the brandy into the pot and cook, scraping up any browned bits at the bottom of the pot, until the liquid has evaporated, 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the reserved marinade, including the bouquet garni. Stir to incorporate, then bring to a boil and cook until the liquid is reduced by half, about 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="10">Return the chicken and half the cooked bacon to the pot. Cover, reduce the heat to low, and simmer for 1 hour, until the chicken is tender and the sauce has thickened. </step>
    <step num="11">Meanwhile, heat the olive oil and butter in a large, preferably nonstick skillet over medium-high heat. Add the pearl onions and a pinch of salt and sugar. Cover, reduce the heat to low, and cook for 15 minutes, shaking the skillet often to move the onions around. </step>
    <step num="12">Uncover, add the quartered mushrooms, and increase the heat to medium-high. Continue to cook until all the vegetables have softened, 5-8 minutes. Add the onions and mushrooms to the coq au vin. </step>
    <step num="13">Sprinkle with chopped parsley and the reserved bacon. Serve with crusty bread. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, season the chicken with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Toss until well coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Tie the thyme sprigs, bay leaves, and parsley stems together with kitchen twine to make a bouquet garni. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the bouquet garni to the bowl with the chicken. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour the wine over the chicken. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cover with plastic wrap and refrigerate for at least 2 hours or, even better, overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a large Dutch oven, cook the bacon over medium-low heat until the fat has rendered and the bacon is crisp, 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Using a slotted spoon, transfer the bacon to a paper towel-lined plate, leaving any excess fat in the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Remove the chicken from the marinade, reserving the liquid, and place on a paper towel-lined sheet pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Pat the chicken with more paper towels until completely dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Heat the bacon fat over medium heat until nearly smoking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Working in batches, add the chicken legs skin-side down in a single layer and cook until well browned, 5 minutes per side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove the chicken from the pot and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the carrots, onion, sliced mushrooms, and garlic to the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Cook until the vegetables are softened and lightly browned, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Stir in the tomato paste and cook for 3 minutes, until darkened and fragrant. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Then, sprinkle in the flour and cook for another minute, until incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Pour the brandy into the pot and cook, scraping up any browned bits at the bottom of the pot, until the liquid has evaporated, 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the reserved marinade, including the bouquet garni. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Stir to incorporate, then bring to a boil and cook until the liquid is reduced by half, about 15 minutes </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Return the chicken and half the cooked bacon to the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Cover, reduce the heat to low, and simmer for 1 hour, until the chicken is tender and the sauce has thickened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Meanwhile, heat the olive oil and butter in a large, preferably nonstick skillet over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Add the pearl onions and a pinch of salt and sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Cover, reduce the heat to low, and cook for 15 minutes, shaking the skillet often to move the onions around. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Uncover, add the quartered mushrooms, and increase the heat to medium-high. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Continue to cook until all the vegetables have softened, 5-8 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Add the onions and mushrooms to the coq au vin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Sprinkle with chopped parsley and the reserved bacon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Serve with crusty bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>