<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Homemade Gluten-Free Pasta Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/homemade-gluten-free-pasta</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 tablespoons ; flax meal </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; cold water, divided plus 9 tablespoons ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; brown rice flour, plus more for dusting ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; quinoa flour ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 teaspoons ; xanthan gum </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ teaspoons ; kosher salt, plus more for cooking </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 tablespoons ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">sauce of choice, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">grated parmesan cheese, to serve </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
    <category num="2">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/137494/hls24_1561678929.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/137494/landscape_720/1561678929</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a small bowl, whisk together the flax meal and 9 tablespoons of cold water. Set aside for 15 minutes, until thickened and gel-like. </step>
    <step num="1">Meanwhile, in a medium bowl, mix together the brown rice flour, quinoa flour, xanthan gum, and salt. Create a well in the center of the mixture. Pour the flax mixture, remaining ¼ cup (60 ml) cold water, and olive oil into the well. Begin to mix dough together with spatula, then transfer the dough to a clean surface and knead until dough comes together and there are no dry spots remaining. Transfer dough back into bowl and cover. Let rest for 20 minutes to allow the flours and xanthan gum to hydrate. </step>
    <step num="2">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="3">Bring a large pot of water to a rolling boil. Season generously with salt. </step>
    <step num="4">Divide the dough into 6 equal pieces. Shape each piece into a flat rectangle. Working 1 portion at a time, lightly dust with flour and use a lightly floured rolling pin to roll out to a long, thin rectangle about 3 inches (7 cm) wide and 12 inches (30 cm) long and ¹⁄₁₆-inch (1 ½ cm) thick. </step>
    <step num="5">Feed the rectangle through a pasta roller, starting on the thickest setting and gradually increasing the setting with each pass until the dough is approximately half as thick, but not so thin that it tears. </step>
    <step num="6">Cut the pasta sheets in half. Feed each half through a fettuccine cutter and twirl each portion into nests on the prepared baking sheet while you cut the rest of the pasta. </step>
    <step num="7">Boil the pasta for 2-3 minutes, until al dente but not falling apart. </step>
    <step num="8">Drain the pasta and toss with the sauce of your choosing. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a small bowl, whisk together the flax meal and 9 tablespoons of cold water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Set aside for 15 minutes, until thickened and gel-like. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Meanwhile, in a medium bowl, mix together the brown rice flour, quinoa flour, xanthan gum, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Create a well in the center of the mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour the flax mixture, remaining ¼ cup (60 ml) cold water, and olive oil into the well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Begin to mix dough together with spatula, then transfer the dough to a clean surface and knead until dough comes together and there are no dry spots remaining. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Transfer dough back into bowl and cover. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Let rest for 20 minutes to allow the flours and xanthan gum to hydrate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Bring a large pot of water to a rolling boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Season generously with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Divide the dough into 6 equal pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Shape each piece into a flat rectangle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Working 1 portion at a time, lightly dust with flour and use a lightly floured rolling pin to roll out to a long, thin rectangle about 3 inches (7 cm) wide and 12 inches (30 cm) long and ¹⁄₁₆-inch (1 ½ cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Feed the rectangle through a pasta roller, starting on the thickest setting and gradually increasing the setting with each pass until the dough is approximately half as thick, but not so thin that it tears. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cut the pasta sheets in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Feed each half through a fettuccine cutter and twirl each portion into nests on the prepared baking sheet while you cut the rest of the pasta. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Boil the pasta for 2-3 minutes, until al dente but not falling apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Drain the pasta and toss with the sauce of your choosing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>