<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chiffon Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chiffon-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">7 ; large eggs, seperated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¾ cup ; cold water ; (180 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; canola oil ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 teaspoons ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; lemon zest </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ½ cups ; sugar, divided ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ teaspoon ; cream of tartar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; butter, 2 sticks, softened ; (230 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 cup ; sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 cup ; evaporated milk ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">seasonal fruit, such as berries, for decoration </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97594/hls24_1528329348.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97594/landscape_720/1528329348</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (160˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a medium bowl, combine the egg yolks, water, oil, vanilla, and lemon zest. Whisk well to combine. </step>
    <step num="2">Sift the flour and baking powder into a separate medium bowl. Add ¾ cup (150 grams) of sugar and salt and whisk to combine. </step>
    <step num="3">Pour the wet ingredients into the dry ingredients and whisk well. </step>
    <step num="4">In a large bowl, beat the egg whites and cream of tartar with an electric hand mixer until foamy. Gradually add the remaining sugar and beat until soft peaks form and the egg whites are glossy. </step>
    <step num="5">Pour the egg yolk batter into the egg whites and fold to combine with a spatula. </step>
    <step num="6">Divide the batter between 2 ungreased 8.5-inch (21 cm) round cake pans (not greasing will help the chiffon cakes rise). </step>
    <step num="7">Bake for 40-50 minutes, then increase the temperature to 350˚F (180˚C) and bake for 10-15 minutes more, or until a toothpick inserted in the center of a cake comes out clean. </step>
    <step num="8">While the cakes are baking, make the buttercream frosting: combine the butter and about half of the sugar in a large bowl and cream with a hand mixer until combined. Add the rest of the sugar and beat to incorporate. With the mixer running, slowly add the evaporated milk and beat until smooth. </step>
    <step num="9">Remove the cakes from the oven and cool the cake upside down. Once cool to the touch, sliding an offset spatula around the edges to release the cakes from the pans. </step>
    <step num="10">Cut off the tops of the cakes so the surfaces are flat and smooth. </step>
    <step num="11">Set 1 cake on a cake platter or serving dish. Spread buttercream over the top of the cake with an offset spatula and sprinkle with some seasonal fruit. Cover the fruit with buttercream. </step>
    <step num="12">Place the other cake on top. Spread buttercream over the top, keeping the sides exposed, and decorate with seasonal fruit and edible flowers. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (160˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a medium bowl, combine the egg yolks, water, oil, vanilla, and lemon zest. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Whisk well to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Sift the flour and baking powder into a separate medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add ¾ cup (150 grams) of sugar and salt and whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour the wet ingredients into the dry ingredients and whisk well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a large bowl, beat the egg whites and cream of tartar with an electric hand mixer until foamy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Gradually add the remaining sugar and beat until soft peaks form and the egg whites are glossy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Pour the egg yolk batter into the egg whites and fold to combine with a spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Divide the batter between 2 ungreased 8.5-inch (21 cm) round cake pans (not greasing will help the chiffon cakes rise). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Bake for 40-50 minutes, then increase the temperature to 350˚F (180˚C) and bake for 10-15 minutes more, or until a toothpick inserted in the center of a cake comes out clean. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">While the cakes are baking, make the buttercream frosting: combine the butter and about half of the sugar in a large bowl and cream with a hand mixer until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the rest of the sugar and beat to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">With the mixer running, slowly add the evaporated milk and beat until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove the cakes from the oven and cool the cake upside down. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Once cool to the touch, sliding an offset spatula around the edges to release the cakes from the pans. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Cut off the tops of the cakes so the surfaces are flat and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Set 1 cake on a cake platter or serving dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Spread buttercream over the top of the cake with an offset spatula and sprinkle with some seasonal fruit. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Cover the fruit with buttercream </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Place the other cake on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Spread buttercream over the top, keeping the sides exposed, and decorate with seasonal fruit and edible flowers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>