<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Halloween Party Punch Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/halloween-party-punch</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">40 oz ; lychees in syrup, peeled and pitted, liquid reserved ; (1 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">40 ; blueberries </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">red food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">12 cups ; cranberry juice ; (3 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 cups ; ginger ale ; (720 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 cups ; reserved lychee juice ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; vodka, optional ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 ; food-safe gloves, powder-free nitrile or latex gloves </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Drinks</category>
    <category num="4">Happy Hour</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/110591/hls24_1538080537.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/110591/landscape_720/1538080537</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Fill each plastic glove with water until about 2 inches (5 cm) from the opening of the glove. Twist the opening and tie into a knot. </step>
    <step num="1">Place in a tray, draping some gloves over others if you want some of the fingers to appear bent. Freeze for at least 4 hours, or overnight, until solid. </step>
    <step num="2">Make the lychee eyeballs: Place a blueberry inside each lychee. </step>
    <step num="3">Use a toothpick to paint a bit of red food coloring on the outside of the lychees to mimic veins on an eyeball. Add the lychees to a large punch bowl. </step>
    <step num="4">Pour in the cranberry juice, ginger ale, reserved lychee juice, and vodka, if using. </step>
    <step num="5">Remove the gloves from the freezer and run under warm water for 15 seconds. Use scissors to cut off the knot and then slide the ice out of each glove and into the punch. </step>
    <step num="6">To serve, ladle punch and a couple eyeballs into glasses. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Fill each plastic glove with water until about 2 inches (5 cm) from the opening of the glove. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Twist the opening and tie into a knot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Place in a tray, draping some gloves over others if you want some of the fingers to appear bent. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Freeze for at least 4 hours, or overnight, until solid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Make the lychee eyeballs: Place a blueberry inside each lychee. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Use a toothpick to paint a bit of red food coloring on the outside of the lychees to mimic veins on an eyeball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the lychees to a large punch bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Pour in the cranberry juice, ginger ale, reserved lychee juice, and vodka, if using. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Remove the gloves from the freezer and run under warm water for 15 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Use scissors to cut off the knot and then slide the ice out of each glove and into the punch. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">To serve, ladle punch and a couple eyeballs into glasses. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>