<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chili Mac 'N' Cheese Pops Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chili-mac-n-cheese-pops</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 tablespoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ; large yellow onion, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; green bell pepper, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 lb ; ground beef ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 ; tomatoes, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">15.5 oz ; red kidney bean, 1 can ; (440 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">4.5 oz ; green chile, 1 can ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 tablespoons ; tomato paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 teaspoons ; cumin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 tablespoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 tablespoon ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">¼ teaspoon ; cayenne pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 lime ; lime, juiced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">5 cups ; whole milk ; (1.2 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 lb ; elbow macaroni ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">½ cup ; unsalted butter, 1 stick ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">½ teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">1 ½ cups ; grated cheddar cheese ; (165 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">1 cup ; grated cheddar cheese ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">9 oz ; corn tortilla, 1 bag ; (255 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">1 cup ; all-purpose flour ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">3 ; large eggs, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="25">oil, for frying </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="26">3 tablespoons ; fresh cilantro, chopped, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="27">18 ; bamboo skewers, thick </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Game Day</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/86385/hls24_1521828439.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/86385/landscape_720/1521828439</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat, until shimmering. Add the onion and cook until caramelized, about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the green bell pepper and cook until softened, about 3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the ground beef, break apart, and cook until no longer pink, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the tomato, kidney beans, green chiles, tomato paste, cumin, pepper, salt, garlic powder, paprika, cayenne pepper, and lime juice. Mix thoroughly and let simmer for about 10 minutes. Remove the pan from the heat and set aside until ready to use. </step>
    <step num="4">In a large pot over medium-high heat, add the milk and macaroni. Stir continuously until the milk reaches a simmer and the pasta is cooked. </step>
    <step num="5">Turn off the heat, and stir in the butter, salt, pepper, Monterey Jack, and cheddar cheeses. Mix until all of the ingredients are incorporated. </step>
    <step num="6">Line a 9x13-inch (23x33 cm) casserole dish with parchment paper so the paper is hanging over the sides of the dish. </step>
    <step num="7">Spread a third of the macaroni evenly on to the bottom of the dish and sprinkle half of the cheddar cheese over the top. Spread half of the chili over the cheese. Spread another third of macaroni over the chili, and sprinkle the remaining cup of cheddar cheese on top. Spread the rest of the chili over the cheese. Spread the rest of the macaroni over the chili. </step>
    <step num="8">Cover the casserole dish with a piece of parchment paper. Freeze for at least 6 hours, up to 12 hours. </step>
    <step num="9">Remove the casserole from the dish using the parchment paper to help you pull it out. Place on a work surface. </step>
    <step num="10">Insert 9 skewers into one long side of the casserole 4 inches (10 cm) deep, spacing about 2 inches (5 cm) apart. Repeat on the other long side of the casserole. Cut the casserole in half vertically, then make 8 horizontal cuts in between the skewers. </step>
    <step num="11">Crush the corn chips until they are a coarse sand-like texture, then pour onto a large plate. Put the flour and eggs in separate medium dishes. </step>
    <step num="12">Place one of the pops in the flour, turning to coat on all sides, and tap off the excess flour. Place the pop in the egg and coat until there is no exposed flour. Place the pop in the crushed corn chips and coat. Repeat with the remaining pops. </step>
    <step num="13">Heat the oil in a large pot until the temperature reaches 325˚F (165˚C). </step>
    <step num="14">Fry the skewers 2 at a time for 8 minutes, until browned and crisp. </step>
    <step num="15">Transfer to a wire rack or paper towels to drain. </step>
    <step num="16">Sprinkle with cilantro and serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="17">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat, until shimmering. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the onion and cook until caramelized, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the green bell pepper and cook until softened, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the ground beef, break apart, and cook until no longer pink, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the tomato, kidney beans, green chiles, tomato paste, cumin, pepper, salt, garlic powder, paprika, cayenne pepper, and lime juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Mix thoroughly and let simmer for about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove the pan from the heat and set aside until ready to use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a large pot over medium-high heat, add the milk and macaroni. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Stir continuously until the milk reaches a simmer and the pasta is cooked. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Turn off the heat, and stir in the butter, salt, pepper, Monterey Jack, and cheddar cheeses. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Mix until all of the ingredients are incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Line a 9x13-inch (23x33 cm) casserole dish with parchment paper so the paper is hanging over the sides of the dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Spread a third of the macaroni evenly on to the bottom of the dish and sprinkle half of the cheddar cheese over the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Spread half of the chili over the cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Spread another third of macaroni over the chili, and sprinkle the remaining cup of cheddar cheese on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Spread the rest of the chili over the cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Spread the rest of the macaroni over the chili. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cover the casserole dish with a piece of parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Freeze for at least 6 hours, up to 12 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Remove the casserole from the dish using the parchment paper to help you pull it out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Place on a work surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Insert 9 skewers into one long side of the casserole 4 inches (10 cm) deep, spacing about 2 inches (5 cm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Repeat on the other long side of the casserole. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Cut the casserole in half vertically, then make 8 horizontal cuts in between the skewers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Crush the corn chips until they are a coarse sand-like texture, then pour onto a large plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Put the flour and eggs in separate medium dishes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Place one of the pops in the flour, turning to coat on all sides, and tap off the excess flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Place the pop in the egg and coat until there is no exposed flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Place the pop in the crushed corn chips and coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Repeat with the remaining pops. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Heat the oil in a large pot until the temperature reaches 325˚F (165˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Fry the skewers 2 at a time for 8 minutes, until browned and crisp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Transfer to a wire rack or paper towels to drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Sprinkle with cilantro and serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>