<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Spring Vegetable Chowder Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/spring-vegetable-chowder</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¼ cup ; olive oil, divided, plus more for drizzling ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">20 oz ; riced cauliflower ; (565 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">5 oz ; leek, tough green ends removed, cut into half moons and rinsed ; (140 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">5 cloves ; garlic, smashed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; kosher salt, plus 2 teaspoons, divided, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 cups ; vegetable stock ; (960 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; non-dairy milk, plus more to taste, divided ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">10 oz ; asparagus, woody stems removed, cut into 1/2 in (1 1/4 cm) pieces ; (285 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">6 oz ; english pea, frozen ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ; lemon, zest </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; fresh basil, plus more for garnish ; (10 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ½ lb ; medium red potato, cut into 1/2 in (1 1/4 cm) cubes ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">cold water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 tablespoons ; fresh lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">freshly ground black pepper, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegan</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/127421/hls24_1552682474.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/127421/landscape_720/1552682474</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large pot, heat 2 tablespoons of olive oil over medium heat. Once the oil is shimmering, add the riced cauliflower, leeks, garlic, and 1 teaspoon of salt. Sauté for 2 minutes, until the leeks just begin to soften. </step>
    <step num="1">Pour in the vegetable stock and 2 cups (480 ml) of non-dairy milk. Increase the heat to medium-high and bring to a boil. Reduce the heat to medium, cover, and simmer for 15-20 minutes, until the cauliflower is completely broken down and tender. </step>
    <step num="2">Meanwhile, in a large pan, heat 2 tablespoons of olive oil over medium heat. Add the asparagus, peas, and 1 teaspoon of salt. Sauté for 2 minutes, until the vegetables are bright green with some crunch. Remove the pan from the heat and stir in the lemon zest and basil. Transfer to a bowl and set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">Wipe out the pan and add the potatoes and enough cold water to cover by 1 inch (1 ¼ cm). Season with 1 tablespoon of salt. Bring to a boil. Once boiling, reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer for 8-10 minutes, until the potatoes are easily pierced with a fork but not mushy. Drain and set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">Remove the pot with the cauliflower from the heat. Blend with an immersion blender until completely smooth and creamy. Add up to 1 cup (240 ml) non-dairy milk or water if needed to thin to your desired consistency. </step>
    <step num="5">Stir in the reserved asparagus, peas, potatoes, and the lemon juice. Season to taste with salt. </step>
    <step num="6">Ladle into bowls and garnish with fresh basil, a drizzle of olive oil, and freshly ground black pepper. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large pot, heat 2 tablespoons of olive oil over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Once the oil is shimmering, add the riced cauliflower, leeks, garlic, and 1 teaspoon of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Sauté for 2 minutes, until the leeks just begin to soften. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Pour in the vegetable stock and 2 cups (480 ml) of non-dairy milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Increase the heat to medium-high and bring to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Reduce the heat to medium, cover, and simmer for 15-20 minutes, until the cauliflower is completely broken down and tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Meanwhile, in a large pan, heat 2 tablespoons of olive oil over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the asparagus, peas, and 1 teaspoon of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Sauté for 2 minutes, until the vegetables are bright green with some crunch. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove the pan from the heat and stir in the lemon zest and basil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Transfer to a bowl and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Wipe out the pan and add the potatoes and enough cold water to cover by 1 inch (1 ¼ cm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Season with 1 tablespoon of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Bring to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Once boiling, reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer for 8-10 minutes, until the potatoes are easily pierced with a fork but not mushy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Drain and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Remove the pot with the cauliflower from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Blend with an immersion blender until completely smooth and creamy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add up to 1 cup (240 ml) non-dairy milk or water if needed to thin to your desired consistency. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Stir in the reserved asparagus, peas, potatoes, and the lemon juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Season to taste with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Ladle into bowls and garnish with fresh basil, a drizzle of olive oil, and freshly ground black pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>