<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chicken And Spinach Pull-Apart Bread Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chicken-and-spinach-pull-apart-bread</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ lb ; rotisserie chicken ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">10 oz ; cream cheese, softened ; (285 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">⅔ cup ; spinach, cooked and drained ; (25 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 cups ; shredded mozzarella cheese ; (230 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">4 cups ; flour ; (500 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">4 tablespoons ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">4 tablespoons ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 teaspoons ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">12 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, cold </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 cups ; whole milk ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="2">Sides</category>
    <category num="3">Game Day</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/80043/hls24_1519164602.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/80043/landscape_720/1519164602</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 400°F (200°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Sift together the flour, sugar, baking powder, and salt in another large mixing bowl. Cut unsalted butter into small chunks and add to bowl or use a cheese grater to grate butter into smaller pieces. </step>
    <step num="2">Use a fork to incorporate the butter into the flour mixture until it forms a crumbly texture. Add milk and stir the dough until it is thick and pulls away from the sides of the bowl. </step>
    <step num="3">Transfer dough to a lightly floured, flat surface. Pat the dough down to about 1-inch (2 cm) in thickness, fold in half, and pat down once more to 1-inch (2 cm) in thickness. Cover with a towel and let rest for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">While dough rests, combine chicken, cream cheese, spinach, mozzarella cheese, garlic powder, pepper, and salt in a large mixing bowl. </step>
    <step num="5">Lightly flour a rolling pin and roll out dough out to about ½-centimeter (¼ inch) thickness. Use the lip of a cup to cut out 45 circles. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove chicken spinach dip from the refrigerator and fill each dough circle with 1 tablespoon of dip. Fold each circle in half and press down the edges to seal the dip inside the dough. Fold the left side and right side of each half circle towards each other like a fortune cookie. </step>
    <step num="7">Place the stuffed dough in an 11-inch (28 cm) nonstick or greased tart pan. Make an outer circle and work your way in, creating 4 circles total. Brush with egg wash. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake for 25 minutes, or until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 400°F (200°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Sift together the flour, sugar, baking powder, and salt in another large mixing bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cut unsalted butter into small chunks and add to bowl or use a cheese grater to grate butter into smaller pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Use a fork to incorporate the butter into the flour mixture until it forms a crumbly texture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add milk and stir the dough until it is thick and pulls away from the sides of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Transfer dough to a lightly floured, flat surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Pat the dough down to about 1-inch (2 cm) in thickness, fold in half, and pat down once more to 1-inch (2 cm) in thickness. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cover with a towel and let rest for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">While dough rests, combine chicken, cream cheese, spinach, mozzarella cheese, garlic powder, pepper, and salt in a large mixing bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Lightly flour a rolling pin and roll out dough out to about ½-centimeter (¼ inch) thickness. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Use the lip of a cup to cut out 45 circles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove chicken spinach dip from the refrigerator and fill each dough circle with 1 tablespoon of dip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Fold each circle in half and press down the edges to seal the dip inside the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Fold the left side and right side of each half circle towards each other like a fortune cookie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Place the stuffed dough in an 11-inch (28 cm) nonstick or greased tart pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Make an outer circle and work your way in, creating 4 circles total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Brush with egg wash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Bake for 25 minutes, or until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>