<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Strawberry Shortcake Meringue Nests Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/strawberry-shortcake-meringue-nests</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; sugar, divided ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 ; large egg whites, room temperature </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 pinch ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 cups ; strawberry, hulled and thinly sliced, plus 2 cups (300 G) hulled and quartered, divided ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ teaspoons ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; whipped cream, lightly sweetened ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; pound cake, cubed (1/2 in (1 1/4 cm) cubes) ; (225 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Date Night</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/133190/hls24_1558128363.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/133190/landscape_720/1558128363</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 200°F (93°C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">Spread ¾ cup (150 G) of sugar on the baking sheet, then bake for 7 minutes to warm. Remove the sugar from the oven and leave the oven on. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large clean, dry bowl, beat the egg whites with an electric hand mixer on low speed until foamy, then add the salt. While beating, add the warm sugar 1 tablespoon at a time, gradually increasing the mixer speed, until thick and shiny peaks form, 5-7 minutes. Add the vanilla and fold in until just incorporated. </step>
    <step num="3">Line 2 baking sheets with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="4">Heap 10 equal scoops of meringue onto the baking sheets, spacing at least 1 inch (2 ½ cm) apart. Use the back of a spoon to create a divot in the center of each mound. </step>
    <step num="5">Bake for about 90 minutes, until the meringues lift cleanly off the parchment. Once done, turn off the oven and let the meringues cool in the oven for 2 hours, up to overnight. When removed from the oven, the meringues should sound hollow when tapped. </step>
    <step num="6">Meanwhile, make the strawberry puree: In a small saucepan, combine the thinly sliced strawberries, ¼ cup (50 G) sugar, and the lemon juice and let sit for 10 minutes to macerate, until some of the juices have released. </step>
    <step num="7">Transfer the pan to the stove and cook over medium heat for 10 minutes, until the strawberries have slightly softened but are still vibrant red. Remove from heat and push through a fine-mesh sieve to remove any seeds. Let cool. Store in the refrigerator until ready to use. </step>
    <step num="8">To serve, heap ¼ cup (60 ml) whipped cream onto each meringue nest. Top with 1 heaping tablespoon pound cake cubes and 2 tablespoons quartered strawberries. Drizzle each with 2 tablespoons strawberry puree. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 200°F (93°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Spread ¾ cup (150 G) of sugar on the baking sheet, then bake for 7 minutes to warm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Remove the sugar from the oven and leave the oven on. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a large clean, dry bowl, beat the egg whites with an electric hand mixer on low speed until foamy, then add the salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">While beating, add the warm sugar 1 tablespoon at a time, gradually increasing the mixer speed, until thick and shiny peaks form, 5-7 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the vanilla and fold in until just incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Line 2 baking sheets with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Heap 10 equal scoops of meringue onto the baking sheets, spacing at least 1 inch (2 ½ cm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Use the back of a spoon to create a divot in the center of each mound. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Bake for about 90 minutes, until the meringues lift cleanly off the parchment. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Once done, turn off the oven and let the meringues cool in the oven for 2 hours, up to overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">When removed from the oven, the meringues should sound hollow when tapped. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Meanwhile, make the strawberry puree: In a small saucepan, combine the thinly sliced strawberries, ¼ cup (50 G) sugar, and the lemon juice and let sit for 10 minutes to macerate, until some of the juices have released. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Transfer the pan to the stove and cook over medium heat for 10 minutes, until the strawberries have slightly softened but are still vibrant red. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove from heat and push through a fine-mesh sieve to remove any seeds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Let cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Store in the refrigerator until ready to use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">To serve, heap ¼ cup (60 ml) whipped cream onto each meringue nest. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Top with 1 heaping tablespoon pound cake cubes and 2 tablespoons quartered strawberries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Drizzle each with 2 tablespoons strawberry puree. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>