<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Short Rib Ragù Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/short-rib-ragu</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 lb ; bone-in beef short rib, cut into 2-inch (5-cm) pieces ; (905 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 teaspoons ; kosher salt, divided, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 teaspoons ; freshly ground black pepper, divided, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; yellow onion, diced ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ cups ; carrot, diced ; (180 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 tablespoons ; tomato paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 cups ; port or red wine ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">28 oz ; crushed tomato, 1 can ; (795 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; beef stock ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 tablespoon ; dijon mustard </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 ; bay leaves </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">6 sprigs ; fresh thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 cup ; water, as needed ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">2 lb ; pappardelle pasta ; (905 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">fresh parsley, finely chopped, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">grated parmesan cheese, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Italian</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Date Night</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98669/hls24_1529015897.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98669/landscape_720/1529015897</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Pat the short ribs with paper towels to remove any excess moisture, then season generously with 2 teaspoons kosher salt and 2 teaspoons pepper. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the olive oil to a Dutch oven or large, heavy-bottomed pot and heat over high heat until shimmering. Add half the short ribs and sear on each side until deep brown, about 7 minutes total. Remove from the pan and set aside. Repeat with the remaining short ribs. </step>
    <step num="2">Discard all but 1 tablespoon of rendered fat from the pot. Add the onion, carrot, garlic, 1 teaspoon of salt, and 1 teaspoon of pepper. Sauté over medium heat until the vegetables are softened, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the tomato paste and sauté for a few more minutes, until darkened and thickened. </step>
    <step num="4">Pour in the wine and use a wooden spoon to scrape any browned bits, or fond, from the bottom and sides of the pan. Reduce the liquid by half, about 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the crushed tomatoes, beef stock, mustard, bay leaves, and thyme to the pot. Stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the short ribs, making sure the meat is submerged. Bring to a boil, then reduce the heat to low and cover. Simmer for about 2 hours, stirring occasionally. Add up to 1 cup (240 ml) of water as needed if the sauce gets too thick. Skim excess fat off the top as needed. The short ribs are done when the meat pulls apart easily. </step>
    <step num="7">Discard any bones that the meat has fallen off of, as well as the bay leaves and thyme stems. Transfer the short ribs to a cutting board. Pull out any remaining bones and discard. Using two forks, shred the meat, then return to the pot. </step>
    <step num="8">Add salt and pepper to taste. Simmer for 15 minutes over low heat. </step>
    <step num="9">Cook the pasta according to the package instructions. Plate the pasta in shallow bowls and ladle a scoop of ragù on top. Garnish with finely chopped parsley and freshly grated Parmesan cheese. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Pat the short ribs with paper towels to remove any excess moisture, then season generously with 2 teaspoons kosher salt and 2 teaspoons pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the olive oil to a Dutch oven or large, heavy-bottomed pot and heat over high heat until shimmering. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add half the short ribs and sear on each side until deep brown, about 7 minutes total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Remove from the pan and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Repeat with the remaining short ribs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Discard all but 1 tablespoon of rendered fat from the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the onion, carrot, garlic, 1 teaspoon of salt, and 1 teaspoon of pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Sauté over medium heat until the vegetables are softened, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the tomato paste and sauté for a few more minutes, until darkened and thickened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Pour in the wine and use a wooden spoon to scrape any browned bits, or fond, from the bottom and sides of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Reduce the liquid by half, about 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the crushed tomatoes, beef stock, mustard, bay leaves, and thyme to the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the short ribs, making sure the meat is submerged. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Bring to a boil, then reduce the heat to low and cover. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Simmer for about 2 hours, stirring occasionally. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add up to 1 cup (240 ml) of water as needed if the sauce gets too thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Skim excess fat off the top as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">The short ribs are done when the meat pulls apart easily. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Discard any bones that the meat has fallen off of, as well as the bay leaves and thyme stems. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Transfer the short ribs to a cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Pull out any remaining bones and discard. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Using two forks, shred the meat, then return to the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Add salt and pepper to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Simmer for 15 minutes over low heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Cook the pasta according to the package instructions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Plate the pasta in shallow bowls and ladle a scoop of ragù on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Garnish with finely chopped parsley and freshly grated Parmesan cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>