<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Baked Sweet Potato Fries Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/baked-sweet-potato-fries</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ; large sweet potatoes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">water, for soaking </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; corn starch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; olive oil, or vegetable oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ teaspoon ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ teaspoon ; brown sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">shredded parmesan cheese, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">fresh parsley, optional, chopped </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Healthy</category>
    <category num="4">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="5">Sides</category>
    <category num="6">Game Day</category>
    <category num="7">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32173/low_1495125402.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32173/mp4_720x1280/1495125402</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Rinse and peel sweet potatoes. </step>
    <step num="1">To cut into fries, cut a small sliver off the edge of the potatoes lengthwise to create a flat side for them to rest on. Turn the potato over to lay on its flat side. Cut each slice lengthwise into three to four fries. </step>
    <step num="2">Place the fries in a bowl of water and soak for one hour. (This helps remove excess starch from the potatoes so your fries will be crispier.) Rinse and dry off. </step>
    <step num="3">Preheat the oven to 425°F (220°C). </step>
    <step num="4">In a large bowl or gallon bag, toss the fries with cornstarch until they’re evenly coated. Then add the oil and toss to coat. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the pepper, paprika, garlic powder, and brown sugar and toss to evenly distribute your spices. (Hold off on adding the salt until after baking. This will help make sure the fries are crispy.) </step>
    <step num="6">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper or aluminum foil and spray with nonstick cooking spray. Lay out the french fries, being sure not to overcrowd the pan. (You may need two pans, depending on how large your pans are. Avoid overcrowding one pan or your fries may not crisp up.) </step>
    <step num="7">Bake for 15 minutes. Flip fries with tongs, then bake for an additional 10–15 minutes. Sprinkle on salt (to taste) and serve! Add shredded Parmesan and chopped parsley for an optional garnish. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Rinse and peel sweet potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">To cut into fries, cut a small sliver off the edge of the potatoes lengthwise to create a flat side for them to rest on. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Turn the potato over to lay on its flat side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cut each slice lengthwise into three to four fries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Place the fries in a bowl of water and soak for one hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">(This helps remove excess starch from the potatoes so your fries will be crispier.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Rinse and dry off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Preheat the oven to 425°F (220°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">In a large bowl or gallon bag, toss the fries with cornstarch until they’re evenly coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Then add the oil and toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the pepper, paprika, garlic powder, and brown sugar and toss to evenly distribute your spices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">(Hold off on adding the salt until after baking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">This will help make sure the fries are crispy.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper or aluminum foil and spray with nonstick cooking spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Lay out the french fries, being sure not to overcrowd the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">(You may need two pans, depending on how large your pans are. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Avoid overcrowding one pan or your fries may not crisp up.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Bake for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Flip fries with tongs, then bake for an additional 10–15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Sprinkle on salt (to taste) and serve! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Add shredded Parmesan and chopped parsley for an optional garnish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>