<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Easy Ice Cube Chocolate Cups Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/easy-ice-cube-chocolate-cups</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 oz ; cream cheese, softened ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; peanut butter ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 ½ teaspoons ; whole milk, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ teaspoon ; vanilla extract, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; powdered sugar, plus 2 tablespoons, divided ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 pinch ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ¼ cups ; whipped cream, divided ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">14 ; chocolate sandwich cookies, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2.5 oz ; pudding mix, chocolate, 1 package ; (70 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ½ cups ; whole milk, cold ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 cups ; milk chocolate, melted ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 cups ; white chocolate, melted ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 cups ; dark chocolate, melted ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">chopped nuts </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">4 ; mini peanut butter cups </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">12 ; raspberries </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">fresh mint leaf </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">12 ; popsicle sticks </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="3">Date Night</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/92123/hls24_1525219844.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/92123/landscape_720/1525219844</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Please be aware, you have to place the ice cube right in the chocolate as soon as you're able to remove it from its slot otherwise it will start to melt and the chocolate will not adhere. </step>
    <step num="1">Fill a 12-cup muffin tin with water. </step>
    <step num="2">Place a popsicle stick into each muffin cup. </step>
    <step num="3">Freeze until solid. </step>
    <step num="4">In a medium bowl, whisk together the cream cheese, peanut butter, 1½ teaspoons milk, ¼ teaspoon vanilla, ¼ cup powdered sugar, and salt until smooth. </step>
    <step num="5">Fold in ¼ cup of whipped cream with spatula. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="6">Separate the cream from 12 chocolate sandwich cookies into a separate medium bowl. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the remaining 2 tablespoons powdered sugar, remaining 2 teaspoons milk, and remaining ¼ teaspoon vanilla to the bowl with the cream filling. Whisk until well-combined. </step>
    <step num="8">Fold in the remaining cup of whipped cream with a spatula. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="9">Transfer the cookies to a zip-top bag and break into crumbs with a rolling pin. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="10">In a small bowl, combine the chocolate pudding mix and cold milk. Whisk for 2 minutes, then let sit for 3 minutes, until the pudding thickens. </step>
    <step num="11">Remove the muffin tin from the freezer. Give the ice a minute to melt down just enough to remove each ice mold from the muffin cups. </step>
    <step num="12">Dip 4 of the ice discs into the melted milk chocolate, making sure not to fully submerge the ice disc. Set the chocolate-dipped ice discs onto a parchment-lined baking sheet or plate. Dip 4 of the ice discs in the melted white chocolate, and the remaining 4 discs in the melted dark chocolate. </step>
    <step num="13">Once the chocolate has set, give the ice discs a minute to melt down slightly. Wiggle the ice disc out of the chocolate to reveal hollow chocolate cups. </step>
    <step num="14">Pipe the peanut butter mousse into the milk chocolate cups. Top with chopped nuts and a mini peanut butter cup. </step>
    <step num="15">Sprinkle chocolate sandwich cookie crumbs on the bottom of the white chocolate cups. Pipe the cookie cream filling on top of the crumbs. Garnish with more cookie crumbs and half of a chocolate sandwich cookie. </step>
    <step num="16">Pipe the chocolate pudding mixture into the dark chocolate cups. Top each one with 3 raspberries and fresh mint leaves. </step>
    <step num="17">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Please be aware, you have to place the ice cube right in the chocolate as soon as you're able to remove it from its slot otherwise it will start to melt and the chocolate will not adhere </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Fill a 12-cup muffin tin with water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Place a popsicle stick into each muffin cup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Freeze until solid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a medium bowl, whisk together the cream cheese, peanut butter, 1½ teaspoons milk, ¼ teaspoon vanilla, ¼ cup powdered sugar, and salt until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Fold in ¼ cup of whipped cream with spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Separate the cream from 12 chocolate sandwich cookies into a separate medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the remaining 2 tablespoons powdered sugar, remaining 2 teaspoons milk, and remaining ¼ teaspoon vanilla to the bowl with the cream filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Whisk until well-combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Fold in the remaining cup of whipped cream with a spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Transfer the cookies to a zip-top bag and break into crumbs with a rolling pin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">In a small bowl, combine the chocolate pudding mix and cold milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Whisk for 2 minutes, then let sit for 3 minutes, until the pudding thickens. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Remove the muffin tin from the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Give the ice a minute to melt down just enough to remove each ice mold from the muffin cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Dip 4 of the ice discs into the melted milk chocolate, making sure not to fully submerge the ice disc. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Set the chocolate-dipped ice discs onto a parchment-lined baking sheet or plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Dip 4 of the ice discs in the melted white chocolate, and the remaining 4 discs in the melted dark chocolate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Once the chocolate has set, give the ice discs a minute to melt down slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Wiggle the ice disc out of the chocolate to reveal hollow chocolate cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Pipe the peanut butter mousse into the milk chocolate cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Top with chopped nuts and a mini peanut butter cup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Sprinkle chocolate sandwich cookie crumbs on the bottom of the white chocolate cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Pipe the cookie cream filling on top of the crumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Garnish with more cookie crumbs and half of a chocolate sandwich cookie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Pipe the chocolate pudding mixture into the dark chocolate cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Top each one with 3 raspberries and fresh mint leaves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>