<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>The Ultimate Thanksgiving Turkey Hack Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/the-ultimate-thanksgiving-turkey-hack</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">15 lb ; turkey ; (6.7 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; kosher salt ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; dark brown sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; freshly ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; granulated garlic </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">cooking oil, of choice, for drizzling </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; turkey carcass </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; medium yellow onion, quartered </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">3 ; carrots, peeled and halved </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">3 stalks ; celery, cut into thirds </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">cooking oil, of choice, for drizzling </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">cold water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 ; bay leaves </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">⅓ cup ; rendered turkey fat, or butter ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">⅓ cup ; all-purpose flour ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 qt ; turkey stock, or chicken stock ; (945 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">1 bunch ; fresh sage, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">freshly ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/114360/hls24_1541446398.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/114360/landscape_720/1541446398</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">The day before serving, prepare the turkey for brining. Pat dry with paper towels. </step>
    <step num="1">Set the neck aside for the stock. Cut off the wing tips and set aside with the neck. </step>
    <step num="2">Butcher the turkey into 8 pieces: 2 breasts, 2 legs, 2 thighs, and 2 wings. Set aside the carcass for the stock. </step>
    <step num="3">Combine the salt, brown sugar, pepper, and granulated garlic in a small bowl. </step>
    <step num="4">Set a wire rack inside a baking sheet. Place the turkey parts skin-side up on the rack and generously sprinkle with the seasoning blend. Refrigerate, uncovered, for at least 2 hours, or overnight. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the stock: Preheat the oven to 450˚F (230˚C). </step>
    <step num="6">Place the turkey carcass, wing tips, and neck on a baking sheet with the onion, carrots, and celery. Season lightly with salt and drizzle with oil. </step>
    <step num="7">Roast for 30-45 minutes, or until the carcass and vegetables are deep brown. </step>
    <step num="8">Transfer the roasted vegetables, turkey carcass, and other parts to a large stock pot. </step>
    <step num="9">From the still-warm baking sheet from roasting the carcass, pour any rendered fat into a small bowl. Add about 1 cup (240 ml) of water to the pan and scrape off any browned bits from roasting process, then pour into a separate bowl. Reserve for the gravy. </step>
    <step num="10">Strain the stock, discarding the solids. The stock will keep for 5 days in the refrigerator or for 3 months in the freezer. </step>
    <step num="11">Cover the carcass with cold water. Add the bay leaves and bring to a gentle simmer over medium heat. Continue to simmer (don’t boil!) for 3 hours. </step>
    <step num="12">Make the gravy: Heat a medium saucepan over medium heat. Add the turkey fat and flour, stirring to combine. Cook the fat and flour together, stirring constantly, for about 5 minutes. This is a roux--you are cooking out the raw flour taste and deepening the flavor. </step>
    <step num="13">Gradually add the stock to the roux, stirring constantly to prevent lumps. Bring to a boil, continuing to stir until thickened. Season with salt and pepper to taste. </step>
    <step num="14">Remove the pan from the heat and let cool to room temperature. Store in the refrigerator until ready to warm for serving with the turkey. The gravy will keep in the fridge for up to 5 days, or in the freezer for up to 3 months. </step>
    <step num="15">2 hours before you are ready to serve the turkey, preheat the oven to 425°F (220˚C). </step>
    <step num="16">Remove the turkey parts from the fridge and drizzle with oil before placing in the hot oven. </step>
    <step num="17">Roast for 30 minutes, then rotate the baking sheet to ensure even browning. Reduce the oven temperature to 400˚F (200˚C). </step>
    <step num="18">Continue roasting until an instant-read thermometer inserted into the thickest part of breast registers 160°F (70˚C). </step>
    <step num="19">Or when the thigh registers 170˚F (77˚C). Start checking after about 20 minutes, removing any parts from the oven as they reach proper temperature so that they don’t overcook. </step>
    <step num="20">Once all parts are done, loosely cover with foil and let rest for 5-10 minutes while you warm the gravy. </step>
    <step num="21">Add the gravy and sage, if using, to a medium saucepan over low heat and bring to a simmer, stirring occasionally. Season to taste with more salt and pepper, if needed. </step>
    <step num="22">Serve the turkey with the gravy and your favorite Thanksgiving dishes. </step>
    <step num="23">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">The day before serving, prepare the turkey for brining. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pat dry with paper towels. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Set the neck aside for the stock. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cut off the wing tips and set aside with the neck. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Butcher the turkey into 8 pieces: 2 breasts, 2 legs, 2 thighs, and 2 wings. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Set aside the carcass for the stock. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Combine the salt, brown sugar, pepper, and granulated garlic in a small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Set a wire rack inside a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Place the turkey parts skin-side up on the rack and generously sprinkle with the seasoning blend. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Refrigerate, uncovered, for at least 2 hours, or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Make the stock: Preheat the oven to 450˚F (230˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place the turkey carcass, wing tips, and neck on a baking sheet with the onion, carrots, and celery. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Season lightly with salt and drizzle with oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Roast for 30-45 minutes, or until the carcass and vegetables are deep brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Transfer the roasted vegetables, turkey carcass, and other parts to a large stock pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">From the still-warm baking sheet from roasting the carcass, pour any rendered fat into a small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add about 1 cup (240 ml) of water to the pan and scrape off any browned bits from roasting process, then pour into a separate bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Reserve for the gravy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Strain the stock, discarding the solids. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">The stock will keep for 5 days in the refrigerator or for 3 months in the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Cover the carcass with cold water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Add the bay leaves and bring to a gentle simmer over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Continue to simmer (don’t boil!) for 3 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Make the gravy: Heat a medium saucepan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Add the turkey fat and flour, stirring to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Cook the fat and flour together, stirring constantly, for about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">This is a roux--you are cooking out the raw flour taste and deepening the flavor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Gradually add the stock to the roux, stirring constantly to prevent lumps. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Bring to a boil, continuing to stir until thickened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Season with salt and pepper to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Remove the pan from the heat and let cool to room temperature. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Store in the refrigerator until ready to warm for serving with the turkey. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">The gravy will keep in the fridge for up to 5 days, or in the freezer for up to 3 months. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">2 hours before you are ready to serve the turkey, preheat the oven to 425°F (220˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Remove the turkey parts from the fridge and drizzle with oil before placing in the hot oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Roast for 30 minutes, then rotate the baking sheet to ensure even browning. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Reduce the oven temperature to 400˚F (200˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="37">Continue roasting until an instant-read thermometer inserted into the thickest part of breast registers 160°F (70˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="38">Or when the thigh registers 170˚F (77˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="39">Start checking after about 20 minutes, removing any parts from the oven as they reach proper temperature so that they don’t overcook. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="40">Once all parts are done, loosely cover with foil and let rest for 5-10 minutes while you warm the gravy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="41">Add the gravy and sage, if using, to a medium saucepan over low heat and bring to a simmer, stirring occasionally. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="42">Season to taste with more salt and pepper, if needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="43">Serve the turkey with the gravy and your favorite Thanksgiving dishes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="44">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>