<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chicken Pot Pie by Wolfgang Puck Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chicken-pot-pie-by-wolfgang-puck</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, at room temperature </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 tablespoons ; all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 cups ; chicken broth, good-quality ; (480 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">freshly ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 pinch ; cayenne pepper, optional, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 tablespoons ; heavy cream, plus more for egg wash </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 lb ; cooked boneless, skinless chicken, shredded ; (910 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ lb ; carrot, peeled, cut into 1/2-inch (1cm) pieces ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ lb ; red-skinned potato, cut into 1/2-inch (1cm) pieces ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ cup ; frozen peas, or shelled fresh peas ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ lb ; puff pastry, defrosted following package instructions ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">black truffle, optional, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ; large egg </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Lunch</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32135/low_1495125363.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32135/mp4_720x1280/1495125363</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Melt the butter in a large, tall saucepan. </step>
    <step num="1">Add flour and whisk to ensure there are no lumps before adding the chicken stock. Cook out this mixture for 5-10 minutes while continuously stirring. </step>
    <step num="2">Check the consistency by dipping the back of a spoon into the sauce and running your finger along the spoon. You want the sauce to cling to the spoon and not run over the swipe you made. </step>
    <step num="3">Continue to cook and stir the sauce over medium heat until you reach the correct consistency. Season with the salt, pepper, and cayenne (if using). Taste the sauce and see if your sauce needs more seasoning. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the cream and stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the shredded chicken, potatoes, carrots, peas, and garlic to the sauce. Cook the vegetables in the sauce for two to three minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Transfer the filling into a clean bowl and chill in the fridge for one hour, or until cool. </step>
    <step num="7">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </step>
    <step num="8">Roll out the puff pastry, using a bit of extra flour to ensure the pastry doesn't stick to your work surface. Use a bowl or plate about an inch (2 cm) larger than the dish you are cooking your pot pie in as a guide to cut out your pastry. </step>
    <step num="9">Carefully spoon in your chilled filling into your dish. </step>
    <step num="10">Break the egg in a small dish and add a tablespoon of water or cream. Whisk with a fork. </step>
    <step num="11">Brush this egg wash on the edges of your dish. Brush a little of your egg wash on the rim of your dish. </step>
    <step num="12">Optional, with a truffle slicer add into fill. Lay your pastry over the top, being careful not to stretch the pastry. Seal the edges of the pastry by lightly pushing it onto the rim of your dish to make sure it is secure. </step>
    <step num="13">Brush the top and sides with more egg wash. </step>
    <step num="14">Place your pot pies on a large baking sheet and bake for 25-35 minutes. Bake until your pastry is a nice golden, dark brown and there are no more grayish raw patches. </step>
    <step num="15">Let cool for five minutes before serving. </step>
    <step num="16">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Melt the butter in a large, tall saucepan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add flour and whisk to ensure there are no lumps before adding the chicken stock. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cook out this mixture for 5-10 minutes while continuously stirring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Check the consistency by dipping the back of a spoon into the sauce and running your finger along the spoon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">You want the sauce to cling to the spoon and not run over the swipe you made. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Continue to cook and stir the sauce over medium heat until you reach the correct consistency. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Season with the salt, pepper, and cayenne (if using). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Taste the sauce and see if your sauce needs more seasoning. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the cream and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the shredded chicken, potatoes, carrots, peas, and garlic to the sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Cook the vegetables in the sauce for two to three minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Transfer the filling into a clean bowl and chill in the fridge for one hour, or until cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Roll out the puff pastry, using a bit of extra flour to ensure the pastry doesn't stick to your work surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Use a bowl or plate about an inch (2 cm) larger than the dish you are cooking your pot pie in as a guide to cut out your pastry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Carefully spoon in your chilled filling into your dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Break the egg in a small dish and add a tablespoon of water or cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Whisk with a fork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Brush this egg wash on the edges of your dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Brush a little of your egg wash on the rim of your dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Optional, with a truffle slicer add into fill. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Lay your pastry over the top, being careful not to stretch the pastry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Seal the edges of the pastry by lightly pushing it onto the rim of your dish to make sure it is secure. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Brush the top and sides with more egg wash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Place your pot pies on a large baking sheet and bake for 25-35 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Bake until your pastry is a nice golden, dark brown and there are no more grayish raw patches. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Let cool for five minutes before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>