<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Berries &amp; Cream Puff Ring Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/berries-cream-puff-ring</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 yolks ; large egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; cornstarch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; vanilla </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; milk ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; unsalted butter, cubed ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¾ cup ; all-purpose flour ; (95 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">5 ; large eggs, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; heavy cream, whipped ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">5 ; strawberries </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">5 ; blackberries </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">5 ; blueberries </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">powdered sugar, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">French</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/84257/hls24_1520899351.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/84257/landscape_720/1520899351</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the custard: In a medium microwave-safe bowl, whisk together the egg yolks, sugar, cornstarch, vanilla, and milk. Cover with plastic wrap. </step>
    <step num="1">Cook the custard in a microwave for 4 minutes, stirring after every 2 minutes until very smooth. Re-cover with plastic wrap, pressing onto the surface of the cream to prevent a skin from forming. Chill in the fridge until cool, about 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="3">Make the pastry: In a medium saucepan, bring the water, butter, and salt to a boil over medium heat. </step>
    <step num="4">As soon as the mixture begins to boil, reduce the heat to medium-low and add the flour. Using a wooden spoon, mix thoroughly to combine. </step>
    <step num="5">Continue stirring (about two minutes). The dough should form into a ball and easily pull away from the sides of the pan. Remove the mixture from the heat and let cool for 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Add 4 of the eggs to the cooled dough, one at a time, being sure to fully incorporate each egg before adding the next. (The eggs will initially be difficult to incorporate into the dough, but continue stirring vigorously and they will eventually come together to form a smooth, shiny dough. When the dough drops making a V shape, it is ready!) </step>
    <step num="7">Transfer the dough to a piping bag and pipe onto the baking sheet in an 7-inch (17-cm) ring shape. Pipe a second ring outside the first ring. Pipe a final ring on top. Beat the remaining egg, then brush over the ring. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake for 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Then, without opening the oven, reduce the heat to 350˚F(180˚C) and bake for another 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="10">Turn off the oven and leave the puff pastry inside for another 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="11">Cut the choux pastry in half horizontally. Pipe the custard into the hollow center of the shell. Pipe whipped cream on top of the custard. Top with berries. Place the top half of the shell. Dust with powdered sugar. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the custard: In a medium microwave-safe bowl, whisk together the egg yolks, sugar, cornstarch, vanilla, and milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cover with plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cook the custard in a microwave for 4 minutes, stirring after every 2 minutes until very smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Re-cover with plastic wrap, pressing onto the surface of the cream to prevent a skin from forming. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Chill in the fridge until cool, about 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Make the pastry: In a medium saucepan, bring the water, butter, and salt to a boil over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">As soon as the mixture begins to boil, reduce the heat to medium-low and add the flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Using a wooden spoon, mix thoroughly to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Continue stirring (about two minutes). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">The dough should form into a ball and easily pull away from the sides of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove the mixture from the heat and let cool for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add 4 of the eggs to the cooled dough, one at a time, being sure to fully incorporate each egg before adding the next. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">(The eggs will initially be difficult to incorporate into the dough, but continue stirring vigorously and they will eventually come together to form a smooth, shiny dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">When the dough drops making a V shape, it is ready!) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Transfer the dough to a piping bag and pipe onto the baking sheet in an 7-inch (17-cm) ring shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Pipe a second ring outside the first ring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Pipe a final ring on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Beat the remaining egg, then brush over the ring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Bake for 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Then, without opening the oven, reduce the heat to 350˚F(180˚C) and bake for another 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Turn off the oven and leave the puff pastry inside for another 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Cut the choux pastry in half horizontally. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Pipe the custard into the hollow center of the shell. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Pipe whipped cream on top of the custard. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Top with berries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Place the top half of the shell. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Dust with powdered sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>