<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Pineapple Upside Down Pancakes Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/pineapple-upside-down-pancakes</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; flour ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 teaspoons ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ½ teaspoons ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ cups ; milk ; (355 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ cup ; butter, 1/4 cup (55g) melted, plus additional for frying ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ cup ; brown sugar ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ½ fl oz ; spiced rum, optional ; (45 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">20 oz ; canned pineapple ring with juice, 1 can, we got about ½ cup (180 ml) of juice once separated from the fruit ; (600 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">maraschino cherry </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="4">Brunch</category>
    <category num="5">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/42664/low_1499279284.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/42664/mp4_720x1280/1499279284</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">To a large mixing bowl, add flour, baking powder, baking soda, salt, and sugar. Mix until thoroughly combined. </step>
    <step num="1">Create a small well in the middle of the dry ingredients. Add milk, half of the reserved pineapple juice, melted butter, and vanilla extract. Whisk until ingredients combine to form a lumpy batter. Set aside while you make the pineapple syrup. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the remaining butter to small sauce pan over medium heat. Once butter is melted, add brown sugar, the remaining pineapple juice, and rum (optional). </step>
    <step num="3">Bring ingredients to a boil allowing for the sugar to melt and caramelize. Once mixture is smooth and has the consistency of syrup, remove from heat and set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">Melt a small amount of butter in a frying pan over medium heat and add a slice of pineapple. Cook pineapple ring until lightly caramelized on one side, about 2 minutes, before flipping it. </step>
    <step num="5">Once flipped, fill the core of the pineapple with 1-2 maraschino cherries before pouring about ¼ cup (30 grams) of the pancake batter over. </step>
    <step num="6">Cook until the edges start to set and the top begins to bubble, about 2 minutes, before carefully flipping the pancake--revealing the pineapple underneath. Cook for an additional 90 seconds to 2 minutes until the pancake is cooked through. </step>
    <step num="7">Store cooked pancakes in a 200˚F (90˚C) oven until ready to serve. </step>
    <step num="8">Serve pancakes warm with reserved pineapple syrup. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">To a large mixing bowl, add flour, baking powder, baking soda, salt, and sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Mix until thoroughly combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Create a small well in the middle of the dry ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add milk, half of the reserved pineapple juice, melted butter, and vanilla extract. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Whisk until ingredients combine to form a lumpy batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Set aside while you make the pineapple syrup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the remaining butter to small sauce pan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Once butter is melted, add brown sugar, the remaining pineapple juice, and rum (optional). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Bring ingredients to a boil allowing for the sugar to melt and caramelize. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Once mixture is smooth and has the consistency of syrup, remove from heat and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Melt a small amount of butter in a frying pan over medium heat and add a slice of pineapple. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cook pineapple ring until lightly caramelized on one side, about 2 minutes, before flipping it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Once flipped, fill the core of the pineapple with 1-2 maraschino cherries before pouring about ¼ cup (30 grams) of the pancake batter over. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Cook until the edges start to set and the top begins to bubble, about 2 minutes, before carefully flipping the pancake--revealing the pineapple underneath. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Cook for an additional 90 seconds to 2 minutes until the pancake is cooked through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Store cooked pancakes in a 200˚F (90˚C) oven until ready to serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Serve pancakes warm with reserved pineapple syrup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>