<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Whole Wheat Sandwich Bread Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/whole-wheat-sandwich-bread</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ¼ cups ; warm water ; (300 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ teaspoons ; honey, or sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ½ teaspoons ; active dry yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 cups ; whole wheat flour ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ⅓ cups ; all-purpose flour ; (165 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 tablespoons ; oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ½ teaspoons ; salt </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Healthy</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="5">Brunch</category>
    <category num="6">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="7">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31493/low_1494634693.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31493/mp4_720x1280/1494634693</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, whisk the water, honey, and yeast. Let sit for 5 minutes, until the yeast has bloomed. </step>
    <step num="1">NOTE: It may be tempting to use all whole wheat flour in this recipe, but, in our testing, that method resulted in dense, tough, squat breads that barely rose when we tried to proof them. Using some all-purpose flour was necessary to give us the rise and soft, pillowy texture we wanted in a good sandwich bread. </step>
    <step num="2">Pour in the wheat flour, all-purpose flour, oil, and salt, and mix until the dough comes together in a ball that does not stick to your fingers. </step>
    <step num="3">NOTE: You can also do the first 2 steps in a standing mixer fitted with a dough hook attachment, mixing on low speed until the dough no longer sticks to the sides. </step>
    <step num="4">On a lightly floured surface, knead the dough a few times until it really starts to form a tight ball. </step>
    <step num="5">Form the dough into a ball shape and transfer to a greased bowl, turning the dough to coat it in grease. Cover the bowl with plastic wrap or a wet towel and store in a warm place for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="6">Allow the dough to proof until it has doubled in size. Save the plastic wrap or towel as you’ll be using it again. </step>
    <step num="7">Transfer the proofed dough to a lightly floured surface and press the dough – don’t stretch – into a 7x7-inch (18x18 cm) square. </step>
    <step num="8">Fold the top 3rd of the square down, and the bottom 3rd up to form an even rectangle. Pinch the top fold to seal the dough. </step>
    <step num="9">Roll the dough over so that the seal faces upward and fold both ends up toward the center, so that the dough has formed an even log shape about the size of your loaf pan. </step>
    <step num="10">Transfer the dough to a greased loaf pan and cover with with the same plastic wrap or towel used before. </step>
    <step num="11">Let the dough rise for 1 hour, until it has poofed over the edge of the loaf pan about 1½ inches (4 cm). </step>
    <step num="12">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </step>
    <step num="13">Remove the plastic wrap or towel and transfer to the oven and bake for 50-55 minutes, until the dough has browned slightly and formed a light brown crust. </step>
    <step num="14">Immediately remove the loaf from the pan and set aside to cool for at least 1 hour before slicing. </step>
    <step num="15">Store in an airtight container or bag. The bread can be stored in freezer up to 6 months. </step>
    <step num="16">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, whisk the water, honey, and yeast. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Let sit for 5 minutes, until the yeast has bloomed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">NOTE: It may be tempting to use all whole wheat flour in this recipe, but, in our testing, that method resulted in dense, tough, squat breads that barely rose when we tried to proof them. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Using some all-purpose flour was necessary to give us the rise and soft, pillowy texture we wanted in a good sandwich bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour in the wheat flour, all-purpose flour, oil, and salt, and mix until the dough comes together in a ball that does not stick to your fingers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">NOTE: You can also do the first 2 steps in a standing mixer fitted with a dough hook attachment, mixing on low speed until the dough no longer sticks to the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">On a lightly floured surface, knead the dough a few times until it really starts to form a tight ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Form the dough into a ball shape and transfer to a greased bowl, turning the dough to coat it in grease. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Cover the bowl with plastic wrap or a wet towel and store in a warm place for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Allow the dough to proof until it has doubled in size. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Save the plastic wrap or towel as you’ll be using it again. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Transfer the proofed dough to a lightly floured surface and press the dough – don’t stretch – into a 7x7-inch (18x18 cm) square. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Fold the top 3rd of the square down, and the bottom 3rd up to form an even rectangle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Pinch the top fold to seal the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Roll the dough over so that the seal faces upward and fold both ends up toward the center, so that the dough has formed an even log shape about the size of your loaf pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Transfer the dough to a greased loaf pan and cover with with the same plastic wrap or towel used before. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Let the dough rise for 1 hour, until it has poofed over the edge of the loaf pan about 1½ inches (4 cm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Remove the plastic wrap or towel and transfer to the oven and bake for 50-55 minutes, until the dough has browned slightly and formed a light brown crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Immediately remove the loaf from the pan and set aside to cool for at least 1 hour before slicing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Store in an airtight container or bag. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">The bread can be stored in freezer up to 6 months. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>