<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Nicaraguan Vigorón And Tajadas As Made By Cat Alvarado Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/nicaraguan-vigoron-and-tajadas-as-made-by-cat-alvarado</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 lb ; yucca, fresh or frozen ; (905 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">6 cups ; cold water ; (1.4 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 teaspoons ; salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; lime, juiced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 cups ; green cabbage, finely shredded ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 ; medium plum tomatoes, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; medium white onion, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 tablespoons ; distilled white vinegar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">canola oil, for frying </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">4 ; unripe green plantains, thinly sliced lengthwise </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">6 ; cabbages, leaves </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">4 oz ; chicharrónes, pork cracklings ; (110 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Latin American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/110617/hls24_1538085179.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/110617/landscape_720/1538085179</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the vigorón: To prepare the yucca, use a sharp knife to cut off the root ends, cut in half crosswise, then carefully peel off the tough brown skin and inner pink layer. </step>
    <step num="1">Cut the peeled piece into quarters lengthwise. You can also buy frozen yucca that is already peeled. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the cold water to a large pot. Place the yucca in the pot and add 1 teaspoon of salt and the lime juice. Bring to a boil over high heat. Once boiling, reduce the heat to medium and maintain a gentle boil for 25 minutes, or until the yucca is tender but not falling apart. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove the yucca from the pot and set aside until cool enough to touch. Remove the woody vein from the middle of the yucca pieces and set aside for serving. </step>
    <step num="4">Bring another large pot of water to boil. Blanch the cabbage for 50-60 seconds, then remove from the pot and pat dry. Do not overcook. </step>
    <step num="5">In a large bowl, combine the tomatoes, onion, remaining teaspoon of salt, and distilled vinegar. Add the blanched cabbage and toss to combine. Set aside for serving. </step>
    <step num="6">Make the tajadas: Heat the canola oil in a large skillet until it reaches 325˚F (170˚C). </step>
    <step num="7">In small batches, carefully fry the sliced plantains for 45 seconds, flipping halfway, until they are lightly golden and a bright yellow in color. Drain over a wire rack or paper towels and season with salt. </step>
    <step num="8">To assemble, place cooked yucca on a cabbage leaf, followed by the tomato, onion, and cabbage salad. Top with pork rinds and serve the tajadas alongside. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the vigorón: To prepare the yucca, use a sharp knife to cut off the root ends, cut in half crosswise, then carefully peel off the tough brown skin and inner pink layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cut the peeled piece into quarters lengthwise. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">You can also buy frozen yucca that is already peeled. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the cold water to a large pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Place the yucca in the pot and add 1 teaspoon of salt and the lime juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Bring to a boil over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Once boiling, reduce the heat to medium and maintain a gentle boil for 25 minutes, or until the yucca is tender but not falling apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove the yucca from the pot and set aside until cool enough to touch. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Remove the woody vein from the middle of the yucca pieces and set aside for serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Bring another large pot of water to boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Blanch the cabbage for 50-60 seconds, then remove from the pot and pat dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Do not overcook. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">In a large bowl, combine the tomatoes, onion, remaining teaspoon of salt, and distilled vinegar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the blanched cabbage and toss to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Set aside for serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Make the tajadas: Heat the canola oil in a large skillet until it reaches 325˚F (170˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">In small batches, carefully fry the sliced plantains for 45 seconds, flipping halfway, until they are lightly golden and a bright yellow in color. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Drain over a wire rack or paper towels and season with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">To assemble, place cooked yucca on a cabbage leaf, followed by the tomato, onion, and cabbage salad. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Top with pork rinds and serve the tajadas alongside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>