<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Scalloped Potato–crusted Rib Eye Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/scalloped-potato-crusted-rib-eye</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; medium white onion, finely diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¾ lb ; crimini mushroom, minced ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">4 cups ; fresh spinach, chopped ; (160 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ½ tablespoons ; garlic, minced, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 lb ; beef ribeye ; (910 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 tablespoons ; canola oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ lb ; prosciutto, sliced ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ cup ; mayonnaise ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ teaspoon ; dried thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 tablespoon ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 ; large russet potatoes, washed and peeled </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 cups ; grated parmesan cheese, divided, plus more for sprinkling ; (230 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
    <category num="2">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/93956/hls24_1526321808.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/93956/landscape_720/1526321808</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Pour 1 tablespoon of oil into a medium skillet over medium heat and sauté the onion, mushrooms, and spinach for about 5-7 minutes, or until the onions begin to turn translucent. Add 1 tablespoon of garlic, salt, and pepper and cook, stirring occasionally, until all the liquid evaporates and the mixture becomes a thick paste. Remove from the pan and let cool completely. </step>
    <step num="2">Generously season the rib eye all over with salt and pepper. Heat the oil in a medium skillet over medium-high heat. Sear the meat for 3-5 minutes on all sides, until a crust has formed all over. Let rest on a wire rack for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Arrange overlapping sheets of plastic wrap until you have a surface twice the length and width of the rib eye. Lay overlapping strips of prosciutto on the plastic in an even layer, making sure the prosciutto sheet is large enough to cover the rib eye. Spread the cooled mushroom mixture evenly over the prosciutto. </step>
    <step num="4">In a small bowl, stir together the mayonnaise, remaining ½ tablespoon minced garlic, ½ teaspoon salt, the thyme, and lemon juice. Generously brush the rib eye with the garlic mayo, then place the rib eye in the center of the prosciutto-mushroom sheet. </step>
    <step num="5">Keeping everything even and tight, wrap the rib eye with the prosciutto, using the plastic wrap to help wrap it tightly and to seal the ends. Tuck the ends of the plastic wrap underneath the wrapped rib eye to keep its shape and chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Using a knife or mandoline, carefully cut the potatoes into slices ⅛-inch (3 mm) thick and lay on paper towels. Sprinkle the potato slices with salt and let sit for 10 minutes to draw out any excess moisture. Pat the potatoes dry. </step>
    <step num="7">Evenly sprinkle 1 cup (115 g) of Parmesan cheese over a parchment-lined baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="8">Arrange the potato slices in overlapping rows over the Parmesan until the pan is covered. Sprinkle the remaining cup of Parmesan evenly over the potatoes. </step>
    <step num="9">Bake for 30 minutes, until slightly golden and the potatoes are still flexible. Remove the potatoes from the oven and increase the heat to 400˚F (200˚C). </step>
    <step num="10">Place the chilled, prosciutto-wrapped rib eye in the center of the potato sheet. Fold the potatoes over the rib eye and peel back the parchment. Sprinkle Parmesan under the seam (it will help seal the potato layer) and all over the top. </step>
    <step num="11">Loosely cover the pan with foil and bake for 30 minutes. Remove the foil and bake for 20 minutes more, or until the potatoes are golden brown and the internal temperature of the beef is at least 135°F (57°C) for medium-rare. Rest for 10 minutes before slicing. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pour 1 tablespoon of oil into a medium skillet over medium heat and sauté the onion, mushrooms, and spinach for about 5-7 minutes, or until the onions begin to turn translucent. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add 1 tablespoon of garlic, salt, and pepper and cook, stirring occasionally, until all the liquid evaporates and the mixture becomes a thick paste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Remove from the pan and let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Generously season the rib eye all over with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Heat the oil in a medium skillet over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Sear the meat for 3-5 minutes on all sides, until a crust has formed all over. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Let rest on a wire rack for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Arrange overlapping sheets of plastic wrap until you have a surface twice the length and width of the rib eye. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Lay overlapping strips of prosciutto on the plastic in an even layer, making sure the prosciutto sheet is large enough to cover the rib eye. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Spread the cooled mushroom mixture evenly over the prosciutto. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">In a small bowl, stir together the mayonnaise, remaining ½ tablespoon minced garlic, ½ teaspoon salt, the thyme, and lemon juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Generously brush the rib eye with the garlic mayo, then place the rib eye in the center of the prosciutto-mushroom sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Keeping everything even and tight, wrap the rib eye with the prosciutto, using the plastic wrap to help wrap it tightly and to seal the ends. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Tuck the ends of the plastic wrap underneath the wrapped rib eye to keep its shape and chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Using a knife or mandoline, carefully cut the potatoes into slices ⅛-inch (3 mm) thick and lay on paper towels. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Sprinkle the potato slices with salt and let sit for 10 minutes to draw out any excess moisture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Pat the potatoes dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Evenly sprinkle 1 cup (115 g) of Parmesan cheese over a parchment-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Arrange the potato slices in overlapping rows over the Parmesan until the pan is covered. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Sprinkle the remaining cup of Parmesan evenly over the potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Bake for 30 minutes, until slightly golden and the potatoes are still flexible. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Remove the potatoes from the oven and increase the heat to 400˚F (200˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Place the chilled, prosciutto-wrapped rib eye in the center of the potato sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Fold the potatoes over the rib eye and peel back the parchment. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Sprinkle Parmesan under the seam (it will help seal the potato layer) and all over the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Loosely cover the pan with foil and bake for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Remove the foil and bake for 20 minutes more, or until the potatoes are golden brown and the internal temperature of the beef is at least 135°F (57°C) for medium-rare. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Rest for 10 minutes before slicing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>