<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Garden Vegetable Vegan Quiche Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/garden-vegetable-vegan-quiche</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¾ cup ; all purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (95 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¾ cup ; whole wheat flour ; (95 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">8 tablespoons ; vegan butter, cubed and chilled </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; cold water, plus more a needed ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; mushroom, thinly sliced ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; leek ; (90 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; black pepper, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; cherry tomato ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">4 cups ; fresh spinach ; (160 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 package ; silken tofu </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 tablespoons ; nutritional yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">½ teaspoon ; black salt, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">½ teaspoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">½ teaspoon ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">¼ teaspoon ; ground turmeric </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">⅛ teaspoon ; cayenne pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">dried chickpeas, for baking </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Vegan</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="4">Brunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/135164/hls24_1559769825.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/135164/landscape_720/1559769825</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the crust: In a large bowl, mix together the all-purpose flour, whole-wheat flour, and salt. Add the butter and, using your hands, work it into the flour until only pea-sized pieces remain. Continue working with your hands until the dough has a shaggy texture. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the water, starting with 3 tablespoons, and mix until the dough is moist enough to hold together. Add more water as needed, 1 tablespoon at a time. Form the dough into a disc and wrap in plastic wrap. Refrigerate for 30-60 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="3">Make the filling: Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. Once the oil is shimmering, add the mushrooms. Sauté for 3-5 minutes, until the mushrooms are beginning to brown lightly. Reduce the heat to medium and add the leeks, ½ teaspoon kosher salt, and ½ teaspoon pepper. Cook for another 3-5 minutes, until the leeks have softened slightly. Add the tomatoes and cook for 1 minute, until slightly softened. Add the spinach and sauté for 1-2 minutes, until just wilted. Remove the pan from the heat. </step>
    <step num="4">Lightly dust a clean surface with flour. Roll out the dough, turning it frequently so it doesn’t stick, to a 12-inch (30 cm) round, about ⅛-inch (3 mm) thick. </step>
    <step num="5">Gently transfer the crust to a 9-inch (22 cm) pie dish. Trim any excess dough around the edges. Fold the edges of dough back underneath itself, then crimp using an index finger knuckle on one hand and the thumb and index finger on the other hand. </step>
    <step num="6">Crumple a piece of parchment paper, then spread it out in the center of the crust. Add the dried beans to the center and spread toward the sides of the crust--this will add weight to keep the crust from puffing up and hold up the walls while baking. </step>
    <step num="7">Bake the crust for 15 minutes. Carefully remove the weights by lifting out the parchment paper, then bake for 5 minutes more, until the dough no longer looks raw. </step>
    <step num="8">Carefully pour the silken tofu into a fine-mesh strainer set over a bowl. Let sit for 10 minutes to allow the excess water to drain. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the tofu, nutritional yeast, remaining ½ teaspoon salt, remaining ½ teaspoon pepper, black salt, garlic powder, paprika, turmeric, and cayenne to a blender. Puree until smooth. </step>
    <step num="10">Spread half the sautéed vegetables evenly over the bottom of the crust. Pour the tofu puree over the vegetables, then add the remaining vegetables on top.. </step>
    <step num="11">Bake for 40-45 minutes, until the center no longer jiggles and the crust is just beginning to brown. </step>
    <step num="12">Let the quiche cool for at least 30 minutes before slicing to allow the filling to set. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the crust: In a large bowl, mix together the all-purpose flour, whole-wheat flour, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the butter and, using your hands, work it into the flour until only pea-sized pieces remain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Continue working with your hands until the dough has a shaggy texture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the water, starting with 3 tablespoons, and mix until the dough is moist enough to hold together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add more water as needed, 1 tablespoon at a time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Form the dough into a disc and wrap in plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Refrigerate for 30-60 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Make the filling: Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Once the oil is shimmering, add the mushrooms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Sauté for 3-5 minutes, until the mushrooms are beginning to brown lightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Reduce the heat to medium and add the leeks, ½ teaspoon kosher salt, and ½ teaspoon pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cook for another 3-5 minutes, until the leeks have softened slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the tomatoes and cook for 1 minute, until slightly softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add the spinach and sauté for 1-2 minutes, until just wilted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove the pan from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Lightly dust a clean surface with flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Roll out the dough, turning it frequently so it doesn’t stick, to a 12-inch (30 cm) round, about ⅛-inch (3 mm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Gently transfer the crust to a 9-inch (22 cm) pie dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Trim any excess dough around the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Fold the edges of dough back underneath itself, then crimp using an index finger knuckle on one hand and the thumb and index finger on the other hand. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Crumple a piece of parchment paper, then spread it out in the center of the crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add the dried beans to the center and spread toward the sides of the crust--this will add weight to keep the crust from puffing up and hold up the walls while baking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Bake the crust for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Carefully remove the weights by lifting out the parchment paper, then bake for 5 minutes more, until the dough no longer looks raw. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Carefully pour the silken tofu into a fine-mesh strainer set over a bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Let sit for 10 minutes to allow the excess water to drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Add the tofu, nutritional yeast, remaining ½ teaspoon salt, remaining ½ teaspoon pepper, black salt, garlic powder, paprika, turmeric, and cayenne to a blender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Puree until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Spread half the sautéed vegetables evenly over the bottom of the crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Pour the tofu puree over the vegetables, then add the remaining vegetables on top.. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Bake for 40-45 minutes, until the center no longer jiggles and the crust is just beginning to brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Let the quiche cool for at least 30 minutes before slicing to allow the filling to set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>