<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Scalloped Potato Loaf Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/scalloped-potato-loaf</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 tablespoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ; large white onion, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 lb ; lean ground beef ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 teaspoons ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 teaspoons ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">14 oz ; diced tomato, 1 can ; (395 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">6 cups ; fresh spinach ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">5 ; russet potatoes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">13 slices ; mozzarella cheese </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 tablespoons ; fresh parsley, chopped, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/88640/hls24_1523299827.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/88640/landscape_720/1523299827</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large skillet, heat the olive oil over medium heat until shimmering. Add the onion and cook until golden, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the ground beef and break apart, then cook for 3 minutes until the meat is no longer pink. Add the pepper, salt, garlic powder, paprika, and tomatoes. Mix thoroughly. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the spinach and cook until just wilted, about 2 minutes. Remove the pan from the heat, cover, and set aside until ready to use. </step>
    <step num="3">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="4">Peel the potatoes and cut into ⅛-inch (3 mm) thick slices. </step>
    <step num="5">In a 9x5-inch (23x13-cm) loaf pan, arrange overlapping potato slices on the bottom of the pan so the entire bottom is covered. Line the perimeter of the pan with overlapping potato slices. </step>
    <step num="6">Place 2 slices of mozzarella over the bottom layer of potatoes. Cut 5 slices of mozzarella in half. Place 2 half slices of cheese against the potatoes on both of the longer sides of the pan and one half on both of the shorter sides. Place one half in each of the corners of the pan. </step>
    <step num="7">Spread ⅓ of the beef mixture on top of the cheese. Arrange another layer of overlapping potato slices over the beef mixture. Place 2 more slices of cheese on top of the potatoes. </step>
    <step num="8">Spread another third of the beef mixture over the cheese, then add another layer of potatoes. Place 2 more slices of cheese on top of the potatoes. Spread the rest of the beef mixture on top of the cheese. </step>
    <step num="9">Tuck potato slices around the sides of the pan until all of the gaps are filled. Place the last 2 slices of cheese on top of the beef mixture. Cover the cheese with overlapping potato slices. </step>
    <step num="10">Bake for 90 minutes, until the top is golden brown and crisp. Let cool a bit. </step>
    <step num="11">Place a cutting board over the loaf pan and invert the loaf. </step>
    <step num="12">Slice and garnish with parsley. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large skillet, heat the olive oil over medium heat until shimmering. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the onion and cook until golden, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the ground beef and break apart, then cook for 3 minutes until the meat is no longer pink. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the pepper, salt, garlic powder, paprika, and tomatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Mix thoroughly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the spinach and cook until just wilted, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove the pan from the heat, cover, and set aside until ready to use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Peel the potatoes and cut into ⅛-inch (3 mm) thick slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a 9x5-inch (23x13-cm) loaf pan, arrange overlapping potato slices on the bottom of the pan so the entire bottom is covered. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Line the perimeter of the pan with overlapping potato slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place 2 slices of mozzarella over the bottom layer of potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cut 5 slices of mozzarella in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Place 2 half slices of cheese against the potatoes on both of the longer sides of the pan and one half on both of the shorter sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Place one half in each of the corners of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Spread ⅓ of the beef mixture on top of the cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Arrange another layer of overlapping potato slices over the beef mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Place 2 more slices of cheese on top of the potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Spread another third of the beef mixture over the cheese, then add another layer of potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Place 2 more slices of cheese on top of the potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Spread the rest of the beef mixture on top of the cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Tuck potato slices around the sides of the pan until all of the gaps are filled. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Place the last 2 slices of cheese on top of the beef mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Cover the cheese with overlapping potato slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Bake for 90 minutes, until the top is golden brown and crisp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Let cool a bit. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Place a cutting board over the loaf pan and invert the loaf. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Slice and garnish with parsley. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>