<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Dairy Free Doughnuts Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/dairy-free-doughnuts</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/6-doughnut-recipes-you-need-to-try</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¼ cup ; vegan margarine ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; soy milk ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; sunflower oil, plus 1 litre (4 cups) extra for frying </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 cups ; plain flour ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; caster sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">British</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Vegan</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="5">Brunch</category>
    <category num="6">Desserts</category>
    <category num="7">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="8">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="9">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/59008/low_1509389289.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/59008/mp4_720x1280/1509389289</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>61.85</start_time>
    <end_time>105.82</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Gently melt the butter over a low-medium heat. Add milk and 2 tablespoons of sunflower oil and mix together. Once combined, take off the heat and set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">In a separate bowl, combine the flour, half of the sugar, baking powder and salt with a fork. Make a well in the centre. </step>
    <step num="2">Pour the butter mixture into the well. Combine gradually until a thick dough forms. </step>
    <step num="3">Using your hands, roll dough into little flat balls and with your thumb, press a hole in the centre of each doughnut. (You may need to flour your hands for this part to avoid getting sticky!) </step>
    <step num="4">Heat up the litre of oil in a pan. To know when it's hot enough, fry a little bit of bread in the oil. If it goes brown and floats to the top, in 45-50 seconds the oil will be ready! </step>
    <step num="5">Gently lay the doughnuts into the oil using a spatula. Fry for about 3-5 minutes on each side, until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="6">Transfer the doughnuts onto some tissue paper to soak up any excess oil. Then roll into a bowl of the remaining sugar. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Gently melt the butter over a low-medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add milk and 2 tablespoons of sunflower oil and mix together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Once combined, take off the heat and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a separate bowl, combine the flour, half of the sugar, baking powder and salt with a fork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Make a well in the centre. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour the butter mixture into the well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Combine gradually until a thick dough forms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Using your hands, roll dough into little flat balls and with your thumb, press a hole in the centre of each doughnut. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">(You may need to flour your hands for this part to avoid getting sticky!) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Heat up the litre of oil in a pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">To know when it's hot enough, fry a little bit of bread in the oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">If it goes brown and floats to the top, in 45-50 seconds the oil will be ready! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Gently lay the doughnuts into the oil using a spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Fry for about 3-5 minutes on each side, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Transfer the doughnuts onto some tissue paper to soak up any excess oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Then roll into a bowl of the remaining sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
  <duration_human>
    <start_time>01915</start_time>
    <end_time>03187</end_time>
  </duration_human>
</recipe>