<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Stuffed Firecracker Chicken Rolls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/stuffed-firecracker-chicken-rolls</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; low sodium soy sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">⅓ cup ; buffalo sauce ; (95 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">4 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">⅓ cup ; honey ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 tablespoons ; sweet chili sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ lb ; boneless, skinless chicken breast ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 tablespoons ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ ; yellow onion, finely diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 ; bell peppers, finely diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 cups ; spinach ; (80 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dinner</category>
    <category num="1">Lunch</category>
    <category num="2">Date Night</category>
    <category num="3">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/75853/hls24_1517420717.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/75853/landscape_720/1517420717</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a shallow dish or large plastic bag, add the soy sauce, buffalo sauce, garlic, honey, and sweet chili sauce. After mixing, reserve half the marinade in a separate bowl for later. </step>
    <step num="1">On a cutting board, slice the chicken breasts horizontally, making sure not to slice all the way through. Cover chicken breast with parchment or plastic wrap and use a mallet to flatten the chicken, about ⅓ inch (8 mm) in thickness. </step>
    <step num="2">Place chicken breasts in the marinade and chill for about 2 hours or overnight. </step>
    <step num="3">Add 1 tablespoon of olive oil to a large pan over medium heat. Once hot, add garlic and cook until aromatic, about 30 seconds. Add the onion and bell peppers, and cook until soft. </step>
    <step num="4">Remove the chicken breast from the marinade and lay flat. Spoon a layer of the onion and the bell pepper mixture across the chicken breast, then add a layer of spinach. </step>
    <step num="5">Roll up chicken breast and secure with a toothpick, about 1½ inches (4 cm) apart. Cut the chicken breast in half. </step>
    <step num="6">Add 1 tablespoon of olive oil to a large pan over medium heat. Once hot, place chicken rolls inside the pan, cook until inside is no longer pink, about 6 minutes on each side. Remove from pan. </step>
    <step num="7">Add reserved marinade to the pan and cook until caramelized, about 3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Serve drizzled in caramelized marinade. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a shallow dish or large plastic bag, add the soy sauce, buffalo sauce, garlic, honey, and sweet chili sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">After mixing, reserve half the marinade in a separate bowl for later. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">On a cutting board, slice the chicken breasts horizontally, making sure not to slice all the way through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cover chicken breast with parchment or plastic wrap and use a mallet to flatten the chicken, about ⅓ inch (8 mm) in thickness. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Place chicken breasts in the marinade and chill for about 2 hours or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add 1 tablespoon of olive oil to a large pan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Once hot, add garlic and cook until aromatic, about 30 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the onion and bell peppers, and cook until soft. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Remove the chicken breast from the marinade and lay flat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Spoon a layer of the onion and the bell pepper mixture across the chicken breast, then add a layer of spinach. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Roll up chicken breast and secure with a toothpick, about 1½ inches (4 cm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cut the chicken breast in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add 1 tablespoon of olive oil to a large pan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Once hot, place chicken rolls inside the pan, cook until inside is no longer pink, about 6 minutes on each side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove from pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add reserved marinade to the pan and cook until caramelized, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Serve drizzled in caramelized marinade. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>