<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Cioppino (Seafood Tomato Stew) Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/cioppino</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; extra virgin olive oil, divided ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ; large carrots, peeled, trimmed, and minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; leek, white part only, trimmed cleaned and minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ; large yellow onion, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; red bell pepper, cored, seeded, and minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; small fennel bulb, trimmed, and minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; green bell pepper, cored, seeded, and minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 ; celeries, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">4 cloves ; garlic, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">3 cloves ; garlic, crushed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">freshly cracked pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">6 oz ; tomato paste ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 tablespoon ; dried basil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 tablespoon ; dried oregano </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 tablespoon ; dried thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">1 teaspoon ; cayenne </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">2 cups ; dry white wine, divided ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">4 cups ; fish stock ; (960 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">15 oz ; crushed italian tomato, 2 cans ; (425 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">3 ; bay leaves </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">½ lb ; sea scallop ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">½ lb ; shrimp, peeled and deveined ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">½ lb ; squid, sliced ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="25">½ lb ; halibut fillet, cut into large pieces ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="26">½ lb ; manila clam, scrubbed ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="27">½ lb ; mussel, scrubbed ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="28">sourdough bread, grilled, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="29">½ bunch ; fresh parsley, chopped, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Seafood</category>
    <category num="3">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="4">Healthy</category>
    <category num="5">Dinner</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/96826/hls24_1527875140.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/96826/landscape_720/1527875140</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large pot over medium heat, melt together 2 tablespoons of butter and 2 tablespoons of olive oil. Add the carrot, leek, onion, red bell pepper, fennel, green bell pepper, celery, and garlic. Season with salt and pepper. Stir and cook until the vegetables are softened, about 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Scoop half of the matignon (sautéed minced vegetables) from the pan and set aside. Stir the tomato paste, basil, oregano, thyme, and cayenne into the remaining vegetables and cook until the tomato paste starts to brown, about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Next, add half of the white wine to deglaze the pan, stirring to loosen any bits stuck to the bottom of the pot. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the fish stock, crushed tomatoes, and bay leaves. Stir together, bring to a boil, then reduce the heat to low, cover, and simmer for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">In a large skillet, heat 2 tablespoons of olive oil over medium-high heat. Season all of the seafood with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the scallops to the pan and sear the first side until golden brown, 3 minutes. Flip and sear on the other side for another 3 minutes. Remove from the pan and set aside. Wipe out the pan if needed. </step>
    <step num="6">Add more olive oil as needed, then add the shrimp to the pan and cook for 3 minutes on one side. Flip and cook on the other side for 3 minutes more. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="7">Add more olive oil and the squid to the hot pan and sauté until cooked, 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Add more olive oil and the halibut to the hot pan, along with the crushed garlic and remaining 2 tablespoons of butter. Sear the halibut on one side, then flip and cook on the other side for 3 minutes. Baste the fish with the melted garlic butter as the second side cooks. Remove from the pan and set aside. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the clams and mussels to the pan, pour in the remaining cup of white white, then cover the pot and steam for 5 minutes, until the shellfish pop open. Remove the pan from the heat. </step>
    <step num="10">Transfer all of the cooked seafood, along with the leftover shellfish steaming liquid and reserved matignon, to the simmering stew; or plate the seafood and reserved matignon artfully in wide bowls and pour the hot stew over the top. </step>
    <step num="11">Serve with grilled sourdough bread and garnish with parsley. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large pot over medium heat, melt together 2 tablespoons of butter and 2 tablespoons of olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the carrot, leek, onion, red bell pepper, fennel, green bell pepper, celery, and garlic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Stir and cook until the vegetables are softened, about 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Scoop half of the matignon (sautéed minced vegetables) from the pan and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Stir the tomato paste, basil, oregano, thyme, and cayenne into the remaining vegetables and cook until the tomato paste starts to brown, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Next, add half of the white wine to deglaze the pan, stirring to loosen any bits stuck to the bottom of the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the fish stock, crushed tomatoes, and bay leaves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Stir together, bring to a boil, then reduce the heat to low, cover, and simmer for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a large skillet, heat 2 tablespoons of olive oil over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Season all of the seafood with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the scallops to the pan and sear the first side until golden brown, 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Flip and sear on the other side for another 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove from the pan and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Wipe out the pan if needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add more olive oil as needed, then add the shrimp to the pan and cook for 3 minutes on one side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Flip and cook on the other side for 3 minutes more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add more olive oil and the squid to the hot pan and sauté until cooked, 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add more olive oil and the halibut to the hot pan, along with the crushed garlic and remaining 2 tablespoons of butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Sear the halibut on one side, then flip and cook on the other side for 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Baste the fish with the melted garlic butter as the second side cooks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Remove from the pan and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Add the clams and mussels to the pan, pour in the remaining cup of white white, then cover the pot and steam for 5 minutes, until the shellfish pop open. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Remove the pan from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Transfer all of the cooked seafood, along with the leftover shellfish steaming liquid and reserved matignon, to the simmering stew; or plate the seafood and reserved matignon artfully in wide bowls and pour the hot stew over the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Serve with grilled sourdough bread and garnish with parsley. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>