<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>20-Minute Beef And Broccoli Noodle Stir-Fry Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/20-minute-beef-and-broccoli-noodle-stir-fry</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 oz ; instant ramen, 3 packages ; (85 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">8 cups ; water, boiling hot ; (1.9 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 clove ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; cornstarch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; sesame oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; lime, juiced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¼ cup ; soy sauce, plus 1 tablespoon ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 cups ; broccoli floret ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; olive oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¾ lb ; flank steak, thinly sliced ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ ; medium yellow onion, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 tablespoons ; green onion, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 tablespoons ; fresh cilantro, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ½ teaspoons ; sesame seeds, toasted </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Chinese</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
    <category num="2">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105912/hls24_1534790361.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105912/landscape_720/1534790361</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Place the ramen noodles in a large bowl (discard the seasoning packets or save for another use) and pour the boiling water over them. Let sit for 6 minutes, stirring every now and then to break up the noodle blocks. Drain and rinse under cold water. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">In a small bowl, combine the garlic, cornstarch, sesame oil, lime juice, and soy sauce. Stir well, then set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">Place the broccoli in a large, microwave-safe bowl and microwave for 1½ minutes, until soft. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">Heat 1 teaspoon of olive oil in a large, nonstick pan over high heat. Add the steak to the pan and toss with 2 tablespoons of the reserved sauce. Cook until browned, about 2 minutes. Remove from the pan and set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">Heat another teaspoon of olive oil in the pan, then add the onion. Cook, stirring often, until browned, about 4 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the broccoli and cook until lightly browned, about 2 minutes. Remove from the pan and set aside. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the remaining teaspoon of olive oil to the pan, then add the noodles and the remaining sauce. Cook, stirring constantly, until the noodles soak up the sauce. Return the cooked vegetables and steak to the pan and stir to distribute. </step>
    <step num="7">Transfer the noodles to a serving dish and garnish with green onions, cilantro, and sesame seeds, if using. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Place the ramen noodles in a large bowl (discard the seasoning packets or save for another use) and pour the boiling water over them. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Let sit for 6 minutes, stirring every now and then to break up the noodle blocks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Drain and rinse under cold water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a small bowl, combine the garlic, cornstarch, sesame oil, lime juice, and soy sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Stir well, then set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Place the broccoli in a large, microwave-safe bowl and microwave for 1½ minutes, until soft. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Heat 1 teaspoon of olive oil in a large, nonstick pan over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the steak to the pan and toss with 2 tablespoons of the reserved sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Cook until browned, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove from the pan and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Heat another teaspoon of olive oil in the pan, then add the onion. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Cook, stirring often, until browned, about 4 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add the broccoli and cook until lightly browned, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove from the pan and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the remaining teaspoon of olive oil to the pan, then add the noodles and the remaining sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cook, stirring constantly, until the noodles soak up the sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Return the cooked vegetables and steak to the pan and stir to distribute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Transfer the noodles to a serving dish and garnish with green onions, cilantro, and sesame seeds, if using. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>