<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Vegan Pumpkin Cheesecake Bars Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/vegan-pumpkin-cheesecake-bars</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/recipes-to-help-you-cut-back-on-dairy</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; pitted date ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¾ cup ; rolled oats ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; almond ; (140 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">195 ; 1 ½ cups ; cashews </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">15 oz ; coconut cream, 1 can, chilled ; (445 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; coconut oil ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ cup ; maple syrup, plus 2 tablespoons, divided ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; pumpkin puree ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 teaspoon ; cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">¼ teaspoon ; allspice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">¼ teaspoon ; ginger </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Vegan</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Desserts</category>
    <category num="5">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="6">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/111192/hls24_1538603419.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/111192/landscape_720/1538603419</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>5.0</start_time>
    <end_time>104.833</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Line an 8-inch (20 cm) square baking dish with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the dates, oats, almonds, and salt to a food processor and pulse until crumbly. Add the water and pulse again until the mixture is sticky enough to hold together. </step>
    <step num="2">Transfer the crust to the prepared baking dish and spread in an even layer. Freeze while you prepare the rest of the recipe. </step>
    <step num="3">Bring a medium pot of water to boil. Add the cashews and boil for 10 minutes. Remove with a slotted spoon and transfer to a food processor. </step>
    <step num="4">Process until smooth. </step>
    <step num="5">In a medium bowl, spoon out the coconut cream from the top of the can of coconut milk (making sure to take only the cream and not the liquid). Beat with an electric hand mixer until soft peaks form. Add the coconut oil, maple syrup, and the vanilla and beat until well combined. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the cashew paste and stir with a spatula until well combined, using a whisk if necessary to smooth out any stubborn lumps. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="7">In a separate, medium bowl, combine the pumpkin puree, remaining 2 tablespoons of maple syrup, cinnamon, allspice, and ginger and mix until well combined. </step>
    <step num="8">Remove the crust from the freezer and pour in the cashew mixture. Smooth evenly. </step>
    <step num="9">Add small dollops of the pumpkin mixture on top of the cashew mixture. Using a wooden skewer, swirl the pumpkin mixture into the cashew mixture. </step>
    <step num="10">Freeze for at least 2 hours, or overnight. </step>
    <step num="11">Remove from freezer and slice into 9 even bars. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Line an 8-inch (20 cm) square baking dish with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the dates, oats, almonds, and salt to a food processor and pulse until crumbly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the water and pulse again until the mixture is sticky enough to hold together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Transfer the crust to the prepared baking dish and spread in an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Freeze while you prepare the rest of the recipe. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Bring a medium pot of water to boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the cashews and boil for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove with a slotted spoon and transfer to a food processor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Process until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a medium bowl, spoon out the coconut cream from the top of the can of coconut milk (making sure to take only the cream and not the liquid). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Beat with an electric hand mixer until soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the coconut oil, maple syrup, and the vanilla and beat until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the cashew paste and stir with a spatula until well combined, using a whisk if necessary to smooth out any stubborn lumps. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">In a separate, medium bowl, combine the pumpkin puree, remaining 2 tablespoons of maple syrup, cinnamon, allspice, and ginger and mix until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove the crust from the freezer and pour in the cashew mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Smooth evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Add small dollops of the pumpkin mixture on top of the cashew mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Using a wooden skewer, swirl the pumpkin mixture into the cashew mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Freeze for at least 2 hours, or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Remove from freezer and slice into 9 even bars. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>