<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chocolate Turtle Poke Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chocolate-turtle-poke-cake</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/easy-poke-cake-4-ways</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; freshly made chocolate cake, prepared from scratch or using a packaged mix </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 can ; 14 oz ; can of dulce de leche, warmed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 can ; 16 oz ; can of chocolate frosting </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; chopped pecans ; (65 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; mini chocolate chips ; (90 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">caramel syrup, to taste </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32540/low_1495477504.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32540/mp4_720x1280/1495477504</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>118.2</start_time>
    <end_time>134.12</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Using the back of a wooden spoon, poke at least 3 rows of 4 holes in the cooked cake, making 12 holes total. Pour the dulce de leche over the cake and let settle into the holes for about 10 minutes. Some of the dulce de leche will still stay on top, which is okay. If necessary, it can be reheated or mixed with a little milk to be thinned. </step>
    <step num="1">Spread the chocolate frosting evenly on top of the cake. Sprinkle the chopped pecans and mini chocolate chips on top of the frosting, then drizzle with the caramel. Chill the cake for at least 3 hours or up to overnight. </step>
    <step num="2">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Using the back of a wooden spoon, poke at least 3 rows of 4 holes in the cooked cake, making 12 holes total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pour the dulce de leche over the cake and let settle into the holes for about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Some of the dulce de leche will still stay on top, which is okay. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">If necessary, it can be reheated or mixed with a little milk to be thinned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Spread the chocolate frosting evenly on top of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Sprinkle the chopped pecans and mini chocolate chips on top of the frosting, then drizzle with the caramel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Chill the cake for at least 3 hours or up to overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>