<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Caramel Apple Hand Pies Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/caramel-apple-hand-pies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 ; granny smith apples </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; granulated sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; cornstarch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 teaspoons ; cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 shells ; pie dough, thawed and prepared </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; medium egg, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; unsalted butter, 1/2 stick ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 cup ; brown sugar ; (220 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; vanilla </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¼ cup ; honey ; (85 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="7">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="8">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/87992/hls24_1522866828.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/87992/landscape_720/1522866828</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">On a cutting board peel and cut the apples into slices ¼-inch (6-mm) thick. </step>
    <step num="1">Place the apple slices in a medium bowl. Add the sugar, cornstarch, cinnamon, and salt. Mix until the apples are well-coated, then set aside until ready to use. </step>
    <step num="2">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="3">Roll out one of the pie crusts. Use a 4-inch (10-cm) diameter glass or ramekin to cut 6 rounds from the dough. Repeat with the remaining crust so you have 12 dough circles total. </step>
    <step num="4">Place a few apple slices on top of one of the dough circles. Place another circle of dough on top, and seal the edges together. With a fork, crimp the edges and poke a few holes on the top of the hand pie. Repeat with the rest of dough and apples. </step>
    <step num="5">Transfer the hand pies to the baking sheet and brush with egg wash. Bake for 20 minutes, until golden. Let cool for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">In a small saucepan over medium heat, melt the butter with the brown sugar, vanilla, salt, and honey. Mix thoroughly until the caramel begins to bubble. Remove the sauce from the heat and pour into a small bowl for dipping. </step>
    <step num="7">Once the hand pies have cooled, dunk them face down into the caramel, let any excess drip off. Flip the hand pies right-side up so the caramel oozes down to the edges. Let cool for 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">On a cutting board peel and cut the apples into slices ¼-inch (6-mm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Place the apple slices in a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the sugar, cornstarch, cinnamon, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Mix until the apples are well-coated, then set aside until ready to use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Roll out one of the pie crusts. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Use a 4-inch (10-cm) diameter glass or ramekin to cut 6 rounds from the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Repeat with the remaining crust so you have 12 dough circles total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Place a few apple slices on top of one of the dough circles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place another circle of dough on top, and seal the edges together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">With a fork, crimp the edges and poke a few holes on the top of the hand pie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Repeat with the rest of dough and apples. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Transfer the hand pies to the baking sheet and brush with egg wash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Bake for 20 minutes, until golden. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Let cool for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">In a small saucepan over medium heat, melt the butter with the brown sugar, vanilla, salt, and honey. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Mix thoroughly until the caramel begins to bubble. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Remove the sauce from the heat and pour into a small bowl for dipping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Once the hand pies have cooled, dunk them face down into the caramel, let any excess drip off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Flip the hand pies right-side up so the caramel oozes down to the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Let cool for 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>