<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Vegan Tofu Bao Buns With Pickled Vegetables Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/vegan-tofu-bao-buns-with-pickled-vegetables</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; warm water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 tablespoons ; organic sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; instant yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 cups ; all purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (375 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 tablespoons ; vegetable oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 tablespoons ; sesame oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 cup ; scallion, sliced ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ cup ; fresh ginger, minced ; (15 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">5 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¼ cup ; organic sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 tablespoons ; chinese 5 spice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">¼ cup ; soy sauce ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">¼ cup ; shaoxing rice wine ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">¼ cup ; dark soy sauce ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">12 oz ; firm tofu, pressed and sliced ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">2 tablespoons ; vegetable oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 cup ; cucumber, julienned </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">1 ; red pepper, seeded and julienned </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">1 cup ; daikon radish, julienned ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">1 cup ; carrot, julienned ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">1 ; yellow pepper, seeded and julienned </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">2 ; jalepenoes, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">½ cup ; water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="25">½ cup ; organic sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="26">1 cup ; rice vinegar ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="27">1 tablespoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="28">hoisin sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="29">scallion, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="30">sesame seed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="31">small rolling pin, or wooden dowel </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="32">12 ; small squares parchment papers </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Chinese</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Vegan</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Dinner</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/122241/hls24_1547081504.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/122241/landscape_720/1547081504</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the bao buns: Add the warm water, sugar, and yeast to a liquid measuring cup. Whisk to combine, then set aside to bloom, five minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, whisk together the flour, baking powder, and salt. Make a well in the center. Add the yeast mixture and vegetable oil to the well and stir with a wooden spoon until a soft dough begins to form. Transfer the dough to a clean surface and knead until smooth and elastic, about 3 minutes. Keep extra flour nearby in case the dough sticks to the surface or your hands. Shape into a ball. </step>
    <step num="2">Lightly grease a clean large bowl with 1 tablespoon of sesame oil. Place the dough in the bowl, cover with plastic wrap, and let rise in a warm place until doubled in size, about 2 hours. </step>
    <step num="3">Meanwhile marinate the tofu: In a medium bowl, whisk together the scallions, ginger, garlic, sugar, five-spice, soy sauce, rice wine, and dark soy sauce. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the tofu to a separate medium bowl and pour the marinade over. Cover with plastic wrap and marinate in the refrigerator for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the pickled vegetables: Prepare the cucumber, red pepper, daikon, carrot, yellow pepper, and jalapeños and set aside while you make the brine. </step>
    <step num="6">In a large pot or deep pan over high heat, combine the water, sugar, rice vinegar, and salt. Stir until the sugar dissolves, then bring the mixture to a boil. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the vegetables the brine. Stir to submerge, then remove the pot from the heat. Let sit while you sear the tofu and bake the buns, about 1 hour, then drain. </step>
    <step num="8">Once the bao dough has risen, turn it out onto a floured surface. Divide the dough in half, then cut each half into 2 ounce pieces. Roll each piece into a ball. </step>
    <step num="9">Working 1 at a time, flatten a ball with your palm on a lightly floured surface. Use a small rolling pin or wooden dowel to roll the dough out to a 5-inch round. Brush the top with sesame oil, fold it in half, and transfer it to a square of parchment paper set on a baking sheet. Repeat with the remaining dough. Cover the bao buns with a kitchen towel and let rest for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="10">Bring a pot of water to a boil and set a bamboo steamer on top. Working in batches, transfer a few of the folded dough rounds at a time to the steamer, making sure the buns are not too crowded. Cover the steamer and steam the buns for 8-10 minutes, until the buns puff up and form a skin on the outside. Very carefully, lift the lid and remove the buns from the steamer. Repeat with the rest of the buns, keeping the steamed buns warm as they finish by covering with a towel. </step>
    <step num="11">Sear the tofu: Remove the tofu from the marinade and pat dry with paper towels. Reserve the marinade. </step>
    <step num="12">Heat the vegetable oil in a large skillet over high heat. Add the tofu and sear on one side until deep brown in color, about 5 minutes. Flip and cook on the other side until deep brown, 5 minutes more. Remove the tofu from the pan. </step>
    <step num="13">Pour the reserved marinade into the skillet on medium heat and reduce until thick and syrupy, about 5 minutes. Return the tofu to the pan and stir to coat with the glaze. Remove the pan from the heat. </step>
    <step num="14">To serve, slather the inside of the bao buns with hoisin sauce, then add the pickled vegetables, glazed tofu, sliced scallions, and sesame seeds. </step>
    <step num="15">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the bao buns: Add the warm water, sugar, and yeast to a liquid measuring cup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Whisk to combine, then set aside to bloom, five minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a large bowl, whisk together the flour, baking powder, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Make a well in the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the yeast mixture and vegetable oil to the well and stir with a wooden spoon until a soft dough begins to form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Transfer the dough to a clean surface and knead until smooth and elastic, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Keep extra flour nearby in case the dough sticks to the surface or your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Shape into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Lightly grease a clean large bowl with 1 tablespoon of sesame oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Place the dough in the bowl, cover with plastic wrap, and let rise in a warm place until doubled in size, about 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Meanwhile marinate the tofu: In a medium bowl, whisk together the scallions, ginger, garlic, sugar, five-spice, soy sauce, rice wine, and dark soy sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the tofu to a separate medium bowl and pour the marinade over. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cover with plastic wrap and marinate in the refrigerator for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Make the pickled vegetables: Prepare the cucumber, red pepper, daikon, carrot, yellow pepper, and jalapeños and set aside while you make the brine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">In a large pot or deep pan over high heat, combine the water, sugar, rice vinegar, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Stir until the sugar dissolves, then bring the mixture to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the vegetables the brine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Stir to submerge, then remove the pot from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Let sit while you sear the tofu and bake the buns, about 1 hour, then drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Once the bao dough has risen, turn it out onto a floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Divide the dough in half, then cut each half into 2 ounce pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Roll each piece into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Working 1 at a time, flatten a ball with your palm on a lightly floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Use a small rolling pin or wooden dowel to roll the dough out to a 5-inch round. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Brush the top with sesame oil, fold it in half, and transfer it to a square of parchment paper set on a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Repeat with the remaining dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Cover the bao buns with a kitchen towel and let rest for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Bring a pot of water to a boil and set a bamboo steamer on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Working in batches, transfer a few of the folded dough rounds at a time to the steamer, making sure the buns are not too crowded. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Cover the steamer and steam the buns for 8-10 minutes, until the buns puff up and form a skin on the outside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Very carefully, lift the lid and remove the buns from the steamer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Repeat with the rest of the buns, keeping the steamed buns warm as they finish by covering with a towel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Sear the tofu: Remove the tofu from the marinade and pat dry with paper towels. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Reserve the marinade. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Heat the vegetable oil in a large skillet over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Add the tofu and sear on one side until deep brown in color, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Flip and cook on the other side until deep brown, 5 minutes more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="37">Remove the tofu from the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="38">Pour the reserved marinade into the skillet on medium heat and reduce until thick and syrupy, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="39">Return the tofu to the pan and stir to coat with the glaze. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="40">Remove the pan from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="41">To serve, slather the inside of the bao buns with hoisin sauce, then add the pickled vegetables, glazed tofu, sliced scallions, and sesame seeds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="42">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>