<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chocolate-Peppermint Macarons</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/peppermint-macarons</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; semi-sweet chocolate chips ; (175 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; heavy cream ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ¾ cups ; powdered sugar ; (210 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; finely ground almond flour ; (95 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 ; large egg whites, room temperature </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¼ cup ; granulated sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ teaspoon ; peppermint extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">red gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">8 ; candy canes, crushed </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Date Night</category>
    <category num="1">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="2">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117922/hls24_1543863558.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117922/landscape_720/1543863558</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the ganache filling: In a medium bowl, combine the chocolate chips and heavy cream. Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring between, until melted and smooth, about 1 minute total. Set aside to cool for at least 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="1">Make the macarons: In the bowl of a food processor, combine the powdered sugar, almond flour, and ½ teaspoon of salt. Process on low speed until very finely ground. Sift the almond flour mixture through a fine-mesh sieve into a large bowl. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">In a separate large bowl, beat the egg whites and the remaining ½ teaspoon of salt with an electric hand mixer until soft peaks form. Gradually add the granulated sugar until fully incorporated. Continue to beat until stiff peaks form (you should be able to turn the bowl upside down without anything falling out). </step>
    <step num="3">Add about ⅓ of the sifted almond flour mixture at a time to the beaten egg whites and use a rubber spatula to gently fold until combined. After the last addition of almond flour, add the peppermint extract. Continue to fold slowly until the batter falls into ribbons and you can make a figure 8 while holding the spatula up. </step>
    <step num="4">Set a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a round tip in a tall drinking glass. Dip a skewer or toothpick in the red gel food coloring and paint 2 stripes on opposite sides of the inside of the piping bag. Transfer the macaron batter to the bag. </step>
    <step num="5">Pipe 4 small dollops of batter in each corner of a rimmed baking sheet, then lay a piece of parchment paper over it, using the batter to help adhere the parchment to the baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="6">Pipe the macarons onto the parchment paper in 2-inch (5-cm) circles, spacing at least 1-inch (2.5-cm) apart. </step>
    <step num="7">Tap the baking sheet on a flat surface 5 times to release any air bubbles. If there are any points on the top of the macarons, let sit for 5 minutes after tapping the pan, then, with a slightly moistened finger, lightly pat down the peaks. </step>
    <step num="8">Let the macarons sit at room temperature for 30–60 minutes, until dry to the touch. </step>
    <step num="9">Preheat the oven to 300˚F (150˚C). </step>
    <step num="10">Bake the macarons for 20 minutes, until the feet are well risen and the macarons don’t stick to the parchment paper. Transfer the macarons to a wire rack to cool completely before filling. </step>
    <step num="11">Transfer the cooled ganache to a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a round tip. </step>
    <step num="12">Pipe a dollop of ganache onto a macaron shell. Top with another macaron shell to create a sandwich. Repeat with remaining macarons and ganache. </step>
    <step num="13">Roll the edges of the macarons in the crushed candy canes. </step>
    <step num="14">If desired, place the macarons in an airtight container for 24 hours to “bloom” before serving, or serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="15">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the ganache filling: In a medium bowl, combine the chocolate chips and heavy cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring between, until melted and smooth, about 1 minute total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Set aside to cool for at least 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Make the macarons: In the bowl of a food processor, combine the powdered sugar, almond flour, and ½ teaspoon of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Process on low speed until very finely ground. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Sift the almond flour mixture through a fine-mesh sieve into a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a separate large bowl, beat the egg whites and the remaining ½ teaspoon of salt with an electric hand mixer until soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Gradually add the granulated sugar until fully incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Continue to beat until stiff peaks form (you should be able to turn the bowl upside down without anything falling out). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add about ⅓ of the sifted almond flour mixture at a time to the beaten egg whites and use a rubber spatula to gently fold until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">After the last addition of almond flour, add the peppermint extract. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Continue to fold slowly until the batter falls into ribbons and you can make a figure 8 while holding the spatula up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Set a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a round tip in a tall drinking glass. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Dip a skewer or toothpick in the red gel food coloring and paint 2 stripes on opposite sides of the inside of the piping bag. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Transfer the macaron batter to the bag. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Pipe 4 small dollops of batter in each corner of a rimmed baking sheet, then lay a piece of parchment paper over it, using the batter to help adhere the parchment to the baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Pipe the macarons onto the parchment paper in 2-inch (5-cm) circles, spacing at least 1-inch (2.5-cm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Tap the baking sheet on a flat surface 5 times to release any air bubbles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">If there are any points on the top of the macarons, let sit for 5 minutes after tapping the pan, then, with a slightly moistened finger, lightly pat down the peaks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Let the macarons sit at room temperature for 30–60 minutes, until dry to the touch. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Preheat the oven to 300˚F (150˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Bake the macarons for 20 minutes, until the feet are well risen and the macarons don’t stick to the parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Transfer the macarons to a wire rack to cool completely before filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Transfer the cooled ganache to a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a round tip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Pipe a dollop of ganache onto a macaron shell. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Top with another macaron shell to create a sandwich. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Repeat with remaining macarons and ganache. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Roll the edges of the macarons in the crushed candy canes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">If desired, place the macarons in an airtight container for 24 hours to “bloom” before serving, or serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>