<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Low-Carb Beef Stroganoff Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/low-carb-beef-stroganoff</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ lb ; sirloin steak, cut into 1-inch (2 cm) cubes ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">oil, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ; medium white onion </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 lb ; mushroom, sliced ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 cup ; beef broth ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ cup ; sour cream ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ; large zucchini </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">thinly sliced chives, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Lunch</category>
    <category num="5">Date Night</category>
    <category num="6">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/90124/hls24_1524098108.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/90124/landscape_720/1524098108</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, season the sirloin liberally with salt and pepper. Toss to coat. </step>
    <step num="1">Heat a bit of oil in a large pot over medium-high heat until shimmering. Place half of the cubed meat in the pan, spacing out to avoid overcrowding. Sear on each side for 1 minute, until well-browned. Transfer the seared beef to a bowl and repeat with the remaining meat. </step>
    <step num="2">Reduce the heat to medium. Add the onion, mushrooms, and a pinch of salt. Sauté until all of moisture has been release from the mushrooms and evaporated and the onions have caramelized, about 12 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the beef broth and scrape up any browned bits from the bottom of the pan. </step>
    <step num="4">Once the liquid has thickened slightly, mix a few tablespoons of the hot broth with the sour cream in a small bowl--this will temper the sour cream and keep it from curdling. Add the sour cream mixture to the broth and mix until incorporated. </step>
    <step num="5">Once the liquid has thickened slightly, add the seasoned sirloin and any juices that have collected in the bowl. </step>
    <step num="6">Stir the the contents of the pot until the meat has cooked through, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Use a vegetable peeler to slice the zucchini into ribbons. </step>
    <step num="8">Heat a drizzle of oil in a medium pan over medium-high heat. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the zucchini ribbons and a pinch of salt and toss until the zucchini has wilted slightly, about 1 minute. Immediately transfer the zucchini to serving dishes to stop cooking. </step>
    <step num="10">Top the zucchini with the stroganoff and a sprinkle of chives. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, season the sirloin liberally with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Heat a bit of oil in a large pot over medium-high heat until shimmering. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Place half of the cubed meat in the pan, spacing out to avoid overcrowding. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Sear on each side for 1 minute, until well-browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Transfer the seared beef to a bowl and repeat with the remaining meat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Reduce the heat to medium. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the onion, mushrooms, and a pinch of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Sauté until all of moisture has been release from the mushrooms and evaporated and the onions have caramelized, about 12 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the beef broth and scrape up any browned bits from the bottom of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Once the liquid has thickened slightly, mix a few tablespoons of the hot broth with the sour cream in a small bowl--this will temper the sour cream and keep it from curdling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the sour cream mixture to the broth and mix until incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Once the liquid has thickened slightly, add the seasoned sirloin and any juices that have collected in the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Stir the the contents of the pot until the meat has cooked through, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Use a vegetable peeler to slice the zucchini into ribbons. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Heat a drizzle of oil in a medium pan over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the zucchini ribbons and a pinch of salt and toss until the zucchini has wilted slightly, about 1 minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Immediately transfer the zucchini to serving dishes to stop cooking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Top the zucchini with the stroganoff and a sprinkle of chives. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>