<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Giant Zebra 'Box' Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/giant-zebra-box-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; whipped cream ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; marshmallow fluff ; (25 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; yellow cake mix, baked according to package instructions in 2 9-inch (23 cm) cake pans and cooled completely </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 cups ; white chocolate chip ; (350 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; coconut oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; dark chocolate chip, melted ; (45 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">cooling rack, for glazing cake </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">pastry bag </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/114457/hls24_1541531157.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/114457/landscape_720/1541531157</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the filling: In a large bowl, combine the whipped cream and marshmallow fluff. Beat with an electric hand mixer until stiff peaks form. </step>
    <step num="1">Use a serrated knife to carefully remove the domed top from the cakes, leaving a flat, even surface. Save the scraps for later – you can eat them with leftover melted chocolate or crumbled over ice cream. </step>
    <step num="2">Spread the filling over the bottom cake, leaving about ¾-inch (2 cm) border around the edge. Place the other cake upside down on top of the filling. </step>
    <step num="3">Trim the cake into a hexagon. Transfer the cake to a wire rack set over a baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="4">Make the coating: Fill a medium saucepan halfway with water. Bring to a boil, reduce the heat to medium-low. Combine the white chocolate chips and coconut oil in a medium heatproof bowl and set it over the pan (make sure the bottom of the bowl isn’t touching the water). When the white chocolate and coconut oil begin to melt, mix together until smooth. Be careful, as the bowl will be very hot. </step>
    <step num="5">Pour the melted white chocolate mixture over the cake. Use a knife to spread to the edges and down the sides. Once smooth, run a knife under the edges of the cake so it doesn’t stick to the rack and place the cake in the refrigerator until the coating is set, 10-15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Transfer the melted dark chocolate chips to a piping bag or zip-top bag with a corner snipped off. Carefully pipe chocolate zebra stripes onto the cake. Return to the refrigerator to set for 10-15 minutes. Remove the cake once the stripes are dry. </step>
    <step num="7">To serve, slowly and carefully slice with a serrated knife so the shell doesn’t crack. Score the slices with a paring knife before cutting to make it easier, if needed. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the filling: In a large bowl, combine the whipped cream and marshmallow fluff. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Beat with an electric hand mixer until stiff peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Use a serrated knife to carefully remove the domed top from the cakes, leaving a flat, even surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Save the scraps for later – you can eat them with leftover melted chocolate or crumbled over ice cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Spread the filling over the bottom cake, leaving about ¾-inch (2 cm) border around the edge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Place the other cake upside down on top of the filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Trim the cake into a hexagon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Transfer the cake to a wire rack set over a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Make the coating: Fill a medium saucepan halfway with water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Bring to a boil, reduce the heat to medium-low. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Combine the white chocolate chips and coconut oil in a medium heatproof bowl and set it over the pan (make sure the bottom of the bowl isn’t touching the water). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">When the white chocolate and coconut oil begin to melt, mix together until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Be careful, as the bowl will be very hot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Pour the melted white chocolate mixture over the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Use a knife to spread to the edges and down the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Once smooth, run a knife under the edges of the cake so it doesn’t stick to the rack and place the cake in the refrigerator until the coating is set, 10-15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Transfer the melted dark chocolate chips to a piping bag or zip-top bag with a corner snipped off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Carefully pipe chocolate zebra stripes onto the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Return to the refrigerator to set for 10-15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Remove the cake once the stripes are dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">To serve, slowly and carefully slice with a serrated knife so the shell doesn’t crack. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Score the slices with a paring knife before cutting to make it easier, if needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>