<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Cinnamon Roll Pancakes With Chloe Coscarelli Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/cinnamon-roll-pancakes-with-chloe-coscarelli</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; all-purpose flour ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 teaspoons ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ teaspoon ; sea salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; almond milk ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; maple syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 tablespoons ; vegan margarine, or refined coconut oil, at room temperature </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">5 tablespoons ; light brown sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 teaspoons ; ground cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">vegetable oil, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 cups ; confectioners sugar ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Vegan</category>
    <category num="4">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="5">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="6">Brunch</category>
    <category num="7">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="8">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/91956/hls24_1525130258.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/91956/landscape_720/1525130258</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, whisk together the flour, baking powder, and salt. In a small bowl or measuring cup, whisk together the almond milk and maple syrup. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the wet ingredient to the dry and whisk to combine. Do not overmix. </step>
    <step num="2">In a small bowl, mix together the margarine, brown sugar, and cinnamon. Transfer to a pastry bag or plastic zip-top bag and snip off one corner. </step>
    <step num="3">Lightly grease a large nonstick skillet or griddle and heat over medium heat. When the pan shimmers, measure out ¼ cup (35 g) of the batter (or eyeball it) and pour it onto the skillet. Pipe a circular swirl of the cinnamon mixture into the batter. Repeat to fill the skillet. </step>
    <step num="4">When small bubbles appear in the center of the pancakes, after about 4 minutes, flip. </step>
    <step num="5">Cook on the other side for about 1 minute more, until lightly browned and cooked through. Repeat with the remaining batter, adding more oil to the skillet between batches as needed. </step>
    <step num="6">In a small bowl, combine the confectioners’ sugar and water and whisk until smooth. </step>
    <step num="7">Drizzle the pancakes with the glaze and serve. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, whisk together the flour, baking powder, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a small bowl or measuring cup, whisk together the almond milk and maple syrup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the wet ingredient to the dry and whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Do not overmix. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a small bowl, mix together the margarine, brown sugar, and cinnamon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Transfer to a pastry bag or plastic zip-top bag and snip off one corner. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Lightly grease a large nonstick skillet or griddle and heat over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">When the pan shimmers, measure out ¼ cup (35 g) of the batter (or eyeball it) and pour it onto the skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Pipe a circular swirl of the cinnamon mixture into the batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Repeat to fill the skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">When small bubbles appear in the center of the pancakes, after about 4 minutes, flip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cook on the other side for about 1 minute more, until lightly browned and cooked through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Repeat with the remaining batter, adding more oil to the skillet between batches as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">In a small bowl, combine the confectioners’ sugar and water and whisk until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Drizzle the pancakes with the glaze and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>