<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Nut &amp; Dairy-Free Pumpkin Pie Cheesecake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/nut-dairy-free-pumpkin-pie-cheesecake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">8 oz ; dairy-free chocolate graham crackers, about 2 sleeves ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">6 ; pitted dates </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">6 tablespoons ; coconut oil, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">12 ¼ oz ; firm silken tofu, 2 packages, drained and patted dry ; (345 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">13 oz ; coconut cream, 1 can ; (370 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¼ cup ; coconut oil, melted ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¾ cup ; maple syrup ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">3 tablespoons ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ cup ; arrowroot powder, or cornstarch ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract, or seeds from 1 vanilla bean </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 cups ; canned unsweetened pumpkin puree ; (450 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ cup ; coconut cream ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">⅓ cup ; maple syrup ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">2 tablespoons ; arrowroot powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 tablespoon ; pumpkin pie spice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">Dairy-free dark chocolate shavings, garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113178/hls24_1540420835.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113178/landscape_720/1540420835</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180˚C). Grease a 10-inch (25-cm) springform pan with coconut oil. </step>
    <step num="1">Make the crust: In a food processor, pulse together the graham crackers, dates, coconut oil, and salt until the dates are completely broken down and a moist, sand-like texture is achieved. The crust should easily hold together when pinched between your fingers. </step>
    <step num="2">Transfer the crust mixture to the prepared springform pan. Using the bottom of a measuring cup or another flat-bottomed glass, pack down the crust against the bottom and about 1 inch (2 cm) up the sides of the pan. </step>
    <step num="3">Bake the crust for 15 minutes, or until toasted and crisp around the edges. Remove from the oven and set aside to cool for about 20 minutes while you prepare the filling. Leave the oven on. </step>
    <step num="4">Clean out the food processor, then make the cheesecake layer: Add the tofu, coconut cream, coconut oil, maple syrup, lemon juice, arrowroot powder, salt, and vanilla bean seeds to the food processor and blend on high speed for 1-3 minutes, or until completely smooth. </step>
    <step num="5">Pour all but 1 cup (225 G) of the mixture over the cooled crust and shake gently to smooth. Freeze for 30 minutes. This will make it easier to add the pumpkin layer. </step>
    <step num="6">Make the pumpkin layer: To the reserved cheesecake mixture in the processor, add the pumpkin puree, coconut cream, maple syrup, arrowroot powder, and pumpkin spice, and blend on high for 1 minute, until smooth. </step>
    <step num="7">Remove the pan from the freezer and gently spoon the pumpkin mixture over the cheesecake layer. Smooth out the top using a rubber spatula or the back of a spoon. </step>
    <step num="8">Wrap the outside of the pan in foil. This will prevent water from the water bath from leaking in to the pan. </step>
    <step num="9">Place the springform pan in a large, deep baking dish and fill with hot water about halfway up the sides of the springform. This will create steam inside the oven that will help the cheesecake bake evenly. Carefully transfer the pan to the oven. </step>
    <step num="10">Bake the cheesecake for 1 hour, then turn off the oven and, without opening the door, leave the cheesecake inside for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="11">Remove from the oven and let cool, then cover and chill in the refrigerator for at least 6 hours, or overnight. </step>
    <step num="12">Release the springform, then slice and serve the chilled cheesecake. Garnish with dark chocolate shavings. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Grease a 10-inch (25-cm) springform pan with coconut oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Make the crust: In a food processor, pulse together the graham crackers, dates, coconut oil, and salt until the dates are completely broken down and a moist, sand-like texture is achieved. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">The crust should easily hold together when pinched between your fingers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Transfer the crust mixture to the prepared springform pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Using the bottom of a measuring cup or another flat-bottomed glass, pack down the crust against the bottom and about 1 inch (2 cm) up the sides of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Bake the crust for 15 minutes, or until toasted and crisp around the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove from the oven and set aside to cool for about 20 minutes while you prepare the filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Leave the oven on. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Clean out the food processor, then make the cheesecake layer: Add the tofu, coconut cream, coconut oil, maple syrup, lemon juice, arrowroot powder, salt, and vanilla bean seeds to the food processor and blend on high speed for 1-3 minutes, or until completely smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Pour all but 1 cup (225 G) of the mixture over the cooled crust and shake gently to smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Freeze for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">This will make it easier to add the pumpkin layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Make the pumpkin layer: To the reserved cheesecake mixture in the processor, add the pumpkin puree, coconut cream, maple syrup, arrowroot powder, and pumpkin spice, and blend on high for 1 minute, until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove the pan from the freezer and gently spoon the pumpkin mixture over the cheesecake layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Smooth out the top using a rubber spatula or the back of a spoon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Wrap the outside of the pan in foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">This will prevent water from the water bath from leaking in to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Place the springform pan in a large, deep baking dish and fill with hot water about halfway up the sides of the springform. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">This will create steam inside the oven that will help the cheesecake bake evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Carefully transfer the pan to the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Bake the cheesecake for 1 hour, then turn off the oven and, without opening the door, leave the cheesecake inside for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Remove from the oven and let cool, then cover and chill in the refrigerator for at least 6 hours, or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Release the springform, then slice and serve the chilled cheesecake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Garnish with dark chocolate shavings. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>