<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Bangers &amp; Mash Yorkshire Pudding Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/bangers-mash-yorkshire-pudding</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ¾ cups ; plain flour ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 ; eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ¼ cups ; milk ; (300 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">vegetable oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 ; medium potatoes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 tablespoons ; sour cream </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ cup ; milk ; (50 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">fresh chives </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 ; onion, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 ; sausages, quartered </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 teaspoon ; gravy </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">fresh chives, to garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">British</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/11150/low_1475256397.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/11150/mp4_720x1280/1475256397</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 220°C (425°F) </step>
    <step num="1">To make the Yorkshire puddings, sift the flour and salt into a large bowl and mix in the eggs and half the milk. Whisk until a paste, then add the other half of the milk and whisk until smooth. Rest for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Add a teaspoon of vegetable oil to each muffin tin hole and heat until sizzling. Turn the oven down to 200°C (400°F) and pour a tablespoon of Yorkshire pudding batter into each hole. Bake for 15 minutes or until risen and golden brown. </step>
    <step num="3">To make the mash, peel and slice three medium potatoes. Boil in salted water until soft. Drain, then add the butter, sour cream, and milk, and mash until smooth. Season with salt, pepper, and fresh chives. </step>
    <step num="4">To make the bangers, quarter two sausages and chop one onion. Fry the onion for two minutes, then add the sausages and fry both until cooked. </step>
    <step num="5">To assemble, add a teaspoon of gravy to the bottom of the Yorkshire pudding, then add the onions on top, then the mash and a sausage quarter. Sprinkle with more chives. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 220°C (425°F) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">To make the Yorkshire puddings, sift the flour and salt into a large bowl and mix in the eggs and half the milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Whisk until a paste, then add the other half of the milk and whisk until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Rest for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add a teaspoon of vegetable oil to each muffin tin hole and heat until sizzling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Turn the oven down to 200°C (400°F) and pour a tablespoon of Yorkshire pudding batter into each hole. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Bake for 15 minutes or until risen and golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">To make the mash, peel and slice three medium potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Boil in salted water until soft. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Drain, then add the butter, sour cream, and milk, and mash until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Season with salt, pepper, and fresh chives. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">To make the bangers, quarter two sausages and chop one onion. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Fry the onion for two minutes, then add the sausages and fry both until cooked. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">To assemble, add a teaspoon of gravy to the bottom of the Yorkshire pudding, then add the onions on top, then the mash and a sausage quarter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Sprinkle with more chives. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>