<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chicken Parmesan As Made By Chris Nasatrini Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chicken-parmesan-as-made-by-chris-nasatrini</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; boneless, skinless chicken breast ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; all-purpose flour, plus 2 tablespoons divided ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; plain breadcrumbs ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; lemon, zest </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; white wine, plus 1 tablespoon, preferably Pinot Grigio, divided ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ cup ; panko bread crumbs ; (25 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ cup ; grated parmesan cheese, plus more for serving ; (25 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">3 tablespoons ; olive oil, plus more for frying </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">4 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">¼ teaspoon ; red pepper flakes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 ; bay leaves </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">½ cup ; chicken stock ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">14 oz ; crushed tomato, 1 can, such as San Marzano ; (395 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">2 tablespoons ; tomato paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">2 tablespoons ; dried oregano, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">¼ cup ; fresh flat-leaf parsley, chopped, plus more for garnish ; (10 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">¼ cup ; fresh basil leaves, sliced ; (10 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">½ cup ; shredded mozzarella cheese ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">spaghetti, cooked noodles, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Italian</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Date Night</category>
    <category num="4">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/128389/hls24_1553725398.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/128389/landscape_720/1553725398</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Using the bumpy side of a meat mallet, pound each chicken breast until ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) thick. Season with salt and black pepper to taste. </step>
    <step num="1">Add 1 cup (125 G) of flour, the eggs, and the plain bread crumbs to 3 separate shallow dishes. </step>
    <step num="2">Season flour with salt, pepper, and the lemon zest. Stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="3">Season the eggs with salt and pepper, and add 1 tablespoon of white wine. Stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="4">To the bread crumbs, add the panko, remaining 2 tablespoons flour, and Parmesan. Stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="5">Working 1 piece at a time, coat the chicken in the flour, shaking off any excess, then in the egg mixture, then in the bread crumbs. Transfer to a baking sheet lined with cling wrap and refrigerate for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Heat a large cast-iron skillet over medium heat. Add enough olive oil to come ¼ inch (6 mm) up the sides of the pan. Working in batches, fry the chicken until lightly browned, 2-3 minutes per side. Drain on paper towels. </step>
    <step num="7">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </step>
    <step num="8">Wipe out the pan with a paper towel. Return to medium heat and add 3 tablespoons of olive oil, the garlic, red pepper flakes, and bay leaves. Cook until fragrant, 1-2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the remaining cup of white wine and the chicken stock. Cook until the liquid is reduced by half, stirring occasionally. </step>
    <step num="10">Stir in the crushed tomatoes and tomato paste. Season with pepper, then add the oregano, crushing between your hands to release more flavor. Simmer the sauce for 5 minutes, until thickened slightly. Add the parsley and basil and stir to incorporate. </step>
    <step num="11">Remove the bay leaves from the pan. Create a bit of space in the center, then return the chicken to the pan. Spoon the sauce over the chicken. </step>
    <step num="12">Sprinkle the mozzarella and more oregano over the chicken pieces. </step>
    <step num="13">Bake for 10-15 minutes, until the cheese is bubbly and melted and the chicken is cooked though. Set the broiler to high and broil for 1-2 minutes, until the cheese browns lightly. </step>
    <step num="14">Serve the chicken with spaghetti that's been tossed in the excess sauce. Garnish with parsley and Parmesan cheese. </step>
    <step num="15">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Using the bumpy side of a meat mallet, pound each chicken breast until ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Season with salt and black pepper to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add 1 cup (125 G) of flour, the eggs, and the plain bread crumbs to 3 separate shallow dishes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Season flour with salt, pepper, and the lemon zest. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Season the eggs with salt and pepper, and add 1 tablespoon of white wine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">To the bread crumbs, add the panko, remaining 2 tablespoons flour, and Parmesan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Working 1 piece at a time, coat the chicken in the flour, shaking off any excess, then in the egg mixture, then in the bread crumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Transfer to a baking sheet lined with cling wrap and refrigerate for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Heat a large cast-iron skillet over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add enough olive oil to come ¼ inch (6 mm) up the sides of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Working in batches, fry the chicken until lightly browned, 2-3 minutes per side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Drain on paper towels. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Wipe out the pan with a paper towel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Return to medium heat and add 3 tablespoons of olive oil, the garlic, red pepper flakes, and bay leaves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Cook until fragrant, 1-2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add the remaining cup of white wine and the chicken stock. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Cook until the liquid is reduced by half, stirring occasionally. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Stir in the crushed tomatoes and tomato paste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Season with pepper, then add the oregano, crushing between your hands to release more flavor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Simmer the sauce for 5 minutes, until thickened slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Add the parsley and basil and stir to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Remove the bay leaves from the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Create a bit of space in the center, then return the chicken to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Spoon the sauce over the chicken. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Sprinkle the mozzarella and more oregano over the chicken pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Bake for 10-15 minutes, until the cheese is bubbly and melted and the chicken is cooked though. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Set the broiler to high and broil for 1-2 minutes, until the cheese browns lightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Serve the chicken with spaghetti that's been tossed in the excess sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Garnish with parsley and Parmesan cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>