<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Guatemalan Paches As Made By Erwin Perez Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/guatemalan-paches-as-made-by-erwin-perez</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/homemade-tamales-around-latin-america</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 tablespoon ; pepitas </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; sesame seeds </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">4 ; francese rolls </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">4 ; medium tomatoes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">5 ; tomatilloes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; pasilla chile, seeded </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; dried guajillo chile, seeded </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 ; small onions, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">4 cloves ; garlic, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">3 lb ; pork shoulder, cubed ; (1.3 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">4 cups ; water ; (960 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">¼ teaspoon ; ground allspice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 lb ; pork lard ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 tablespoon ; annatto paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">5 lb ; russet potato, boiled and peeled ; (2.2 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 lb ; instant corn masa ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">banana leaves, cut into 10x12-inch (24x30 cm) rectangles </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Latin American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Lunch</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/109686/hls24_1537463153.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/109686/landscape_720/1537463153</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>281.0</start_time>
    <end_time>414.666</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium cast iron skillet over medium-high heat, toast the pepitas and sesame seeds until aromatic and lightly browned, 2-4 minutes. Transfer the seeds to a small bowl and return the pan to the heat. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the Francese rolls to the pan and toast until charred on both sides, about 5 minutes. Transfer the charred bread to a pan and cover with water. Let soak for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the tomatoes, tomatillos, ½ of an onion, pasilla, guajillo, and 1 clove of garlic to the pan and char on all sides, 10-20 minutes. Remove items as they become charred and set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">In a medium pot, combine the cubed pork, salt, ½ of an onion, 1 garlic clove, and the water. Bring to a boil, then cover and simmer for 1 hour, or until the pork is tender. Strain the pork from the broth and set both aside. </step>
    <step num="4">Squeeze out as much water as possible from the soaked bread, then add to a blender with the toasted seeds, charred vegetables, pepper, and allspice. Blend until smooth. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the pork lard to a medium bowl and microwave for 2 minutes, until melted. Stir in the annatto paste until smooth. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the hot, peeled potatoes to a large roasting pan. Mash the potatoes until smooth. Add the melted lard mixture, half the of blended tomatillo sauce, and ½ of the instant corn masa. Mix with your hands until well combined. Season with salt. The mixture should be red and somewhat tacky. If the dough is too dry, add more of the sauce. If too thin, add more corn masa. </step>
    <step num="7">To assemble the paches, lay a banana leaf on a clean work surface. Add a bit of potato dough to the center. Place some of the meat in the center, covering with the potato dough. Fold the leaf around the dough, then wrap with a second leaf and a piece of aluminum foil. Repeat with the remaining ingredients. </step>
    <step num="8">Layer a base of banana leaves in a large pot and place the wrapped paches on top. Fill the pot halfway with water. Cover the top with more banana leaves and the lid, then steam over medium heat for 1 hour. Remove the paches from the pot and let cool slightly. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium cast iron skillet over medium-high heat, toast the pepitas and sesame seeds until aromatic and lightly browned, 2-4 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Transfer the seeds to a small bowl and return the pan to the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the Francese rolls to the pan and toast until charred on both sides, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Transfer the charred bread to a pan and cover with water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Let soak for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the tomatoes, tomatillos, ½ of an onion, pasilla, guajillo, and 1 clove of garlic to the pan and char on all sides, 10-20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove items as they become charred and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a medium pot, combine the cubed pork, salt, ½ of an onion, 1 garlic clove, and the water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Bring to a boil, then cover and simmer for 1 hour, or until the pork is tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Strain the pork from the broth and set both aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Squeeze out as much water as possible from the soaked bread, then add to a blender with the toasted seeds, charred vegetables, pepper, and allspice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Blend until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the pork lard to a medium bowl and microwave for 2 minutes, until melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Stir in the annatto paste until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the hot, peeled potatoes to a large roasting pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Mash the potatoes until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the melted lard mixture, half the of blended tomatillo sauce, and ½ of the instant corn masa. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Mix with your hands until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Season with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">The mixture should be red and somewhat tacky. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">If the dough is too dry, add more of the sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">If too thin, add more corn masa. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">To assemble the paches, lay a banana leaf on a clean work surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Add a bit of potato dough to the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Place some of the meat in the center, covering with the potato dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Fold the leaf around the dough, then wrap with a second leaf and a piece of aluminum foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Repeat with the remaining ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Layer a base of banana leaves in a large pot and place the wrapped paches on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Fill the pot halfway with water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Cover the top with more banana leaves and the lid, then steam over medium heat for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Remove the paches from the pot and let cool slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>