<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Meat Lovers Sandwich Roll Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/meat-lovers-sandwich-roll</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">12 slices ; sandwich bread </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ; large egg, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; mayonnaise ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">9 slices ; provolone cheese </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">5 slices ; mortadella </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">8 slices ; ham </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">12 slices ; capicola </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">14 slices ; pepperoni </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">16 slices ; salami </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; peperoncini ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">4 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ teaspoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ teaspoon ; italian seasoning </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Lunch</category>
    <category num="5">Game Day</category>
    <category num="6">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="7">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/87033/hls24_1522273959.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/87033/landscape_720/1522273959</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Place a slice of bread on top of a piece of plastic wrap on large cutting board. Brush the right edge of the bread with egg wash and place the left edge of another slice of bread over the brushed edge, pressing together firmly. Repeat with the rest of the bread so you have a rectangle of 4 slices across and 3 slices down. </step>
    <step num="1">Using a rolling pin, roll out the bread so all of the pieces of bread are sealed together. </step>
    <step num="2">Spread mayonnaise over the bread, then arrange the sliced provolone across, starting about ¼ of the way up the bread. Layer on the mortadella, ham, capicola, pepperoni, salami, and peperoncini. </step>
    <step num="3">Starting at the bottom, roll the sandwich tightly, then cover snugly with plastic wrap. Chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="5">In a small bowl, melt the butter in the microwave for 1 minute, stirring every 15 seconds, or until fully melted. Mix in the garlic powder and Italian seasoning. </step>
    <step num="6">Transfer the sandwich roll to the baking sheet. Brush the outside with the garlic butter and bake for 18-20 minutes or until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="7">Let the roll sit for 5 minutes before cutting into thick slices. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Place a slice of bread on top of a piece of plastic wrap on large cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Brush the right edge of the bread with egg wash and place the left edge of another slice of bread over the brushed edge, pressing together firmly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Repeat with the rest of the bread so you have a rectangle of 4 slices across and 3 slices down. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Using a rolling pin, roll out the bread so all of the pieces of bread are sealed together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Spread mayonnaise over the bread, then arrange the sliced provolone across, starting about ¼ of the way up the bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Layer on the mortadella, ham, capicola, pepperoni, salami, and peperoncini. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Starting at the bottom, roll the sandwich tightly, then cover snugly with plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a small bowl, melt the butter in the microwave for 1 minute, stirring every 15 seconds, or until fully melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Mix in the garlic powder and Italian seasoning. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Transfer the sandwich roll to the baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Brush the outside with the garlic butter and bake for 18-20 minutes or until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Let the roll sit for 5 minutes before cutting into thick slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>