<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Coconut Broth Clams Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/coconut-broth-clams</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 lb ; littleneck clam, or manila clams, scrubbed ; (910 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">cold water, for soaking </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 tablespoons ; sea salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; sourdough baguette </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">olive oil, for brushing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">sea salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; coconut oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ ; medium red onion, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 large stalks ; lemongrass </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">3 tablespoons ; fresh ginger, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">4 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 teaspoon ; red pepper flakes, or 2 minced thai chilies </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 cup ; dry white wine ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 tablespoon ; brown sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 tablespoon ; fish sauce, or low sodium soy sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">2 cups ; vegetable broth, or chicken broth ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">13 oz ; full-fat coconut milk, 1 can ; (370 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">scallions, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">fresh cilantro, chopped </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Seafood</category>
    <category num="1">Thai</category>
    <category num="2">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Healthy</category>
    <category num="4">Dinner</category>
    <category num="5">Date Night</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113945/hls24_1541091005.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113945/landscape_720/1541091005</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Pick through the clams and discard any that are open and do not close when firmly tapped–these clams are dead and should not be eaten. Add the rest to a colander. </step>
    <step num="1">Rinse and scrub the remaining live clams to remove any sand or barnacles from the shells. </step>
    <step num="2">Fill a bowl large enough to fit the colander with cold water and 3-4 tablespoons of salt for every 6 cups (1.5 liters) of water. Place the colander in the bowl of salt water and soak the clams for at least 1 hour, up to overnight, so they release any grit and sand. The colander allows the grit to fall to the bottom of the bowl. Live clams will filter the water while they push out any impurities in the process. </step>
    <step num="3">Transfer the clams in the colander to another large bowl of fresh water to desalt for 15-30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Grill the bread: Slice the sourdough baguette into ½-inch (1 cm) pieces. </step>
    <step num="5">Brush each slice with olive oil and sprinkle with salt. </step>
    <step num="6">Toast the bread on a grill pan over medium-high heat until golden brown and crusty, about 2 minutes per side. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="7">Make the coconut broth: Melt the coconut oil in a wok or large pan over medium heat. Add the red onion and cook until it starts to become translucent, about 3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Firmly tap the lemongrass stalks with a wooden spoon to bruise, which helps release aroma and flavor during cooking. Trim the ends, then slice into approximately 4-inch (10 cm) pieces. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the lemongrass to the wok, along with the ginger, garlic, and red pepper flakes. Cook until fragrant, about 3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="10">Carefully pour in the white wine and stir to deglaze the pan. Bring to a simmer and cook until reduced by half, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="11">Add the brown sugar, fish sauce, vegetable broth, and coconut milk. Bring to a boil. </step>
    <step num="12">Add the clams, return to a boil, and cook for 5-8 minutes, or until all of the clams are fully opened. If any clams remain closed, discard them. </step>
    <step num="13">Discard the lemongrass stalks and divide the clams and broth between serving bowls. Garnish with scallions and cilantro and serve with the grilled bread for dipping. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Pick through the clams and discard any that are open and do not close when firmly tapped–these clams are dead and should not be eaten. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the rest to a colander. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Rinse and scrub the remaining live clams to remove any sand or barnacles from the shells. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Fill a bowl large enough to fit the colander with cold water and 3-4 tablespoons of salt for every 6 cups (1.5 liters) of water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Place the colander in the bowl of salt water and soak the clams for at least 1 hour, up to overnight, so they release any grit and sand. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">The colander allows the grit to fall to the bottom of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Live clams will filter the water while they push out any impurities in the process. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Transfer the clams in the colander to another large bowl of fresh water to desalt for 15-30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Grill the bread: Slice the sourdough baguette into ½-inch (1 cm) pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Brush each slice with olive oil and sprinkle with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Toast the bread on a grill pan over medium-high heat until golden brown and crusty, about 2 minutes per side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Make the coconut broth: Melt the coconut oil in a wok or large pan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the red onion and cook until it starts to become translucent, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Firmly tap the lemongrass stalks with a wooden spoon to bruise, which helps release aroma and flavor during cooking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Trim the ends, then slice into approximately 4-inch (10 cm) pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the lemongrass to the wok, along with the ginger, garlic, and red pepper flakes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cook until fragrant, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Carefully pour in the white wine and stir to deglaze the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Bring to a simmer and cook until reduced by half, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Add the brown sugar, fish sauce, vegetable broth, and coconut milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Bring to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add the clams, return to a boil, and cook for 5-8 minutes, or until all of the clams are fully opened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">If any clams remain closed, discard them. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Discard the lemongrass stalks and divide the clams and broth between serving bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Garnish with scallions and cilantro and serve with the grilled bread for dipping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>