<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Vegetarian Breakfast Apple Sausages Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/vegetarian-breakfast-apple-sausages</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 tablespoons ; olive oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; onion, minced ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; apple, minced ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; baby bella mushroom, minced ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; fennel seeds </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; dried rosemary </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; sage powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; maple syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">15 oz ; cannellini bean, 1 can, drained and rinsed ; (425 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ cup ; chickpeas, canned, rinsed and drained, or cooked ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 cup ; vital wheat gluten, or all-purpose flour ; (125 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Vegan</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="5">Brunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/108700/hls24_1536708005.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/108700/landscape_720/1536708005</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Heat 1 tablespoon of olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat. Add the onion and garlic and cook for about 4 minutes, until fragrant and the onion is translucent. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the apples, mushrooms, fennel seeds, rosemary, sage, maple syrup, salt, and pepper and stir to combine. Reduce the heat to medium-low and cook for about 10 minutes, until the mixture is tender and the liquid released from the mushrooms has evaporated. Remove from the heat and let cool. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the cannellini beans and chickpeas to a food processor and pulse into a smooth paste. </step>
    <step num="3">Transfer the bean paste to a large bowl and add the apple/mushroom mixture and vital wheat gluten. Mix with a spatula and then your hands until well combined. </step>
    <step num="4">Form the sausage mixture into a loaf, wrap in plastic wrap, and refrigerate for 2 hours. </step>
    <step num="5">Unwrap the chilled sausage mixture and divide into 10-12 equal pieces, depending on what size sausages you would like. </step>
    <step num="6">Roll a piece between your palms into a sausage shape. Place in the center of a large sheet of plastic wrap and roll the plastic over it so the sausage is completely encased. Twist the ends of the wrap and knot them together tightly. Repeat for each sausage. </step>
    <step num="7">Bring a large pot of water to a simmer. Plunge the wrapped sausages in the water and simmer for 45-50 minutes, until the sausages are firm. </step>
    <step num="8">Remove from the water and let cool for about 5 minutes, then unwrap. </step>
    <step num="9">Heat the remaining tablespoon of olive oil in a large skillet over medium-low heat. Fry the sausages for 1-2 minutes on each side, until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="10">Serve immediately or keep wrapped in the refrigerator for up to 4 days. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Heat 1 tablespoon of olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the onion and garlic and cook for about 4 minutes, until fragrant and the onion is translucent. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the apples, mushrooms, fennel seeds, rosemary, sage, maple syrup, salt, and pepper and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Reduce the heat to medium-low and cook for about 10 minutes, until the mixture is tender and the liquid released from the mushrooms has evaporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Remove from the heat and let cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the cannellini beans and chickpeas to a food processor and pulse into a smooth paste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Transfer the bean paste to a large bowl and add the apple/mushroom mixture and vital wheat gluten. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Mix with a spatula and then your hands until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Form the sausage mixture into a loaf, wrap in plastic wrap, and refrigerate for 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Unwrap the chilled sausage mixture and divide into 10-12 equal pieces, depending on what size sausages you would like </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Roll a piece between your palms into a sausage shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place in the center of a large sheet of plastic wrap and roll the plastic over it so the sausage is completely encased. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Twist the ends of the wrap and knot them together tightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Repeat for each sausage. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Bring a large pot of water to a simmer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Plunge the wrapped sausages in the water and simmer for 45-50 minutes, until the sausages are firm </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Remove from the water and let cool for about 5 minutes, then unwrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Heat the remaining tablespoon of olive oil in a large skillet over medium-low heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Fry the sausages for 1-2 minutes on each side, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Serve immediately or keep wrapped in the refrigerator for up to 4 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>