<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Slow Cooker Roast Beef And No Knead Beer Bread Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/slow-cooker-roast-beef-and-no-knead-beer-bread</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ teaspoons ; active dry yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 ½ cups ; all-purpose flour ; (560 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; water, warm ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">12 fl oz ; beer, any brand ; (355 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 teaspoons ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">top sirloin steak, or top round </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">carrot, as desired </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">celery, as desired </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">onion, as desired </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; beef broth, or vegetable stock ; (235 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">corn meal, to prevent dough sticking </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32013/low_1495125003.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32013/mp4_720x1280/1495125003</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Combine 1 ½ teaspoons of dry active yeast, ½ cup (60 g) all-purpose flour, and ½ a cup (120ml) of warm water. Cover and set a warm place for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Then add 1 12 oz bottle of beer of your preference, 2 teaspoons salt, and roughly 4 cups of flour. Add the last cup of flour slowly to so that the dough dose not become dry. </step>
    <step num="2">Work into a ball until all the ingredients are combined. Cover with a hot damp towel and set in a warm place for 2 hours. </step>
    <step num="3">Use top round or top sirloin cuts of beef. Salt all sides generously. </step>
    <step num="4">Sear on all sides in a very hot, heavy skillet. If a pool of fat begins to form in the skillet, remove some so that the meat sears evenly. </step>
    <step num="5">Place in a slow cooker on a bed of onion, carrot, and celery. Pour over with a cup of beef or vegetable stock. </step>
    <step num="6">Cook 2 hours on high, or until internal temperature reaches 130°F (55°C). </step>
    <step num="7">Scrape the dough down from the sides of the bowl and onto a flowered work surface. </step>
    <step num="8">Pull the edges of the dough down underneath itself until a smooth loaf is formed. Sprinkle flour on top of the loaf. </step>
    <step num="9">Next, sprinkle cornmeal onto a baking sheet and set the loaf on top. Sprinkle flour on top of the loaf. Cover with a dry towel for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="10">Scar the top with a knife. </step>
    <step num="11">Bake at 425°F (220°C) for 35 minutes. Place a pan of water on the rack below the dough in the oven. Cool to room temperature before cutting. </step>
    <step num="12">Remove steak from slow cooker. Rest 20 minutes before slicing. Strain juices to use as a dip or stock in other cooking. Cool to room temperature before cutting. </step>
    <step num="13">Thinly slice steak and place between pieces of sliced bread. Serve with juices from slow cooker on the side for dipping. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Combine 1 ½ teaspoons of dry active yeast, ½ cup (60 g) all-purpose flour, and ½ a cup (120ml) of warm water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cover and set a warm place for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Then add 1 12 oz bottle of beer of your preference, 2 teaspoons salt, and roughly 4 cups of flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the last cup of flour slowly to so that the dough dose not become dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Work into a ball until all the ingredients are combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cover with a hot damp towel and set in a warm place for 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Use top round or top sirloin cuts of beef. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Salt all sides generously. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Sear on all sides in a very hot, heavy skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">If a pool of fat begins to form in the skillet, remove some so that the meat sears evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place in a slow cooker on a bed of onion, carrot, and celery. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Pour over with a cup of beef or vegetable stock. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cook 2 hours on high, or until internal temperature reaches 130°F (55°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Scrape the dough down from the sides of the bowl and onto a flowered work surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Pull the edges of the dough down underneath itself until a smooth loaf is formed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Sprinkle flour on top of the loaf. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Next, sprinkle cornmeal onto a baking sheet and set the loaf on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Sprinkle flour on top of the loaf. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Cover with a dry towel for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Scar the top with a knife. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Bake at 425°F (220°C) for 35 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Place a pan of water on the rack below the dough in the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Cool to room temperature before cutting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Remove steak from slow cooker. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Rest 20 minutes before slicing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Strain juices to use as a dip or stock in other cooking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Cool to room temperature before cutting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Thinly slice steak and place between pieces of sliced bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Serve with juices from slow cooker on the side for dipping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>