<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Bacon Cheddar Deviled Eggs Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/bacon-cheddar-deviled-eggs</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">6 ; eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 tablespoons ; mayonnaise </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; apple cider vinegar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; French's yellow mustard </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 ; scallions, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 strips ; bacon, cooked and coarsely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; shredded cheddar cheese ; (25 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">freshly ground black pepper </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="1">Snacks</category>
    <category num="2">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/132126/hls24_1557358532.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/132126/landscape_720/1557358532</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Place eggs in a small saucepan. Add cold water to the pot to completely submerge the eggs. Bring to a boil, then cover pot with a lid and turn off the heat. Let eggs sit in the hot water for 14 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Transfer the eggs to a bowl of ice water to cool. Peel the eggs. </step>
    <step num="2">Slice eggs in half lengthwise and carefully remove the yolks. Transfer the yolks to a mixing bowl and set aside the halved egg whites. </step>
    <step num="3">Mash the yolks with a fork until crumbly. Stir in the mayonnaise, vinegar, salt, and French’s Yellow Mustard until the filling is smooth. </step>
    <step num="4">Transfer the filling to a piping bag and pipe into the halved egg whites. </step>
    <step num="5">Top the deviled eggs with the scallions, bacon, and cheddar cheese, dividing evenly. Top with freshly ground pepper and serve. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Place eggs in a small saucepan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add cold water to the pot to completely submerge the eggs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Bring to a boil, then cover pot with a lid and turn off the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Let eggs sit in the hot water for 14 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Transfer the eggs to a bowl of ice water to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Peel the eggs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Slice eggs in half lengthwise and carefully remove the yolks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Transfer the yolks to a mixing bowl and set aside the halved egg whites. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Mash the yolks with a fork until crumbly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Stir in the mayonnaise, vinegar, salt, and French’s Yellow Mustard until the filling is smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Transfer the filling to a piping bag and pipe into the halved egg whites. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Top the deviled eggs with the scallions, bacon, and cheddar cheese, dividing evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Top with freshly ground pepper and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>