<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>White Chocolate Chip Truffle Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/white-chocolate-chip-truffle</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/easy-chocolate-truffles-4-ways</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 cups ; white chocolate chip ; (525 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; heavy cream ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; semi-sweet chocolate chips ; (175 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; semi-sweet chocolate chips, melted ; (175 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; white chocolate chips, melted ; (45 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">French</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/8233/low_1472567031.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/8233/mp4_720x1280/1472567031</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>21.0</start_time>
    <end_time>40.54</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium pan, combine the white chocolate chips, vanilla, and heavy cream over low heat. Mix until smooth. Pour the mixture into a loaf pan. Allow to sit in the refrigerator for 20 minutes to cool. </step>
    <step num="1">Pour the semisweet chocolate chips into the truffle mix and stir to combine evenly. Place in the refrigerator for 1 hour, or until the mixture is solid. </step>
    <step num="2">With an ice cream scoop, form balls from the mixture (refreeze the truffle mix if it begins to thaw). Keep the truffle balls in the refrigerator while you prepare the topping. </step>
    <step num="3">Make the topping by melting the semisweet chocolate and white chocolate in separate bowls. Dip each truffle in the melted semisweet chocolate and allow to try. Drizzle the truffles with the melted white chocolate and refrigerate. Serve cold. </step>
    <step num="4">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium pan, combine the white chocolate chips, vanilla, and heavy cream over low heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Mix until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Pour the mixture into a loaf pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Allow to sit in the refrigerator for 20 minutes to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour the semisweet chocolate chips into the truffle mix and stir to combine evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Place in the refrigerator for 1 hour, or until the mixture is solid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">With an ice cream scoop, form balls from the mixture (refreeze the truffle mix if it begins to thaw). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Keep the truffle balls in the refrigerator while you prepare the topping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Make the topping by melting the semisweet chocolate and white chocolate in separate bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Dip each truffle in the melted semisweet chocolate and allow to try. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Drizzle the truffles with the melted white chocolate and refrigerate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Serve cold. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
  <duration_human>
    <start_time>00688</start_time>
    <end_time>01497</end_time>
  </duration_human>
</recipe>