<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Strawberries ‘N’ Cream Pyramid Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/strawberries-n-cream-pyramid-cake</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/easy-desserts-for-girls-night</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">16 oz ; good-quality white chocolate, finely chopped ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¾ cup ; heavy cream ; (180 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; pound cake, store-bought </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">8 oz ; fresh strawberry , chopped ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 cups ; whipped cream ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">strawberry topping, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/94548/hls24_1526574123.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/94548/landscape_720/1526574123</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>156.0</start_time>
    <end_time>223.333</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the ganache: In a medium bowl, combine the white chocolate and heavy cream. Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring after each one, until the texture is silky and smooth. </step>
    <step num="1">Refrigerate for 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Place the pound cake on a cutting board and slice lengthwise into 4 equally thick pieces. </step>
    <step num="3">Set the bottom piece of the cake down first on a small baking pan or serving platter. </step>
    <step num="4">Spread an even layer of white chocolate ganache over the cake, then sprinkle with a layer of strawberries. Repeat making with the next two pieces of pound cake. Place the final piece of pound cake on top of the last strawberry layer and cover it with an even layer of white chocolate ganache. Refrigerate for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="5">Remove the cake from the refrigerator and place it on the edge of a cutting board sitting at the edge of your work surface. Use a serrated knife to cut the cake diagonally, lengthwise, creating two, right-angled pieces of cake. Use the edge of the cutting board to help guide your knife. </step>
    <step num="6">Set the two right-angled pieces next to each other to form a triangle with the final layer of ganache and base cake piece at the center. Cover with whipped cream. </step>
    <step num="7">Serve with strawberry topping. </step>
    <step num="8">Pairs well with rosé. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the ganache: In a medium bowl, combine the white chocolate and heavy cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring after each one, until the texture is silky and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Refrigerate for 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Place the pound cake on a cutting board and slice lengthwise into 4 equally thick pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Set the bottom piece of the cake down first on a small baking pan or serving platter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Spread an even layer of white chocolate ganache over the cake, then sprinkle with a layer of strawberries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Repeat making with the next two pieces of pound cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Place the final piece of pound cake on top of the last strawberry layer and cover it with an even layer of white chocolate ganache. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Refrigerate for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove the cake from the refrigerator and place it on the edge of a cutting board sitting at the edge of your work surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Use a serrated knife to cut the cake diagonally, lengthwise, creating two, right-angled pieces of cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Use the edge of the cutting board to help guide your knife. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Set the two right-angled pieces next to each other to form a triangle with the final layer of ganache and base cake piece at the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Cover with whipped cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Serve with strawberry topping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Pairs well with rosé. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>