<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Animal Doughnuts By Alexander Roberts Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/animal-doughnuts-by-alexander-roberts</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 qt ; peanut oil, or vegetable oil ; (1.8 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 ½ cups ; all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (560 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ¼ cups ; granulated sugar ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ teaspoon ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">4 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, cold, cubed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; buttermilk ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 ; large egg yolks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 tablespoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">4 cups ; powdered sugar, sifted ; (480 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 tablespoon ; honey </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">¼ cup ; milk ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">food coloring, of your choice, optional </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Brunch</category>
    <category num="2">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="4">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/103281/hls24_1532641585.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/103281/landscape_720/1532641585</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Heat the oil in a large pot until it reaches 350˚F (180˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper and dust with flour. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the flour, granulated sugar, salt, baking powder, and baking soda to a large bowl. Whisk to combine. </step>
    <step num="2">Rub the butter cubes into the dry mixture until well-incorporated and no large chunks remain. </step>
    <step num="3">In a small bowl or liquid measuring cup, combine the buttermilk, egg yolks, eggs, and vanilla. Whisk with a fork to combine. </step>
    <step num="4">Make a well in the center of the dry ingredients. Pour the wet ingredients into the well and fold together gently with a spatula until no flour streaks remain. </step>
    <step num="5">Flour a clean surface and dump the dough from the bowl. Sprinkle a generous amount of flour on top of the dough and shape into a disc. </step>
    <step num="6">Wrap the dough in plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Remove the dough from the refrigerator, sprinkle with more flour, and roll out to ½ inch (1-cm) thick. </step>
    <step num="8">Flour a 3½-inch (9-cm) round cookie cutter and cut rounds from the dough, then cut out the centers using a ½-inch (1-cm) cookie cutter. </step>
    <step num="9">Place the cut doughnuts on the prepared baking sheet. Reroll the leftover dough, keeping the cut-out centers, to make more doughnuts. </step>
    <step num="10">Make the animal shapes: For cat doughnuts, cut a small triangle out of the top of a doughnut. For dog doughnuts, use the small cookie cutter to cut 2 half circles out of the bottom of the doughnut and press the cut edges to round. For the bear and frog doughnuts, use a wet finger to press 2 divots at the top of a doughnut, then attach 2 cut-out centers for ears. Flip the doughnuts over so the side with the centers is against the baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="11">Working in batches, lower the doughnuts carefully into the hot oil. Fry for about 1 minute, then flip and fry for another minute, until golden brown all over. Remove the doughnuts from the oil using tongs or a spider. Cool on a wire rack for 2-3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="12">To make the glaze, add the powdered sugar, honey, and ¼ cup (60 ml) of milk to a large bowl and whisk until smooth. Add food coloring of your choice, if desired. </step>
    <step num="13">Dip the doughnuts in the glaze. Return to the wire rack and let dry. </step>
    <step num="14">Decorate, if desired. Use melted chocolate and leftover glaze to pipe faces onto the different animal doughnuts. </step>
    <step num="15">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Heat the oil in a large pot until it reaches 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper and dust with flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the flour, granulated sugar, salt, baking powder, and baking soda to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Rub the butter cubes into the dry mixture until well-incorporated and no large chunks remain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In a small bowl or liquid measuring cup, combine the buttermilk, egg yolks, eggs, and vanilla. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Whisk with a fork to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Make a well in the center of the dry ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Pour the wet ingredients into the well and fold together gently with a spatula until no flour streaks remain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Flour a clean surface and dump the dough from the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Sprinkle a generous amount of flour on top of the dough and shape into a disc. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Wrap the dough in plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove the dough from the refrigerator, sprinkle with more flour, and roll out to ½ inch (1-cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Flour a 3½-inch (9-cm) round cookie cutter and cut rounds from the dough, then cut out the centers using a ½-inch (1-cm) cookie cutter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Place the cut doughnuts on the prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Reroll the leftover dough, keeping the cut-out centers, to make more doughnuts. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Make the animal shapes: For cat doughnuts, cut a small triangle out of the top of a doughnut. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">For dog doughnuts, use the small cookie cutter to cut 2 half circles out of the bottom of the doughnut and press the cut edges to round. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">For the bear and frog doughnuts, use a wet finger to press 2 divots at the top of a doughnut, then attach 2 cut-out centers for ears. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Flip the doughnuts over so the side with the centers is against the baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Working in batches, lower the doughnuts carefully into the hot oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Fry for about 1 minute, then flip and fry for another minute, until golden brown all over. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Remove the doughnuts from the oil using tongs or a spider. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Cool on a wire rack for 2-3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">To make the glaze, add the powdered sugar, honey, and ¼ cup (60 ml) of milk to a large bowl and whisk until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Add food coloring of your choice, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Dip the doughnuts in the glaze. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Return to the wire rack and let dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Decorate, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Use melted chocolate and leftover glaze to pipe faces onto the different animal doughnuts. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>