<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Fluffy Chocolate Lava Pancakes Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/fluffy-chocolate-lava-pancakes</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; heavy cream, hot ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; dark chocolate ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ; egg yolks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; white sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 tablespoons ; butter, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ cups ; milk ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 teaspoons ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">4 ; egg whites </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">maple syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">powdered sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">fresh berries </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">butter </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="4">Brunch</category>
    <category num="5">Kid-Friendly</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/95039/hls24_1526924667.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/95039/landscape_720/1526924667</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Add the dark chocolate into the heated heavy cream. Mix both together until the chocolate fully melts forming a chocolate ganache. </step>
    <step num="1">Pour the ganache into mason jar lid rings that are laying on a parchment paper-lined sheet tray. Freeze the chocolate ganache for at least 15 minutes to firm up. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large bowl, add the egg yolks, sugar, and melted butter, whisk until smooth. Add in the milk, whisk again. Then sift in the flour, baking powder and salt. </step>
    <step num="3">Whisk the dry ingredients into the wet until as smooth as possible. Small lumps are perfectly fine. </step>
    <step num="4">Beat the egg whites until stiff peaks form and then fold them into the pancake batter until just combined. </step>
    <step num="5">In a small skillet, melt butter until bubbling and then add your pancake batter. Take chocolate ganache disc straight from the freezer and place on top of the batter and press in down to the center. Put another layer of batter over the top. </step>
    <step num="6">Cover the skillet with a lid and let the pancakes cook on low heat for 20-30 minutes or until the top has full set. Then flip the pancake and cook the other side for 2 minutes on medium heat to color the other side. </step>
    <step num="7">Serve with butter, maple syrup, powdered sugar, or berries (optional). </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Add the dark chocolate into the heated heavy cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Mix both together until the chocolate fully melts forming a chocolate ganache. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Pour the ganache into mason jar lid rings that are laying on a parchment paper-lined sheet tray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Freeze the chocolate ganache for at least 15 minutes to firm up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a large bowl, add the egg yolks, sugar, and melted butter, whisk until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add in the milk, whisk again. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Then sift in the flour, baking powder and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Whisk the dry ingredients into the wet until as smooth as possible. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Small lumps are perfectly fine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Beat the egg whites until stiff peaks form and then fold them into the pancake batter until just combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a small skillet, melt butter until bubbling and then add your pancake batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Take chocolate ganache disc straight from the freezer and place on top of the batter and press in down to the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Put another layer of batter over the top </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Cover the skillet with a lid and let the pancakes cook on low heat for 20-30 minutes or until the top has full set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Then flip the pancake and cook the other side for 2 minutes on medium heat to color the other side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Serve with butter, maple syrup, powdered sugar, or berries (optional). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>