<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Matcha Macarons Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/matcha-macarons</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; egg white </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; granulated sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; almond flour ; (25 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">⅓ cup ; powdered sugar ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; matcha </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; cream cheese, room temperature ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; powdered sugar ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; milk </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">French</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/81789/hls24_1519862826.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/81789/landscape_720/1519862826</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a medium mixing bowl, beat the egg whites with an electric hand mixer on medium speed until soft peaks form. Add ½ of the granulated sugar and with mixer on high, continue to beat until egg whites are stiff peaks. Repeat with last ½ of sugar, beating until whites are shiny and fluffy. </step>
    <step num="2">Using a fine mesh strainer, sieve the almond flour, powdered sugar, and matcha into the bowl with the egg whites. Discard any large pieces that remain in the strainer. Fold until just combined </step>
    <step num="3">Fill a piping bag with the macaron mixture and pipe 1½-inch (4 cm) dollops onto a parchment paper-lined baking sheet. Let the cookies rest until they are no longer wet to the touch and a skin forms on top (can be up to 1 hour). </step>
    <step num="4">While resting, make the filling by mixing the cream cheese, powdered sugar and milk in a bowl until smooth. Transfer to a piping bag and set aside until ready to fill. </step>
    <step num="5">When the cookies are dry to the touch, bake at 300˚F (150˚C) for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Let rest for 10 minutes, or until cool before filling. Pipe the cream cheese mixture on the macron and sandwich with another one. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a medium mixing bowl, beat the egg whites with an electric hand mixer on medium speed until soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add ½ of the granulated sugar and with mixer on high, continue to beat until egg whites are stiff peaks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Repeat with last ½ of sugar, beating until whites are shiny and fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Using a fine mesh strainer, sieve the almond flour, powdered sugar, and matcha into the bowl with the egg whites. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Discard any large pieces that remain in the strainer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Fold until just combined </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Fill a piping bag with the macaron mixture and pipe 1½-inch (4 cm) dollops onto a parchment paper-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Let the cookies rest until they are no longer wet to the touch and a skin forms on top (can be up to 1 hour). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">While resting, make the filling by mixing the cream cheese, powdered sugar and milk in a bowl until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Transfer to a piping bag and set aside until ready to fill. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">When the cookies are dry to the touch, bake at 300˚F (150˚C) for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Let rest for 10 minutes, or until cool before filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Pipe the cream cheese mixture on the macron and sandwich with another one. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>