<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Mushroom Wellington Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/mushroom-wellington</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/3-vegetarian-holiday-mains</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">16 oz ; cremini mushroom ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 tablespoons ; olive oil, divided, plus more as needed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; onion, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; vegetable broth ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 tablespoons ; soy sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; chopped fresh thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">4 oz ; spinach ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">nonstick cooking spray, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 sheet ; puff pastry, sheet </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">flour, for rolling out puff pastry </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 ; medium potatoes, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 tablespoon ; non-dairy milk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">vegan gravy, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Vegan</category>
    <category num="4">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="5">Dinner</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/63579/low_1511300857.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/63579/mp4_720x1280/1511300857</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>0</start_time>
    <end_time>86.98</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Add the mushrooms to a food processor and pulse until crumbly, 10-12 times. Be careful not to over-process. </step>
    <step num="2">Heat 2 tablespoons of olive oil in a medium pan over medium heat. Add the onion and sauté for 3-5 minutes. Add the vegetable broth and sauté until the onions are translucent and most of the broth has evaporated. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the garlic and sauté for 3 minutes more, or until fragrant. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the mushrooms and soy sauce and sauté until most of the liquid has released from the mushrooms and evaporated, 10-12 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Push the sautéed veggies to the sides of the pan and add a bit more olive oil to the center. Sauté the thyme in the oil until fragrant, then incorporate into the rest of mixture. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the spinach and sauté until wilted. </step>
    <step num="7">Grease an 18 x 13-inch baking sheet with nonstick spray. On a lightly floured surface, use a rolling pin to roll out puff pastry sheet to fit the baking sheet. Transfer the puff pastry to the pan. </step>
    <step num="8">In center third of the pastry, add a layer of potato slices. Top with half of the mushroom mixture and spread in an even layer, about ¾-inch thick. Add another layer of potatoes and the rest of the mushrooms, and top with a final layer of potatoes. </step>
    <step num="9">Fold one side of pastry over the filling, then the other side. Seal the top and bottom ends over the filling. Score the top of the Wellington diagonally with a sharp knife. </step>
    <step num="10">In a ramekin or small bowl, combine the non-dairy milk with the remaining tablespoon of olive oil. Brush over the Wellington. Decorate with more pastry, if desired. Poke air vents in the side of the Wellington. </step>
    <step num="11">Bake for 35-40 minutes. until golden brown and puffed. </step>
    <step num="12">Let rest for 10 minutes before cutting into thick slices. </step>
    <step num="13">Serve with vegan gravy. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 375°F (190°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add mushrooms to a food processor and pulse until a crumbly consistency is formed, about 10-12 times. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Be careful not to over-process. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add 2 tablespoons olive oil to medium-sized sauté pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add sliced onion and sauté for 3-5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Then add vegetable broth and sauté until translucent and most of the broth has evaporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add minced garlic to pan and sauté for 3 more minutes, or until fragrant. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add mushrooms to pans along with soy sauce, and sauté until most water had evaporated, approximately 10-12 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add a drizzle of olive oil to pan and sauté fresh thyme in oil until fragrant; then incorporate into rest of mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add in spinach and sauté until wilted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Use a rolling pin to roll out puff pastry sheet into 18x13-inch (46x33 cm) rectangle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Spray 18x13-inch (46x33 cm) baking sheet with non-stick cooking spray, then transfer puff pastry to baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">In center of puff pastry rectangle, layer potato slices in rows of two or three. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Make sure to leave a border of 1½ inches (4 cm) of pastry on either end of top and bottom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Layer mushroom mixture on top of potato slices about ¾-inch (2 cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Repeat layering the potato and mushroom once more, then finish with a layer of potatoes on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Fold one side of puff pastry over layers of filling, then repeat with opposite side of pastry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Fold in two small ends on top and bottom of Wellington and make sure all pastry is sealed and no inside filling is exposed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Decorate Wellington to your liking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Then in ramekin or small bowl, combine one tablespoon non-dairy milk with one tablespoon olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Using small brush, brush wellington with mixture until completely coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Make air vents. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Bake Wellington for 35-40 minutes until golden brown and puffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Let rest 10 minutes before cutting into thick slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Serve with vegetarian gravy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
  <duration_human>
    <start_time>00001</start_time>
    <end_time>02629</end_time>
  </duration_human>
</recipe>