<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Tasty 101 Cinnamon Rolls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/tasty-101-cinnamon-rolls</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; whole milk, warm to the touch ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">8 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 ¼ teaspoons ; active dry yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">5 cups ; all-purpose flour, divided ; (625 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¾ cup ; light brown sugar ; (165 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">12 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, softened </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 tablespoons ; ground cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">4 oz ; cream cheese, softened and cubed ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">4 tablespoons ; milk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 cup ; powdered sugar ; (120 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="1">Brunch</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="3">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/121022/hls24_1545418173.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/121022/landscape_720/1545418173</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the dough: In a large bowl, whisk together the warm milk, sugar, and melted butter. The mixture should be just warm, registering between 100-110˚F (37-43˚C). If any warmer, allow to cool slightly. </step>
    <step num="1">Sprinkle the yeast evenly over the milk mixture, stir, and let sit in a warm place for about 10 minutes until the yeast has bloomed. </step>
    <step num="2">Add 4 cups (500 g) of flour to the milk mixture and stir with a wooden spoon until just combined. </step>
    <step num="3">Cover the bowl with a kitchen towel or plastic wrap and let rise in a warm place for 1 hour, until nearly doubled in size. </step>
    <step num="4">Generously butter 2 9-inch (23 cm) round baking pans and set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the filling: In a medium bowl, combine the brown sugar, butter, and cinnamon. Mix well, then set aside. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove the plastic wrap from the dough and add the remaining cup of flour, baking powder, and salt. Stir well, then turn out onto a clean surface. Leave a bit of flour nearby to use as needed, but try not to incorporate too much. </step>
    <step num="7">Knead the dough for at least 10 minutes, adding more flour as necessary, until the dough just loses its stickiness and does not stick to the surface or your hands. The dough should be very smooth and spring back when poked. </step>
    <step num="8">Roll the dough out into a large rectangle, about ½-inch (1 cm) thick. Fix the corners with a bench scraper or a spatula to make sure they are sharp and even. </step>
    <step num="9">Spread the filling evenly over the dough. </step>
    <step num="10">Starting from one short end, roll up the dough into a log and pinch the seam closed. Place seam-side down. Trim any uneven ends. </step>
    <step num="11">Using unflavored dental floss, cut the log into evenly pieces, about 1½ inches (8cm) thick. Place the cinnamon rolls in the prepared pans, 1 in the center and about 5 around the sides. Cover with a towel and let rise in a warm place for 35-45 minutes, until expanded by about half of their original volume. If you’re saving the cinnamon rolls for later, cover with plastic wrap and freeze for up 3 months. </step>
    <step num="12">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="13">Bake the cinnamon rolls for 25-30 minutes, until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="14">While the cinnamon rolls are baking, make the frosting: In a medium bowl, whisk together the cream cheese, melted butter, milk, and vanilla extract until smooth. Gradually add the powdered sugar and whisk until homogenous and runny. </step>
    <step num="15">When the cinnamon rolls are finished, let cool for about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="16">Drizzle the frosting over the cinnamon rolls, using the back of a spoon to spread if desired. </step>
    <step num="17">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the dough: In a large bowl, whisk together the warm milk, sugar, and melted butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">The mixture should be just warm, registering between 100-110˚F (37-43˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">If any warmer, allow to cool slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Sprinkle the yeast evenly over the milk mixture, stir, and let sit in a warm place for about 10 minutes until the yeast has bloomed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add 4 cups (500 g) of flour to the milk mixture and stir with a wooden spoon until just combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cover the bowl with a kitchen towel or plastic wrap and let rise in a warm place for 1 hour, until nearly doubled in size. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Generously butter 2 9-inch (23 cm) round baking pans and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Make the filling: In a medium bowl, combine the brown sugar, butter, and cinnamon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Mix well, then set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove the plastic wrap from the dough and add the remaining cup of flour, baking powder, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Stir well, then turn out onto a clean surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Leave a bit of flour nearby to use as needed, but try not to incorporate too much. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Knead the dough for at least 10 minutes, adding more flour as necessary, until the dough just loses its stickiness and does not stick to the surface or your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">The dough should be very smooth and spring back when poked. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Roll the dough out into a large rectangle, about ½-inch (1 cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Fix the corners with a bench scraper or a spatula to make sure they are sharp and even. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Spread the filling evenly over the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Starting from one short end, roll up the dough into a log and pinch the seam closed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Place seam-side down. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Trim any uneven ends. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Using unflavored dental floss, cut the log into evenly pieces, about 1½ inches (8cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Place the cinnamon rolls in the prepared pans, 1 in the center and about 5 around the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Cover with a towel and let rise in a warm place for 35-45 minutes, until expanded by about half of their original volume. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">If you’re saving the cinnamon rolls for later, cover with plastic wrap and freeze for up 3 months. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Bake the cinnamon rolls for 25-30 minutes, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">While the cinnamon rolls are baking, make the frosting: In a medium bowl, whisk together the cream cheese, melted butter, milk, and vanilla extract until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Gradually add the powdered sugar and whisk until homogenous and runny. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">When the cinnamon rolls are finished, let cool for about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Drizzle the frosting over the cinnamon rolls, using the back of a spoon to spread if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>