<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Mexican Red Pork Tamales As Made By Edna Peredia Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/mexican-red-pork-tamales-as-made-by-edna-peredia</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/homemade-tamales-around-latin-america</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 bag ; dry corn husk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">hot water, for soaking </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ; roma tomatoes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ ; small white onion </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 ; dried guajillo chiles, dried </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 ; dried pasilla chiles </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cloves ; garlic </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">4 cups ; water, divided, plus 1 tablespoon ; (960 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 teaspoons ; salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ tablespoon ; ground cumin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 tablespoons ; canola oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">3 lb ; pork shoulder, cubed ; (1.5 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 teaspoon ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">¾ cup ; lard ; (145 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">2 lb ; fresh corn masa ; (905 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">salsa verde, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Latin American</category>
    <category num="1">Mexican</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/109686/hls24_1537463153.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/109686/landscape_720/1537463153</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>7.5</start_time>
    <end_time>140.0</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Place the dry corn husks in a baking dish. Pour hot water over the husks to cover. Weigh the husks down so they are completely submerged and let soak for 2 hours, or until pliable. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the tomatoes, onion, guajillos, pasillas, garlic, and 4 cups (960 ml) of water to a small pot. Cover, bring to a boil, and cook for 10 minutes, or until the vegetables have softened. </step>
    <step num="2">Transfer the vegetables to a blender, Add salt and pepper to taste, the cumin, and about ½ cup (60 ml) of the cooking liquid. Blend until smooth. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">Heat the canola oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. Add the pork and season with salt and pepper. Fry the pork until well-browned and most of the fat has evaporated. Drain any excess fat, if necessary. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the sauce to the pan with the pork, bring to a boil, cover, and let simmer until tender, about 1 hour. Remove from the heat and let cool. </step>
    <step num="5">In a small bowl, combine the baking soda, baking powder, and 1 tablespoon water. Stir to dissolve, then set aside. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the lard to a large bowl. With an electric hand mixer, whip the lard until light and fluffy, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the masa and baking soda mixture and mix with your hands until smooth, about 5 minutes. It should be spreadable but still hold its shape. </step>
    <step num="8">Drain the soaked corn husks. </step>
    <step num="9">Place 1 husk on a clean surface and add 1-2 tablespoons of masa to the center of the husk. Spread with the back of the spoon to about ¼ inch (¾ cm) from the edges. </step>
    <step num="10">Place 1 tablespoon of meat in the center. Roll the corn husk over the filling from left to right and fold the top down to create a little pocket. Set aside. Repeat with the remaining ingredients. </step>
    <step num="11">Place the tamales, open ends up, in a steamer basket set over a large pot of boiling water. Cover with a clean kitchen towel and the lid. Let steam for 1 hour, then turn off the heat and let the tamales rest for 1 hour more. </step>
    <step num="12">Unwrap the tamales and serve with salsa verde. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Place the dry corn husks in a baking dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pour hot water over the husks to cover. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Weigh the husks down so they are completely submerged and let soak for 2 hours, or until pliable. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the tomatoes, onion, guajillos, pasillas, garlic, and 4 cups (960 ml) of water to a small pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Cover, bring to a boil, and cook for 10 minutes, or until the vegetables have softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Transfer the vegetables to a blender, Add salt and pepper to taste, the cumin, and about ½ cup (60 ml) of the cooking liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Blend until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Heat the canola oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the pork and season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Fry the pork until well-browned and most of the fat has evaporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Drain any excess fat, if necessary. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the sauce to the pan with the pork, bring to a boil, cover, and let simmer until tender, about 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove from the heat and let cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">In a small bowl, combine the baking soda, baking powder, and 1 tablespoon water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Stir to dissolve, then set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the lard to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">With an electric hand mixer, whip the lard until light and fluffy, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the masa and baking soda mixture and mix with your hands until smooth, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">It should be spreadable but still hold its shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Drain the soaked corn husks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Place 1 husk on a clean surface and add 1-2 tablespoons of masa to the center of the husk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Spread with the back of the spoon to about ¼ inch (¾ cm) from the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Place 1 tablespoon of meat in the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Roll the corn husk over the filling from left to right and fold the top down to create a little pocket. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Repeat with the remaining ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Place the tamales, open ends up, in a steamer basket set over a large pot of boiling water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Cover with a clean kitchen towel and the lid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Let steam for 1 hour, then turn off the heat and let the tamales rest for 1 hour more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Unwrap the tamales and serve with salsa verde. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>