<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Dijon-Crusted Pork Tenderloin Honey-Glazed Carrots Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/dijon-crusted-pork-tenderloin-honey-glazed-carrots</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/fancy-3-course-holiday-party</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 tablespoons ; dijon mustard </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 teaspoons ; fresh thyme, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 teaspoons ; fresh rosemary, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ teaspoon ; ground black pepper, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ lb ; pork tenderloin ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 tablespoons ; olive oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 bunches ; broccolini, woody stems removed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">8 ; medium carrots, cute into ½-inch (1-cm) coins </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 tablespoons ; honey </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; lemon, cut into 4 wedges </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">fresh parsley, chopped, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113908/hls24_1541029130.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113908/landscape_720/1541029130</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>119.666</start_time>
    <end_time>221.6</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a small bowl, stir together the mustard, thyme, rosemary, salt, and pepper. </step>
    <step num="2">Dry the pork tenderloin thoroughly with paper towels, then season with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="3">Heat 2 tablespoons of olive oil in a square pan over medium-high heat. Add the tenderloin and cook, rotating 90˚ every 3-4 minutes, until golden brown all over (the tenderloin will not be cooked through at this point), about 12 minutes total. Remove the pan from the heat and use tongs to transfer the tenderloin to a cutting board. </step>
    <step num="4">Brush the mustard mixture evenly over the top and sides of the tenderloin. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the broccolini to the pan, and toss with the oil until coated evenly. Push the broccolini to the sides of the pan, just enough to make room for the tenderloin, then return the pork to the pan. </step>
    <step num="6">Transfer the pan to the oven and roast, tossing the broccolini halfway through cooking, until an instant-read thermometer inserted in the thickest part of the pork reads 160°F (70˚C) and the broccolini is tender, 23-25 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">While the pork cooks, heat the remaining tablespoon of olive oil in a medium skillet over medium-high heat. Add the carrots, season with salt and pepper, and cook, tossing, until barely tender, about 6 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Drizzle with the honey and continue cooking, tossing often, until the honey is reduced to a thick glaze and the carrots are tender, 2 to 4 minutes more. Remove the skillet from the heat. </step>
    <step num="9">Transfer the square pan to a rack and let the pork and broccolini rest for 10 minutes. Place the tenderloin on a cutting board and cut into ½-inch (1-cm) thick slices. </step>
    <step num="10">Divide the pork and vegetables among 4 serving plates. Serve each with a lemon wedge and sprinkle with parsley. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a small bowl, stir together the mustard, thyme, rosemary, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Dry the pork tenderloin thoroughly with paper towels, then season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Heat 2 tablespoons of olive oil in a square pan over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the tenderloin and cook, rotating 90˚ every 3-4 minutes, until golden brown all over (the tenderloin will not be cooked through at this point), about 12 minutes total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Remove the pan from the heat and use tongs to transfer the tenderloin to a cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Brush the mustard mixture evenly over the top and sides of the tenderloin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the broccolini to the pan, and toss with the oil until coated evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Push the broccolini to the sides of the pan, just enough to make room for the tenderloin, then return the pork to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Transfer the pan to the oven and roast, tossing the broccolini halfway through cooking, until an instant-read thermometer inserted in the thickest part of the pork reads 160°F (70˚C) and the broccolini is tender, 23-25 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">While the pork cooks, heat the remaining tablespoon of olive oil in a medium skillet over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the carrots, season with salt and pepper, and cook, tossing, until barely tender, about 6 minutes </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Drizzle with the honey and continue cooking, tossing often, until the honey is reduced to a thick glaze and the carrots are tender, 2 to 4 minutes more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove the skillet from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Transfer the square pan to a rack and let the pork and broccolini rest for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Place the tenderloin on a cutting board and cut into ½-inch (1-cm) thick slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Divide the pork and vegetables among 4 serving plates. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Serve each with a lemon wedge and sprinkle with parsley. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>