<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>7-Layer Steak Sandwich Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/7-layer-steak-sandwich</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/delicious-steak-dinner-recipes</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">24 oz ; sirloin steak, or top loin steak ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">fresh ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; vegetable oil, plus 2 tablespoons, divided ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ ; large yellow onion, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; button mushroom, chopped ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; sourdough bread, large </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">6 slices ; cheddar cheese </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; baby spinach ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">6 strips ; bacon, cooked </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">6 slices ; provolone cheese, or swiss cheese </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/116167/hls24_1542707879.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/116167/landscape_720/1542707879</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>160.0</start_time>
    <end_time>226.0</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Season each steak generously with salt and pepper, making sure to rub the salt and pepper into the sides of the steak. </step>
    <step num="1">In a cast iron skillet, heat the vegetable over high heat until smoking hot. Lay the steaks in the pan and cook for about 2 minutes. Flip the steaks, then add the butter, swirling it around the pan. Using a large spoon, scoop the melted butter over the tops of the steak, basting them continuously. Cook for about 2 minutes to get medium rare. (Check the steaks with an instant read thermometer if you have one; you want an internal temperature of about 135˚F.) Set the steaks aside on a cutting board to rest. </step>
    <step num="2">Wipe out the skillet and heat the remaining 2 tablespoons of oil over medium-high heat. Add the onion and mushrooms and sauté, stirring constantly, until caramelized, about 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Using a serrated knife, slice the top off the bread and scoop out the insides to create a bread bowl. Nestle one steak into the bottom of the bread bowl. Layer the cheddar cheese evenly on top. Add the caramelized onions and mushrooms and use a spoon to spread them evenly over the cheese. Top with the spinach, then the bacon, then the Swiss cheese. Finally, put the second steak on top, tucking it under the lip of the bread bowl. Cover with the bread lid and wrap the entire loaf in foil. </step>
    <step num="4">Place the wrapped sandwich in the fridge and put a cutting board on top of it. Stack books on the cutting board to compress the sandwich. Chill in the fridge for at least 5 hours. </step>
    <step num="5">Preheat the oven to 250˚F. Remove the foil from the sandwich and place it on a baking sheet. Bake for 20 minutes, until the bread is slightly crisp. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Season each steak generously with salt and pepper, making sure to rub the salt and pepper into the sides of the steak. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a cast iron skillet, heat the vegetable over high heat until smoking hot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Lay the steaks in the pan and cook for about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Flip the steaks, then add the butter, swirling it around the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Using a large spoon, scoop the melted butter over the tops of the steak, basting them continuously. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cook for about 2 minutes to get medium rare. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">(Check the steaks with an instant read thermometer if you have one; you want an internal temperature of about 135˚F.) Set the steaks aside on a cutting board to rest. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Wipe out the skillet and heat the remaining 2 tablespoons of oil over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the onion and mushrooms and sauté, stirring constantly, until caramelized, about 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Using a serrated knife, slice the top off the bread and scoop out the insides to create a bread bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Nestle one steak into the bottom of the bread bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Layer the cheddar cheese evenly on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the caramelized onions and mushrooms and use a spoon to spread them evenly over the cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Top with the spinach, then the bacon, then the Swiss cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Finally, put the second steak on top, tucking it under the lip of the bread bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cover with the bread lid and wrap the entire loaf in foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Place the wrapped sandwich in the fridge and put a cutting board on top of it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Stack books on the cutting board to compress the sandwich. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Chill in the fridge for at least 5 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Preheat the oven to 250˚F. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Remove the foil from the sandwich and place it on a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Bake for 20 minutes, until the bread is slightly crisp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>