<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Cookies And Cream Funnel Cake Sandwiches Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/cookies-and-cream-funnel-cake-sandwiches</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">30 ; chocolate sandwich cookies, divided, doublestuffed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 cups ; heavy cream, cold ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">8 oz ; cream cheese, room temperature ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 ½ cups ; all purpose flour ; (310 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; granulated sugar, 1 teaspoon of vanilla extract ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ½ cups ; whole milk ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">canola oil, for frying </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">powdered sugar, for dusting </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="2">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/133115/hls24_1558114022.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/133115/landscape_720/1558114022</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Take 20 cookies and separate the cookies from the cream filling. Reserve the filling in a medium bowl and place the cookies in a food processor. Process the cookies until broken down to a fine dust, about 1 minute. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">Chop the remaining 10 cookies into small pieces. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the heavy cream to a large bowl. Using an electric hand mixer, beat the heavy cream until stiff peaks form, about 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">To the bowl with the reserved cream filling, add the cream cheese. Using the hand mixer, beat together until smooth and creamy. Gently fold the whipped cream into the cream cheese mixture, then fold in the chopped cookies. Refrigerate until ready to assemble the sandwiches. </step>
    <step num="4">In a medium bowl, mix together the flour, cookie crumbs, baking powder, and salt. </step>
    <step num="5">In a large bowl, whisk together the eggs, sugar, vanilla, milk, and water. </step>
    <step num="6">Sift the dry ingredients into the wet ingredients, about ⅓ at a time. Use a rubber spatula to stir the batter together. Transfer the batter to a 32-ounce (905 G) squeeze bottle with a wide tip (trimmed if necessary). </step>
    <step num="7">Fill a small pot, no more than 6 inches (15 cm) wide, ⅔ of the way with canola oil and heat over medium heat until the temperature reaches 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="8">Starting from the outside and working inward, squeeze a 4-inch (10 cm) wide circle of batter in the center of the hot oil and in a circular fashion, fill in the center of the circle to create the funnel cake. Fry for 90 seconds on each side, until golden brown. Transfer to a paper towel-lined baking sheet to drain. Repeat with remaining batter. </step>
    <step num="9">Scoop 2 ounces of filling onto a funnel cake and top with another cake. Repeat with the remaining cakes and filling. Dust with powdered sugar, then serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Take 20 cookies and separate the cookies from the cream filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Reserve the filling in a medium bowl and place the cookies in a food processor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Process the cookies until broken down to a fine dust, about 1 minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Chop the remaining 10 cookies into small pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the heavy cream to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Using an electric hand mixer, beat the heavy cream until stiff peaks form, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">To the bowl with the reserved cream filling, add the cream cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Using the hand mixer, beat together until smooth and creamy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Gently fold the whipped cream into the cream cheese mixture, then fold in the chopped cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Refrigerate until ready to assemble the sandwiches. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">In a medium bowl, mix together the flour, cookie crumbs, baking powder, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">In a large bowl, whisk together the eggs, sugar, vanilla, milk, and water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Sift the dry ingredients into the wet ingredients, about ⅓ at a time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Use a rubber spatula to stir the batter together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Transfer the batter to a 32-ounce (905 G) squeeze bottle with a wide tip (trimmed if necessary). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Fill a small pot, no more than 6 inches (15 cm) wide, ⅔ of the way with canola oil and heat over medium heat until the temperature reaches 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Starting from the outside and working inward, squeeze a 4-inch (10 cm) wide circle of batter in the center of the hot oil and in a circular fashion, fill in the center of the circle to create the funnel cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Fry for 90 seconds on each side, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Transfer to a paper towel-lined baking sheet to drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Repeat with remaining batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Scoop 2 ounces of filling onto a funnel cake and top with another cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Repeat with the remaining cakes and filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Dust with powdered sugar, then serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>