<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Neapolitan Swiss Roll Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/neapolitan-swiss-roll</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">6 ; eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; oil ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 package ; vanilla cake mix </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; sour cream ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; cocoa powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 tablespoons ; strawberry instant gelatin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 cups ; vanilla frosting ; (345 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/80025/hls24_1519161760.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/80025/landscape_720/1519161760</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, whisk the eggs until light yellow and frothy. Add the water, oil, cake mix, sour cream, and stir until combined. </step>
    <step num="2">Separate the batter into three bowls. Add the cocoa powder to one of the bowls of batter, and stir until combined. Pour the chocolate batter into a piping bag, cut off the tip off of the piping bag. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the strawberry gelatin powder to one of the bowls of batter, and stir until combined. Pour the strawberry batter into a piping bag, cut off the tip off of the piping bag. </step>
    <step num="4">Pour the rest of the vanilla batter into a piping bag, cut off the tip off of the piping bag. </step>
    <step num="5">Pipe the strawberry onto a parchment paper-lined baking sheet, starting in the upper left corner. Pipe 3 1-inch (2 cm) lines of batter diagonally across the pan, beginning with the strawberry, following with the chocolate, then the vanilla. Continue this pattern until you have filled the entire baking sheet. Tap pan on the counter 3 times to release any air bubbles. </step>
    <step num="6">Bake for 7 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">While warm, flip cake carefully onto a large dish towel. While still warm, roll with the towel tightly but carefully. Set aside to cool for at least 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Unroll the cake carefully, and peel away the parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="9">Spread the vanilla frosting evenly on the cake. </step>
    <step num="10">Gently roll the cake up making sure not to roll too tight or the frosting will come out of the sides of the cake roll. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a large bowl, whisk the eggs until light yellow and frothy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the water, oil, cake mix, sour cream, and stir until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Separate the batter into three bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the cocoa powder to one of the bowls of batter, and stir until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour the chocolate batter into a piping bag, cut off the tip off of the piping bag. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the strawberry gelatin powder to one of the bowls of batter, and stir until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Pour the strawberry batter into a piping bag, cut off the tip off of the piping bag. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Pour the rest of the vanilla batter into a piping bag, cut off the tip off of the piping bag. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Pipe the strawberry onto a parchment paper-lined baking sheet, starting in the upper left corner. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Pipe 3 1-inch (2 cm) lines of batter diagonally across the pan, beginning with the strawberry, following with the chocolate, then the vanilla. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Continue this pattern until you have filled the entire baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Tap pan on the counter 3 times to release any air bubbles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Bake for 7 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">While warm, flip cake carefully onto a large dish towel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">While still warm, roll with the towel tightly but carefully. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Set aside to cool for at least 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Unroll the cake carefully, and peel away the parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Spread the vanilla frosting evenly on the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Gently roll the cake up making sure not to roll too tight or the frosting will come out of the sides of the cake roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>