<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Pasta Alla Norma Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/pasta-alla-norma</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; medium eggplant </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; olive oil, divided ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 cloves ; garlic, smashed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">56 oz ; whole peeled tomato, drained and roughly chopped, juices reserved ; (1.75 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ teaspoon ; red pepper flakes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 lb ; whole wheat spaghetti ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ cup ; ricotta salata, crumbled ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 bunch ; fresh basil, thinly sliced </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/121379/hls24_1545939260.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/121379/landscape_720/1545939260</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Trim the ends of the eggplant, then slice into ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) thick rounds. Lay the eggplant rounds on a paper towel and season generously on both sides with salt. Let rest for 10 minutes to draw out excess moisture. After 10 minutes, pat the eggplant rounds with a paper towel to remove the moisture. </step>
    <step num="1">Heat a griddle pan over medium-high heat and grease with 2 tablespoons of the olive oil, or your oil of choice. Grill the eggplant for about 2 minutes on each side, or until grill marks are formed. Set aside to cool, then cut into bite-size pieces. </step>
    <step num="2">Heat the remaining 2 tablespoons of olive oil in a large pan over medium heat. When the oil is hot, add the smashed garlic and cook until fragrant and lightly browned but not burnt, flipping as needed. Remove the garlic from the oil and set aside to cool, then mince. </step>
    <step num="3">To the garlic oil, add the chopped tomatoes. Cook for 5-10 minutes, or until caramelized. Add the reserved tomato juice and simmer until reduced to a sauce-like consistency, 5-8 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Add ½ teaspoon salt, the red pepper flakes, and the minced fried garlic. Stir well, reduce the heat to low, and simmer while you make the pasta. </step>
    <step num="5">In a large pot of boiling water, cook the pasta according to the package instructions. Drain and return to the pot. </step>
    <step num="6">Pour the tomato sauce over the hot pasta. Add the eggplant, ricotta salata, and fresh basil. Toss until well combined. </step>
    <step num="7">Serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Trim the ends of the eggplant, then slice into ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) thick rounds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Lay the eggplant rounds on a paper towel and season generously on both sides with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Let rest for 10 minutes to draw out excess moisture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">After 10 minutes, pat the eggplant rounds with a paper towel to remove the moisture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Heat a griddle pan over medium-high heat and grease with 2 tablespoons of the olive oil, or your oil of choice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Grill the eggplant for about 2 minutes on each side, or until grill marks are formed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Set aside to cool, then cut into bite-size pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Heat the remaining 2 tablespoons of olive oil in a large pan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">When the oil is hot, add the smashed garlic and cook until fragrant and lightly browned but not burnt, flipping as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove the garlic from the oil and set aside to cool, then mince. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">To the garlic oil, add the chopped tomatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cook for 5-10 minutes, or until caramelized. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the reserved tomato juice and simmer until reduced to a sauce-like consistency, 5-8 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add ½ teaspoon salt, the red pepper flakes, and the minced fried garlic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Stir well, reduce the heat to low, and simmer while you make the pasta. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">In a large pot of boiling water, cook the pasta according to the package instructions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Drain and return to the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Pour the tomato sauce over the hot pasta. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the eggplant, ricotta salata, and fresh basil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Toss until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>