<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Stars and Stripes S’mores Cups Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/stars-and-stripes-smores-cups</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">nonstick cooking spray </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">10 oz ; mini marshmallows, 1 bag ; (285 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">480 ; 4 cups ; graham cracker cereals, such as Golden Grahams </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">255 ; 3 cups ; marshmallow fluffs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">red food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">blue food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ⅓ cups ; milk chocolate chips ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; red, white, and blue mixed sprinkles, preferably star-shaped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">red, white, and blue sparkler birthday candles, optional </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/100685/hls24_1530554892.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/100685/landscape_720/1530554892</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Spray a 12-cup muffin tin with nonstick spray. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large pot, melt the butter over medium heat. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the marshmallows, and stir with a silicone spoon until completely melted. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the graham cereal, and stir until evenly coated. </step>
    <step num="4">Decrease the heat to low and leave the pot on the burner to keep the mixture warm. </step>
    <step num="5">Using a 2-ounce ice cream scoop, transfer one scoop of the cereal mixture to a muffin cup. Let stand for 20 seconds to cool enough to handle, then use your fingers to press the ball into the bottom and up the side to mold it to the shape of the cup. </step>
    <step num="6">Repeat with the remaining cereal mixture, working with one scoop at a time, then let all the cereal cups cool to room temperature. You will have about 2 scoops-worth of cereal mixture leftover. Discard or save for another use. </step>
    <step num="7">Divide the marshmallow fluff evenly among 3 small bowls. Stir 1 teaspoon of water into each bowl of fluff. Stir the red food coloring into one bowl, and stir the blue food coloring into a second bowl. The third bowl will be plain white. </step>
    <step num="8">Transfer each bowl of fluff to a small piping bag or plastic zip-top bag. </step>
    <step num="9">Cut the bottoms or corners off each bag and fill 4 cereal cups with each color. </step>
    <step num="10">Place the chocolate chips in a heatproof bowl and microwave until melted. Transfer the melted chocolate to a small piping bag or plastic zip-top bag. </step>
    <step num="11">Cut the bottom or corner off the bag and drizzle the chocolate in a zigzag pattern over the top of each cup. </step>
    <step num="12">Scatter the sprinkles evenly over each cup then refrigerate the cups to set the fluff filling, at least 30 minutes or up to 1 day. </step>
    <step num="13">Stand a sparkler candle in the center of each cup, if you like, and light on fire just before serving. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Spray a 12-cup muffin tin with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a large pot, melt the butter over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the marshmallows, and stir with a silicone spoon until completely melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the graham cereal, and stir until evenly coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Decrease the heat to low and leave the pot on the burner to keep the mixture warm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Using a 2-ounce ice cream scoop, transfer one scoop of the cereal mixture to a muffin cup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Let stand for 20 seconds to cool enough to handle, then use your fingers to press the ball into the bottom and up the side to mold it to the shape of the cup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Repeat with the remaining cereal mixture, working with one scoop at a time, then let all the cereal cups cool to room temperature. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">You will have about 2 scoops-worth of cereal mixture leftover. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Discard or save for another use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Divide the marshmallow fluff evenly among 3 small bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Stir 1 teaspoon of water into each bowl of fluff. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Stir the red food coloring into one bowl, and stir the blue food coloring into a second bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">The third bowl will be plain white. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Transfer each bowl of fluff to a small piping bag or plastic zip-top bag. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cut the bottoms or corners off each bag and fill 4 cereal cups with each color. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Place the chocolate chips in a heatproof bowl and microwave until melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Transfer the melted chocolate to a small piping bag or plastic zip-top bag. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Cut the bottom or corner off the bag and drizzle the chocolate in a zigzag pattern over the top of each cup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Scatter the sprinkles evenly over each cup then refrigerate the cups to set the fluff filling, at least 30 minutes or up to 1 day. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Stand a sparkler candle in the center of each cup, if you like, and light on fire just before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>