<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chocolate Berry Charlotte Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chocolate-berry-charlotte</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">nonstick cooking spray, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">6 ; large eggs, seperated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ teaspoon ; cream of tartar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¾ cup ; granulated sugar, divided ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ¼ cups ; all purpose flour ; (155 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 cups ; heavy cream, cold ; (720 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¾ cup ; heavy cream, hot ; (180 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ cup ; sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">6 oz ; dark chocolate, chopped ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">fresh blackberry </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">fresh raspberry </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">chocolate shaving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">fresh mint sprig </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">ribbon </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/125394/hls24_1550777818.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/125394/landscape_720/1550777818</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). Line 3 baking sheets (work in batches if necessary) with parchment paper and grease with nonstick spray. </step>
    <step num="1">Make the ladyfingers: In a large bowl, beat the egg whites and cream of tartar with an electric hand mixer until foamy. Gradually add ¼ cup sugar while continuing to beat until stiff peaks form. </step>
    <step num="2">In a medium bowl, beat together the egg yolks and remaining ½ cup sugar until thick and pale in color, about 3 minutes. Gently fold the yolks into egg white mixture with a rubber spatula. Sift in the flour and salt and fold to incorporate. Transfer the batter to a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a large round tip. </step>
    <step num="3">Release the bottom from a 9-inch springform pan and set the ring in the center of a prepared baking sheet. Starting at the center of the ring and working your way outward, pipe the batter in a spiral pattern, about 1 centimeter thick, leaving a ½-inch border around the edge. Remove the ring. With the remaining batter, pipe 40 3-inch (10-centimeter) long by 1-inch (2½-centimeter) wide cookies onto the remaining 2 prepared baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="4">Bake the spiral and cookies for 15-17 minutes, until lightly golden around the edges. Do not allow to get too dark. Let cool completely. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the chocolate mousse: In a large bowl, beat the cold heavy cream with an electric hand mixer until soft peaks form. Add the sugar and beat to incorporate. </step>
    <step num="6">In a medium bowl, pour the hot heavy cream over the chocolate. Stir with a rubber spatula until melted and smooth. </step>
    <step num="7">Fold the chocolate mixture into the whipped cream until incorporated. </step>
    <step num="8">Set the spiral cake base on the bottom of the springform pan and attach the ring. There should be a small gap between the cake and the ring mold. Line the gap on the inside edge of the ring with the ladyfingers, flat sides facing in. You want a snug fit so use as many ladyfingers as needed. </step>
    <step num="9">Pour the chocolate mousse into the center and smooth in an even layer. Chill until set, at least 4 hours in the refrigerator or about 2 hours in the freezer. </step>
    <step num="10">Garnish the charlotte with blackberries, raspberries, chocolate shavings, and mint sprigs. Release the springform and tie a ribbon around the outside of the charlotte. </step>
    <step num="11">Remove the ribbon before slicing and serving. Refrigerate any leftovers for up to 2 days. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line 3 baking sheets (work in batches if necessary) with parchment paper and grease with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Make the ladyfingers: In a large bowl, beat the egg whites and cream of tartar with an electric hand mixer until foamy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Gradually add ¼ cup sugar while continuing to beat until stiff peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a medium bowl, beat together the egg yolks and remaining ½ cup sugar until thick and pale in color, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Gently fold the yolks into egg white mixture with a rubber spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Sift in the flour and salt and fold to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Transfer the batter to a piping bag or zip-top bag fitted with a large round tip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Release the bottom from a 9-inch springform pan and set the ring in the center of a prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Starting at the center of the ring and working your way outward, pipe the batter in a spiral pattern, about 1 centimeter thick, leaving a ½-inch border around the edge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Remove the ring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">With the remaining batter, pipe 40 3-inch (10-centimeter) long by 1-inch (2½-centimeter) wide cookies onto the remaining 2 prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Bake the spiral and cookies for 15-17 minutes, until lightly golden around the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Do not allow to get too dark. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Make the chocolate mousse: In a large bowl, beat the cold heavy cream with an electric hand mixer until soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the sugar and beat to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">In a medium bowl, pour the hot heavy cream over the chocolate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Stir with a rubber spatula until melted and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Fold the chocolate mixture into the whipped cream until incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Set the spiral cake base on the bottom of the springform pan and attach the ring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">There should be a small gap between the cake and the ring mold. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Line the gap on the inside edge of the ring with the ladyfingers, flat sides facing in. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">You want a snug fit so use as many ladyfingers as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Pour the chocolate mousse into the center and smooth in an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Chill until set, at least 4 hours in the refrigerator or about 2 hours in the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Garnish the charlotte with blackberries, raspberries, chocolate shavings, and mint sprigs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Release the springform and tie a ribbon around the outside of the charlotte. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Remove the ribbon before slicing and serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Refrigerate any leftovers for up to 2 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>