<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Monkey Bread Brie Fondue Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/monkey-bread-brie-fondue</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 tablespoon ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ; medium white onion, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">26 oz ; pizza dough ; (735 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; bacon, chopped ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, 1/2 stick, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">8 oz ; brie cheese, 1 wheel ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; fresh chives, chopped, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">broccoli floret, steamed, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">baby potato, boiled, halved, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">mushroom, sauteed, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="2">Game Day</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/106001/hls24_1534812239.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/106001/landscape_720/1534812239</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). Prepare a 9-inch (22 cm) round cake pan with a 3½- inch (8 cm) ramekin in the center and set nearby. </step>
    <step num="1">Melt the butter in a large pan over medium-low heat. Add the onion and sauté until caramelized, stirring occasionally for about 15 minutes. Remove the pan from the heat. </step>
    <step num="2">Take a golf ball-sized piece of pizza dough and flatten it out with your fingers. Stuff the dough with about a teaspoon of caramelized onions and cooked bacon. Close the dough ball by pinching at the seam and roll into a ball in your hands. Repeat with the remaining dough and fillings. </step>
    <step num="3">Dip each stuffed ball in the melted butter. Place the stuffed balls in the prepared cake pan, stacking them around the ramekin. </step>
    <step num="4">Bake for 30 minutes, or until golden brown. Remove from the oven and reduce the oven temperature to 350˚F (180°C). Remove the ramekin with tongs (it will be hot!). </step>
    <step num="5">Place the wheel of brie in the center. Return the pan to the oven for 10 minutes more, or until the brie is soft. </step>
    <step num="6">Brush the monkey bread with more melted butter and sprinkle the bread and cheese with chives. Serve with vegetables like broccoli, potatoes, and mushrooms for dipping. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Prepare a 9-inch (22 cm) round cake pan with a 3½- inch (8 cm) ramekin in the center and set nearby. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Melt the butter in a large pan over medium-low heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the onion and sauté until caramelized, stirring occasionally for about 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Remove the pan from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Take a golf ball-sized piece of pizza dough and flatten it out with your fingers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Stuff the dough with about a teaspoon of caramelized onions and cooked bacon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Close the dough ball by pinching at the seam and roll into a ball in your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Repeat with the remaining dough and fillings. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Dip each stuffed ball in the melted butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place the stuffed balls in the prepared cake pan, stacking them around the ramekin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Bake for 30 minutes, or until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove from the oven and reduce the oven temperature to 350˚F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove the ramekin with tongs (it will be hot!). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Place the wheel of brie in the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Return the pan to the oven for 10 minutes more, or until the brie is soft. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Brush the monkey bread with more melted butter and sprinkle the bread and cheese with chives. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Serve with vegetables like broccoli, potatoes, and mushrooms for dipping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>