<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chinese Fried Sesame Balls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chinese-fried-sesame-balls</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¼ cup ; red bean, dried ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 cups ; water ; (960 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">⅔ cup ; hot water ; (160 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; light brown sugar ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 cups ; glutinous rice flour, plus more for dusting ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; sesame seed ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">7 cups ; vegetable oil ; (1.5 L) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Chinese</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/123036/hls24_1547772838.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/123036/landscape_720/1547772838</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the red bean filling: In a medium bowl, combine the red beans with 1 cup (240 ml) of water. Cover with plastic wrap and soak overnight. </step>
    <step num="1">Drain the red beans, then transfer to a small saucepan with the remaining 3 cups (720 ml) of water. Bring to a boil over medium-high heat, then cover and cook for 1 hour, until soft enough to mash with a fork. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the sugar and cook, stirring frequently, until the liquid evaporates and a thick red bean paste forms. </step>
    <step num="3">Transfer the red bean paste to a bowl. Cover with plastic wrap, pressing it directly onto the surface of the paste to prevent a skin from forming. Refrigerate until ready to use. </step>
    <step num="4">Make the dough: In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, whisk the hot water with the light brown sugar until the sugar dissolves. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the glutinous rice flour to a medium bowl and use a spoon to create a small well in the center. </step>
    <step num="6">Pour the sugar syrup into the well and stir for 5 minutes, until the dough is well combined and no longer sticks to the bowl. </step>
    <step num="7">Lightly dust a clean surface with glutinous rice flour. Turn the dough out and knead for 5 minutes, until it forms a smooth, round ball. Use a little bit more flour or water as needed. </step>
    <step num="8">Divide the dough into 8 pieces. Roll the pieces into small balls, then flatten into discs about ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) thick and 2½-inches (6.5 cm) in diameter. </step>
    <step num="9">Place 1 teaspoon of red bean filling in the center of a piece of dough. Fold in the edges to cover the filling, then roll into a ball. Roll the ball in the sesame seeds until the dough is covered. Repeat with the remaining ingredients. </step>
    <step num="10">Heat the vegetable oil in a large pot until it reaches 350°F (180°C). </step>
    <step num="11">Fry the sesame balls for 15 minutes, stirring frequently, until golden brown. Transfer to a wire rack set over a baking sheet to drain and let cool for 15 minutes before serving. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the red bean filling: In a medium bowl, combine the red beans with 1 cup (240 ml) of water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cover with plastic wrap and soak overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Drain the red beans, then transfer to a small saucepan with the remaining 3 cups (720 ml) of water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Bring to a boil over medium-high heat, then cover and cook for 1 hour, until soft enough to mash with a fork. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the sugar and cook, stirring frequently, until the liquid evaporates and a thick red bean paste forms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Transfer the red bean paste to a bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cover with plastic wrap, pressing it directly onto the surface of the paste to prevent a skin from forming. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Refrigerate until ready to use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Make the dough: In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, whisk the hot water with the light brown sugar until the sugar dissolves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the glutinous rice flour to a medium bowl and use a spoon to create a small well in the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Pour the sugar syrup into the well and stir for 5 minutes, until the dough is well combined and no longer sticks to the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Lightly dust a clean surface with glutinous rice flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Turn the dough out and knead for 5 minutes, until it forms a smooth, round ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Use a little bit more flour or water as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Divide the dough into 8 pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Roll the pieces into small balls, then flatten into discs about ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) thick and 2½-inches (6.5 cm) in diameter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Place 1 teaspoon of red bean filling in the center of a piece of dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Fold in the edges to cover the filling, then roll into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Roll the ball in the sesame seeds until the dough is covered. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Repeat with the remaining ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Heat the vegetable oil in a large pot until it reaches 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Fry the sesame balls for 15 minutes, stirring frequently, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Transfer to a wire rack set over a baking sheet to drain and let cool for 15 minutes before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>