<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Instant-Pot Whole Herb Chicken Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/instant-pot-whole-herb-chicken</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 tablespoon ; fresh sage, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; fresh thyme, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; fresh chives, plus more for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; oil, divided, plus 1 tablespoon ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 ½ lb ; whole chicken, rinsed and patted dry ; (1.5 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 ; lemons, quartered and seeded, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ; medium yellow onion, roughly chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">4 cloves ; garlic, smashed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ½ cups ; chicken stock ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ cup ; dry sherry ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">3 tablespoons ; water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">3 tablespoons ; cornstarch </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Healthy</category>
    <category num="4">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="5">Dinner</category>
    <category num="6">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="7">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124753/hls24_1550012661.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124753/landscape_720/1550012661</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a small bowl, combine the sage, thyme, chives, ¼ cup (60 ML) oil, and a pinch of salt. Stir into a paste. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">Generously season the chicken all over with salt and pepper. Then, using your fingers, gently release the skin over the chicken breast so that your fingers can slide between the skin and the breast meat. Spread half of the herb paste evenly between both breasts, then massage the skin with your fingers to push the herb paste to the places it didn’t reach. Reserve the remaining herb paste for later. Place 1 quartered lemon inside the cavity, then tie the legs together with kitchen twine. Tuck the wings under the chicken. </step>
    <step num="2">To a 6-quart Instant-Pot, add the onion, remaining 2 lemons, and the garlic. Place the chicken, breast-side up, on top, then pour in the chicken stock and sherry. Brush the remaining herb paste over the chicken. Cover with the Instant Pot lid, making sure the release valve is set to “sealing.” Set the Instant Pot to high pressure cook for 25 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Release the pressure from the Instant Pot by switching the vent from “sealing” to “venting,” making sure your hand is not over the top of the release switch, as the hot steam will come out of the top. Wait for the pressure to release and the Instant Pot to unlock before taking off the lid. </step>
    <step num="4">Transfer the chicken from the Instant Pot onto a baking sheet. If you would like crispier skin, set the broiler to high. Roast the chicken under the broiler for 3-4 minutes, or until the skin crisps and becomes a deep golden brown. </step>
    <step num="5">While the chicken skin crisps, turn the Instant Pot to high sauté mode. Bring the liquid in the pot to a boil and reduce by half, 5-6 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the cornstarch to the water and whisk together until smooth. When the sauce is reduced, whisk in the cornstarch slurry and continue to boil the gravy for another 2 minutes, or until the gravy is thick and coats the back of a spoon. </step>
    <step num="7">Strain the gravy through a fine mesh sieve. </step>
    <step num="8">Cut the chicken off the bone, place on a platter, and garnish with chives. Serve with the gravy. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a small bowl, combine the sage, thyme, chives, ¼ cup (60 ML) oil, and a pinch of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Stir into a paste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Generously season the chicken all over with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Then, using your fingers, gently release the skin over the chicken breast so that your fingers can slide between the skin and the breast meat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Spread half of the herb paste evenly between both breasts, then massage the skin with your fingers to push the herb paste to the places it didn’t reach. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Reserve the remaining herb paste for later. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Place 1 quartered lemon inside the cavity, then tie the legs together with kitchen twine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Tuck the wings under the chicken. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">To a 6-quart Instant-Pot, add the onion, remaining 2 lemons, and the garlic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place the chicken, breast-side up, on top, then pour in the chicken stock and sherry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Brush the remaining herb paste over the chicken. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cover with the Instant Pot lid, making sure the release valve is set to “sealing.” Set the Instant Pot to high pressure cook for 25 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Release the pressure from the Instant Pot by switching the vent from “sealing” to “venting,” making sure your hand is not over the top of the release switch, as the hot steam will come out of the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Wait for the pressure to release and the Instant Pot to unlock before taking off the lid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Transfer the chicken from the Instant Pot onto a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">If you would like crispier skin, set the broiler to high. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Roast the chicken under the broiler for 3-4 minutes, or until the skin crisps and becomes a deep golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">While the chicken skin crisps, turn the Instant Pot to high sauté mode. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Bring the liquid in the pot to a boil and reduce by half, 5-6 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Add the cornstarch to the water and whisk together until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">When the sauce is reduced, whisk in the cornstarch slurry and continue to boil the gravy for another 2 minutes, or until the gravy is thick and coats the back of a spoon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Strain the gravy through a fine mesh sieve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Cut the chicken off the bone, place on a platter, and garnish with chives. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Serve with the gravy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>