<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Blood Orange Chocolate Olive Oil Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/blood-orange-chocolate-olive-oil-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">5 ; blood oranges </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; olive oil, plus more for greasing ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ½ cups ; all purpose flour ; (185 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">⅔ cup ; dark cocoa powder, unsweetened ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ½ teaspoons ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ¼ cups ; organic sugar ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; filtered water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ½ teaspoons ; white vinegar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; powdered sugar ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; pistachio, raw, roughly chopped ; (30 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Vegan</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/128464/hls24_1553798035.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/128464/landscape_720/1553798035</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Zest all 5 blood oranges and divide between 3 separate small bowls: 2 bowls should contain the zest of 1 orange each, and 1 bowl should contain the zest of 3 oranges. Set aside the 2 bowls with less zest for later use. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the olive oil to the bowl with the zest of 3 oranges. Set aside for 30-60 minutes to infuse. </step>
    <step num="2">Juice 3 of the oranges and set aside 3 tablespoons of juice for the glaze. Reserve the remaining orange juice in a liquid measuring cup. You should have about ½ cup. (120 ML) </step>
    <step num="3">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚F). </step>
    <step num="4">In a large bowl, sift together the flour, cocoa powder, baking soda, and salt. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the sugar, blood orange olive oil (with the zest), ½ cup (120 ml) of the blood orange juice, water, and white vinegar. Whisk until the batter is smooth with no lumps. </step>
    <step num="6">Lightly grease the bottom and sides of an 8-9-inch (20-22 cm) round cake pan with olive oil, and place a parchment round in the bottom of the pan. (To make the parchment round, tear off an 18 x 13-inch (45x33 cm) piece of parchment paper. With a long edge closest to you, fold down the top right corner to meet the bottom edge. Press down on the long side of the triangle to flatten, then turn so that side is facing you and fold in half, bringing the points together. Turn again so the long side of the new triangle is on top and fold in half twice more. Flip the cake pan upside down and hold the pointy end of the triangle at the center of the pan. Trim the excess parchment that extends past the edge of the pan. Flip the pan, unfold the triangle, and place the parchment round in the bottom). </step>
    <step num="7">Pour the batter into the prepared pan and bake for 35-40 minutes, until a toothpick inserted in the center of the cake comes out clean. </step>
    <step num="8">While the cake bakes, prepare the toppings: Cut the top and the bottoms off the 2 remaining zested oranges. Using a paring knife, carefully remove the skin and pith from the oranges until you are left with just the flesh. Turn each orange on its side and cut into ¼-inch (6 mm) wide rounds. Place the rounds between 2 paper towels to blot some of the excess juice. This will allow them to stick to the glaze more effectively. </step>
    <step num="9">Make the glaze: Sift the powdered sugar into a medium bowl. Add the reserved zest of 1 orange, and the remaining 3 tablespoons of blood orange juice. Whisk into a glaze. It should be thick, but spreadable. </step>
    <step num="10">Remove the cake from the oven. Let cool in the pan for 10 minutes, then flip onto a wire rack set over a baking sheet to cool completely. </step>
    <step num="11">Once the cake has cooled, pour the glaze over the cake, letting it drip down the sides. Decorate the top with the orange slices, pistachios, and remaining orange zest. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Zest all 5 blood oranges and divide between 3 separate small bowls: 2 bowls should contain the zest of 1 orange each, and 1 bowl should contain the zest of 3 oranges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Set aside the 2 bowls with less zest for later use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the olive oil to the bowl with the zest of 3 oranges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set aside for 30-60 minutes to infuse. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Juice 3 of the oranges and set aside 3 tablespoons of juice for the glaze. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Reserve the remaining orange juice in a liquid measuring cup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">You should have about ½ cup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">(120 ML) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚F). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a large bowl, sift together the flour, cocoa powder, baking soda, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the sugar, blood orange olive oil (with the zest), ½ cup (120 ml) of the blood orange juice, water, and white vinegar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Whisk until the batter is smooth with no lumps. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Lightly grease the bottom and sides of an 8-9-inch (20-22 cm) round cake pan with olive oil, and place a parchment round in the bottom of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">(To make the parchment round, tear off an 18 x 13-inch (45x33 cm) piece of parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">With a long edge closest to you, fold down the top right corner to meet the bottom edge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Press down on the long side of the triangle to flatten, then turn so that side is facing you and fold in half, bringing the points together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Turn again so the long side of the new triangle is on top and fold in half twice more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Flip the cake pan upside down and hold the pointy end of the triangle at the center of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Trim the excess parchment that extends past the edge of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Flip the pan, unfold the triangle, and place the parchment round in the bottom). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Pour the batter into the prepared pan and bake for 35-40 minutes, until a toothpick inserted in the center of the cake comes out clean. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">While the cake bakes, prepare the toppings: Cut the top and the bottoms off the 2 remaining zested oranges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Using a paring knife, carefully remove the skin and pith from the oranges until you are left with just the flesh. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Turn each orange on its side and cut into ¼-inch (6 mm) wide rounds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Place the rounds between 2 paper towels to blot some of the excess juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">This will allow them to stick to the glaze more effectively. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Make the glaze: Sift the powdered sugar into a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Add the reserved zest of 1 orange, and the remaining 3 tablespoons of blood orange juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Whisk into a glaze. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">It should be thick, but spreadable. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Remove the cake from the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Let cool in the pan for 10 minutes, then flip onto a wire rack set over a baking sheet to cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Once the cake has cooled, pour the glaze over the cake, letting it drip down the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Decorate the top with the orange slices, pistachios, and remaining orange zest. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>