<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Pot Roast With Mashed Cauliflower Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/pot-roast-with-mashed-cauliflower</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/4-easy-instant-pot-dinners</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ lb ; chuck roast ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ; white onion, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 ; carrots, sliced 2 inch (5 cm) long </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 cups ; beef broth ; (475 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 tablespoons ; flour </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ; cauliflower, cut into florets </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; beef broth ; (235 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 clove ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 tablespoon ; sour cream </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">fresh chives, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Lunch</category>
    <category num="4">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/79548/hls24_1518807520.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/79548/landscape_720/1518807520</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>193.833</start_time>
    <end_time>297.333</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Pat the chuck roast dry with paper towels. Season on all sides with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="1">Put the Instant Pot on “Saute”. Once it says “Hot”, add the oil. </step>
    <step num="2">When the oil is shimmering, add the chuck roast. Sear the meat until brown, about 3-5 minutes per side. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the onion, carrots, and beef broth to the pot. Mix around until evenly distributed. </step>
    <step num="4">Set the pressure knob to “Sealing” and close the lid until it beeps. Tip: Closing the lid can be tricky. Have the pressure knob at 11 o’clock and turn right. </step>
    <step num="5">Select “Manual” and increase to 50 minutes. It will say “On” in a few seconds. Note: the Instant Pot will need to warm up for 5-10 minutes. Steam will be released and a few minutes later, the time will start counting down. </step>
    <step num="6">After the time has expired, let the pot roast rest in the pot for 10 minutes. It will count up and read “L 0:10”. </step>
    <step num="7">Using a towel or mit, release the pressure knob from “Sealing” to “Venting”. After the steam has been released, carefully take out the roast and veggies and transfer to a plate or cutting board, only leaving the liquid in the pot. Cover the roast and veggies with foil. </step>
    <step num="8">Set the Instant Pot to “Saute” and once the liquid comes to a boil, add the flour. Whisk until mixed in and sauce has thickened, about 1-2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Hit “Cancel” and remove the pot. Pour the sauce into another small bowl and cover to keep warm. Then clean out the Instant Pot. </step>
    <step num="10">Place the cauliflower florets in the pot. Pour in the beef broth. </step>
    <step num="11">Seal the lid and set the pressure knob to “Sealing”. </step>
    <step num="12">Select “Manual” and set time to 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="13">Once time is up, using a towel or mit, release the pressure knob from “Sealing” to “Venting”. After steam has been released, carefully remove pot and dump out the liquid. </step>
    <step num="14">Using a potato masher or fork, mash the cauliflower until smooth. </step>
    <step num="15">Add the salt, pepper, garlic, and sour cream. Stir until everything is combined. </step>
    <step num="16">Serve with pot roast and gravy. </step>
    <step num="17">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Pat the chuck roast dry with paper towels. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Season on all sides with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Put the Instant Pot on “Saute”. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Once it says “Hot”, add the oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">When the oil is shimmering, add the chuck roast. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Sear the meat until brown, about 3-5 minutes per side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the onion, carrots, and beef broth to the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Mix around until evenly distributed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Set the pressure knob to “Sealing” and close the lid until it beeps. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Tip: Closing the lid can be tricky. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Have the pressure knob at 11 o’clock and turn right. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Select “Manual” and increase to 50 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">It will say “On” in a few seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Note: the Instant Pot will need to warm up for 5-10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Steam will be released and a few minutes later, the time will start counting down. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">After the time has expired, let the pot roast rest in the pot for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">It will count up and read “L 0:10”. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Using a towel or mit, release the pressure knob from “Sealing” to “Venting”. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">After the steam has been released, carefully take out the roast and veggies and transfer to a plate or cutting board, only leaving the liquid in the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Cover the roast and veggies with foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Set the Instant Pot to “Saute” and once the liquid comes to a boil, add the flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Whisk until mixed in and sauce has thickened, about 1-2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Hit “Cancel” and remove the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Pour the sauce into another small bowl and cover to keep warm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Then clean out the Instant Pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Place the cauliflower florets in the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Pour in the beef broth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Seal the lid and set the pressure knob to “Sealing”. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Select “Manual” and set time to 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Once time is up, using a towel or mit, release the pressure knob from “Sealing” to “Venting”. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">After steam has been released, carefully remove pot and dump out the liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Using a potato masher or fork, mash the cauliflower until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Add the salt, pepper, garlic, and sour cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Stir until everything is combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Serve with pot roast and gravy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
  <duration_human>
    <start_time>04147</start_time>
    <end_time>07132</end_time>
  </duration_human>
</recipe>