<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Bacon Croque Madame Brunch Ring Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/bacon-croque-madame-brunch-ring</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¼ cup ; salted butter, 1/2 stick ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">12 strips ; bacon, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; all-purpose flour ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 cups ; milk, warm ; (960 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; dijon mustard </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">15 slices ; white bread </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">17 slices ; ham </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">3 cups ; shredded mozzarella cheese, divided ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 teaspoon ; fresh chives, chopped, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">8 ; eggs, made sunny-side up, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">French</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="4">Brunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/103761/hls24_1533143737.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/103761/landscape_720/1533143737</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium pan over high heat, cook the bacon until browned, about 12 minutes. Transfer the bacon bits to a paper towel to drain and leave the bacon grease in the pan. </step>
    <step num="1">To the pan, add the flour, pepper, and salt and whisk to combine for 5 minutes. Add the milk and Dijon mustard and cook until thickened, about 5 minutes. Remove the béchamel sauce from the heat and cover to keep warm. </step>
    <step num="2">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). Grease a bundt pan with the salted butter. Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="3">With a rolling pin, roll out the bread to flatten and cut 8 slices in half. </step>
    <step num="4">Arrange the 7 whole slices around the outer sides of the bundt pan and 4 half slices around the inner ring. Place 5 slices of ham over the bread. Sprinkle 1 cup (100 g) of mozzarella and ⅓ of the chopped bacon on top of the ham. </step>
    <step num="5">Place 6 half slices of bread on top of the bacon layer. Top with 8 slices of ham, another cup of mozzarella, and another ⅓ of the chopped bacon. Top with another 4 slices of ham. Place 6 half slices of bread on top of the ham. </step>
    <step num="6">Bake for 25 minutes, or until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="7">Invert the ring onto the prepared baking sheet, remove the bundt pan, and brush the top of the ring with béchamel sauce. Sprinkle with the remaining cup of mozzarella and the rest of the bacon. </step>
    <step num="8">Broil for 10 minutes, until the cheese is melted and browned. </step>
    <step num="9">Sprinkle the ring with parsley. Transfer the rest of the béchamel sauce to a small bowl and place in the middle of the ring. </step>
    <step num="10">Slice the ring and serve warm with the sauce and sunny-side up eggs. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium pan over high heat, cook the bacon until browned, about 12 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Transfer the bacon bits to a paper towel to drain and leave the bacon grease in the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">To the pan, add the flour, pepper, and salt and whisk to combine for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the milk and Dijon mustard and cook until thickened, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Remove the béchamel sauce from the heat and cover to keep warm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Grease a bundt pan with the salted butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">With a rolling pin, roll out the bread to flatten and cut 8 slices in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Arrange the 7 whole slices around the outer sides of the bundt pan and 4 half slices around the inner ring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place 5 slices of ham over the bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Sprinkle 1 cup (100 g) of mozzarella and ⅓ of the chopped bacon on top of the ham. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Place 6 half slices of bread on top of the bacon layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Top with 8 slices of ham, another cup of mozzarella, and another ⅓ of the chopped bacon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Top with another 4 slices of ham. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Place 6 half slices of bread on top of the ham. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Bake for 25 minutes, or until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Invert the ring onto the prepared baking sheet, remove the bundt pan, and brush the top of the ring with béchamel sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Sprinkle with the remaining cup of mozzarella and the rest of the bacon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Broil for 10 minutes, until the cheese is melted and browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Sprinkle the ring with parsley. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Transfer the rest of the béchamel sauce to a small bowl and place in the middle of the ring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Slice the ring and serve warm with the sauce and sunny-side up eggs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>