<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Blooming Quesadilla Ring Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/blooming-quesadilla-ring</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; cooked and shredded chicken ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ; onion, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; red bell pepper, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; jalapeño, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; taco sauce ; (260 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">20 ; taco-size tortillas </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 cups ; shredded cheddar cheese ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 cups ; shredded monterey jack cheese ; (300 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Mexican</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Game Day</category>
    <category num="6">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="7">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/53952/low_1506556254.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/53952/mp4_720x1280/1506556254</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a bowl, add the chicken, red bell pepper, onion, jalapeño, and taco sauce, and mix to combine. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">Cut each tortilla in half. Evenly spread about 2 tablespoons each of the cheddar cheese, Monterey Jack cheese, and chicken mixture on one half of the tortilla. </step>
    <step num="3">Roll the tortilla into a cone starting from the cut edge making sure not to push the ingredients out of the tortilla. </step>
    <step num="4">Place a wide mouth jar or glass in the center of a parchment paper-lined baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="5">Create a ring around the jar with the tortilla cones. The point of the cones should be in the center, touching the surface of the jar. There should be about 13 cones in the first layer. </step>
    <step num="6">Sprinkle both cheddar cheese and Monterey Jack cheese over the first layer of cones. </step>
    <step num="7">Start the second layer of cones by placing one cone on top and in between 2 cones in the first layer. Continue this process with the rest of the cones. There should be 3 full layers of cones with 3 left to fill some of the empty space in the top. </step>
    <step num="8">Sprinkle the rest of the cheddar and Monterey Jack on top of the blooming quesadilla. Remove jar from center of ring. Bake until the cheese is melted and the edges of the tortillas are crispy, 15 to 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Transfer to a plate. Place dip of choice inside the ring. Top with desired garnishes. </step>
    <step num="10">Serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a bowl, add the chicken, red bell pepper, onion, jalapeño, and taco sauce, and mix to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cut each tortilla in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Evenly spread about 2 tablespoons each of the cheddar cheese, Monterey Jack cheese, and chicken mixture on one half of the tortilla. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Roll the tortilla into a cone starting from the cut edge making sure not to push the ingredients out of the tortilla. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Place a wide mouth jar or glass in the center of a parchment paper-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Create a ring around the jar with the tortilla cones. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">The point of the cones should be in the center, touching the surface of the jar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">There should be about 13 cones in the first layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Sprinkle both cheddar cheese and Monterey Jack cheese over the first layer of cones. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Start the second layer of cones by placing one cone on top and in between 2 cones in the first layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Continue this process with the rest of the cones. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">There should be 3 full layers of cones with 3 left to fill some of the empty space in the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Sprinkle the rest of the cheddar and Monterey Jack on top of the blooming quesadilla. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove jar from center of ring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Bake until the cheese is melted and the edges of the tortillas are crispy, 15 to 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Transfer to a plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Place dip of choice inside the ring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Top with desired garnishes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>