<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Angel Food Cake In A Springform Pan Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/angel-food-cake-in-a-springform-pan</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; cake flour, not self-rising ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ cups ; granulated sugar, divided ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">9 ; large egg whites </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 pinch of ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ¼ teaspoons ; cream of tartar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 lb ; fresh strawberry , hulled and thinly sliced ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 tablespoons ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 tablespoons ; granulated sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">3 cups ; whipped cream ; (750 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; aluminum springform pan, 10 inch (25 1/2 cm) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ; tall aluminum can </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Brunch</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129884/hls24_1555095936.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129884/landscape_720/1555095936</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 350ºF (180ºC). </step>
    <step num="1">Place a medium mixing bowl in the refrigerator to chill. </step>
    <step num="2">Cut a round of parchment paper to the same circumference as the base of the pan, with a hole in the center that is the same circumference as the can. Line the springform with the parchment. Cover the sides of the can completely with parchment, securing with tape and making sure that the tape is covered by parchment. </step>
    <step num="3">In a medium bowl, sift the flour and ½ cup (100 grams) of the sugar together. </step>
    <step num="4">In a large bowl, combine the egg whites, vanilla extract, salt, and cream of tartar. Using an electric mixer, beat the mixture on medium speed until soft peaks form. You will know when they’ve reached the soft peak stage because the whites will just barely be able to hold their shape. </step>
    <step num="5">Increase the mixer speed to high and gradually add the remaining cup of sugar, 2 tablespoons at a time. Beat until the mixture forms stiff peaks. This may take up to 10-12 minutes. You will know that you are getting close to stiff peaks when the whites turn very glossy with a satin-like appearance. Lift the beater out of the bowl and check if the peak stands straight up in a point with no curling at the tip. Once it does, your ready for the next step. </step>
    <step num="6">Sift the flour and sugar mixture into the egg whites, about ⅓ cup (80 ml) at a time. Using a large flexible spatula, carefully fold in the flour until there are no clumps left. Be careful not to overmix at this point, which will deflate the batter and decrease the volume of the cake. </step>
    <step num="7">Add ¼ cup (60 ml) water to the can to weigh it down, so it stays steady in the springform pan. </step>
    <step num="8">Carefully transfer the batter to the prepared pan, working your way around the aluminum can and smoothing the top of the batter with the flexible spatula. </step>
    <step num="9">Bake for 40-45 minutes, until the cake has risen completely, nearly reached the top of the pan, and the top is evenly golden brown with a few cracks. The top of the cake should spring back when gently pressed with your fingertip. If there is any indentation left, the cake needs to bake for longer. Return to the oven and check every 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="10">Remove the springform pan from the oven. Pour out any excess water from the can, then replace can and immediately invert the pan over a wire rack. (The soda can will prop up the cake while it cools, allowing air to circulate around it.) Let cool completely, about 45 minutes. </step>
    <step num="11">Meanwhile, prepare the strawberries. In a medium bowl, toss to combine the sliced strawberries with the lemon juice and sugar. Refrigerate the berries until you are ready to serve the cake. </step>
    <step num="12">Remove the aluminum can from the center of the cake. Carefully run a knife along the outer edge of the pan to release the cake (it should release easily). Remove the parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="13">Top the cake with whipped cream and macerated strawberries. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 350ºF (180ºC). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Place a medium mixing bowl in the refrigerator to chill. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cut a round of parchment paper to the same circumference as the base of the pan, with a hole in the center that is the same circumference as the can. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Line the springform with the parchment. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Cover the sides of the can completely with parchment, securing with tape and making sure that the tape is covered by parchment. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In a medium bowl, sift the flour and ½ cup (100 grams) of the sugar together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a large bowl, combine the egg whites, vanilla extract, salt, and cream of tartar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Using an electric mixer, beat the mixture on medium speed until soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">You will know when they’ve reached the soft peak stage because the whites will just barely be able to hold their shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Increase the mixer speed to high and gradually add the remaining cup of sugar, 2 tablespoons at a time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Beat until the mixture forms stiff peaks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">This may take up to 10-12 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">You will know that you are getting close to stiff peaks when the whites turn very glossy with a satin-like appearance. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Lift the beater out of the bowl and check if the peak stands straight up in a point with no curling at the tip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Once it does, your ready for the next step. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Sift the flour and sugar mixture into the egg whites, about ⅓ cup (80 ml) at a time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Using a large flexible spatula, carefully fold in the flour until there are no clumps left. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Be careful not to overmix at this point, which will deflate the batter and decrease the volume of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add ¼ cup (60 ml) water to the can to weigh it down, so it stays steady in the springform pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Carefully transfer the batter to the prepared pan, working your way around the aluminum can and smoothing the top of the batter with the flexible spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Bake for 40-45 minutes, until the cake has risen completely, nearly reached the top of the pan, and the top is evenly golden brown with a few cracks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">The top of the cake should spring back when gently pressed with your fingertip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">If there is any indentation left, the cake needs to bake for longer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Return to the oven and check every 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Remove the springform pan from the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Pour out any excess water from the can, then replace can and immediately invert the pan over a wire rack. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">(The soda can will prop up the cake while it cools, allowing air to circulate around it.) Let cool completely, about 45 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Meanwhile, prepare the strawberries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">In a medium bowl, toss to combine the sliced strawberries with the lemon juice and sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Refrigerate the berries until you are ready to serve the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Remove the aluminum can from the center of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Carefully run a knife along the outer edge of the pan to release the cake (it should release easily). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Remove the parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Top the cake with whipped cream and macerated strawberries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>