<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Beef Braciole (Stuffed Italian Beef Roll) Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/beef-braciole-stuffed-italian-beef-roll</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ cup ; bread crumbs ; (25 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; shredded pecorino romano cheese, plus more for serving ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; fresh basil, chopped ; (20 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">⅓ cup ; shredded provolone cheese ; (35 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; fresh italian parsley, chopped ; (20 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">8 cloves ; garlic, minced, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">freshly ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ cup ; olive oil ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 lb ; flank steak ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 tablespoons ; canola oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 tablespoon ; butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 ; medium carrot, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ; small onion, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 stalk ; celery, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 cup ; dry white wine ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">28 oz ; crushed tomato, 1 can ; (795 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">2 ; dried bay leaves </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 tablespoon ; dried oregano </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">½ teaspoon ; red pepper flakes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">1 lb ; orecchiette pasta, or polenta cooked for serving, optional ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">¼ cup ; fresh basil, cut into ribbons, for serving ; (10 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Fusion</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/103017/hls24_1532476626.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/103017/landscape_720/1532476626</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium bowl, combine the bread crumbs, pecorino Romano, ½ cup (20 g) chopped basil, provolone, parsley, 5 minced cloves of garlic, salt, pepper, and the olive oil. Stir and set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">Lay the flank steak on a cutting board. Season both sides with salt and pepper. Cover the the meat with a sheet of parchment paper. Using a meat mallet or rolling pin, pound the steak until it’s ¼ inch (6 mm) thick. </step>
    <step num="2">Remove the parchment and sprinkle the bread crumb mixture evenly over the steak. </step>
    <step num="3">Starting from the bottom, roll the meat into a log. Using butcher’s twine, tie up the roll so it holds its shape while cooking. Season with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="4">Heat the canola oil in a large Dutch oven over high heat. When the oil is shimmering, add the steak roll and, without moving it, cook until a dark brown crust forms on one side, about 3 minutes. Turn the roll and repeat until all sides and the ends have been seared. Remove the roll from the pan and set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </step>
    <step num="6">Add the butter, carrot, onion, celery, remaining 3 cloves of garlic, salt, and pepper to the pan and cook until caramelized, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the white wine and stir to loosen any brown bits from the bottom of the pot. Cook until the wine reduces and the pan is slightly dry again. </step>
    <step num="8">Add the tomatoes, bay leaves, oregano, and red pepper flakes. Stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="9">Return the beef roll to the pot. Cover and bake for 1 hour, flipping the roll halfway through (if the sauce is drying up too much, add more crushed tomatoes or water), until the beef is tender. </step>
    <step num="10">Slice the braciole and arrange on a serving platter with the sauce. Serve the braciole with orecchiette or polenta. Garnish with grated pecorino Romano and fresh basil. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium bowl, combine the bread crumbs, pecorino Romano, ½ cup (20 g) chopped basil, provolone, parsley, 5 minced cloves of garlic, salt, pepper, and the olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Stir and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Lay the flank steak on a cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Season both sides with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Cover the the meat with a sheet of parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Using a meat mallet or rolling pin, pound the steak until it’s ¼ inch (6 mm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove the parchment and sprinkle the bread crumb mixture evenly over the steak. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Starting from the bottom, roll the meat into a log. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Using butcher’s twine, tie up the roll so it holds its shape while cooking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Heat the canola oil in a large Dutch oven over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">When the oil is shimmering, add the steak roll and, without moving it, cook until a dark brown crust forms on one side, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Turn the roll and repeat until all sides and the ends have been seared. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove the roll from the pan and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the butter, carrot, onion, celery, remaining 3 cloves of garlic, salt, and pepper to the pan and cook until caramelized, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the white wine and stir to loosen any brown bits from the bottom of the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cook until the wine reduces and the pan is slightly dry again. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the tomatoes, bay leaves, oregano, and red pepper flakes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Return the beef roll to the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Cover and bake for 1 hour, flipping the roll halfway through (if the sauce is drying up too much, add more crushed tomatoes or water), until the beef is tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Slice the braciole and arrange on a serving platter with the sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Serve the braciole with orecchiette or polenta. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Garnish with grated pecorino Romano and fresh basil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>