<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>GoT Cocktails: Mezcal And Jalapeño Infused Dragon Mother</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/dragon-mother</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; granulated sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; jalapeño, quartered lengthwise, seeds and ribs removed for a milder syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; coarse salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; ground chile powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 wedge ; lime </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 fl oz ; grapefruit juice ; (90 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 fl oz ; mezcal ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 oz ; campari ; (30 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Drinks</category>
    <category num="1">Happy Hour</category>
    <category num="2">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129054/hls24_1554398782.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129054/landscape_720/1554398782</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a small saucepan over medium heat, whisk together water and sugar. Bring to a gentle simmer, just until the sugar dissolves completely. </step>
    <step num="1">Remove the pot from the heat, add the jalapeño, and cover the pot. Let infuse for at least 1 hour, or overnight in the refrigerator. </step>
    <step num="2">Pour the syrup through a fine-mesh strainer into an airtight container. Store in the refrigerator for up to 3 months. </step>
    <step num="3">On a small plate, mix together the salt and chile powder. </step>
    <step num="4">Run the lime wedge around the rim of a rocks glass. Dip the rim in the salt mixture. Fill with ice and set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">In a cocktail shaker filled with ice, combine the grapefruit juice, mezcal, Campari, and 1 ounce jalapeño simple syrup. Shake vigorously for 20 seconds. </step>
    <step num="6">Strain into the salt-rimmed glass. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a small saucepan over medium heat, whisk together water and sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Bring to a gentle simmer, just until the sugar dissolves completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Remove the pot from the heat, add the jalapeño, and cover the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Let infuse for at least 1 hour, or overnight in the refrigerator. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour the syrup through a fine-mesh strainer into an airtight container. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Store in the refrigerator for up to 3 months. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">On a small plate, mix together the salt and chile powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Run the lime wedge around the rim of a rocks glass. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Dip the rim in the salt mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Fill with ice and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a cocktail shaker filled with ice, combine the grapefruit juice, mezcal, Campari, and 1 ounce jalapeño simple syrup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Shake vigorously for 20 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Strain into the salt-rimmed glass. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>