<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chicken Curry Naan Bowls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chicken-curry-naan-bowls</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 tablespoons ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; ground pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; ground cumin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; smoked paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; ground turmeric </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; coriander </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; ground cardamom </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; dry mustard </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; cayenne </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ teaspoon ; allspice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">3 lb ; boneless, skinless chicken thighs, cut into 2 in (5 cm) cubes ; (1.3 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">5 tablespoons ; full-fat yogurt, divided, plus more for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">9 cloves ; garlic, minced, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 tablespoon ; fresh ginger, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">3 tablespoons ; olive oil, plus more as needed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">3 ; carrots, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 ; white onion, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">1 lb ; yukon gold potato, chopped ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">2 tablespoons ; tomato paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">28 oz ; crushed tomatoes, 1 can ; (795 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">2 cups ; chicken broth ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">basmati rice, or long-grain jasmine, cooked, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">1 ; fresh cilantro, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">Lime wedges, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">½ cup ; warm water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="25">2 tablespoons ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="26">1 tablespoon ; active dry yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="27">4 cups ; all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (500 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="28">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="29">1 teaspoon ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="30">1 tablespoon ; kosher salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="31">1 cup ; full-fat yogurt ; (245 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="32">1 cup ; whole milk, room temperature ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="33">olive oil, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="34">½ cup ; unsalted butter, 1 stick, melted ; (115 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Indian</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/110966/hls24_1538417081.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/110966/landscape_720/1538417081</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a small bowl, combine the salt, pepper, cumin, smoked paprika, turmeric, coriander, cardamom, dry mustard, cayenne, and allspice. Stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, add the cubed chicken thighs, 2 tablespoons of yogurt, 4 cloves of minced garlic, the ginger, and half of the spice mixture. Toss the chicken until it is fully coated. Cover the bowl with plastic wrap, and marinate in the fridge for 2 hours or overnight. </step>
    <step num="2">Make the naan bowls: In a liquid measuring cup, combine the warm water, sugar, and yeast. Set aside to bloom for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">In the meantime, mix the flour, baking powder, baking soda, and salt together in a large bowl. </step>
    <step num="4">To the yeast mixture, add the yogurt and milk. Stir until smooth, then pour into the dry ingredients. Stir to combine, then dump the dough out onto a floured surface and knead with your hands until it forms a smooth, soft ball, about 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Place the dough in a clean large bowl greased with olive oil and cover with a clean kitchen towel or plastic wrap. Let rise at room temperature until doubled in size, about 2 hours. </step>
    <step num="6">Heat the olive oil in a large Dutch oven over medium-high heat. Working in batches to avoid overcrowding the pot, cook the marinated chicken on all sides until cooked through and browned, about 20 minutes. Drizzle in more oil, as needed, to prevent the meat from sticking to the bottom of the pot. Transfer the browned meat to a plate as it finishes cooking and set aside. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the carrots, onion, potatoes, remaining 5 cloves of minced garlic, and reserved spice mixture, Stir and cook until the vegetables brown slightly and start to soften, 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Stir in the tomato paste and cook until aromatic, about 3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the crushed tomatoes and chicken broth. Stir to combine. Bring to a simmer. </step>
    <step num="10">Add the chicken, stir, and return to a simmer. Cover and cook for 30 minutes, or until the potatoes are tender and the chicken is cooked through. </step>
    <step num="11">Stir in the remaining 3 tablespoons of yogurt, then cover and keep warm. </step>
    <step num="12">Once the naan dough has risen, dump onto a floured surface, and divide into 6 equal portions. Roll each portion into a ¼-inch (1 /2 cm) thick circle, approximately 10 inches (25 cm) in diameter. </step>
    <step num="13">Heat a large cast-iron skillet over medium-high heat. Place a disc of naan dough in the skillet. Cook for about 2 minutes, until the dough puffs up, then flip and cook on the other side until browned, 1 minute. Transfer the naan to a medium bowl and place another bowl on top. Repeat with the rest of the naan dough, stacking bowls between each round. As the naan cools, they will retain the bowl shape. </step>
    <step num="14">Brush the naan bowls with warm melted butter. </step>
    <step num="15">Fill the naan bowls with the chicken curry and rice. Serve with yogurt, cilantro, and lime wedges. </step>
    <step num="16">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a small bowl, combine the salt, pepper, cumin, smoked paprika, turmeric, coriander, cardamom, dry mustard, cayenne, and allspice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a large bowl, add the cubed chicken thighs, 2 tablespoons of yogurt, 4 cloves of minced garlic, the ginger, and half of the spice mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Toss the chicken until it is fully coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Cover the bowl with plastic wrap, and marinate in the fridge for 2 hours or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Make the naan bowls: In a liquid measuring cup, combine the warm water, sugar, and yeast. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Set aside to bloom for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In the meantime, mix the flour, baking powder, baking soda, and salt together in a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">To the yeast mixture, add the yogurt and milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Stir until smooth, then pour into the dry ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Stir to combine, then dump the dough out onto a floured surface and knead with your hands until it forms a smooth, soft ball, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place the dough in a clean large bowl greased with olive oil and cover with a clean kitchen towel or plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Let rise at room temperature until doubled in size, about 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Heat the olive oil in a large Dutch oven over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Working in batches to avoid overcrowding the pot, cook the marinated chicken on all sides until cooked through and browned, about 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Drizzle in more oil, as needed, to prevent the meat from sticking to the bottom of the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Transfer the browned meat to a plate as it finishes cooking and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Add the carrots, onion, potatoes, remaining 5 cloves of minced garlic, and reserved spice mixture, Stir and cook until the vegetables brown slightly and start to soften, 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Stir in the tomato paste and cook until aromatic, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add the crushed tomatoes and chicken broth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Bring to a simmer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add the chicken, stir, and return to a simmer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Cover and cook for 30 minutes, or until the potatoes are tender and the chicken is cooked through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Stir in the remaining 3 tablespoons of yogurt, then cover and keep warm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Once the naan dough has risen, dump onto a floured surface, and divide into 6 equal portions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Roll each portion into a ¼-inch (1 /2 cm) thick circle, approximately 10 inches (25 cm) in diameter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Heat a large cast-iron skillet over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Place a disc of naan dough in the skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Cook for about 2 minutes, until the dough puffs up, then flip and cook on the other side until browned, 1 minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Transfer the naan to a medium bowl and place another bowl on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Repeat with the rest of the naan dough, stacking bowls between each round. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">As the naan cools, they will retain the bowl shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Brush the naan bowls with warm melted butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Fill the naan bowls with the chicken curry and rice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Serve with yogurt, cilantro, and lime wedges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>