<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Infinity Stone Cupcakes Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/infinity-stone-cupcakes</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¼ cup ; cold water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; gelatin powder, plus 1 1/2 tsp </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; water, room temperature ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ½ cups ; sugar ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">nonstick cooking spray, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">red liquid food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">blue liquid food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">green liquid food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">yellow liquid food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">18 ; vanilla cupcakes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 cups ; vanilla frosting ; (230 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">edible gold dust, for sprinkling </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">piping bag </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">5/8 inch round tip </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="2">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129245/hls24_1554497720.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129245/landscape_720/1554497720</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a small bowl, combine the cold water and gelatin. Let the gelatin bloom for 5 minutes, until the water is mostly absorbed. Microwave for 20–30 seconds, or until the gelatin is melted. </step>
    <step num="1">Combine the room temperature water and sugar in a medium pot. Bring to a low boil over medium-low heat. </step>
    <step num="2">Pour the gelatin mixture into the boiling sugar water, whisking constantly to combine. Cook at a low boil for 5 minutes, until the sugar and gelatin are completely dissolved. </step>
    <step num="3">Transfer the gelatin mixture to a 2-cup (480 ml) liquid measuring cup for easy pouring. Let sit for 5 minutes to cool slightly. Skim off any foam that rises to the top. </step>
    <step num="4">Grease 6 cups of a muffin tin with nonstick spray. </step>
    <step num="5">Evenly divide the gelatin mixture between the 6 greased cups of the muffin tin, about ¼ cup (30 grams) per section. </step>
    <step num="6">Use the liquid food coloring to dye each section: For red, add 3 drops of red. For green, add 3 drops of green. For purple, add 1 drop of red and 1 drop of blue. For blue, add 4 drops of blue. For orange, add 1 drop of red and 3 drops of yellow. For yellow, add 4 drops of yellow. Using a toothpick or clean fork, stir each section to combine. </step>
    <step num="7">Carefully transfer the muffin tin to the refrigerator. Chill the gelatin until set, at least 4 hours or up to overnight. </step>
    <step num="8">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper and grease with nonstick spray. </step>
    <step num="9">Remove each gelatin cup and tear into ¾-inch (2 cm) square chunks, to resemble stones. Spread evenly on the prepared baking sheet, keeping each color separate. Let dry at room temperature for 2–3 days, until the outer layer becomes hard to the touch with a matte exterior. Note: If you want to use a cover to keep debris out, place in a baking dish and cover with plastic wrap with the corner left open so they can dry out but the plastic is not touching the stones. </step>
    <step num="10">When ready to assemble the cupcakes, add the frosting to a piping bag fitted with a ⅝-inch (1 ½ cm) round tip or a plastic zip-top bag with the corner cut off. Pipe the frosting onto the cupcakes. </step>
    <step num="11">Using a fine-mesh sieve, lightly sprinkle edible gold luster dust over the frosted cupcakes. </step>
    <step num="12">Place 2–3 colored stones on top of each cupcake. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a small bowl, combine the cold water and gelatin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Let the gelatin bloom for 5 minutes, until the water is mostly absorbed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Microwave for 20–30 seconds, or until the gelatin is melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Combine the room temperature water and sugar in a medium pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Bring to a low boil over medium-low heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour the gelatin mixture into the boiling sugar water, whisking constantly to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cook at a low boil for 5 minutes, until the sugar and gelatin are completely dissolved. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Transfer the gelatin mixture to a 2-cup (480 ml) liquid measuring cup for easy pouring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Let sit for 5 minutes to cool slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Skim off any foam that rises to the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Grease 6 cups of a muffin tin with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Evenly divide the gelatin mixture between the 6 greased cups of the muffin tin, about ¼ cup (30 grams) per section. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Use the liquid food coloring to dye each section: For red, add 3 drops of red. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">For green, add 3 drops of green. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">For purple, add 1 drop of red and 1 drop of blue. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">For blue, add 4 drops of blue. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">For orange, add 1 drop of red and 3 drops of yellow. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">For yellow, add 4 drops of yellow. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Using a toothpick or clean fork, stir each section to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Carefully transfer the muffin tin to the refrigerator. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Chill the gelatin until set, at least 4 hours or up to overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper and grease with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Remove each gelatin cup and tear into ¾-inch (2 cm) square chunks, to resemble stones. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Spread evenly on the prepared baking sheet, keeping each color separate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Let dry at room temperature for 2–3 days, until the outer layer becomes hard to the touch with a matte exterior. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Note: If you want to use a cover to keep debris out, place in a baking dish and cover with plastic wrap with the corner left open so they can dry out but the plastic is not touching the stones. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">When ready to assemble the cupcakes, add the frosting to a piping bag fitted with a ⅝-inch (1 ½ cm) round tip or a plastic zip-top bag with the corner cut off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Pipe the frosting onto the cupcakes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Using a fine-mesh sieve, lightly sprinkle edible gold luster dust over the frosted cupcakes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Place 2–3 colored stones on top of each cupcake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>