<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Kale, Sweet Potato, and Onion Frittata Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/kale-sweet-potato-and-onion-frittata</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">7 ; large egg whites </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ; small sweet potato, cut in ½-inch (1 cm) cubes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 teaspoons ; extra virgin olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; small yellow onion, roughly chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">ground pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; kale leaves, chopped, ribs and stems removed ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ ; blood orange, or ½ a small navel orange </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 cup ; water ; (235 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="4">Healthy</category>
    <category num="5">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="6">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="7">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="8">Brunch</category>
    <category num="9">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="10">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32053/low_1495125041.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32053/mp4_720x1280/1495125041</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 450°F (230°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Whisk together the 3 egg yolks in a small mixing bowl and set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">NOTE: You’ll have 4 yolks leftover. You can either discard them, or freeze them for later use. </step>
    <step num="3">Beat the seven egg whites (or nine egg whites) in a large mixing bowl with a large whisk until they form soft peaks. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the yolks to the beaten whites and very gently whisk the mixture, just to combine. Set the eggs aside in the fridge while you cook the vegetables. </step>
    <step num="5">Combine the cubed sweet potato with 1 cup water (235 ml) in a large, nonstick, oven-safe skillet over high heat. Bring to a boil, then reduce the heat to a simmer and cook, stirring occasionally, just until all the water has evaporated and the sweet potato is soft on the outside, about 8 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">NOTE: If you don’t have a large nonstick skillet, you can use a regular, oven-safe skillet. Just be sure to coat it thoroughly with oil. </step>
    <step num="7">As soon as the water is evaporated, add the olive oil and onion, stir together, and season with salt and pepper. Cook over medium heat, stirring often, until the onion starts to soften, about a minute. </step>
    <step num="8">Add the chopped kale and cook, stirring often, until the kale is wilted and dark green, about 2 minutes more. </step>
    <step num="9">Spread the vegetables evenly over the bottom of the skillet, then pour the egg mixture on top and spread it in an even layer. </step>
    <step num="10">Bake in the preheated oven until the frittata is puffed, cooked through, and very lightly browned on top, 5 to 6 minutes. </step>
    <step num="11">Let the frittata cool in the skillet for 5 minutes, then flip it onto a cutting board and cut it in half. </step>
    <step num="12">Eat half for breakfast, with ½ a blood orange, cut into wedges. </step>
    <step num="13">For the leftovers, let the remaining half cool completely before storing in an airtight container in the fridge. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 450°F (230°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Whisk together the 3 egg yolks in a small mixing bowl and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">NOTE: You’ll have 4 yolks leftover. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">You can either discard them, or freeze them for later use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Beat the seven egg whites (or nine egg whites) in a large mixing bowl with a large whisk until they form soft peaks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the yolks to the beaten whites and very gently whisk the mixture, just to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Set the eggs aside in the fridge while you cook the vegetables. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Combine the cubed sweet potato with 1 cup water (235 ml) in a large, nonstick, oven-safe skillet over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Bring to a boil, then reduce the heat to a simmer and cook, stirring occasionally, just until all the water has evaporated and the sweet potato is soft on the outside, about 8 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">NOTE: If you don’t have a large nonstick skillet, you can use a regular, oven-safe skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Just be sure to coat it thoroughly with oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">As soon as the water is evaporated, add the olive oil and onion, stir together, and season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cook over medium heat, stirring often, until the onion starts to soften, about a minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the chopped kale and cook, stirring often, until the kale is wilted and dark green, about 2 minutes more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Spread the vegetables evenly over the bottom of the skillet, then pour the egg mixture on top and spread it in an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Bake in the preheated oven until the frittata is puffed, cooked through, and very lightly browned on top, 5 to 6 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Let the frittata cool in the skillet for 5 minutes, then flip it onto a cutting board and cut it in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Eat half for breakfast, with ½ a blood orange, cut into wedges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">For the leftovers, let the remaining half cool completely before storing in an airtight container in the fridge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>