<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Rubik’s Cube Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/rubiks-cube-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; pound cake, store-bought frozen </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; vanilla frosting ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ teaspoon ; lemon zest </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; lime zest </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; orange marmalade </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; strawberry jam </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; blueberry jam </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 bag ; marshmallow, white </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; water, plus more as needed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">4 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, softened </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">5 cups ; powdered sugar, plus more as needed ; (550 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">nonstick cooking spray, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">red gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">blue gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">green gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">yellow gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">orange gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">2 ; large chocolate bars, cut into four 3 in (7 cm) squared </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">food safe plastic gloves </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="2">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/133409/hls24_1558388472.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/133409/landscape_720/1558388472</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">With a sharp knife, divide the cake crosswise into thirds, about 3 inches (7 cm) each. Slice the domed tops off of each piece. Very carefully slice each piece of cake into 4 even layers. Stack the layers in sets of 2 (there should be 6 stacks) with the bottom facing up on the prepared baking sheet. Each set of stacks will be a different color cube (white, yellow, green, orange, red, and blue)--write in marker on the parchment paper to label each stack. </step>
    <step num="2">Open each set of layers like a book. Spread a layer of vanilla frosting on each slice. </step>
    <step num="3">For the white cubes, stack the slices, frosted sides touching. For the yellow cubes, sprinkle with the lemon zest, then stack the slices, frosted sides touching. For the green cubes, sprinkle with the lime zest, then stack the slices, frosted sides touching. For the orange cubes, spread the orange marmalade on one piece and stack the slices. For the red cubes, spread the strawberry jam on one piece and stack the slices. For the blue cubes, spread the blueberry jam on one piece and stack the slices. Freeze for at least 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Make the marshmallow fondant: In a large microwave-safe bowl, combine the marshmallows and water. Microwave on medium power for 2-3 minutes, stirring every 30 seconds, until the marshmallows are completely melted. Add the softened butter and use a silicone spatula to stir until combined. </step>
    <step num="5">Add 5 cups (550 G) of powdered sugar to a separate large bowl and make a well in the center. Pour in the marshmallow mixture. Stir to combine. When it is mostly combined, grease your hands with nonstick spray and knead to bring the fondant together into a ball in the bowl. Add more powdered sugar as needed if the fondant is sticking to your hands. </step>
    <step num="6">Grease a clean work surface and your hands with more nonstick spray. Turn the fondant out onto the greased surface. If it gets too dry, add a bit more water. Use more nonstick spray if the fondant is sticking to the surface. Continue kneading for 8-10 minutes, until the fondant is smooth and holds its shape. </step>
    <step num="7">Divide the fondant into 6 even pieces, spray with nonstick spray, and cover with plastic wrap so they don’t dry out. Using the gel food coloring, dye 5 of the pieces green, blue, orange, red, and yellow by kneading each gel color into 1 section of fondant. Leave the remaining piece white. Spray again with nonstick spray and cover with plastic wrap. </step>
    <step num="8">Remove the cake stacks from the freezer. Using a sharp knife and a ruler to measure, slice each stack into 9 ¾-inch (22 cm) cubes. Return to the marked baking sheet and separate into individual pieces, then freeze again for at least 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Roll the green fondant into a log, then cut into 9 equal pieces. Grease the pieces you aren’t using yet with nonstick spray and cover with plastic wrap. Sprinkle a piece of fondant with powdered sugar and roll out to a ¼-inch-thick (6 mm) square. Remove the green cake cubes from the freezer. Cover a cube with the rolled out fondant on 5 sides, removing the excess fondant with a knife. Repeat with the remaining fondant and cake cubes. </step>
    <step num="10">To assemble the cake, stack 9 cubes of varying color on a plate, spaced about ¼ inch (6 mm) apart. Place a piece of chocolate squarely on top of the cubes. Carefully stack another 9 cubes on top of the chocolate. Place another chocolate square on top of the cubes, slightly askew. Stack 9 more cubes on top of the chocolate. Repeat to make another cake. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">With a sharp knife, divide the cake crosswise into thirds, about 3 inches (7 cm) each. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Slice the domed tops off of each piece. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Very carefully slice each piece of cake into 4 even layers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Stack the layers in sets of 2 (there should be 6 stacks) with the bottom facing up on the prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Each set of stacks will be a different color cube (white, yellow, green, orange, red, and blue)--write in marker on the parchment paper to label each stack. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Open each set of layers like a book. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Spread a layer of vanilla frosting on each slice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">For the white cubes, stack the slices, frosted sides touching. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">For the yellow cubes, sprinkle with the lemon zest, then stack the slices, frosted sides touching. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">For the green cubes, sprinkle with the lime zest, then stack the slices, frosted sides touching. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">For the orange cubes, spread the orange marmalade on one piece and stack the slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">For the red cubes, spread the strawberry jam on one piece and stack the slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">For the blue cubes, spread the blueberry jam on one piece and stack the slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Freeze for at least 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Make the marshmallow fondant: In a large microwave-safe bowl, combine the marshmallows and water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Microwave on medium power for 2-3 minutes, stirring every 30 seconds, until the marshmallows are completely melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Add the softened butter and use a silicone spatula to stir until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add 5 cups (550 G) of powdered sugar to a separate large bowl and make a well in the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Pour in the marshmallow mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">When it is mostly combined, grease your hands with nonstick spray and knead to bring the fondant together into a ball in the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add more powdered sugar as needed if the fondant is sticking to your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Grease a clean work surface and your hands with more nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Turn the fondant out onto the greased surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">If it gets too dry, add a bit more water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Use more nonstick spray if the fondant is sticking to the surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Continue kneading for 8-10 minutes, until the fondant is smooth and holds its shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Divide the fondant into 6 even pieces, spray with nonstick spray, and cover with plastic wrap so they don’t dry out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Using the gel food coloring, dye 5 of the pieces green, blue, orange, red, and yellow by kneading each gel color into 1 section of fondant. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Leave the remaining piece white. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Spray again with nonstick spray and cover with plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Remove the cake stacks from the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Using a sharp knife and a ruler to measure, slice each stack into 9 ¾-inch (22 cm) cubes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Return to the marked baking sheet and separate into individual pieces, then freeze again for at least 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Roll the green fondant into a log, then cut into 9 equal pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Grease the pieces you aren’t using yet with nonstick spray and cover with plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="37">Sprinkle a piece of fondant with powdered sugar and roll out to a ¼-inch-thick (6 mm) square. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="38">Remove the green cake cubes from the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="39">Cover a cube with the rolled out fondant on 5 sides, removing the excess fondant with a knife. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="40">Repeat with the remaining fondant and cake cubes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="41">To assemble the cake, stack 9 cubes of varying color on a plate, spaced about ¼ inch (6 mm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="42">Place a piece of chocolate squarely on top of the cubes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="43">Carefully stack another 9 cubes on top of the chocolate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="44">Place another chocolate square on top of the cubes, slightly askew. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="45">Stack 9 more cubes on top of the chocolate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="46">Repeat to make another cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="47">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>