<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Banana Bread Chocolate Cheesecake Swiss Roll Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/banana-bread-chocolate-cheesecake-swiss-roll</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ; ripe bananas </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; vanilla </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; granulated sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ½ cups ; flour ; (185 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">nonstick cooking spray, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">powdered sugar, for dusting </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">8 oz ; packages of cream cheese, softened ; (2 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ cup ; granulated sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 teaspoon ; vanilla </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 tablespoons ; milk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 cup ; semi-sweet chocolate chips, melted ; (175 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">whipped cream, for decorating </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">chocolate bar, for decorating </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105163/hls24_1534180472.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105163/landscape_720/1534180472</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Make the cake: Place the peeled bananas in a medium bowl and use a fork to mash them. Add the eggs, vanilla, and sugar and whisk until the mixture turns pale yellow. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the flour, baking powder, baking soda, and salt and whisk to combine. </step>
    <step num="3">Grease a baking sheet well and line with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="4">Pour the batter onto the baking sheet and use a spatula to spread evenly. </step>
    <step num="5">Bake for 12 minutes, or until the bread is golden brown and springs back when gently pressed. </step>
    <step num="6">Cover a large, clean dish towel with powdered sugar (this will help keep the cake from sticking to the towel). While the cake is still warm, carefully flip the baking sheet onto the towel. Lift up the sheet and remove the parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="7">Starting from a short end, gently roll up the cake with the towel. Let cool for at least 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="8">Make the filling: Add the cream cheese to a medium bowl and whip with a fork until light and fluffy. Add the sugar, vanilla, and milk. Mix until the filling is silky and smooth. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the melted chocolate and fold with a spatula to combine. </step>
    <step num="10">Unroll the banana bread and spread the filling evenly over it. Roll the banana bread back up without the towel, wrap the outside with the towel or plastic wrap, and chill for 4 hours. </step>
    <step num="11">Remove the roll from the fridge and sift powdered sugar over the top. Top with whipped cream. Run a vegetable peeler across a chocolate bar to sprinkle chocolate curls over the whipped cream. </step>
    <step num="12">Slice and serve. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Make the cake: Place the peeled bananas in a medium bowl and use a fork to mash them. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the eggs, vanilla, and sugar and whisk until the mixture turns pale yellow. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the flour, baking powder, baking soda, and salt and whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Grease a baking sheet well and line with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour the batter onto the baking sheet and use a spatula to spread evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Bake for 12 minutes, or until the bread is golden brown and springs back when gently pressed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cover a large, clean dish towel with powdered sugar (this will help keep the cake from sticking to the towel). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">While the cake is still warm, carefully flip the baking sheet onto the towel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Lift up the sheet and remove the parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Starting from a short end, gently roll up the cake with the towel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Let cool for at least 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Make the filling: Add the cream cheese to a medium bowl and whip with a fork until light and fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the sugar, vanilla, and milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Mix until the filling is silky and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the melted chocolate and fold with a spatula to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Unroll the banana bread and spread the filling evenly over it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Roll the banana bread back up without the towel, wrap the outside with the towel or plastic wrap, and chill for 4 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Remove the roll from the fridge and sift powdered sugar over the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Top with whipped cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Run a vegetable peeler across a chocolate bar to sprinkle chocolate curls over the whipped cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Slice and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>