<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Black History Month Inspired Jollof Risotto With Suya Spiced Shrimp</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/jollof-risotto-with-suya-spiced-shrimp</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; roma tomato, chopped ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ ; medium red onion, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; red bell pepper, seeded and chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; habanero pepper, or Scotch Bonnet pepper, depending on desired spice level </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ; bay leaf </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; vegetable oil ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; dried thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; curry powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 ; meggi seasoning cubes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 tablespoons ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ ; medium yellow onion, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 ; garlics, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 tablespoons ; tomato paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 cup ; arborio rice ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">½ cup ; dry white wine ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">3 cups ; chicken stock, hot ; (720 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 lb ; large prawn, peeled and deveined, tails left on ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">3 teaspoons ; suya spice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">1 tablespoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">2 ; garlics, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">fresh flat-leaf parsley, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">fried sweet plantains, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dinner</category>
    <category num="1">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124970/hls24_1550172732.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124970/landscape_720/1550172732</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the stew: In a blender, combine the tomatoes, onion, bell pepper, and habanero. Blend until smooth. </step>
    <step num="1">Pour the tomato puree into a medium pot set over medium-high heat. 3. Add the bay leaf. Bring to boil and cook for 10-15 minutes, stirring occasionally, until the water has cooked off and the sauce is reduced by about half. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the vegetable oil and fry the sauce for 10-15 minutes more. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the thyme and curry powder, then crumble in the Maggi cubes. Cook for another 10 minutes. Remove from the heat and set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">Make the risotto: Heat the olive oil in a medium skillet over medium heat. Add the onion and cook for 3-5 minutes, until softened. Add the garlic and tomato paste and cook until the tomato paste is deep brick-red in color, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the rice and sauté until well-coated with the tomato oil. Deglaze the pan with the wine and reduce until the pan is almost dry. </step>
    <step num="6">Add 1 ladle of hot stock to the rice. Stir the rice until the stock is absorbed and the pan is almost dry. Continue adding stock, 1 ladle at a time, until the rice is tender, but still firm. It should be moist and creamy, but not runny. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the stew and stir to incorporate. Remove the risotto from the heat, then season with salt and stir in the butter, then stir until melted and well incorporated. Remove the risotto from the heat. </step>
    <step num="8">Make the shrimp: In a medium bowl, toss the shrimp with the suya spice until well coated. </step>
    <step num="9">Heat the olive oil in a medium skillet over medium heat. Add the garlic and prawns and cook, flipping once, until the prawns are pink and opaque, 4-5 minutes. Remove the pan from the heat and sprinkle the shrimp with the parsley. </step>
    <step num="10">Divide the risotto between 2 warm serving plates. Top with the shrimp and serve with fried plantains alongside. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the stew: In a blender, combine the tomatoes, onion, bell pepper, and habanero. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Blend until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Pour the tomato puree into a medium pot set over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the bay leaf. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Bring to boil and cook for 10-15 minutes, stirring occasionally, until the water has cooked off and the sauce is reduced by about half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the vegetable oil and fry the sauce for 10-15 minutes more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the thyme and curry powder, then crumble in the Maggi cubes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cook for another 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Remove from the heat and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Make the risotto: Heat the olive oil in a medium skillet over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the onion and cook for 3-5 minutes, until softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the garlic and tomato paste and cook until the tomato paste is deep brick-red in color, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the rice and sauté until well-coated with the tomato oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Deglaze the pan with the wine and reduce until the pan is almost dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add 1 ladle of hot stock to the rice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Stir the rice until the stock is absorbed and the pan is almost dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Continue adding stock, 1 ladle at a time, until the rice is tender, but still firm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">It should be moist and creamy, but not runny. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the stew and stir to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Remove the risotto from the heat, then season with salt and stir in the butter, then stir until melted and well incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Remove the risotto from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Make the shrimp: In a medium bowl, toss the shrimp with the suya spice until well coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Heat the olive oil in a medium skillet over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Add the garlic and prawns and cook, flipping once, until the prawns are pink and opaque, 4-5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Remove the pan from the heat and sprinkle the shrimp with the parsley. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Divide the risotto between 2 warm serving plates. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Top with the shrimp and serve with fried plantains alongside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>