<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Palmier Cookies Easy Dessert Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/palmier-cookies-easy-dessert</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/4-easy-3-ingredient-desserts</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 sheet ; frozen puff pastry, thawed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 tablespoons ; butter, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; cane sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/8418/low_1472567725.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/8418/mp4_720x1280/1472567725</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>56.0</start_time>
    <end_time>87.309</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Unwrap the puff pastry. Using your hands or a rolling pin, flatten out the seams if your puff pastry has then, making an even rectangle. Brush melted butter evenly over the puff pastry. Sprinkle half of the sugar on the pastry, then spread it around evenly. Using a rolling pin, roll the pastry into a tall rectangle, pressing the sugar into the pastry. Flip the pastry, then repeat the process, brushing with butter and rolling in the rest of the sugar. </step>
    <step num="1">Tightly roll the bottom of the pastry toward the middle, stopping at the center, then roll the top of the pastry to meet in the centre as well. The rolls should be the same size. Wrap in plastic wrap and chill for about 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Preheat the oven to 425°F (220°C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove the plastic wrap and push one of the rolls directly on top of the other. Trim off the uneven ends of the pastry, then slice into ½-inch (1 cm) rounds. They should look like smushed hearts. Place the slices on the baking sheet about 2 inches (5 cm) apart to allow for expansion. Bake for 15 minutes, flipping them halfway, until the sugar is caramelized and the cookies are golden brown. </step>
    <step num="4">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 425°F (220°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Brush the melted butter evenly over the puff pastry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Sprinkle half the sugar on the pastry, then spread it around evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Using a rolling pin, roll the pastry into a rectangle, pressing the sugar into the pastry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Flip the pastry, then repeat the process, brushing with butter and rolling in the rest of the sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Starting from the shorter edges, roll them tightly towards the middle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Wrap in cling film and chill for about 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove the cling film and push one of the rolls directly on top of the other. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Trim off the uneven ends of the pastry, then slice 1-centimeter (½ inch) cookie rounds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">They should look like smushed hearts. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place the slices on a baking tray lined with parchment paper about 2 inches (5 cm) apart to allow for expansion. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Bake for 15 minutes, flipping them halfway, until the sugar is caramelized and the cookies are golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cool and serve! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
  <duration_human>
    <start_time>01632</start_time>
    <end_time>02636</end_time>
  </duration_human>
</recipe>