<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Pull-apart Holiday Monkey Bread Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/pull-apart-holiday-monkey-bread</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">32 oz ; biscuit dough, 2 cans ; (925 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 lb ; brie cheese, cubed ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">14 oz ; cranberry sauce, 1 can ; (395 mg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; fresh thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; fresh rosemary </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Brunch</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/15775/low_1479922493.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/15775/mp4_720x1280/1479922493</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Cut brie into cubes. Open biscuit dough and separate into individual biscuit pieces. Using your hands (or a knife for extra precision), tear each piece of biscuit dough into 2-3 pieces. </step>
    <step num="2">Flatten the torn dough in the palm of your hand and place 1-2 pieces of brie in the middle. Pinch dough around the cheese, then roll together until it forms a small ball with the cheese inside. Repeat until all of the dough and cheese have been rolled together. </step>
    <step num="3">Place cheese-filled doughballs into a standard bundt pan that has been generously coated with nonstick spray, spacing them out evenly. Once a layer of dough has been placed into the pan, sprinkle generously with ⅓ of the thyme and rosemary. </step>
    <step num="4">After the sprinkling of herbs, spoon in about ⅓ of the can of cranberry sauce. Repeat this (dough, herbs, sauce) pattern until all of the ingredients have been layered evenly in the pan. </step>
    <step num="5">Bake in preheated oven for 40 minutes. Loaf should be fragrant with cheese and cranberry sauce should be bubbling on top when removed. </step>
    <step num="6">Let cool for 10 minutes before covering and inverting the bread onto a large serving dish. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cut brie into cubes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Open biscuit dough and separate into individual biscuit pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Using your hands (or a knife for extra precision), tear each piece of biscuit dough into 2-3 pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Flatten the torn dough in the palm of your hand and place 1-2 pieces of brie in the middle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pinch dough around the cheese, then roll together until it forms a small ball with the cheese inside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Repeat until all of the dough and cheese have been rolled together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Place cheese-filled doughballs into a standard bundt pan that has been generously coated with nonstick spray, spacing them out evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Once a layer of dough has been placed into the pan, sprinkle generously with ⅓ of the thyme and rosemary. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">After the sprinkling of herbs, spoon in about ⅓ of the can of cranberry sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Repeat this (dough, herbs, sauce) pattern until all of the ingredients have been layered evenly in the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Bake in preheated oven for 40 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Loaf should be fragrant with cheese and cranberry sauce should be bubbling on top when removed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Let cool for 10 minutes before covering and inverting the bread onto a large serving dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>