<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Traditional Vietnamese Beef Pho Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/traditional-vietnamese-beef-pho</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">10 lb ; mixed beef leg bones, shin, knuckle and marrow bones ; (4.5 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">12 oz ; ginger, 2 large hands, halved lengthwise ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 head ; large garlic, halved crosswise </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">4 kg ; medium yellow onion, halved lengthwise ; 4 kg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">8 sticks ; cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; whole black peppercorn </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">6 pods ; whole star anise </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 lb ; beef brisket ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ cup ; fish sauce, plus more to taste ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 lb ; boneless sirloin steak ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 lb ; flat rice noodle, cooked according to package instructions ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 cups ; fresh mung bean sprouts ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ; small red onion, very thinly sliced lengthwise </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 ; jalapeño, sliced into thin rounds </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 large bunch ; fresh thai basil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 ; lime, cut into wedges </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">hoisin sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">siracha </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vietnamese</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/91445/hls24_1524780649.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/91445/landscape_720/1524780649</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Place the beef bones in a large stock pot, then add enough cold water to cover by 2 inches (5 cm). Bring the mixture to a boil over high heat and cook for 10 minutes to blanch the bones and remove any impurities. </step>
    <step num="1">Set a rack in the upper third of the oven and preheat the broiler. </step>
    <step num="2">Drain the bones in a colander and rinse under cold running water. Return the blanched bones to the stockpot. </step>
    <step num="3">Meanwhile, arrange the ginger, garlic, and onions cut-side up on a rimmed baking sheet and broil on high until the aromatics are deeply charred in spots, 5 minutes. Remove from the oven and add to the stockpot with the bones. </step>
    <step num="4">Meanwhile, combine the cinnamon sticks, peppercorns, and star anise in a medium skillet over medium-high heat and toast, shaking the pan occasionally, until the spices are darkened in spots and extremely fragrant, about 5 minutes. Add the toasted spices to the stockpot. </step>
    <step num="5">Season the brisket liberally with salt and add it to the stockpot. </step>
    <step num="6">Fill the pot with enough cold water to cover everything by 1 inch (2 cm). Bring to a boil over high heat, then reduce the heat to medium to maintain a gentle simmer, skimming off and discarding any fat that floats to the top as needed, until the brisket is fork-tender, 2-3 hours. </step>
    <step num="7">Using tongs, transfer the brisket to a plate and let cool completely. Refrigerate the brisket until ready to serve. </step>
    <step num="8">Continue to simmer the broth to get as much flavor out of the bones as possible, 3-4 hours more. </step>
    <step num="9">Using tongs, remove and discard the bones and aromatics. Slowly strain the broth through a fine mesh strainer set over a large pot. Skim and discard the fat from the broth, then stir in the fish sauce. Taste and add more as desired. </step>
    <step num="10">Thinly slice the brisket. Very thinly slice the raw sirloin steak against the grain. </step>
    <step num="11">Divide the noodles among 6-8 large bowls, then top with the brisket and raw steak. Ladle the hot broth over the noodles and meat and serve immediately with the bean sprouts, onion, jalapeño, Thai basil, lime wedges, hoisin sauce, and Sriracha alongside. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Place the beef bones in a large stock pot, then add enough cold water to cover by 2 inches (5 cm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Bring the mixture to a boil over high heat and cook for 10 minutes to blanch the bones and remove any impurities. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Set a rack in the upper third of the oven and preheat the broiler. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Drain the bones in a colander and rinse under cold running water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Return the blanched bones to the stockpot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Meanwhile, arrange the ginger, garlic, and onions cut-side up on a rimmed baking sheet and broil on high until the aromatics are deeply charred in spots, 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove from the oven and add to the stockpot with the bones. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Meanwhile, combine the cinnamon sticks, peppercorns, and star anise in a medium skillet over medium-high heat and toast, shaking the pan occasionally, until the spices are darkened in spots and extremely fragrant, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the toasted spices to the stockpot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Season the brisket liberally with salt and add it to the stockpot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Fill the pot with enough cold water to cover everything by 1 inch (2 cm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Bring to a boil over high heat, then reduce the heat to medium to maintain a gentle simmer, skimming off and discarding any fat that floats to the top as needed, until the brisket is fork-tender, 2-3 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Using tongs, transfer the brisket to a plate and let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Refrigerate the brisket until ready to serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Continue to simmer the broth to get as much flavor out of the bones as possible, 3-4 hours more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Using tongs, remove and discard the bones and aromatics. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Slowly strain the broth through a fine mesh strainer set over a large pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Skim and discard the fat from the broth, then stir in the fish sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Taste and add more as desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Thinly slice the brisket. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Very thinly slice the raw sirloin steak against the grain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Divide the noodles among 6-8 large bowls, then top with the brisket and raw steak. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Ladle the hot broth over the noodles and meat and serve immediately with the bean sprouts, onion, jalapeño, Thai basil, lime wedges, hoisin sauce, and Sriracha alongside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>