<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>The Ultimate Funfetti Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/the-ultimate-funfetti-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">nonstick cooking spray </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ cups ; buttermilk ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 teaspoons ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; vegetable oil ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 cups ; all purpose flour, or cake flour ; (500 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 teaspoons ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ½ teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 cups ; granulated sugar ; (400 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; light brown sugar, lightly packed ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; unsalted butter, 2 sticks, room temperature ; (230 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">4 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">4 ; large egg yolks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ cup ; rainbow sprinkles ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 cups ; unsalted butter, 4 sticks, room temperature ; (460 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 lb ; cream cheese ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">kosher salt, a pinch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">3 cups ; powdered sugar ; (360 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">½ cup ; rainbow sprinkles, for decoration ; (80 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/100758/hls24_1530563183.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/100758/landscape_720/1530563183</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium bowl or liquid measuring cup, combine the buttermilk, vanilla extract, and vegetable oil. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, whisk together the flour, baking powder, salt, and baking soda. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">In a separate large bowl, combine the granulated sugar, light brown sugar, and butter. Beat with an electric hand mixer on high speed until super light and fluffy, about 4 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the eggs and egg yolks one at a time, beating in between additions. Beat the batter until almost doubled in volume and very light and fluffy, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">With the mixer on low, gently beat in a third of the flour mixture. Before it's fully combined, add half of the buttermilk mixture. Repeat with remaining flour and buttermilk until everything is well-blended and no lumps remain. </step>
    <step num="5">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). Spray 3 9-inch (23 cm) round cake pans with nonstick spray. </step>
    <step num="6">Add ½ cup (80 g) of sprinkles and gently fold into the batter with a spatula until well-incorporated. </step>
    <step num="7">Divide the cake batter among the prepared pans and place 2 pans on the top oven rack and 1 pan on the middle rack. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake for 30 minutes, rotating the pan on the middle rack to the top rack, and vice versa, halfway through baking, so the cakes bake evenly. The cakes are done when they are golden brown, pull away from the sides of the pans, and the tops spring back slightly when pressed. </step>
    <step num="9">Remove the cakes from the oven and invert them onto a wire rack to cool completely. (If you don't have a wire rack, let them cool in the cake pans on the counter.) </step>
    <step num="10">Make the frosting: In a large bowl, use an electric hand mixer on high speed to beat the butter, cream cheese, and salt. Mix until light and creamy, about 4 minutes. </step>
    <step num="11">Add the powdered sugar and beat on low speed to combine. Once the sugar is incorporated, beat on high speed until there are no lumps and the frosting is super white and fluffy, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="12">Place a dab of frosting on a cake stand or an inverted plate. Place a layer of cake on the cake wheel, then evenly spread frosting on top with an offset spatula. Place the next layer of cake on top of the frosted layer, and spread frosting on top. Add the last cake layer and lightly frost the entire outside of the cake to create a thin crumb coat. </step>
    <step num="13">Chill the cake in the refrigerator for 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="14">Remove the cake from the refrigerator and use the remaining icing to frost the cake in an even layer. Take the end of an offset spatula or knife and gently press it against the against the frosting at the bottom of the cake. Then, spin the cake and slowly raise the spatula after each rotation to create a ribbed effect. Smooth the top of the cake with the spatula. </step>
    <step num="15">Place sprinkles around the edge of the cake. Set a small cookie cutter, any shape you like, in the center of the cake and fill in with sprinkles. Gently remove the cookie cutter. </step>
    <step num="16">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium bowl or liquid measuring cup, combine the buttermilk, vanilla extract, and vegetable oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a large bowl, whisk together the flour, baking powder, salt, and baking soda. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a separate large bowl, combine the granulated sugar, light brown sugar, and butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Beat with an electric hand mixer on high speed until super light and fluffy, about 4 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the eggs and egg yolks one at a time, beating in between additions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Beat the batter until almost doubled in volume and very light and fluffy, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">With the mixer on low, gently beat in a third of the flour mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Before it's fully combined, add half of the buttermilk mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Repeat with remaining flour and buttermilk until everything is well-blended and no lumps remain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Spray 3 9-inch (23 cm) round cake pans with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add ½ cup (80 g) of sprinkles and gently fold into the batter with a spatula until well-incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Divide the cake batter among the prepared pans and place 2 pans on the top oven rack and 1 pan on the middle rack. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Bake for 30 minutes, rotating the pan on the middle rack to the top rack, and vice versa, halfway through baking, so the cakes bake evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">The cakes are done when they are golden brown, pull away from the sides of the pans, and the tops spring back slightly when pressed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Remove the cakes from the oven and invert them onto a wire rack to cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">(If you don't have a wire rack, let them cool in the cake pans on the counter.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Make the frosting: In a large bowl, use an electric hand mixer on high speed to beat the butter, cream cheese, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Mix until light and creamy, about 4 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Add the powdered sugar and beat on low speed to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Once the sugar is incorporated, beat on high speed until there are no lumps and the frosting is super white and fluffy, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Place a dab of frosting on a cake stand or an inverted plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Place a layer of cake on the cake wheel, then evenly spread frosting on top with an offset spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Place the next layer of cake on top of the frosted layer, and spread frosting on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Add the last cake layer and lightly frost the entire outside of the cake to create a thin crumb coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Chill the cake in the refrigerator for 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Remove the cake from the refrigerator and use the remaining icing to frost the cake in an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Take the end of an offset spatula or knife and gently press it against the against the frosting at the bottom of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Then, spin the cake and slowly raise the spatula after each rotation to create a ribbed effect. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Smooth the top of the cake with the spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Place sprinkles around the edge of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Set a small cookie cutter, any shape you like, in the center of the cake and fill in with sprinkles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Gently remove the cookie cutter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>