<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Potato Bake Side Meal Prep Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/potato-bake-meal-prep</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; medium red potato, sliced into 1/2 in (1 1/4 cm) thick rounds ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; bacon, crumbled cooked bacon ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 oz ; small broccoli floret, divided ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; cheese sauce ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; shredded cheddar cheese ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; cream cheese ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ cup ; heavy cream ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; shredded mozzarella cheese, divided ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">9 oz ; frozen spinach, 1 package, thawed and drained well ; (255 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 lb ; medium red potato, sliced into 1/2 in (1 1/4 cm) thick rounds ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 lb ; medium red potato, sliced into 1/2 in (1 1/4 cm) thick rounds ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 teaspoon ; chili powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">½ teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">2 cups ; chili, prepared ; (485 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">½ cup ; shredded cheddar cheese ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">1 lb ; medium red potato, sliced into 1/2 in (1 1/4 cm) thick rounds ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">½ teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">1 teaspoon ; dried oregano </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">1 cup ; marinara sauce ; (260 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="25">1 cup ; shredded mozzarella cheese ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="26">8 slices ; pepperoni </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Lunch</category>
    <category num="1">BBQ</category>
    <category num="2">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/128048/hls24_1553301634.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/128048/landscape_720/1553301634</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). Tear off 8 12-inch (30 cm) square sheets of foil. Stack 2 sheets of foil and fold in the long sides, then the short sides, to make a tray. Repeat with the remaining foil and set the trays in an 18 x 13-inch (45 x 33 cm) baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="1">Make the cheddar broccoli potatoes: In a large bowl, season the potatoes with the salt and pepper and toss to coat. Add the bacon, 1 cup of broccoli (150 G), and the nacho cheese sauce. Mix until the potatoes are fully coated. </step>
    <step num="2">Pour the mixture into 1 section of the prepared pan. Sprinkle the cheddar cheese and remaining cup of broccoli on top. </step>
    <step num="3">Make the creamy spinach potatoes: In a medium microwave-safe bowl, mix together the cream cheese, heavy cream, ½ cup (150 G) mozzarella cheese, and the spinach. Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring between, until the cheese is completely melted, about 1 minute total. </step>
    <step num="4">In a large bowl, season the potatoes with the salt and pepper and toss to coat. Add the spinach mixture and mix until the potatoes are fully coated. </step>
    <step num="5">Pour the mixture into another section of the prepared pan. Sprinkle the remaining ½ cup (50 G) mozzarella on top. </step>
    <step num="6">Make the chili potatoes: In a large bowl, season the potatoes with the chili powder, pepper, and salt and toss to coat. Add the chili and mix until the potatoes are fully coated. </step>
    <step num="7">Pour the mixture into another section of the prepared pan and sprinkle the cheddar cheese on top. </step>
    <step num="8">Make the pizza potatoes: In a large bowl, season the potatoes with the salt, pepper, and oregano. Add the marinara sauce and mix until the potatoes are fully coated. </step>
    <step num="9">Pour the mixture into the last section of the prepared pan and sprinkle the mozzarella cheese on top. Arrange pepperoni on top. </step>
    <step num="10">Bake for 45 minutes, until the potatoes are tender. </step>
    <step num="11">Serve immediately, or portion into reusable containers and store in the fridge for up to 4 days. To reheat, place portion in a microwave-safe container. Place in microwave and cook for 2-3 minutes. If contents are not heated through, continue cooking in 30-second intervals. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Tear off 8 12-inch (30 cm) square sheets of foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Stack 2 sheets of foil and fold in the long sides, then the short sides, to make a tray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Repeat with the remaining foil and set the trays in an 18 x 13-inch (45 x 33 cm) baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Make the cheddar broccoli potatoes: In a large bowl, season the potatoes with the salt and pepper and toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the bacon, 1 cup of broccoli (150 G), and the nacho cheese sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Mix until the potatoes are fully coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Pour the mixture into 1 section of the prepared pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Sprinkle the cheddar cheese and remaining cup of broccoli on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Make the creamy spinach potatoes: In a medium microwave-safe bowl, mix together the cream cheese, heavy cream, ½ cup (150 G) mozzarella cheese, and the spinach. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring between, until the cheese is completely melted, about 1 minute total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">In a large bowl, season the potatoes with the salt and pepper and toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the spinach mixture and mix until the potatoes are fully coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Pour the mixture into another section of the prepared pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Sprinkle the remaining ½ cup (50 G) mozzarella on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Make the chili potatoes: In a large bowl, season the potatoes with the chili powder, pepper, and salt and toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add the chili and mix until the potatoes are fully coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Pour the mixture into another section of the prepared pan and sprinkle the cheddar cheese on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Make the pizza potatoes: In a large bowl, season the potatoes with the salt, pepper, and oregano. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add the marinara sauce and mix until the potatoes are fully coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Pour the mixture into the last section of the prepared pan and sprinkle the mozzarella cheese on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Arrange pepperoni on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Bake for 45 minutes, until the potatoes are tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Serve immediately, or portion into reusable containers and store in the fridge for up to 4 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">To reheat, place portion in a microwave-safe container. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Place in microwave and cook for 2-3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">If contents are not heated through, continue cooking in 30-second intervals. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>