<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Bacon Cheddar Loaded Cheeseburger Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/bacon-cheddar-loaded-cheeseburger</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">5 strips ; bacon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 oz ; cream cheese, at room temperature ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; green onion, thinly sliced ; (35 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; shredded sharp cheddar cheese ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 lb ; ground beef ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">4 slices ; cheddar cheese </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">4 ; hamburger buns, toasted </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Lunch</category>
    <category num="5">Game Day</category>
    <category num="6">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/62532/low_1510857328.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/62532/mp4_720x1280/1510857328</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a pan over medium-high heat, add the bacon, and cook until crispy. Transfer to a cutting board and roughly chop. </step>
    <step num="1">In a bowl, add the bacon, cream cheese, green onions, and shredded cheddar. Mix well. </step>
    <step num="2">Divide the ground beef into four even portions and shape into balls. Form a well into the center of each, large enough for the cheese mixture. </step>
    <step num="3">Place a quarter of the cheese mixture into the center of each ball, and enclose inside the ground beef. Gently press each ball into a patty shape, and season both sides generously with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="4">Heat a cast-iron pan over medium-high heat. Once hot, add the burgers and cook for 4-5 minutes on one side. </step>
    <step num="5">Flip the burgers, and cook for 2 minutes. Add a slice of cheese on each burger and cook for an additional 2 minutes, until the burger is cooked through and the cheese is melted. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove burgers from pan, and place on top a toasted burger bun. Top with condiments of your choice. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a pan over medium-high heat, add the bacon, and cook until crispy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Transfer to a cutting board and roughly chop. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a bowl, add the bacon, cream cheese, green onions, and shredded cheddar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Mix well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Divide the ground beef into four even portions and shape into balls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Form a well into the center of each, large enough for the cheese mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Place a quarter of the cheese mixture into the center of each ball, and enclose inside the ground beef. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Gently press each ball into a patty shape, and season both sides generously with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Heat a cast-iron pan over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Once hot, add the burgers and cook for 4-5 minutes on one side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Flip the burgers, and cook for 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add a slice of cheese on each burger and cook for an additional 2 minutes, until the burger is cooked through and the cheese is melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove burgers from pan, and place on top a toasted burger bun. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Top with condiments of your choice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>