<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Rainbow Swirl Meringues Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/rainbow-swirl-meringues</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¾ cup ; granulated sugar ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">⅓ cup ; fresh egg white, room temperature ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">gel food coloring, of your choosing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; buttercream icing ; (255 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¼ cup ; raspberry jam ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">wooden skewer </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">French</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98672/hls24_1529017819.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98672/landscape_720/1529017819</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 200°F (95°C). Line 2 baking sheets with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the sugar to a baking sheet and bake for 7 minutes. The edges may begin to caramelize – this is good! Remove the sugar from the oven and leave the oven on. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large clean, dry bowl, whip the egg whites with an electric hand mixer on low speed until foamy, then add the salt. Continue whipping on high speed until medium peaks form. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the toasted sugar to the egg whites 1 tablespoon at a time, increasing the mixer speed gradually as you add more sugar. Once all of the sugar is incorporated, continue whipping for 5-7 minutes, until the meringue is very thick and shiny. </step>
    <step num="4">Add in vanilla, just whipping until incorporated. </step>
    <step num="5">Prop open a piping bag or zip-top bag in a tall drinking glass. Using wooden skewers, lightly paint 2 thin stripes of different-colored gel food coloring on opposite sides of the bag. Paint additional bags with more colors, if desired. </step>
    <step num="6">Fill each bag with the meringue batter, dividing evenly amongst different colors, if using. </step>
    <step num="7">Pipe 1-inch (2-cm) wide “kisses” of meringue onto a baking sheet about ½ inch (1 cm) apart. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake for about 1 hour, or until you can easily lift a kiss off of the paper. </step>
    <step num="9">Cool the meringues on the baking sheet at room temperature until no longer warm. </step>
    <step num="10">To fill, pipe buttercream icing around the edge of a cookie and place a small dollop of jam in the center. Sandwich with another cookie. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 200°F (95°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line 2 baking sheets with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the sugar to a baking sheet and bake for 7 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">The edges may begin to caramelize – this is good! Remove the sugar from the oven and leave the oven on. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a large clean, dry bowl, whip the egg whites with an electric hand mixer on low speed until foamy, then add the salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Continue whipping on high speed until medium peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the toasted sugar to the egg whites 1 tablespoon at a time, increasing the mixer speed gradually as you add more sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Once all of the sugar is incorporated, continue whipping for 5-7 minutes, until the meringue is very thick and shiny. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add in vanilla, just whipping until incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Prop open a piping bag or zip-top bag in a tall drinking glass. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Using wooden skewers, lightly paint 2 thin stripes of different-colored gel food coloring on opposite sides of the bag. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Paint additional bags with more colors, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Fill each bag with the meringue batter, dividing evenly amongst different colors, if using. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Pipe 1-inch (2-cm) wide “kisses” of meringue onto a baking sheet about ½ inch (1 cm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Bake for about 1 hour, or until you can easily lift a kiss off of the paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cool the meringues on the baking sheet at room temperature until no longer warm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">To fill, pipe buttercream icing around the edge of a cookie and place a small dollop of jam in the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Sandwich with another cookie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>