<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Mint Chocolate Cookie Dome Made With Brownies And Mousse</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/mint-chocolate-cookie-dome-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">10 oz ; brownie mix, 1 box, batter prepared according to package instructions ; (285 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 ¼ cups ; heavy cream, plus 1/2 (120 ml) cup, hot, divided ; (780 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ teaspoon ; peppermint extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; granulated sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 drops ; green gel food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; white chocolate chip ; (175 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 cup ; mini chocolate chips ; (175 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">30 ; mint chocolate cookies, crushed plus 45 whole, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">fresh mint leaf, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/125541/hls24_1551119544.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/125541/landscape_720/1551119544</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Prepare the brownie batter according to the package instructions. Pour the batter into a greased 9-inch (22 cm) round cake pan. Bake according to the package instructions, about 30 minutes, until a knife inserted in the center comes out clean. Let cool completely. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large bowl, beat the cold heavy cream with an electric hand mixer until soft peaks form. Fold in the peppermint extract, sugar, and green food coloring with a rubber spatula until incorporated. </step>
    <step num="3">In a medium bowl, pour the hot heavy cream over the white chocolate chips. Let sit for 1 minute, then stir with a rubber spatula until smooth. Fold the white chocolate mixture into the whipped cream until no streaks remain. Fold in the mini chocolate chips and crushed mint chocolate cookies. </step>
    <step num="4">Line a 10-inch (25 cm) diameter bowl with the whole mint chocolate cookies. Carefully pour the whipped cream mixture over the cookies and spread evenly. Place the brownie upside down on top and lightly press into the cream. </step>
    <step num="5">Cover and freeze until solid, at least 5 hours or overnight. </step>
    <step num="6">Invert the bowl onto a serving plate and let the the ice cream dome to release from the bowl. Slice and serve, garnished with fresh mint. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Prepare the brownie batter according to the package instructions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Pour the batter into a greased 9-inch (22 cm) round cake pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Bake according to the package instructions, about 30 minutes, until a knife inserted in the center comes out clean. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In a large bowl, beat the cold heavy cream with an electric hand mixer until soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Fold in the peppermint extract, sugar, and green food coloring with a rubber spatula until incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a medium bowl, pour the hot heavy cream over the white chocolate chips. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Let sit for 1 minute, then stir with a rubber spatula until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Fold the white chocolate mixture into the whipped cream until no streaks remain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Fold in the mini chocolate chips and crushed mint chocolate cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Line a 10-inch (25 cm) diameter bowl with the whole mint chocolate cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Carefully pour the whipped cream mixture over the cookies and spread evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Place the brownie upside down on top and lightly press into the cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Cover and freeze until solid, at least 5 hours or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Invert the bowl onto a serving plate and let the the ice cream dome to release from the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Slice and serve, garnished with fresh mint. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>