<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Garlic And Herb Leg Of Lamb With Potatoes Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/garlic-and-herb-leg-of-lamb-with-potatoes</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">8 lb ; bone-in lamb roast with fat cap ; (3.8 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">12 cloves ; garlic, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; olive oil ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">⅓ cup ; whole grain mustard, plus more for serving ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ; lemon, juiced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">10 sprigs ; fresh rosemary, stemmed and leaves finely chopped, plus whole sprigs for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">10 sprigs ; fresh thyme, stemmed and leaves finely chopped, plus whole sprigs for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ½ tablespoons ; sea salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; freshly ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¾ cup ; dry white wine ; (180 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 ½ lb ; yukon gold potato, halved ; (1.2 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">flaky sea salt, for sprinkling </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/87025/hls24_1522272668.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/87025/landscape_720/1522272668</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">2-3 hours before roasting, prepare the lamb. Use a small, sharp knife to make 15 to 20 incisions, each about 2 inches (5 cm) deep, through the fat cap on top of the meat. Thinly slice 3 cloves of garlic and use your fingers to press the slices into the incisions. </step>
    <step num="1">In a blender, combine the remaining 9 garlic cloves, the olive oil, mustard, lemon juice, rosemary leaves, thyme leaves, salt, and pepper. Blend until a paste forms. </step>
    <step num="2">Spread the paste evenly all over the lamb. Let marinate at room temperature for 2 to 3 hours. </step>
    <step num="3">Preheat the oven to 425°F (220°C). </step>
    <step num="4">Place the lamb on a roasting rack in a roasting pan and pour the wine into the bottom of the pan. Roast for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Remove the pan from the oven and reduce the heat to 325°F (160°C). </step>
    <step num="6">Arrange the potatoes, cut side down, in the roasting pan and place the lamb on the rack on top. Roast for 2 hours, tossing the potatoes and basting the lamb with the roasting liquid halfway through. </step>
    <step num="7">Transfer the potatoes to a platter, baste the lamb again with the remaining pan juices, and return the lamb to the oven. Continue to roast, basting often, until an instant-read thermometer inserted into thickest part of the leg reaches 130°F (for medium-rare), 45 minutes to 2 hours more, depending on thickness. (As a general rule, the lamb should roast 20 minutes per pound for medium-rare). </step>
    <step num="8">Transfer the lamb to a platter and set aside to rest for 20 minutes. While the lamb rests, return the potatoes to the roasting pan, season with flaky salt, and warm in the oven until just heated through, about 20 minutes. Return the potatoes to the serving platter. </step>
    <step num="9">Carve the lamb into ½-inch (1 cm) thick slices and arrange on the platter with the potatoes, garnished with rosemary and thyme sprigs. Serve with whole grain mustard alongside. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">2-3 hours before roasting, prepare the lamb. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Use a small, sharp knife to make 15 to 20 incisions, each about 2 inches (5 cm) deep, through the fat cap on top of the meat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Thinly slice 3 cloves of garlic and use your fingers to press the slices into the incisions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a blender, combine the remaining 9 garlic cloves, the olive oil, mustard, lemon juice, rosemary leaves, thyme leaves, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Blend until a paste forms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Spread the paste evenly all over the lamb. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Let marinate at room temperature for 2 to 3 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Preheat the oven to 425°F (220°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Place the lamb on a roasting rack in a roasting pan and pour the wine into the bottom of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Roast for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Remove the pan from the oven and reduce the heat to 325°F (160°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Arrange the potatoes, cut side down, in the roasting pan and place the lamb on the rack on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Roast for 2 hours, tossing the potatoes and basting the lamb with the roasting liquid halfway through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Transfer the potatoes to a platter, baste the lamb again with the remaining pan juices, and return the lamb to the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Continue to roast, basting often, until an instant-read thermometer inserted into thickest part of the leg reaches 130°F (for medium-rare), 45 minutes to 2 hours more, depending on thickness. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">(As a general rule, the lamb should roast 20 minutes per pound for medium-rare). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Transfer the lamb to a platter and set aside to rest for 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">While the lamb rests, return the potatoes to the roasting pan, season with flaky salt, and warm in the oven until just heated through, about 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Return the potatoes to the serving platter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Carve the lamb into ½-inch (1 cm) thick slices and arrange on the platter with the potatoes, garnished with rosemary and thyme sprigs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Serve with whole grain mustard alongside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>