<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Fluffy Jiggly Japanese Cheesecake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/fluffy-jiggly-japanese-cheesecake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">7 tablespoons ; butter ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 oz ; cream cheese ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; milk ; (130 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">8 ; eggs, yolk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; flour ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; cornstarch ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">13 ; large egg whites </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">⅔ cup ; granulated sugar ; (130 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">hot water, for baking </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">powdered sugar, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">Strawberries, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Japanese</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Date Night</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/19921/low_1483635924.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/19921/mp4_720x1280/1483635924</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 320°F (160°C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a small pot over medium heat, whisk the milk, cream cheese, and butter until smooth. Remove from heat and cool. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large bowl, whisk the egg yolks until smooth, then slowly drizzle in the cream mixture, stirring until evenly combined. </step>
    <step num="3">Sift in the flour and the cornstarch, whisking to make sure there are no lumps. </step>
    <step num="4">In another large bowl, beat the egg whites with a hand mixer until you see soft peaks when lifting the mixer up from the egg whites. Gradually add the sugar while continuing to beat until you see hard peaks when lifting the mixer up. </step>
    <step num="5">Take about ¼ of the egg whites and fold them into the egg yolk mixture, then repeat with the remaining egg whites until the batter is evenly combined. </step>
    <step num="6">Place a 4-inch (10-cm) parchment paper strip around the edge of a 9x3-inch (23 cm) cake pan that is already lined with parchment at the bottom. If you are using a springform pan, make sure to wrap the bottom and sides completely in foil, twice, to prevent any leakage. </step>
    <step num="7">Pour the batter into the parchment-lined pan and shake to release any large air bubbles. </step>
    <step num="8">Place the filled pan into a larger baking pan or dish lined with 2 paper towels at the bottom. The paper towels ensure that the heat is distributed evenly along the bottom of the pan. Fill the larger pan about 1-inch (2-cm) with hot water. </step>
    <step num="9">Bake for 25 minutes, then reduce the heat to 280°F (135°C), and bake for another 55 minutes, until the cake has risen to almost double its height. </step>
    <step num="10">Remove from oven, and carefully, invert the cake onto your dominant hand and peel off the paper. Be extremely careful, the cake will be hot. You can also invert the cake onto a plate, but this will cause the cake to deflate more. </step>
    <step num="11">Sprinkle the top of the cake with powdered sugar, slice, and serve with strawberries while still warm! </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 320°F (160°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a small pot over medium heat, whisk the milk, cream cheese, and butter until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Remove from heat and cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a large bowl, whisk the egg yolks until smooth, then slowly drizzle in the cream mixture, stirring until evenly combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Sift in the flour and the cornstarch, whisking to make sure there are no lumps. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In another large bowl, beat the egg whites with a hand mixer until you see soft peaks when lifting the mixer up from the egg whites. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Gradually add the sugar while continuing to beat until you see hard peaks when lifting the mixer up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Take about ¼ of the egg whites and fold them into the egg yolk mixture, then repeat with the remaining egg whites until the batter is evenly combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Place a 4-inch (10-cm) parchment paper strip around the edge of a 9x3-inch (23 cm) cake pan that is already lined with parchment at the bottom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">If you are using a springform pan, make sure to wrap the bottom and sides completely in foil, twice, to prevent any leakage. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Pour the batter into the parchment-lined pan and shake to release any large air bubbles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place the filled pan into a larger baking pan or dish lined with 2 paper towels at the bottom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">The paper towels ensure that the heat is distributed evenly along the bottom of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Fill the larger pan about 1-inch (2-cm) with hot water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Bake for 25 minutes, then reduce the heat to 280°F (135°C), and bake for another 55 minutes, until the cake has risen to almost double its height. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove from oven, and carefully, invert the cake onto your dominant hand and peel off the paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Be extremely careful, the cake will be hot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">You can also invert the cake onto a plate, but this will cause the cake to deflate more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Sprinkle the top of the cake with powdered sugar, slice, and serve with strawberries while still warm! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>