<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Strawberry Macaron Ice Cream Sandwich Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/strawberry-macaron-ice-cream-sandwich</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; superfine almond flour, if unable to find superfine, pulse almond flour in a food processor first ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ¾ cups ; powdered sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 ; large egg whites, room temperature </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; granulated sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 drops ; red food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 pt ; strawberry ice cream ; (345 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">12 ; raspberries </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">French</category>
    <category num="1">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/39544/low_1498753162.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/39544/mp4_720x1280/1498753162</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Line a baking tray with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">Using a fine mesh sieve, sift together the almond flour and powdered sugar in a medium bowl. Discard any large pieces that remain in the sieve. </step>
    <step num="2">In a medium mixing bowl, beat the egg whites with an electric hand mixer on medium speed until soft peaks form. </step>
    <step num="3">Add a third of the granulated sugar and with mixer on high, continue to beat until egg whites are stiff peaks. </step>
    <step num="4">Add another third of the sugar and beat again until egg whites are back to stiff peaks. Repeat with the remaning sugar, beating until whites are shiny and fluffy. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the sifted flour and sugar to the bowl with the egg whites. Add 2 drops of food coloring. With a rubber scraper, fold the mixture into the egg whites, about 35-45 strokes, or until the batter falls on itself but a slight peak remains. </step>
    <step num="6">NOTE: Do not over-mix or batter will be too thin and runny. </step>
    <step num="7">Fill a piping bag fitted with a round tip. </step>
    <step num="8">Pipe batter onto prepared baking tray into 3-inch (8 cm) disks. </step>
    <step num="9">Lift and drop the baking tray onto a hard surface 2-3 times to smooth out the batter and knock out any air bubbles. Allow macarons to rest at room temperature for one hour, until a skin forms on the surface. </step>
    <step num="10">Preheat oven to 275˚F (140˚C). </step>
    <step num="11">After about one hour, gently brush the top a macaron with your finger to check that a skin has formed. The batter should not stick to your finger, if it does, allow to set for an additional 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="12">Bake cookies in preheated oven for 15 minutes, or until the macarons peel away from the parchment when lifted. </step>
    <step num="13">Allow the macaron shells to cool completely. </step>
    <step num="14">Using a small ice cream scoop, scoop ice cream and put onto the bottom side of the macaron shell. Place raspberries in between ice cream scoops, and sandwich together with a similarly sized macaron. </step>
    <step num="15">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Line a baking tray with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Using a fine mesh sieve, sift together the almond flour and powdered sugar in a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Discard any large pieces that remain in the sieve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a medium mixing bowl, beat the egg whites with an electric hand mixer on medium speed until soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add a third of the granulated sugar and with mixer on high, continue to beat until egg whites are stiff peaks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add another third of the sugar and beat again until egg whites are back to stiff peaks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Repeat with the remaning sugar, beating until whites are shiny and fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the sifted flour and sugar to the bowl with the egg whites. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add 2 drops of food coloring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">With a rubber scraper, fold the mixture into the egg whites, about 35-45 strokes, or until the batter falls on itself but a slight peak remains. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">NOTE: Do not over-mix or batter will be too thin and runny. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Fill a piping bag fitted with a round tip. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Pipe batter onto prepared baking tray into 3-inch (8 cm) disks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Lift and drop the baking tray onto a hard surface 2-3 times to smooth out the batter and knock out any air bubbles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Allow macarons to rest at room temperature for one hour, until a skin forms on the surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Preheat oven to 275˚F (140˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">After about one hour, gently brush the top a macaron with your finger to check that a skin has formed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">The batter should not stick to your finger, if it does, allow to set for an additional 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Bake cookies in preheated oven for 15 minutes, or until the macarons peel away from the parchment when lifted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Allow the macaron shells to cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Using a small ice cream scoop, scoop ice cream and put onto the bottom side of the macaron shell. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Place raspberries in between ice cream scoops, and sandwich together with a similarly sized macaron. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>