<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Bacon BBQ Chicken Loaf Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/bacon-bbq-chicken-loaf</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">5 ; chicken breasts </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; smoked paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; onion powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; chili powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ teaspoon ; cayenne pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">20 slices ; bacon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; BBQ sauce, divided ; (290 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">10 slices ; cheddar cheese </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 ; green bell peppers, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ ; red onion, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 ; red bell peppers, sliced </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">BBQ</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">BBQ</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/90855/hls24_1524593555.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/90855/landscape_720/1524593555</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Cut each chicken breast in half crosswise, then cut the larger half again horizontally, creating 3 cutlets. Transfer to a large bowl. </step>
    <step num="2">In a small bowl, combine the salt, garlic powder, smoked paprika, onion powder, chili powder, black pepper, and cayenne pepper. Stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="3">Pour the spice mix over the chicken cutlets and toss to coat completely in the seasoning. Set the chicken aside. </step>
    <step num="4">Arrange the bacon slices in a 9x5-inch (23x13-cm) loaf pan, making sure the bottom and sides are fully covered, and that the strips hang over the sides. </step>
    <step num="5">Layer in 4 seasoned chicken cutlets, 2 tablespoons of barbecue sauce, 5 slices of cheddar cheese, 4 more chicken cutlets, another 2 tablespoons of barbecue sauce, the green pepper, onion, 2 tablespoons of barbecue sauce, the red pepper, 5 remaining cheese slices, and the remaining chicken. Then, wrap the overhanging strips of bacon over the top of the loaf. </step>
    <step num="6">Cover the loaf with foil and bake for 1 hour. Then remove the foil, drain any excess fat, and bake for another 30 minutes uncovered, making sure the chicken is cooked through and the bacon is brown and crispy. </step>
    <step num="7">Remove the bacon loaf from the oven and turn on the broiler. Invert the loaf onto a wire rack set atop a baking sheet and baste the loaf with the remaining barbecue sauce. </step>
    <step num="8">Broil for 5 minutes, until the glaze dries slightly. </step>
    <step num="9">Slice and serve with rolls or other barbecue party food. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cut each chicken breast in half crosswise, then cut the larger half again horizontally, creating 3 cutlets. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Transfer to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a small bowl, combine the salt, garlic powder, smoked paprika, onion powder, chili powder, black pepper, and cayenne pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour the spice mix over the chicken cutlets and toss to coat completely in the seasoning. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Set the chicken aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Arrange the bacon slices in a 9x5-inch (23x13-cm) loaf pan, making sure the bottom and sides are fully covered, and that the strips hang over the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Layer in 4 seasoned chicken cutlets, 2 tablespoons of barbecue sauce, 5 slices of cheddar cheese, 4 more chicken cutlets, another 2 tablespoons of barbecue sauce, the green pepper, onion, 2 tablespoons of barbecue sauce, the red pepper, 5 remaining cheese slices, and the remaining chicken. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Then, wrap the overhanging strips of bacon over the top of the loaf. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Cover the loaf with foil and bake for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Then remove the foil, drain any excess fat, and bake for another 30 minutes uncovered, making sure the chicken is cooked through and the bacon is brown and crispy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove the bacon loaf from the oven and turn on the broiler. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Invert the loaf onto a wire rack set atop a baking sheet and baste the loaf with the remaining barbecue sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Broil for 5 minutes, until the glaze dries slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Slice and serve with rolls or other barbecue party food. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>