<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Bubble Wrap Honeycomb Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/bubble-wrap-honeycomb-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; unsalted butter, softened ; (460 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; cream cheese, softened ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; honey ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">4 cups ; powdered sugar, sifted ; (480 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 pinch of ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">15.25 oz ; yellow cake mix, baked according to package instructions in 2 8-inch round cake pans, cooled completely and trimmed level (to remove domed tops) ; (430 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">15.25 oz ; chocolate cake mix, baked according to package instructions in 2 8-inch round cake pans, cooled completely and trimmed level (to remove domed tops) ; (430 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">24 oz ; yellow candy melts ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">homemade honeycomb, to garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">⅓ cup ; crushed honeycomb, to garnish ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">honey, for drizzling </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">cake turntable </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">cardboard cake round </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">large offset spatula </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">bubble wrap, Clean, atleast 27x7 inch (70x18 cm) piece. 5/16 inch (1 cm) thick </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="2">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129487/hls24_1554847975.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129487/landscape_720/1554847975</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the honey buttercream frosting: In a large bowl, cream together the butter and cream cheese with an electric mixer on medium speed until well combined, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed. Add the honey and beat to incorporate. Add the powdered sugar and a pinch of salt and beat on low until mostly combined. Increase the mixer speed to high and beat for 3-5 minutes more, until the buttercream is light and fluffy. If the frosting feels soft, you can also refrigerate it for 10-15 minutes so it stiffens slightly. </step>
    <step num="1">Assemble the cake: Place a cardboard cake round on a cake turntable and dab a small amount of frosting in the center of the cardboard round. Center one yellow cake layer over the dab of frosting, then evenly spread about ½ cup of buttercream on top with an offset spatula. Top with a layer of chocolate cake, then another ½ cup of frosting. Repeat with the remaining cake layers and frosting. After adding the final layer, lightly frost the entire cake to create a thin crumb coat. </step>
    <step num="2">Refrigerate the cake for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Cover the chilled cake with the remaining frosting in an even layer. Return the cake to the refrigerator for 15 minutes more, to allow the frosting to stiffen. </step>
    <step num="4">Take the cake out of the refrigerator. With the bubbles facing outward so they don’t get frosting on them, wrap the sheet of bubble wrap around the perimeter of the cake. Trim the wrap to form a collar that fits loosely around the cake and comes about 2 inches over the top edge. Remove the bubble wrap. Keep the cake in the refrigerator until you’re ready to finish the assembly. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the yellow candy honeycomb: Place the candy melts in a medium microwave-safe bowl. Microwave on medium power (not on high, which will cause the candy to seize) in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until the candy is fully melted and smooth. </step>
    <step num="6">Place the bubble wrap bubble-side up on a flat surface. Pour most of the melted candy along the bottom two-thirds of the bubble wrap. Working quickly, use an offset spatula to spread the candy over the bubble wrap, leaving the top third empty. Once the bottom two-thirds are evenly covered, use a spatula to spread the candy in a wave pattern along the top edge. Let sit for 5 minutes. While you wait, remove the cake from the refrigerator and position it near the bubble wrap. </step>
    <step num="7">After 5 minutes, test the bubble wrap by lifting up a corner. If it looks like it is beginning to harden and has a sheen to it but is still pliable, it is ready to be used. If the candy is still very loose and dripping, let sit for another 1-3 minutes, checking every minute. </step>
    <step num="8">Once the candy has set, pick it up by the top corners and quickly wrap the side with the candy around the cake. Press it onto the cake so it sticks. Once attached, try to slowly peel one corner of bubble wrap off. It it sticks, let sit for 1-3 minutes, checking every minute, until ready to peel. If it begins to peel, continue slowly peeling off the bubble wrap until entirely removed. If the candy cracks while you are peeling off the bubble wrap, either remelt and repeat the process, or break it into large shards to decorate the outside of the cake. Refrigerate until serving time. </step>
    <step num="9">Immediately before serving, top the cake with homemade honeycomb pieces and crushed honeycomb. Drizzle honey around the edges of the yellow candy honeycomb. </step>
    <step num="10">Carefully slice the cake. Drizzle each piece with more honey before serving. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
    <step num="12">For instructions for how to make your own Honey Comb, check out https://tasty.co/recipe/homemade-honeycomb </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the honey buttercream frosting: In a large bowl, cream together the butter and cream cheese with an electric mixer on medium speed until well combined, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the honey and beat to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the powdered sugar and a pinch of salt and beat on low until mostly combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Increase the mixer speed to high and beat for 3-5 minutes more, until the buttercream is light and fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">If the frosting feels soft, you can also refrigerate it for 10-15 minutes so it stiffens slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Assemble the cake: Place a cardboard cake round on a cake turntable and dab a small amount of frosting in the center of the cardboard round. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Center one yellow cake layer over the dab of frosting, then evenly spread about ½ cup of buttercream on top with an offset spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Top with a layer of chocolate cake, then another ½ cup of frosting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Repeat with the remaining cake layers and frosting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">After adding the final layer, lightly frost the entire cake to create a thin crumb coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Refrigerate the cake for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cover the chilled cake with the remaining frosting in an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Return the cake to the refrigerator for 15 minutes more, to allow the frosting to stiffen. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Take the cake out of the refrigerator. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">With the bubbles facing outward so they don’t get frosting on them, wrap the sheet of bubble wrap around the perimeter of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Trim the wrap to form a collar that fits loosely around the cake and comes about 2 inches over the top edge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Remove the bubble wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Keep the cake in the refrigerator until you’re ready to finish the assembly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Make the yellow candy honeycomb: Place the candy melts in a medium microwave-safe bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Microwave on medium power (not on high, which will cause the candy to seize) in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until the candy is fully melted and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Place the bubble wrap bubble-side up on a flat surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Pour most of the melted candy along the bottom two-thirds of the bubble wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Working quickly, use an offset spatula to spread the candy over the bubble wrap, leaving the top third empty. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Once the bottom two-thirds are evenly covered, use a spatula to spread the candy in a wave pattern along the top edge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Let sit for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">While you wait, remove the cake from the refrigerator and position it near the bubble wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">After 5 minutes, test the bubble wrap by lifting up a corner. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">If it looks like it is beginning to harden and has a sheen to it but is still pliable, it is ready to be used. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">If the candy is still very loose and dripping, let sit for another 1-3 minutes, checking every minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Once the candy has set, pick it up by the top corners and quickly wrap the side with the candy around the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Press it onto the cake so it sticks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Once attached, try to slowly peel one corner of bubble wrap off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">It it sticks, let sit for 1-3 minutes, checking every minute, until ready to peel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">If it begins to peel, continue slowly peeling off the bubble wrap until entirely removed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">If the candy cracks while you are peeling off the bubble wrap, either remelt and repeat the process, or break it into large shards to decorate the outside of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Refrigerate until serving time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Immediately before serving, top the cake with homemade honeycomb pieces and crushed honeycomb. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="37">Drizzle honey around the edges of the yellow candy honeycomb. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="38">Carefully slice the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="39">Drizzle each piece with more honey before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="40">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="41">For instructions for how to make your own Honey Comb, check out https://tasty.co/recipe/homemade-honeycomb </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>