<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Caramel Rose Apple Pie Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/caramel-rose-apple-pie</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 ; apples </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ; lemon, juiced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; granulated sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; brown sugar ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ teaspoon ; cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ teaspoon ; nutmeg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; prepared pie dough </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; heavy cream ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/54276/low_1506702849.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/54276/mp4_720x1280/1506702849</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 375˚F (190°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Peel the apples and cut in quarters. Soak the apples in lemon water to prevent the apples from browning. Slice the apples into thin slices. </step>
    <step num="2">In a small bowl, combine sugar, brown sugar, cinnamon and nutmeg. Stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="3">Sprinkle sugar and spice mixture over sliced apples and let sit for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Line a pie dough in a cast iron pan, and prick the dough with a fork all around. Chill. </step>
    <step num="5">Drain the apples, squeezing them with your hands to remove the excess moisture. Reserve the liquid to make caramel sauce. </step>
    <step num="6">Line the apple slices in the cast iron pan by overlapping each slice to make look like a rose. For the center, roll up one apple slice tightly and place it in the center of the tart, creating a rose bud shape. </step>
    <step num="7">Cover the pan with a piece of aluminum foil and bake for 30 minutes. Uncover the foil and bake for 10 minutes, or until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="8">In a saucepan, bring the leftover liquid from apple to a boil. Once the liquid is reduced by half, add the heavy cream and stir well. </step>
    <step num="9">Pour caramel sauce over to the apple pie. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 375˚F (190°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Peel the apples and cut in quarters. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Soak the apples in lemon water to prevent the apples from browning. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Slice the apples into thin slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a small bowl, combine sugar, brown sugar, cinnamon and nutmeg. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Sprinkle sugar and spice mixture over sliced apples and let sit for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Line a pie dough in a cast iron pan, and prick the dough with a fork all around. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Chill. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Drain the apples, squeezing them with your hands to remove the excess moisture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Reserve the liquid to make caramel sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Line the apple slices in the cast iron pan by overlapping each slice to make look like a rose. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">For the center, roll up one apple slice tightly and place it in the center of the tart, creating a rose bud shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Cover the pan with a piece of aluminum foil and bake for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Uncover the foil and bake for 10 minutes, or until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">In a saucepan, bring the leftover liquid from apple to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Once the liquid is reduced by half, add the heavy cream and stir well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Pour caramel sauce over to the apple pie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>