<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Skillet Phyllo Pie Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/skillet-phyllo-pie</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¼ cup ; extra virgin olive oil, plus 6 tablespoons, divided ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ; yellow onions, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">fine sea salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">freshly ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 cloves ; garlic, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; leek, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 bunch ; asparagus, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">4 ; scallions, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¾ cup ; frozen peas, or fresh peas ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ; lemon, zested, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 cup ; ricotta cheese ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">¼ cup ; grated parmesan cheese ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">6 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">10 sheets ; frozen phyllo, thawed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">flaky sea salt, for sprinkling </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="4">Snacks</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/87021/hls24_1522272247.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/87021/landscape_720/1522272247</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large skillet over medium heat, sauté the onions in ¼ cup (60 ml) of olive oil, stirring often, for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Season with salt and pepper, reduce the heat to medium-low, and add the garlic and leek. Continue to cook, stirring often, until the onions are very golden and tender, 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Stir in the asparagus and scallions and continue to sauté for 5 minutes. Stir in the peas and half of the lemon zest and cook 1 minute. Remove the pan from the heat, and set aside to cool completely. </step>
    <step num="3">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </step>
    <step num="4">In a large bowl, whisk together the eggs, ricotta, Parmesan, and remaining lemon zest. Season with salt and pepper. Fold in the cooled vegetable mixture. </step>
    <step num="5">In a small bowl, whisk together the remaining 6 tablespoons of olive oil and the melted butter. Place one phyllo sheet on a work surface (make sure to cover the remaining phyllo sheets with a slightly damp paper towel to prevent them from drying out). </step>
    <step num="6">Use a pastry brush to lightly brush the sheet with the oil-butter mixture. Top with another sheet and brush again. Repeat until you have 5 sheets stacked, finishing with the butter-oil mixture. </step>
    <step num="7">Cut the stack of phyllo into four equal rectangles. </step>
    <step num="8">Repeat the stacking and cutting with the remaining phyllo sheets. </step>
    <step num="9">Brush eight 8-ounce (225 g) ramekins with the oil-butter mixture. </step>
    <step num="10">Press a rectangle of phyllo into each of prepared ramekins (it’s okay if they break a bit), and divide the vegetable mixture among the prepared cups. Fold the edges over the filling, leaving the center slightly exposed. Brush lightly with the oil-butter mixture and sprinkle with flaky salt. </step>
    <step num="11">Transfer the ramekins to a baking sheet and bake until the phyllo is golden brown and crisp, 30-35 minutes. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large skillet over medium heat, sauté the onions in ¼ cup (60 ml) of olive oil, stirring often, for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Season with salt and pepper, reduce the heat to medium-low, and add the garlic and leek. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Continue to cook, stirring often, until the onions are very golden and tender, 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Stir in the asparagus and scallions and continue to sauté for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Stir in the peas and half of the lemon zest and cook 1 minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Remove the pan from the heat, and set aside to cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a large bowl, whisk together the eggs, ricotta, Parmesan, and remaining lemon zest. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Fold in the cooled vegetable mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a small bowl, whisk together the remaining 6 tablespoons of olive oil and the melted butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place one phyllo sheet on a work surface (make sure to cover the remaining phyllo sheets with a slightly damp paper towel to prevent them from drying out). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Use a pastry brush to lightly brush the sheet with the oil-butter mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Top with another sheet and brush again. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Repeat until you have 5 sheets stacked, finishing with the butter-oil mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cut the stack of phyllo into four equal rectangles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Repeat the stacking and cutting with the remaining phyllo sheets. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Brush eight 8-ounce (225 g) ramekins with the oil-butter mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Press a rectangle of phyllo into each of prepared ramekins (it’s okay if they break a bit), and divide the vegetable mixture among the prepared cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Fold the edges over the filling, leaving the center slightly exposed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Brush lightly with the oil-butter mixture and sprinkle with flaky salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Transfer the ramekins to a baking sheet and bake until the phyllo is golden brown and crisp, 30-35 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>