<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Paleo Beef and Veggie Stir-fry Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/paleo-beef-and-veggie-stir-fry</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 lb ; flank steak, trimmed and sliced thin against grain into 2-inch (5 cm) pieces ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 teaspoons ; lime juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 teaspoons ; coconut amino </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; avocado oil, or other oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 ; carrots, peeled and sliced ¼ -inch (6 mm) thick on the bias </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 head ; small napa cabbage, thinly sliced, plus more for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 ; fresh scallions, minced, plus more for thinly sliced for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 tablespoon ; ginger, grated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">4 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">6 tablespoons ; coconut amino </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 tablespoons ; lime juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ½ teaspoons ; tapioca flour </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Healthy</category>
    <category num="1">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/33321/low_1496437346.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/33321/mp4_720x1280/1496437346</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Add the flank steak, coconut aminos, and lime juice to a bowl, and toss to combine. Set aside to marinate for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Heat 1 tablespoon of oil over medium-high heat in a large nonstick skillet. Place half the meat in the skillet and sear for 1 minute on each side. </step>
    <step num="2">Place the seared steak in a clean bowl and repeat with the second batch, draining excess liquid from the skillet as needed. </step>
    <step num="3">Once all of the meat has been seared and removed from the pan, heat the remaining 1 tablespoon of oil in the pan. Add in the carrots and sauté until softened, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the Napa cabbage to the pan and quickly toss with the carrots. </step>
    <step num="5">Move the cabbage and carrots away from the center of the pan and sprinkle in the scallions, ginger, and garlic. Stir the mixture in the center of the pan until fragrant, about 30 seconds. </step>
    <step num="6">Mix all contents of the pan together and toss in the meat. </step>
    <step num="7">Pour in the coconut aminos, lime juice, and tapioca flour. Stir the contents of the pan until well combined and the sauce has thickened, about 1-2 minutes. Remove from heat. </step>
    <step num="8">Divided the mixture between bowls filled with Napa cabbage and garnish with scallions. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Add the flank steak, coconut aminos, and lime juice to a bowl, and toss to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Set aside to marinate for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Heat 1 tablespoon of oil over medium-high heat in a large nonstick skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Place half the meat in the skillet and sear for 1 minute on each side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Place the seared steak in a clean bowl and repeat with the second batch, draining excess liquid from the skillet as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Once all of the meat has been seared and removed from the pan, heat the remaining 1 tablespoon of oil in the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add in the carrots and sauté until softened, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the Napa cabbage to the pan and quickly toss with the carrots. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Move the cabbage and carrots away from the center of the pan and sprinkle in the scallions, ginger, and garlic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Stir the mixture in the center of the pan until fragrant, about 30 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Mix all contents of the pan together and toss in the meat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Pour in the coconut aminos, lime juice, and tapioca flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Stir the contents of the pan until well combined and the sauce has thickened, about 1-2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove from heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Divided the mixture between bowls filled with Napa cabbage and garnish with scallions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>