<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>No-Bake Chocolate Peanut Butter Balls (Buckeyes) Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/no-bake-chocolate-peanut-butter-balls-buckeyes</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ cup ; melted butter, melted ; (114 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ cups ; peanut butter ; (360 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ½ cups ; powdered sugar ; (400 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">chocolate chips, enough for dipping </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Game Day</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31859/low_1495124896.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31859/mp4_720x1280/1495124896</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Mix butter, peanut butter, and powdered sugar until well blended. More or less powdered sugar can be used to make mixture more or less dry. </step>
    <step num="1">Make 1 inch balls and freeze for about 20 minutes or until firm. </step>
    <step num="2">Microwave chocolate chips for 60 seconds, stopping every 15 seconds to check and stir. Adding some vegetable shortening can make the chocolate thinner and easier work with. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove balls from freezer and dip most of the way into the chocolate, coating all but a small circle on top. Using a toothpick for this works well but simply dipping it in and pulling it out with a fork also works. Place completed buckeyes on wax paper and allow to harden. Refrigerate if needed. </step>
    <step num="4">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Mix butter, peanut butter, and powdered sugar until well blended. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">More or less powdered sugar can be used to make mixture more or less dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Make 1 inch balls and freeze for about 20 minutes or until firm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Microwave chocolate chips for 60 seconds, stopping every 15 seconds to check and stir. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Adding some vegetable shortening can make the chocolate thinner and easier work with. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Remove balls from freezer and dip most of the way into the chocolate, coating all but a small circle on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Using a toothpick for this works well but simply dipping it in and pulling it out with a fork also works. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Place completed buckeyes on wax paper and allow to harden. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Refrigerate if needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>