<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Vegan Tiramisu Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/vegan-tiramisu</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ cups ; all-purpose flour ; (185 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ teaspoons ; cornstarch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">6 tablespoons ; unsalted vegan butter, softened </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¾ cup ; vegan sugar ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; aquafaba, liquid from can of chickpeas ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ cup ; unsweetened almond milk ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">nonstick cooking spray, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ½ cups ; raw cashews ; (195 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">boiling water, for soaking cashews </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ cup ; unsweetened almond milk ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">⅓ cup ; maple syrup ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">⅓ cup ; unrefined coconut oil, melted ; (65 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">¼ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">½ teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 teaspoon ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">25 oz ; full-fat coconut milk, chilled ; (740 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">2 tablespoons ; powdered sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">6 fl oz ; espresso, room teperature ; (175 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">¾ cup ; water ; (180 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">3 tablespoons ; dark rum </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">cocoa powder, for dusting </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Vegan</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/127987/hls24_1553290638.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/127987/landscape_720/1553290638</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the ladyfingers: In a medium bowl, sift together the flour, cornstarch, baking powder, baking soda, and salt. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">In a separate medium bowl, cream together the butter and sugar with an electric hand mixer until fully combined. Add the aquafaba and vanilla and beat for 2-3 minutes, until light and fluffy. The mixture may look broken, but will come together once the dry ingredients are added. </step>
    <step num="2">Add ½ of the flour mixture to the wet ingredients and beat until just combined. Scrape down the sides of the bowl and add the almond milk. Beat until combined. Add the rest of the dry ingredients and beat until smooth. </step>
    <step num="3">Line 2 baking sheets with parchment paper and grease with nonstick spray. </step>
    <step num="4">Transfer the batter to a piping bag fitted with a ½-inch round tip or a zip-top bag with a corner snipped off. Pipe the ladyfingers onto the prepared baking sheets, spacing at least 1½ inches apart. Each cookie should be 2¼ inches long and ¾ inch wide. You should have 50-55 total. </step>
    <step num="5">Chill the piped cookies in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="7">Bake the ladyfingers for 13-15 minutes, until the edges are light brown. Let cool completely. </step>
    <step num="8">Make the vegan mascarpone: Add the cashews to a medium heatproof bowl and pour in enough boiling water to cover by 1 inch (2.5 cm). Let soak until slightly plumped and softened, about 10 minutes. Drain. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the cashews, almond milk, maple syrup, coconut oil, salt, vanilla, and lemon juice to a blender. Blend until smooth. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="10">Scoop the solid layer from the cans of chilled coconut milk into a large bowl. Discard the liquid or save for another use. Add the powdered sugar and beat with an electric hand mixer until light and fluffy, 2-3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="11">Using a rubber spatula, fold the blended cashew mixture into the whipped coconut milk. </step>
    <step num="12">Make the soaking liquid: In a shallow bowl, combine the espresso, water, and rum. Alternatively, replace the espresso and water with 1½ cups (360 ml) of brewed coffee cooled to room temperature. </step>
    <step num="13">Assemble the tiramisu: Spread about a ½ cup (65 grams) of the mascarpone in the bottom of an 8-inch square baking dish. Quickly dip a ladyfinger in the espresso mixture and place on top of the cream. Repeat with more ladyfingers to cover the cream, 16-18 total. Carefully spread about 1 cup (130 grams) of the mascarpone over the ladyfingers, then add another layer of ladyfingers, another layer of cream, and a final layer of the remaining ladyfingers. Spread the remaining mascarpone cream on top. </step>
    <step num="14">Cover the baking dish with plastic wrap and refrigerate for at least 2 hours, or overnight. </step>
    <step num="15">Before serving, uncover the tiramisu and lightly dust the top with cocoa powder. </step>
    <step num="16">Slice into 9 portions and serve. </step>
    <step num="17">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the ladyfingers: In a medium bowl, sift together the flour, cornstarch, baking powder, baking soda, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a separate medium bowl, cream together the butter and sugar with an electric hand mixer until fully combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the aquafaba and vanilla and beat for 2-3 minutes, until light and fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">The mixture may look broken, but will come together once the dry ingredients are added. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add ½ of the flour mixture to the wet ingredients and beat until just combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Scrape down the sides of the bowl and add the almond milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Beat until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the rest of the dry ingredients and beat until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Line 2 baking sheets with parchment paper and grease with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Transfer the batter to a piping bag fitted with a ½-inch round tip or a zip-top bag with a corner snipped off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Pipe the ladyfingers onto the prepared baking sheets, spacing at least 1½ inches apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Each cookie should be 2¼ inches long and ¾ inch wide. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">You should have 50-55 total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Chill the piped cookies in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Bake the ladyfingers for 13-15 minutes, until the edges are light brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Make the vegan mascarpone: Add the cashews to a medium heatproof bowl and pour in enough boiling water to cover by 1 inch (2.5 cm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Let soak until slightly plumped and softened, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Add the cashews, almond milk, maple syrup, coconut oil, salt, vanilla, and lemon juice to a blender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Blend until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Scoop the solid layer from the cans of chilled coconut milk into a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Discard the liquid or save for another use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Add the powdered sugar and beat with an electric hand mixer until light and fluffy, 2-3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Using a rubber spatula, fold the blended cashew mixture into the whipped coconut milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Make the soaking liquid: In a shallow bowl, combine the espresso, water, and rum. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Alternatively, replace the espresso and water with 1½ cups (360 ml) of brewed coffee cooled to room temperature. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Assemble the tiramisu: Spread about a ½ cup (65 grams) of the mascarpone in the bottom of an 8-inch square baking dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Quickly dip a ladyfinger in the espresso mixture and place on top of the cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Repeat with more ladyfingers to cover the cream, 16-18 total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Carefully spread about 1 cup (130 grams) of the mascarpone over the ladyfingers, then add another layer of ladyfingers, another layer of cream, and a final layer of the remaining ladyfingers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Spread the remaining mascarpone cream on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Cover the baking dish with plastic wrap and refrigerate for at least 2 hours, or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Before serving, uncover the tiramisu and lightly dust the top with cocoa powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="37">Slice into 9 portions and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="38">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>