<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Hasselback Cheesesteak Sandwiches Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/hasselback-cheesesteak-sandwiches</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 loaf ; whole wheat bread </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ; green bell peppers </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 lb ; flank steak ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; pepper, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; vegetable oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; medium white onion, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">13 slices ; provolone cheese </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/103752/hls24_1533142257.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/103752/landscape_720/1533142257</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Place the loaf of bread on a cutting board with a chopstick on either long side of the loaf. Make 9 equal slices crosswise through the loaf, using the chopsticks to keep from cutting all the way through. </step>
    <step num="1">Cut around the sides of the bell peppers, discarding the centers with the ribs and seeds, then thinly slice. </step>
    <step num="2">Season the flank steak all over with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="3">Thinly slice the steak at a 45-degree angle into ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) thick pieces. </step>
    <step num="4">Heat the oil in a large cast-iron skillet over high heat. Cook the steak for 4 minutes on each side, or until a nice brown crust forms. Remove the steak from the pan and set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the onion to the pan and cook for 5 minutes until it starts to soften and brown on the edges. </step>
    <step num="7">Move the onions to one side of the pan and add the peppers to the other side. Season with salt and pepper to taste. Cook the peppers and onion for another 5 minutes, or until caramelized. Remove the pan from the heat. </step>
    <step num="8">Set the sliced loaf of bread on the prepared baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="9">Fold 9 provolone slices in half and place in between the slices of bread. Place 2 pieces of flank steak in every other slit. Place peppers and onion in the slits with the steak. Place the remaining 4 slices of provolone over the loaf of bread. </step>
    <step num="10">Bake for 20 minutes, or until the cheese is browned. </step>
    <step num="11">Pull apart the sandwich at the slits with just cheese. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Place the loaf of bread on a cutting board with a chopstick on either long side of the loaf. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Make 9 equal slices crosswise through the loaf, using the chopsticks to keep from cutting all the way through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cut around the sides of the bell peppers, discarding the centers with the ribs and seeds, then thinly slice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Season the flank steak all over with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Thinly slice the steak at a 45-degree angle into ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) thick pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Heat the oil in a large cast-iron skillet over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cook the steak for 4 minutes on each side, or until a nice brown crust forms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove the steak from the pan and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Preheat the oven to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the onion to the pan and cook for 5 minutes until it starts to soften and brown on the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Move the onions to one side of the pan and add the peppers to the other side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Season with salt and pepper to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Cook the peppers and onion for another 5 minutes, or until caramelized. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove the pan from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Set the sliced loaf of bread on the prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Fold 9 provolone slices in half and place in between the slices of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Place 2 pieces of flank steak in every other slit. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Place peppers and onion in the slits with the steak. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Place the remaining 4 slices of provolone over the loaf of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Bake for 20 minutes, or until the cheese is browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Pull apart the sandwich at the slits with just cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>