<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Dutch-Oven Jalapeño Cheddar Bread Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/dutch-oven-jalapeno-cheddar-bread</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 ½ cups ; bread flour, plus more for dusting ; (445 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ½ cups ; shredded sharp cheddar cheese, divided ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ; jalapeñoes, seeded and coarsely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; jalapeño, sliced into rings, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 cups ; warm water ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 ¼ teaspoons ; instant yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 tablespoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">dutch oven with lid </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">silicone spatula, if you don't have one, you can use your slightly moistened hand </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Brunch</category>
    <category num="1">Sides</category>
    <category num="2">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="3">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117122/hls24_1543431827.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117122/landscape_720/1543431827</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, combine the bread flour, 2 cups (200 g) of cheddar cheese, the chopped jalapeños, and salt. Stir well. </step>
    <step num="1">In a separate large bowl, combine the warm water and yeast. Pour the flour mixture on top of the water and use a silicone spatula to stir until the dough comes together. </step>
    <step num="2">With the spatula, fold the dough around the edges of the bowl toward the center, rotating the bowl each time and folding a total of 8 times. Cover with a kitchen towel and let rest in a warm place for 60 minutes, or until almost doubled in size. </step>
    <step num="3">Using the spatula, fold the dough toward the center again 8 more times. Cover with the towel and let rest for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the Dutch oven and lid to the oven, and preheat to 450˚F (230˚C) for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Lightly flour a clean work surface and your hands. Carefully peel the dough out of the bowl and onto the floured surface. Flip over and carefully brush away excess flour. Fold the edges of the dough towards the center 8 times, then flip over the dough and transfer to a piece of parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="6">Brush the top of the dough with the olive oil, so the cheese will stick. Sprinkle the remaining ½ cup (50 g) of cheese on top. Use a sharp knife to score the bread with an “X”, which will allow steam to escape. Arrange the jalapeño rings on top of the cheese. </step>
    <step num="7">Carefully remove the Dutch oven from the oven and use the parchment to lift the bread into the pot. Cover with the lid and bake for 30 minutes, then remove the lid and bake for 20 more minutes, until the bread is golden brown. </step>
    <step num="8">Carefully slide the bread out of the pot and onto a wire rack. Remove the parchment paper and let the bread cool for at least 1 hour before slicing. </step>
    <step num="9">Slice the bread and serve as desired. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, combine the bread flour, 2 cups (200 g) of cheddar cheese, the chopped jalapeños, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Stir well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a separate large bowl, combine the warm water and yeast. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Pour the flour mixture on top of the water and use a silicone spatula to stir until the dough comes together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">With the spatula, fold the dough around the edges of the bowl toward the center, rotating the bowl each time and folding a total of 8 times. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cover with a kitchen towel and let rest in a warm place for 60 minutes, or until almost doubled in size. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Using the spatula, fold the dough toward the center again 8 more times. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cover with the towel and let rest for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the Dutch oven and lid to the oven, and preheat to 450˚F (230˚C) for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Lightly flour a clean work surface and your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Carefully peel the dough out of the bowl and onto the floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Flip over and carefully brush away excess flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Fold the edges of the dough towards the center 8 times, then flip over the dough and transfer to a piece of parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Brush the top of the dough with the olive oil, so the cheese will stick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Sprinkle the remaining ½ cup (50 g) of cheese on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Use a sharp knife to score the bread with an “X”, which will allow steam to escape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Arrange the jalapeño rings on top of the cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Carefully remove the Dutch oven from the oven and use the parchment to lift the bread into the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Cover with the lid and bake for 30 minutes, then remove the lid and bake for 20 more minutes, until the bread is golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Carefully slide the bread out of the pot and onto a wire rack. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Remove the parchment paper and let the bread cool for at least 1 hour before slicing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Slice the bread and serve as desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>