<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Strawberry Cheesecake–Stuffed Pound Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/strawberry-cheesecake-stuffed-pound-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; pound cake, store-bought </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">8 oz ; cream cheese, 1 block, softened ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; powdered sugar ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; lemon zest </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; strawberry, diced ; (150 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/9603/low_1472847099.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/9603/mp4_720x1280/1472847099</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Cut the center out of the pound cake, leaving a half-inch border on the bottom and along each side. </step>
    <step num="1">In a medium bowl, use a hand mixer to beat together the cream cheese, powdered sugar, and lemon zest until the mixture is smooth. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the strawberries and beat until the mixture has turned a light pink color but there are still nice strawberry chunks. </step>
    <step num="3">Pour the cream cheese mixture into the hollowed-out pound cake shell. </step>
    <step num="4">Using the removed pieces of pound cake, crumble bits of cake on top of the cheesecake mixture to form a thick layer of crumbs. Refrigerate for at least 8 hours. </step>
    <step num="5">Be careful when filling the pound cake and when transferring to the refrigerator. Cutting the border too thin may cause the sides to spread too far once the cheesecake mixture is added. You can simply place the pound cake on a plate or tray before filling to make the transfer to the refrigerator easier. Use something to prop up the sides in case they’ve bowed out too much, to prevent breaking. Once the filling has set in the fridge, it will hold its shape. </step>
    <step num="6">Slice into 10 half-inch (1 cm) slices and serve. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Cut the center out of the pound cake, leaving a half-inch border on the bottom and along each side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a medium bowl, use a hand mixer to beat together the cream cheese, powdered sugar, and lemon zest until the mixture is smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the strawberries and beat until the mixture has turned a light pink color but there are still nice strawberry chunks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Pour the cream cheese mixture into the hollowed-out pound cake shell. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Using the removed pieces of pound cake, crumble bits of cake on top of the cheesecake mixture to form a thick layer of crumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Refrigerate for at least 8 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Be careful when filling the pound cake and when transferring to the refrigerator. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cutting the border too thin may cause the sides to spread too far once the cheesecake mixture is added. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">You can simply place the pound cake on a plate or tray before filling to make the transfer to the refrigerator easier. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Use something to prop up the sides in case they’ve bowed out too much, to prevent breaking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Once the filling has set in the fridge, it will hold its shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Slice into 10 half-inch (1 cm) slices and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>