<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Slow Cooker Rosemary Bread Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/slow-cooker-rosemary-bread</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ¼ cups ; lukewarm water ; (300 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 teaspoon ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 packet ; active dry yeast, about 2 1/4 teaspoons </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; salt, plus more for sprinkling </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 tablespoons ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 tablespoons ; fresh rosemary, chopped, plus more for sprinkling </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 ¾ cups ; all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (470 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Sides</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/108696/hls24_1536707505.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/108696/landscape_720/1536707505</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, mix together the water and sugar. Sprinkle the yeast over the water and stir. Let sit for 15 minutes, until the surface is foamy. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the salt, olive oil, and rosemary. Mix well. </step>
    <step num="2">Slowly add the flour and mix with a wooden spoon until well combined. </step>
    <step num="3">Knead the dough for at least 10 minutes, until it is no longer sticky. </step>
    <step num="4">Set the dough in the middle of a piece of parchment paper large enough to line the slow cooker. </step>
    <step num="5">Place the parchment paper with the dough in the slow cooker. Drape a kitchen towel over the top and cover with the lid. Set the slow cooker to warm and let the dough proof for about 30 minutes, until doubled in size. Check occasionally to make sure the dough is not cooking. </step>
    <step num="6">Lift the parchment paper to remove the dough from the slow cooker. </step>
    <step num="7">Sprinkle a bit of flour on a clean surface. Knead the dough for about 5 minutes, then shape it into a ball that will fit in the slow cooker. </step>
    <step num="8">Place the dough back on the parchment paper and return to the slow cooker. Sprinkle the top with salt and rosemary. </step>
    <step num="9">Cover the slow cooker with the towel and the lid and cook on high heat for 1½-2 hours, until the bread has a thick, dry, white crust, or a thermometer inserted in the loaf reaches 190°F (90°C). </step>
    <step num="10">Preheat the oven to 500°F (260°C). </step>
    <step num="11">Using the parchment paper, transfer the bread to a baking sheet. Trim the excess parchment. </step>
    <step num="12">Bake for 5-10 minutes, until the crust is golden brown. </step>
    <step num="13">Let cool for about 15 minutes, then slice. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, mix together the water and sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Sprinkle the yeast over the water and stir. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Let sit for 15 minutes, until the surface is foamy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the salt, olive oil, and rosemary. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Mix well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Slowly add the flour and mix with a wooden spoon until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Knead the dough for at least 10 minutes, until it is no longer sticky. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Set the dough in the middle of a piece of parchment paper large enough to line the slow cooker. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Place the parchment paper with the dough in the slow cooker. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Drape a kitchen towel over the top and cover with the lid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Set the slow cooker to warm and let the dough proof for about 30 minutes, until doubled in size. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Check occasionally to make sure the dough is not cooking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Lift the parchment paper to remove the dough from the slow cooker. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Sprinkle a bit of flour on a clean surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Knead the dough for about 5 minutes, then shape it into a ball that will fit in the slow cooker. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Place the dough back on the parchment paper and return to the slow cooker. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Sprinkle the top with salt and rosemary. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cover the slow cooker with the towel and the lid and cook on high heat for 1½-2 hours, until the bread has a thick, dry, white crust, or a thermometer inserted in the loaf reaches 190°F (90°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Preheat the oven to 500°F (260°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Using the parchment paper, transfer the bread to a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Trim the excess parchment. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Bake for 5-10 minutes, until the crust is golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Let cool for about 15 minutes, then slice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>