<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Gluten-Free Grilled Flatbread Pizzas Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/gluten-free-grilled-flatbread-pizzas</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ cups ; warm water ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 packet ; active dry yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 large ; large egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 ¼ cups ; gluten-free flour blend ; (405 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">topping of your choice </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Game Day</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/101955/hls24_1531519524.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/101955/landscape_720/1531519524</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Pour the water into a large bowl and add the yeast. Let sit for 2 minutes while the yeast activates. The mixture should become foamy and some of the yeast will sink in the water. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the eggs and oil. Whisk until smooth. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the gluten-free pizza dough mix and stir with a wooden spoon until well-combined. </step>
    <step num="3">Use a bowl scraper to divide the dough in half. Grease 2 medium bowls with olive oil. Place each dough half in a bowl and top with another drizzle of oil. </step>
    <step num="4">Toss the dough to evenly coat in oil, then cover the bowls with clean kitchen towels. Let rise for 20 minutes, until the dough has expanded, but not quite doubled in size. </step>
    <step num="5">Heat a grill pan over high heat. </step>
    <step num="6">Turn a dough portion onto a lightly floured pizza peel or other flat surface, like a cutting board or cookie sheet. Dust the dough with more flour and roll out into a 10-inch (25-cm) round, or whatever size will fit the pan you’re working with. </step>
    <step num="7">Carefully slide the dough onto the grill pan. Grill each side for 6-8 minutes, until dark grill marks form. Remove from the heat. Repeat with the remaining dough. </step>
    <step num="8">Top with your desired toppings, slice, and serve. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Pour the water into a large bowl and add the yeast. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Let sit for 2 minutes while the yeast activates. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">The mixture should become foamy and some of the yeast will sink in the water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the eggs and oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Whisk until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the gluten-free pizza dough mix and stir with a wooden spoon until well-combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Use a bowl scraper to divide the dough in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Grease 2 medium bowls with olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Place each dough half in a bowl and top with another drizzle of oil </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Toss the dough to evenly coat in oil, then cover the bowls with clean kitchen towels. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Let rise for 20 minutes, until the dough has expanded, but not quite doubled in size. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Heat a grill pan over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Turn a dough portion onto a lightly floured pizza peel or other flat surface, like a cutting board or cookie sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Dust the dough with more flour and roll out into a 10-inch (25-cm) round, or whatever size will fit the pan you’re working with. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Carefully slide the dough onto the grill pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Grill each side for 6-8 minutes, until dark grill marks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Remove from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Repeat with the remaining dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Top with your desired toppings, slice, and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>