<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Watermelon Salad With Fresh Herbs Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/watermelon-salad-with-fresh-herbs</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/watermelon-salads-3-ways</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; small watermelon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; balsamic vinaigrette ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ ; red onion, peeled, halved, and thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; fresh mint leaf ; (10 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; fresh basil leaf, thinly sliced ; (10 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 tablespoons ; fresh thyme leaf </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Healthy</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Brunch</category>
    <category num="3">Lunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/96222/hls24_1527619829.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/96222/landscape_720/1527619829</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>-1</start_time>
    <end_time>-1</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Using a sharp knife, cut off the top and bottom of the watermelon to reveal the red flesh and create flat surfaces on both sides. Stand the watermelon upright, and slice off the remaining peel so only the red core remains. </step>
    <step num="1">Cut the watermelon into roughly 1-inch (2-cm) cubes and transfer to a large bowl. </step>
    <step num="2">In a medium pot over high heat, bring the balsamic vinegar to a boil and reduce until roughly ¼ cup (60 ml) remains and the vinegar has thickened significantly, about 10 minutes. Remove the pot from the heat and set aside to cool. </step>
    <step num="3">Arrange the watermelon cubes on a plate or place in a large bowl. </step>
    <step num="4">Arrange the red onion, mint leaves, drops of balsamic reduction, basil, and thyme decoratively over the watermelon. Or, if using a bowl, toss the watermelon, onion, and herbs together, then drizzle with balsamic reduction. </step>
    <step num="5">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Using a sharp knife, cut off the top and bottom of the watermelon to reveal the red flesh and create flat surfaces on both sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Stand the watermelon upright, and slice off the remaining peel so only the red core remains. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cut the watermelon into roughly 1-inch (2-cm) cubes and transfer to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a medium pot over high heat, bring the balsamic vinegar to a boil and reduce until roughly ¼ cup (60 ml) remains and the vinegar has thickened significantly, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Remove the pot from the heat and set aside to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Arrange the watermelon cubes on a plate or place in a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Arrange the red onion, mint leaves, drops of balsamic reduction, basil, and thyme decoratively over the watermelon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Or, if using a bowl, toss the watermelon, onion, and herbs together, then drizzle with balsamic reduction. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
  <duration_human>
    <start_time>00124</start_time>
    <end_time>03723</end_time>
  </duration_human>
</recipe>