<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Miso and Mushroom Arancini</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/jens-japanese-arancini</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ oz ; dried shiitake mushroom ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">5 cups ; cold water ; (1 ¼ L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; awase miso paste ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; canola oil, plus more for frying </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ ; large white onion, finely diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; fresh ginger, 1 in (2 1/4 cm) peeled and minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¾ cup ; japanese short grain rice ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">⅓ cup ; dry sake ; (80 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¾ cup ; freshly grated parmesan cheese ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 ; green onions, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">¾ cup ; all purpose flour ; (95 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">3 ; large eggs, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 ½ cups ; panko breadcrumbs ; (75 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="1">Snacks</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/137101/hls24_1561493989.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/137101/landscape_720/1561493989</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large skillet over high heat, combine the shiitake mushrooms and water and bring to a boil. Reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer until the mushrooms have plumped and become tender, about 20 minutes. Remove the pot from the heat and drain the mushrooms with a fine-mesh sieve lined with a couple layers of paper towels (this will catch any dirt that might have been on the mushrooms) set over a medium pot to catch the broth. Let the mushrooms cool slightly. </step>
    <step num="1">Whisk the miso paste into the mushroom broth until dissolved. Cover the pot with a lid to keep the broth warm. </step>
    <step num="2">Once the mushrooms are cool enough to handle, cut away and discard the stems, then finely dice the mushroom caps. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">Heat 2 tablespoons of canola oil in a large pan over medium heat. Once the oil begins to shimmer, add the onion and ½ teaspoon of salt and cook, stirring frequently, until the onion is tender, 4-6 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the garlic and ginger and cook until softened, stirring frequently, 1-2 minutes. Stir in the diced mushrooms. </step>
    <step num="5">Stir in the rice and toast for 1-2 minutes, stirring frequently, until fragrant and starting to brown. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the sake and cook until fully evaporated, stirring occasionally, 1-2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Reduce the heat to medium-low, add 1 cup of the warm mushroom broth, and stir to combine. Cook, stirring frequently, until the stock is fully absorbed. Continue to add the broth, ½ cup (120 ML) at a time, stirring continuously for 25-35 minutes total until the rice is al dente. You may have some broth left over. </step>
    <step num="8">Remove the pan from the heat and stir in the Parmesan cheese. Gently stir in the green onions and season with salt to taste. </step>
    <step num="9">Spread the risotto in an even layer on a baking sheet lined with parchment paper. Let cool slightly, then cover with plastic wrap and refrigerate until completely cooled, at least 2 hours but up to overnight. </step>
    <step num="10">Add the flour, eggs, and bread crumbs to 3 separate shallow dishes. </step>
    <step num="11">Scoop heaping tablespoons of the cooled risotto mixture and roll into balls. You should have about 25 total. Working 1 at a time, dredge the rice balls first in the flour, then in the eggs, and finally in the bread crumbs. Place the breaded rice balls back on the same baking sheet. Chill in the refrigerator while you heat the oil. </step>
    <step num="12">Fill a large pot halfway with canola oil and heat over medium-high heat until it reaches 350°F (180°C). </step>
    <step num="13">Working in batches, fry the rice balls in the hot oil until deep golden brown, 4-5 minutes, turning occasionally. Transfer to a wire rack set over a baking sheet to drain. </step>
    <step num="14">Serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="15">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large skillet over high heat, combine the shiitake mushrooms and water and bring to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer until the mushrooms have plumped and become tender, about 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Remove the pot from the heat and drain the mushrooms with a fine-mesh sieve lined with a couple layers of paper towels (this will catch any dirt that might have been on the mushrooms) set over a medium pot to catch the broth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Let the mushrooms cool slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Whisk the miso paste into the mushroom broth until dissolved. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cover the pot with a lid to keep the broth warm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Once the mushrooms are cool enough to handle, cut away and discard the stems, then finely dice the mushroom caps. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Heat 2 tablespoons of canola oil in a large pan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Once the oil begins to shimmer, add the onion and ½ teaspoon of salt and cook, stirring frequently, until the onion is tender, 4-6 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the garlic and ginger and cook until softened, stirring frequently, 1-2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Stir in the diced mushrooms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Stir in the rice and toast for 1-2 minutes, stirring frequently, until fragrant and starting to brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the sake and cook until fully evaporated, stirring occasionally, 1-2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Reduce the heat to medium-low, add 1 cup of the warm mushroom broth, and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cook, stirring frequently, until the stock is fully absorbed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Continue to add the broth, ½ cup (120 ML) at a time, stirring continuously for 25-35 minutes total until the rice is al dente. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">You may have some broth left over. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Remove the pan from the heat and stir in the Parmesan cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Gently stir in the green onions and season with salt to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Spread the risotto in an even layer on a baking sheet lined with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Let cool slightly, then cover with plastic wrap and refrigerate until completely cooled, at least 2 hours but up to overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add the flour, eggs, and bread crumbs to 3 separate shallow dishes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Scoop heaping tablespoons of the cooled risotto mixture and roll into balls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">You should have about 25 total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Working 1 at a time, dredge the rice balls first in the flour, then in the eggs, and finally in the bread crumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Place the breaded rice balls back on the same baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Chill in the refrigerator while you heat the oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Fill a large pot halfway with canola oil and heat over medium-high heat until it reaches 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Working in batches, fry the rice balls in the hot oil until deep golden brown, 4-5 minutes, turning occasionally. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Transfer to a wire rack set over a baking sheet to drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>