<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Holiday Garlic Herb Porchetta Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/holiday-garlic-herb-porchetta</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">8 lb ; skin on pork belly ; (3.5 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; kosher salt, plus 2 teaspoons kosher salt, divided ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; fennel seeds </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; fresh rosemary ; (35 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 ; lemon zests </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">⅓ cup ; fresh thyme ; (15 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">8 cloves ; garlic </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; coarsely ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 ½ lb ; boneless pork loin, Not tenderloin, trimmed of excess fat ; (1 ¼ kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">nonstick cooking spray, for greasing </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Italian</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/120425/hls24_1545159186.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/120425/landscape_720/1545159186</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Set the pork belly on a rimmed baking sheet. Season all over with ½ cup (120 g) of salt and the sugar. Wrap tightly in plastic wrap and refrigerate for 24 hours. </step>
    <step num="1">When ready to cook the pork, preheat the oven to 250˚F (120˚C). </step>
    <step num="2">Unwrap the pork belly and rinse off all the salt and sugar with cold water. Pat dry with paper towels, then place skin-side down on a baking sheet or large cutting board. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the fennel seeds to a food processor and pulse until finely ground. Transfer to a small bowl and wipe out the processor. </step>
    <step num="4">To the clean food processor, add the rosemary, lemon zest, thyme, garlic, 2 teaspoons of salt, and the pepper, and pulse until finely chopped and well combined. </step>
    <step num="5">Spread the garlic-herb paste evenly over the meat side of the pork belly. </step>
    <step num="6">Place the pork loin parallel along a short side of the pork belly. Roll up the belly to encase the loin and position the roll seam-side down. </step>
    <step num="7">Set a wire rack over a baking sheet and grease with nonstick spray. Arrange 8 30-inch (75 cm) long pieces of kitchen twine over the wire rack, spacing 1½ inches (4 cm) apart. Place the pork roll, seam-side down, across the center of the twine pieces. </step>
    <step num="8">Starting with the centermost piece, tie the twine as tightly as you can around the pork roll, using 2 double knots. Work your way from the center toward either end to tie the rest of the twine. Cut off the excess twine. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the other ½ cup (120 g) of salt to the bowl with the ground fennel seeds and stir to combine. Sprinkle over the pork roll and rub into the skin. </step>
    <step num="10">Roast the porchetta for about 3 hours, until an instant-read thermometer inserted into the center reaches 145˚F (63˚C). Remove from the oven. </step>
    <step num="11">Increase the oven temperature to 450˚F (230˚C). Transfer the pork roll, still on the wire rack, to a cutting board. Pour any pan juices into a small bowl and skim off any fat. </step>
    <step num="12">Set the porchetta on the wire rack over the baking sheet, then return to the oven and roast for about 30 minutes more, until the skin is bubbling, crisp, and golden. </step>
    <step num="13">Transfer the porchetta to a cutting board and let rest for 20 minutes. Removed the twine and carve into ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) thick slices. Serve hot, with pan juices spooned over. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Set the pork belly on a rimmed baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Season all over with ½ cup (120 g) of salt and the sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Wrap tightly in plastic wrap and refrigerate for 24 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">When ready to cook the pork, preheat the oven to 250˚F (120˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Unwrap the pork belly and rinse off all the salt and sugar with cold water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pat dry with paper towels, then place skin-side down on a baking sheet or large cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the fennel seeds to a food processor and pulse until finely ground. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Transfer to a small bowl and wipe out the processor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">To the clean food processor, add the rosemary, lemon zest, thyme, garlic, 2 teaspoons of salt, and the pepper, and pulse until finely chopped and well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Spread the garlic-herb paste evenly over the meat side of the pork belly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place the pork loin parallel along a short side of the pork belly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Roll up the belly to encase the loin and position the roll seam-side down. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Set a wire rack over a baking sheet and grease with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Arrange 8 30-inch (75 cm) long pieces of kitchen twine over the wire rack, spacing 1½ inches (4 cm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Place the pork roll, seam-side down, across the center of the twine pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Starting with the centermost piece, tie the twine as tightly as you can around the pork roll, using 2 double knots. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Work your way from the center toward either end to tie the rest of the twine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cut off the excess twine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the other ½ cup (120 g) of salt to the bowl with the ground fennel seeds and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Sprinkle over the pork roll and rub into the skin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Roast the porchetta for about 3 hours, until an instant-read thermometer inserted into the center reaches 145˚F (63˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Remove from the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Increase the oven temperature to 450˚F (230˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Transfer the pork roll, still on the wire rack, to a cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Pour any pan juices into a small bowl and skim off any fat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Set the porchetta on the wire rack over the baking sheet, then return to the oven and roast for about 30 minutes more, until the skin is bubbling, crisp, and golden. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Transfer the porchetta to a cutting board and let rest for 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Removed the twine and carve into ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) thick slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Serve hot, with pan juices spooned over. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>