<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Cocoa Crispy Rice Chocolate Hazelnut Mousse Pie Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/cocoa-crispy-rice-chocolate-hazelnut-mousse-pie</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 cups ; cocoa crispy rice cereal ; (90 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; semi-sweet chocolate chips ; (175 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">4 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, 1/2 stick </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">nonstick cooking spray, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; chocolate hazelnut spread ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ cups ; heavy cream, cold ; (360 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¼ cup ; sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">⅓ cup ; sugar ; (65 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; cocoa crispy rice cereal ; (15 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ cup ; toasted hazelnuts, coarsely chopped ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¼ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/126965/hls24_1552345277.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/126965/landscape_720/1552345277</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the crust: Add the crispy rice cereal to a zip-top bag, seal, and crush into crumbs with a rolling pin. Transfer the crumbs to a large bowl. </step>
    <step num="1">In a medium bowl, combine the chocolate chips and butter. Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring between, until melted and smooth, about 1 minute total. </step>
    <step num="2">Pour the melted chocolate mixture over the cereal crumbs and stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="3">Grease 9½-inch (24-centimeter) pie dish with nonstick spray. Pour the crust mixture into the dish and press into an even layer against the bottom and up the sides of the pan. </step>
    <step num="4">Chill in the refrigerator while you make the mousse. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the chocolate hazelnut mousse: Microwave the chocolate hazelnut spread for 30 seconds. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="6">In a large bowl, beat the cold heavy cream with an electric hand mixer until soft peaks form. Add the sugar and beat to incorporate. </step>
    <step num="7">Using a rubber spatula, fold the warm chocolate hazelnut spread into the whipped cream until incorporated. </step>
    <step num="8">Remove the crust from the refrigerator and pour in the mousse. Spread in an even layer. </step>
    <step num="9">Cover the pie with plastic wrap and freeze for at least 6 hours, or overnight. </step>
    <step num="10">Make the crispy rice topping: Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="11">Add the sugar to a medium nonstick skillet over medium-high heat. Cook without stirring for 1-2 minutes, until the sugar begins to caramelize. Swirl it around in the pan to help caramelize evenly. </step>
    <step num="12">Once the sugar is light amber in color, reduce the heat to low and add the butter. Use a rubber spatula to stir until the butter is melted, then turn off the heat. Add the crispy rice cereal and toasted hazelnuts and quickly stir to coat. </step>
    <step num="13">Transfer the topping to the prepared baking sheet and sprinkle with the salt. Use two forks to separate the mixture into smaller chunks, being careful not to touch the hot sugar with your hands. Let cool completely, about 15 minutes. The topping can be made 1 day ahead. Store in an airtight container once cooled. </step>
    <step num="14">When ready to serve, remove the pie from the freezer. Decorate the top with the crispy rice topping. Let the pie sit at room temperature for 10 minutes before slicing with a sharp knife. Warm the blade in hot water and wipe between each cut for clean slices. </step>
    <step num="15">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the crust: Add the crispy rice cereal to a zip-top bag, seal, and crush into crumbs with a rolling pin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Transfer the crumbs to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a medium bowl, combine the chocolate chips and butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring between, until melted and smooth, about 1 minute total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour the melted chocolate mixture over the cereal crumbs and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Grease 9½-inch (24-centimeter) pie dish with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Pour the crust mixture into the dish and press into an even layer against the bottom and up the sides of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Chill in the refrigerator while you make the mousse. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Make the chocolate hazelnut mousse: Microwave the chocolate hazelnut spread for 30 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a large bowl, beat the cold heavy cream with an electric hand mixer until soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the sugar and beat to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Using a rubber spatula, fold the warm chocolate hazelnut spread into the whipped cream until incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove the crust from the refrigerator and pour in the mousse. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Spread in an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cover the pie with plastic wrap and freeze for at least 6 hours, or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Make the crispy rice topping: Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Add the sugar to a medium nonstick skillet over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Cook without stirring for 1-2 minutes, until the sugar begins to caramelize. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Swirl it around in the pan to help caramelize evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Once the sugar is light amber in color, reduce the heat to low and add the butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Use a rubber spatula to stir until the butter is melted, then turn off the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add the crispy rice cereal and toasted hazelnuts and quickly stir to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Transfer the topping to the prepared baking sheet and sprinkle with the salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Use two forks to separate the mixture into smaller chunks, being careful not to touch the hot sugar with your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Let cool completely, about 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">The topping can be made 1 day ahead. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Store in an airtight container once cooled. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">When ready to serve, remove the pie from the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Decorate the top with the crispy rice topping. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Let the pie sit at room temperature for 10 minutes before slicing with a sharp knife. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Warm the blade in hot water and wipe between each cut for clean slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>