<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Rainbow Croissants Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/rainbow-croissants</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">⅔ cup ; whole milk ; (170 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">⅔ cup ; water ; (170 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">5 cups ; unbleached all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (600 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; granulated sugar ; (45 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; instant dry yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 tablespoons ; unsalted european-style butter, cubed, softened </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">5 ; food colorings, different colors </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ¼ cups ; unsalted european-style butter, shaped into an 8X6-in (20x15-cm) rectangle, cold ; (275 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ; large egg, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">food-safe glove </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">French</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="3">Brunch</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/103586/hls24_1532993857.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/103586/landscape_720/1532993857</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, combine the milk and water. </step>
    <step num="1">On top of the liquid, add the flour, sugar, salt, yeast, and cubed butter. </step>
    <step num="2">Mix just until the dough comes together, but don’t overmix. </step>
    <step num="3">Set aside ¼ of the dough and transfer the rest to a lightly floured surface. Knead until the flour is fully incorporated. Shape into a ball, place in a large bowl, cover with plastic wrap, and let rest at room temperature for 2 hours. </step>
    <step num="4">Divide the reserved quarter of dough into 5 equal pieces. Add a few drop of different colored food coloring to each one. </step>
    <step num="5">Wearing food-safe gloves so you don’t stain your skin, work each color into the dough. </step>
    <step num="6">Shape the colored dough into balls, place on a plate, and cover with plastic. Let rest for 2 hours at room temperature. </step>
    <step num="7">Transfer the large piece of rested dough to a parchment-lined baking sheet. Shape into an 8x11-inch (20x27 cm) rectangle, cover with plastic wrap, and chill in the refrigerator overnight. </step>
    <step num="8">Transfer the colored dough to another parchment-lined baking sheet. Shape into 2x3-inch (5x7 cm) rectangles, cover with plastic wrap, and chill overnight. </step>
    <step num="9">Transfer the plain rested dough to a clean, lightly floured surface. Roll into a 16x8-inch (40x20 cm) rectangle. Pat the edges with a knife to straighten. </step>
    <step num="10">Place the butter rectangle at the center of the dough rectangle. Fold the top and bottom of the dough over to cover the butter, pinching the center seam and sides to seal. </step>
    <step num="11">Rotate 90° and roll out to a large rectangle, about 8x18 inches (20x45 cm). Flatten the edges. </step>
    <step num="12">Fold the top and bottom edges to meet in the center of the dough. Fold over once more, then freeze for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="13">Roll out the dough again to a large rectangle, about 24x8 inches (60x20 cm). Brush off any excess flour. Fold the dough in thirds, brush again, then freeze for another 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="14">Cut the chilled, colored doughs in half lengthwise. Roll into ropes about 10 inches (25 cm) long. </step>
    <step num="15">Brush the ropes with water and line up together, in rainbow order or as desired. Press together. Lightly dust with flour and roll out into a rectangle roughly the same size as the plain dough. </step>
    <step num="16">Brush the plain dough with water, then lay on the colored dough sheet on top. </step>
    <step num="17">Roll out into a large, 13x21-inch (33x53 cm) rectangle and about ¼-inch (6 mm) thick. </step>
    <step num="18">Cut the dough into 10 triangles with bases that are about 4 inches (10 cm) wide. </step>
    <step num="19">Lay the dough triangles colored side down, and starting with the wide end, gently roll up. </step>
    <step num="20">Place the croissants on a parchment-lined baking sheet, seam-side down. Cover with plastic wrap and let proof at room temperature for 2 hours. </step>
    <step num="21">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). </step>
    <step num="22">Brush the croissants with egg wash. </step>
    <step num="23">Bake for 20-25 minutes, until golden brown. Let cool on a wire rack. </step>
    <step num="24">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, combine the milk and water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">On top of the liquid, add the flour, sugar, salt, yeast, and cubed butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Mix just until the dough comes together, but don’t overmix. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set aside ¼ of the dough and transfer the rest to a lightly floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Knead until the flour is fully incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Shape into a ball, place in a large bowl, cover with plastic wrap, and let rest at room temperature for 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Divide the reserved quarter of dough into 5 equal pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add a few drop of different colored food coloring to each one. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Wearing food-safe gloves so you don’t stain your skin, work each color into the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Shape the colored dough into balls, place on a plate, and cover with plastic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Let rest for 2 hours at room temperature. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Transfer the large piece of rested dough to a parchment-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Shape into an 8x11-inch (20x27 cm) rectangle, cover with plastic wrap, and chill in the refrigerator overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Transfer the colored dough to another parchment-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Shape into 2x3-inch (5x7 cm) rectangles, cover with plastic wrap, and chill overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Transfer the plain rested dough to a clean, lightly floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Roll into a 16x8-inch (40x20 cm) rectangle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Pat the edges with a knife to straighten. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Place the butter rectangle at the center of the dough rectangle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Fold the top and bottom of the dough over to cover the butter, pinching the center seam and sides to seal. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Rotate 90° and roll out to a large rectangle, about 8x18 inches (20x45 cm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Flatten the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Fold the top and bottom edges to meet in the center of the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Fold over once more, then freeze for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Roll out the dough again to a large rectangle, about 24x8 inches (60x20 cm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Brush off any excess flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Fold the dough in thirds, brush again, then freeze for another 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Cut the chilled, colored doughs in half lengthwise. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Roll into ropes about 10 inches (25 cm) long. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Brush the ropes with water and line up together, in rainbow order or as desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Press together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Lightly dust with flour and roll out into a rectangle roughly the same size as the plain dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Brush the plain dough with water, then lay on the colored dough sheet on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Roll out into a large, 13x21-inch (33x53 cm) rectangle and about ¼-inch (6 mm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Cut the dough into 10 triangles with bases that are about 4 inches (10 cm) wide. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Lay the dough triangles colored side down, and starting with the wide end, gently roll up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Place the croissants on a parchment-lined baking sheet, seam-side down. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="37">Cover with plastic wrap and let proof at room temperature for 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="38">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="39">Brush the croissants with egg wash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="40">Bake for 20-25 minutes, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="41">Let cool on a wire rack. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="42">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>