<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Strawberry Cheesecake French Toast Roll Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/strawberry-cheesecake-french-toast-roll</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">16 oz ; cream cheese, room temperature ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; powdered sugar, plus more for serving ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">10 slices ; brioche bread </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 ; eggs, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">16 oz ; strawberry, chopped ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">⅓ cup ; milk ; (80 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 teaspoons ; granulated sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">maple syrup, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">⅓ cup ; powdered sugar, for serving ; (40 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="2">Brunch</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/91381/hls24_1524774968.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/91381/landscape_720/1524774968</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the filling: In a large bowl, use a spatula to combine the cream cheese, powdered sugar, and the vanilla extract. Mix together until fluffy and smooth. </step>
    <step num="1">Lay out a piece of plastic wrap and arrange 4 rows of 2 whole slices of brioche bread. Cut 2 pieces of brioche bread in half and add to the end of each row. </step>
    <step num="2">Beat 1 egg in a small bowl. Brush egg wash on the left side of each piece of bread, except for the farthest left pieces in each row. Overlap the right edges over the egg wash and press to adhere. Brush egg was along the bottom of each row of bread, except for the bottom row. Overlap the top edges of each row over the egg wash and press to adhere. </step>
    <step num="3">Use a spatula to spread an even layer of the filling over the bread. Distribute the strawberries over the filling. </step>
    <step num="4">Using the plastic wrap for help, roll up the bread. Twist the ends of the plastic to seal. </step>
    <step num="5">Freeze for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="6">In a medium bowl, whisk together the remaining 3 eggs, the milk, sugar, and cinnamon. </step>
    <step num="7">Preheat the oven to 425°F (220°C). </step>
    <step num="8">Remove the roll from the freezer. Remove plastic wrap and transfer to a greased baking sheet. Brush all over with the cinnamon egg mixture. </step>
    <step num="9">Bake for 12 minutes, or until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="10">Remove from oven. Dust with powdered sugar, slice, and serve with a drizzle of maple syrup. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the filling: In a large bowl, use a spatula to combine the cream cheese, powdered sugar, and the vanilla extract. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Mix together until fluffy and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Lay out a piece of plastic wrap and arrange 4 rows of 2 whole slices of brioche bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cut 2 pieces of brioche bread in half and add to the end of each row. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Beat 1 egg in a small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Brush egg wash on the left side of each piece of bread, except for the farthest left pieces in each row. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Overlap the right edges over the egg wash and press to adhere. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Brush egg was along the bottom of each row of bread, except for the bottom row. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Overlap the top edges of each row over the egg wash and press to adhere. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Use a spatula to spread an even layer of the filling over the bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Distribute the strawberries over the filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Using the plastic wrap for help, roll up the bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Twist the ends of the plastic to seal. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Freeze for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">In a medium bowl, whisk together the remaining 3 eggs, the milk, sugar, and cinnamon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Preheat the oven to 425°F (220°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Remove the roll from the freezer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Remove plastic wrap and transfer to a greased baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Brush all over with the cinnamon egg mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Bake for 12 minutes, or until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Remove from oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Dust with powdered sugar, slice, and serve with a drizzle of maple syrup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>