<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Mini Egg Pies Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/mini-egg-pies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 ; eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 sheet ; puff pastry </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 teaspoons ; oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">British</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="4">Brunch</category>
    <category num="5">Snacks</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32075/low_1495125327.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32075/mp4_720x1280/1495125327</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 220째C (430째F). </step>
    <step num="1">Using a cup or mug with roughly the same diameter as the bottoms of your muffin tin, cut out 3 circles of puff pastry dough. Make sure you cut the circles out as closely as possible to save dough. </step>
    <step num="2">With the remaining dough, cut out strips to wrap around the inside of the muffin tin cups. The strips should be about three centimeters (1 inch) wider than the depth of the muffin tin cups. </step>
    <step num="3">Rub oil in the bottom of 3 to 4 cups in the center of your muffin tin. Place the puff pastry dough circles at the bottom of the cups, then wrap the dough strips along the walls of the cups. </step>
    <step num="4">NOTE: The dough strips should come up a couple of centimeters (about an inch) taller than the wall of each muffin tin cup. </step>
    <step num="5">Using your fingers, pinch and press the beginning and end of the strips together and then press the edges of the strips down near the edges of the circles to create one cohesive dough cup. </step>
    <step num="6">Crack one egg into each dough cup and then season with a pinch of salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="7">Working carefully, pinch small sections of the tops of each dough wall together, crimping around the edge so that you bend the dough closer to the center and make five crimped crests on the top of each pie. You want to build a top to the pies but there will still be a circle in the middle with exposed egg. </step>
    <step num="8">Place the muffin tin on a center rack in the oven and bake for 15-20 minutes, or until the puff pastry is golden brown and the egg looks set. Remove from muffin tin. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 220째C (430째F). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Using a cup or mug with roughly the same diameter as the bottoms of your muffin tin, cut out 3 circles of puff pastry dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Make sure you cut the circles out as closely as possible to save dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">With the remaining dough, cut out strips to wrap around the inside of the muffin tin cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">The strips should be about three centimeters (1 inch) wider than the depth of the muffin tin cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Rub oil in the bottom of 3 to 4 cups in the center of your muffin tin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Place the puff pastry dough circles at the bottom of the cups, then wrap the dough strips along the walls of the cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">NOTE: The dough strips should come up a couple of centimeters (about an inch) taller than the wall of each muffin tin cup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Using your fingers, pinch and press the beginning and end of the strips together and then press the edges of the strips down near the edges of the circles to create one cohesive dough cup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Crack one egg into each dough cup and then season with a pinch of salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Working carefully, pinch small sections of the tops of each dough wall together, crimping around the edge so that you bend the dough closer to the center and make five crimped crests on the top of each pie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">You want to build a top to the pies but there will still be a circle in the middle with exposed egg. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Place the muffin tin on a center rack in the oven and bake for 15-20 minutes, or until the puff pastry is golden brown and the egg looks set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove from muffin tin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>