<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Giant Cinnamon Roll Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/giant-cinnamon-roll</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ cup ; unsalted butter, melted, plus more for greasing the pan ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 cups ; whole milk, warm to the touch ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; granulated sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 pack ; active dry yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">5 cups ; all-purpose flour, divided ; (625 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 teaspoons ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¾ cup ; butter, softened ; (175 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¾ cup ; light brown sugar ; (165 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 tablespoons ; ground cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">4 oz ; cream cheese, softened ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 tablespoons ; butter, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 tablespoons ; whole milk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 cup ; powdered sugar ; (160 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Brunch</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/45339/low_1501267466.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/45339/mp4_720x1280/1501267466</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Generously butter a 9-inch (23cm) cast iron or cake pan. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, whisk together warm milk, melted butter, and granulated sugar. The mixture should be just warm, registering between 100-110˚F (40˚C). If hotter, allow to cool slightly. </step>
    <step num="2">Sprinkle the yeast evenly over the warm mixture and let sit for 1 minute. </step>
    <step num="3">Add 4 cups (500 grams) of all-purpose flour to the milk mixture and mix with a wooden spoon until just combined. </step>
    <step num="4">Cover the bowl with a towel or plastic wrap and set in a warm place to rise for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="5">Preheat oven to 325˚F (160˚C). </step>
    <step num="6">After 1 hour, the dough should have nearly doubled in size. Remove the towel and add an additional ¾ cup (95 grams) of flour, the baking powder, and salt. Stir well, then turn out onto a well-floured surface. </step>
    <step num="7">Knead the dough lightly, adding additional flour as necessary, until the dough just loses its stickiness and does not stick to the surface. </step>
    <step num="8">Roll the dough out into a large rectangle, about ½-inch (1.5 cm) thick. Fix corners to make sure they are sharp and even. </step>
    <step num="9">In a small bowl combine the filling ingredients and stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="10">Spread the filling mixture evenly over the rolled out dough, spreading right to the edges. </step>
    <step num="11">Using a pizza cutter, make 3 horizontal cuts to divide the dough into four long, evenly sized strips. </step>
    <step num="12">Starting from the bottom, roll the first strip up right to left. Take the first roll and place it back on top of the next strip, starting again on the right side and rolling up right to left, building on the first. Continue with the remaining two strips until you have a giant cinnamon roll. </step>
    <step num="13">Place the giant cinnamon roll in the prepared cast iron or cake pan and cover with plastic wrap. Place in a warm spot and leave to rise for 30 minutes. The cinnamon roll should expand to the edges of the pan during this time. </step>
    <step num="14">Bake for 45 minutes. Cover the cinnamon roll with foil to prevent the outside from burning, and bake for an additional 35 minutes. </step>
    <step num="15">While the cinnamon roll is baking, prepare the frosting. </step>
    <step num="16">In a medium-size mixing bowl, whisk together cream cheese, butter, vanilla, whole milk, and powdered sugar, until smooth. </step>
    <step num="17">Remove the cinnamon roll from the oven and let cool in the pan for at least 20 minutes. Once cool, remove from pan and drizzle frosting over the roll before serving. </step>
    <step num="18">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Generously butter a 9-inch (23cm) cast iron or cake pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a large bowl, whisk together warm milk, melted butter, and granulated sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">The mixture should be just warm, registering between 100-110˚F (40˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">If hotter, allow to cool slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Sprinkle the yeast evenly over the warm mixture and let sit for 1 minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add 4 cups (500 grams) of all-purpose flour to the milk mixture and mix with a wooden spoon until just combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cover the bowl with a towel or plastic wrap and set in a warm place to rise for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Preheat oven to 325˚F (160˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">After 1 hour, the dough should have nearly doubled in size. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove the towel and add an additional ¾ cup (95 grams) of flour, the baking powder, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Stir well, then turn out onto a well-floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Knead the dough lightly, adding additional flour as necessary, until the dough just loses its stickiness and does not stick to the surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Roll the dough out into a large rectangle, about ½-inch (1.5 cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Fix corners to make sure they are sharp and even. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">In a small bowl combine the filling ingredients and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Spread the filling mixture evenly over the rolled out dough, spreading right to the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Using a pizza cutter, make 3 horizontal cuts to divide the dough into four long, evenly sized strips. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Starting from the bottom, roll the first strip up right to left. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Take the first roll and place it back on top of the next strip, starting again on the right side and rolling up right to left, building on the first. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Continue with the remaining two strips until you have a giant cinnamon roll. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Place the giant cinnamon roll in the prepared cast iron or cake pan and cover with plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Place in a warm spot and leave to rise for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">The cinnamon roll should expand to the edges of the pan during this time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Bake for 45 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Cover the cinnamon roll with foil to prevent the outside from burning, and bake for an additional 35 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">While the cinnamon roll is baking, prepare the frosting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">In a medium-size mixing bowl, whisk together cream cheese, butter, vanilla, whole milk, and powdered sugar, until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Remove the cinnamon roll from the oven and let cool in the pan for at least 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Once cool, remove from pan and drizzle frosting over the roll before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>