<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>One Pot Vegan Eggplant Lasagna Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/one-pot-vegan-eggplant-lasagna</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; raw cashews ; (260 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; extra virgin olive oil ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; fresh basil leaf, lightly packed ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; nutritional yeast ; (10 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; onion powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ teaspoon ; freshly ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 clove ; garlic, roughtly chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">nonstick cooking spray </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¼ cup ; extra virgin olive oil, plus 2 tablespoons, divided ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 ½ lb ; eggplant, cubed ; (1.1 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ; small carrot, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 stalk ; celery, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 ; small yellow onion, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">freshly ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">½ cup ; dry white wine ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">2 tablespoons ; tomato paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">3 cups ; vegetable stock ; (720 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">28 oz ; crushed tomato, 1 can ; (795 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">8 oz ; vegan "no-boil" lasagna noodle, broken in half ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">2 cups ; shredded vegan mozzarella cheese ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="25">fresh flat-leaf parsley, finely chopped, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="26">garlic bread, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="5">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/112522/hls24_1539884568.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/112522/landscape_720/1539884568</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the pesto cashew cream cubes: In a blender, combine the cashews, olive oil, basil, nutritional yeast, lemon juice, salt, onion powder, garlic powder, pepper, and garlic. Blend until smooth. </step>
    <step num="1">Grease an ice cube tray with nonstick spray. Spoon the pesto into the cups in the tray. Cover with plastic wrap and freeze until the cubes are firm, at least 4 hours or up to 3 days. </step>
    <step num="2">Make the lasagna: Heat a large pot over medium-high heat. Add ¼ cup (60 ml) of olive oil to the pot and swirl to evenly coat. Add the eggplant and cook, stirring occasionally, until very soft and caramelized, 30 minutes. Transfer the eggplant to a bowl and set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the remaining 2 tablespoons of olive oil to the pot. Then, add the carrot, celery, and onion, and cook, stirring, until softened and starting to caramelize, 10 minutes. Season with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the wine and cook, stirring, until completely evaporated, about 4 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the tomato paste and garlic, and cook, stirring, until lightly caramelized, about 2 minutes over medium heat. </step>
    <step num="6">Stir in the reserved eggplant, vegetable stock, and crushed tomatoes and stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="7">Remove the pesto cubes from the ice cube tray, and immediately distribute the frozen pesto cubes throughout the eggplant sauce. </step>
    <step num="8">Using your fingers or a pair of tongs, insert the noodle pieces vertically in the sauce around the pot. Cover the pot. </step>
    <step num="9">Reduce the heat to medium-low, and cook for 18 minutes, then uncover the pot and use a spatula to push down the exposed noodles so they are covered in sauce. Cover and cook for 18 minutes more, until the noodles are tender. </step>
    <step num="10">Uncover and sprinkle the mozzarella over the top of the lasagna. Cover again and cook until the cheese is melted, about 5 minutes. Remove the pot from the heat. </step>
    <step num="11">Sprinkle the lasagna with parsley and serve with garlic bread alongside. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the pesto cashew cream cubes: In a blender, combine the cashews, olive oil, basil, nutritional yeast, lemon juice, salt, onion powder, garlic powder, pepper, and garlic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Blend until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Grease an ice cube tray with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Spoon the pesto into the cups in the tray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Cover with plastic wrap and freeze until the cubes are firm, at least 4 hours or up to 3 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Make the lasagna: Heat a large pot over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add ¼ cup (60 ml) of olive oil to the pot and swirl to evenly coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the eggplant and cook, stirring occasionally, until very soft and caramelized, 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Transfer the eggplant to a bowl and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the remaining 2 tablespoons of olive oil to the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Then, add the carrot, celery, and onion, and cook, stirring, until softened and starting to caramelize, 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the wine and cook, stirring, until completely evaporated, about 4 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the tomato paste and garlic, and cook, stirring, until lightly caramelized, about 2 minutes over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Stir in the reserved eggplant, vegetable stock, and crushed tomatoes and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove the pesto cubes from the ice cube tray, and immediately distribute the frozen pesto cubes throughout the eggplant sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Using your fingers or a pair of tongs, insert the noodle pieces vertically in the sauce around the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cover the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Reduce the heat to medium-low, and cook for 18 minutes, then uncover the pot and use a spatula to push down the exposed noodles so they are covered in sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Cover and cook for 18 minutes more, until the noodles are tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Uncover and sprinkle the mozzarella over the top of the lasagna. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Cover again and cook until the cheese is melted, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Remove the pot from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Sprinkle the lasagna with parsley and serve with garlic bread alongside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>