<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>The Ultimate Grilled Cheese And Tomato Soup Bowl Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/the-ultimate-grilled-cheese-and-tomato-soup-bowl</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ; large yellow onion, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">15 oz ; crushed tomato, 1 can ; (395 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 cups ; chicken broth ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; heavy cream ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 teaspoons ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">11 slices ; white bread </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 tablespoons ; butter, melted, plus more for greasing bowl </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ; large egg, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">7 slices ; cheddar cheese </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 tablespoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 teaspoons ; dried oregano </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">½ teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Lunch</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/88806/hls24_1523392534.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/88806/landscape_720/1523392534</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the tomato soup: melt the butter in a large pot over medium-high heat. Add the onion and stir for 6-8 minutes, until the onions just start to brown. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the garlic and stir for another minute. Stir in the crushed tomatoes, chicken broth, heavy cream, salt, and pepper. </step>
    <step num="2">Bring the soup to a boil, then reduce the heat to low, cover, and simmer for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove the soup from heat and transfer to a blender. Remove vent so that steam can escape. Blend for 2 minutes, until the soup is smooth and thick. Alternatively, leave the soup in the pot and use an immersion blender. </step>
    <step num="4">Make the grilled cheese bowl: cut the crusts off the bread and set aside in a medium bowl. </step>
    <step num="5">Arrange the bread slices into 3 lines: a line of 5, a line of 4, and a line of 2. </step>
    <step num="6">In a small bowl, combine the melted butter and garlic and use a brush to spread the mixture over each piece of bread. </step>
    <step num="7">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). </step>
    <step num="8">Brush the bottom of each slice in egg wash and then dab the bottom of each piece of bread in the line of 5 and the line of 4. Dab all four sides of the bread in the group of 2. Overlap the edges of the 5 pieces of bread, then press the edges together to adhere. Repeat with the line of 4. </step>
    <step num="9">In a greased medium oven-safe bowl, place one of the single slices of bread. Then, take the line of 5 slices and make it into a circle on the inside of the bowl. Press down the edges to adhere to the piece of bread at the bottom of the bowl. </step>
    <step num="10">Cover the bread with 6 slices of cheese. Lay the remaining single slice of bread over the cheese, then make a circle with the line of 4 slices of bread, pressing to seal the edges and adhere to the bread below. Lay the remaining slice of cheese on the bottom. </step>
    <step num="11">Using a small bowl, press down on the bread bowl to compress slightly. </step>
    <step num="12">Bake for 15 minutes, until the bread is golden brown. </step>
    <step num="13">Make the crouton fries: Add the olive oil, oregano, pepper, and salt to the bowl with the crusts. Toss until thoroughly coated. Transfer the crusts to a large baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="14">Bake for 5 minutes, until the crusts are golden brown. </step>
    <step num="15">Remove the bowl and crouton fries from oven. Use tongs to move the bread bowl from the bowl to a serving dish. Fill with tomato soup. </step>
    <step num="16">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the tomato soup: melt the butter in a large pot over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the onion and stir for 6-8 minutes, until the onions just start to brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the garlic and stir for another minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Stir in the crushed tomatoes, chicken broth, heavy cream, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Bring the soup to a boil, then reduce the heat to low, cover, and simmer for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Remove the soup from heat and transfer to a blender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove vent so that steam can escape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Blend for 2 minutes, until the soup is smooth and thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Alternatively, leave the soup in the pot and use an immersion blender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Make the grilled cheese bowl: cut the crusts off the bread and set aside in a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Arrange the bread slices into 3 lines: a line of 5, a line of 4, and a line of 2. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">In a small bowl, combine the melted butter and garlic and use a brush to spread the mixture over each piece of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Brush the bottom of each slice in egg wash and then dab the bottom of each piece of bread in the line of 5 and the line of 4. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Dab all four sides of the bread in the group of 2. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Overlap the edges of the 5 pieces of bread, then press the edges together to adhere. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Repeat with the line of 4. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">In a greased medium oven-safe bowl, place one of the single slices of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Then, take the line of 5 slices and make it into a circle on the inside of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Press down the edges to adhere to the piece of bread at the bottom of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Cover the bread with 6 slices of cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Lay the remaining single slice of bread over the cheese, then make a circle with the line of 4 slices of bread, pressing to seal the edges and adhere to the bread below. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Lay the remaining slice of cheese on the bottom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Using a small bowl, press down on the bread bowl to compress slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Bake for 15 minutes, until the bread is golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Make the crouton fries: Add the olive oil, oregano, pepper, and salt to the bowl with the crusts. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Toss until thoroughly coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Transfer the crusts to a large baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Bake for 5 minutes, until the crusts are golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Remove the bowl and crouton fries from oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Use tongs to move the bread bowl from the bowl to a serving dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Fill with tomato soup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>