<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Honey-Garlic Shrimp Chow Mein Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/honey-garlic-shrimp-chow-mein</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/chow-mein-4-ways</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 tablespoon ; ginger, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 tablespoons ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; soy sauce ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; honey ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 lb ; jumbo shrimp, peeled and deveined ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 tablespoons ; cooking oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 package ; chow mein noodle, hong kong style pan fried noodles, par cooked according to package instructions </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; white onion, sliced ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 cup ; broccoli floret ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; carrot, julienned ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ cup ; cabbage ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">scallion, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Chinese</category>
    <category num="1">Seafood</category>
    <category num="2">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Date Night</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97163/hls24_1528149276.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97163/landscape_720/1528149276</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>-1</start_time>
    <end_time>-1</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a 2-cup (480ml) liquid measuring cup, combine the ginger, garlic, soy sauce, and honey. </step>
    <step num="1">Pour about ⅓ cup (80 ml) of sauce over the shrimp in a medium bowl and toss to coat. Reserve the rest of the sauce. Cover the shrimp with plastic wrap and marinate in the refrigerator for 30 minutes to 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="2">In a wok or deep skillet over medium-high heat, heat 2 tablespoons of cooking oil, then add the par-cooked noodles. Cook for 1-2 minutes, allowing the noodles to crisp, then flip and cook for another 1-2 minutes. Transfer to a plate and set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">In the same wok, heat 1 tablespoon of cooking oil, then add the onion, broccoli, carrots, and ⅓ cup (80 ml) of the sauce. Cook for 2-3 minutes, or until the onions are translucent. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the cabbage and season with salt and pepper to taste. Cook for 2 minutes more, or until the vegetables have softened. </step>
    <step num="5">Push the vegetables to one side of the wok and add the remaining cooking oil to the empty side, followed by the marinated shrimp. Cook for 1 minute without disturbing, then flip the shrimp over and cook for another 2 minutes, until the shrimp are pink and their tails have curled in. </step>
    <step num="6">Mix the cooked shrimp with the vegetables and add the crispy chow mein noodles and the remaining sauce. Toss gently and cook for another 2-3 minutes, or until everything is well combined. Garnish with sliced scallions. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a 2-cup (480ml) liquid measuring cup, combine the ginger, garlic, soy sauce, and honey. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pour about ⅓ cup (80 ml) of sauce over the shrimp in a medium bowl and toss to coat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Reserve the rest of the sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cover the shrimp with plastic wrap and marinate in the refrigerator for 30 minutes to 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a wok or deep skillet over medium-high heat, heat 2 tablespoons of cooking oil, then add the par-cooked noodles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cook for 1-2 minutes, allowing the noodles to crisp, then flip and cook for another 1-2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Transfer to a plate and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In the same wok, heat 1 tablespoon of cooking oil, then add the onion, broccoli, carrots, and ⅓ cup (80 ml) of the sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Cook for 2-3 minutes, or until the onions are translucent. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the cabbage and season with salt and pepper to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Cook for 2 minutes more, or until the vegetables have softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Push the vegetables to one side of the wok and add the remaining cooking oil to the empty side, followed by the marinated shrimp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cook for 1 minute without disturbing, then flip the shrimp over and cook for another 2 minutes, until the shrimp are pink and their tails have curled in. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Mix the cooked shrimp with the vegetables and add the crispy chow mein noodles and the remaining sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Toss gently and cook for another 2-3 minutes, or until everything is well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Garnish with sliced scallions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
  <duration_human>
    <start_time>02015</start_time>
    <end_time>03612</end_time>
  </duration_human>
</recipe>