<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Braised Chicken Thighs With Red Rice As Made By Hugh Acheson Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/braised-chicken-thighs-with-red-rice-as-made-by-hugh-acheson</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">5 oz ; bone-in, skin-on chicken thighs ; (140 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ teaspoon ; sea salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ teaspoon ; freshly ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; canola oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; yellow onion, minced ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; fresh tomato, diced ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; poblano chile, seeded and minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 cloves ; garlic, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ teaspoon ; hot smoked paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; red wine vinegar ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; low sodium chicken stock ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ cup ; bacon, diced ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ ; medium red onion, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 cup ; red bell pepper, seeded and diced ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 stalk ; celery, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">½ ; jalapeño, red, seeded and minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 cup ; basmati rice ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">1 cup ; chopped tomato, peeled and seeded, juices reserved ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">3 ; bay leaves, dried </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">sea salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">1 ½ cups ; low sodium chicken broth ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dinner</category>
    <category num="1">Date Night</category>
    <category num="2">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/136268/hls24_1560798139.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/136268/landscape_720/1560798139</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Season the chicken thighs on both sides with the salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="1">Heat the oil in a wide, heavy-bottomed pot with a lid over medium heat. When the oil is hot, add the chicken thighs, skin-side down and let cook without disturbing for 10 minutes. This will allow the skin to caramelize and develop a ton of flavor in the process. Turn the thighs over, cook for 1 minute more, then transfer to a plate. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the onion, tomatoes, poblano, garlic, and paprika to the pan. Cook for 5 minutes, until the vegetables are softened. </step>
    <step num="3">Carefully add the vinegar and stir to loosen any browned bits stuck to the bottom of the pot. Cook until the vinegar is reduced by half, 2-4 minutes, then pour in the stock. </step>
    <step num="4">Return the chicken to the pan, skin-side up. Cover and reduce the heat to low. Cook for 20 minutes, then remove lid and continue cooking until the internal temperature of the chicken thighs reaches 165˚F (75˚C). </step>
    <step num="5">Meanwhile, make the red rice: In a large pan, cook the slab bacon over medium heat until the fat renders and it begins to crisp, 5-8 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the onion, bell pepper, celery, and jalapeño and cook until softened, about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the rice and stir until toasted, about 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Stir in the tomatoes, ½ cup (100 G) of the reserved tomato juice, bay leaves, and season with salt. 9. Add the chicken broth. Bring to a boil, then cover, reduce the heat to low, and simmer for 20 minutes, until the liquid is absorbed and the rice is tender. </step>
    <step num="9">Serve the chicken over the rice with some of the braising jus and vegetables ladled over. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Season the chicken thighs on both sides with the salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Heat the oil in a wide, heavy-bottomed pot with a lid over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">When the oil is hot, add the chicken thighs, skin-side down and let cook without disturbing for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">This will allow the skin to caramelize and develop a ton of flavor in the process. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Turn the thighs over, cook for 1 minute more, then transfer to a plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the onion, tomatoes, poblano, garlic, and paprika to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cook for 5 minutes, until the vegetables are softened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Carefully add the vinegar and stir to loosen any browned bits stuck to the bottom of the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Cook until the vinegar is reduced by half, 2-4 minutes, then pour in the stock. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Return the chicken to the pan, skin-side up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Cover and reduce the heat to low. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cook for 20 minutes, then remove lid and continue cooking until the internal temperature of the chicken thighs reaches 165˚F (75˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Meanwhile, make the red rice: In a large pan, cook the slab bacon over medium heat until the fat renders and it begins to crisp, 5-8 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the onion, bell pepper, celery, and jalapeño and cook until softened, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add the rice and stir until toasted, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Stir in the tomatoes, ½ cup (100 G) of the reserved tomato juice, bay leaves, and season with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">9. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Add the chicken broth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Bring to a boil, then cover, reduce the heat to low, and simmer for 20 minutes, until the liquid is absorbed and the rice is tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Serve the chicken over the rice with some of the braising jus and vegetables ladled over. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>