<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>3-ingredient Cookie Butter Cakes Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/3-ingredient-cookie-butter-cakes</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">14.1 oz ; cookie butter, 2 jars, we used crunchy cookie butter ; (400 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">5 ; large eggs </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32070/low_1495125308.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32070/mp4_720x1280/1495125308</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (175˚C) </step>
    <step num="1">Empty half of Cookie Butter into a microwave safe bowl. Microwave for 50 seconds, stirring halfway. Set aside to cool while you prepare the egg mixture. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large mixing bowl add sugar and 5 eggs. Beat with an electric mixer on high for 6 to 8 minutes, until tripled in size. </step>
    <step num="3">With a rubber spoon, fold some of the egg mixture into the slightly cooled cookie butter. Gradually fold the cookie butter mixture back into the remaining egg mixture (this will help prevent the eggs from deflating) until fully incorporated. </step>
    <step num="4">Pour batter into a greased 12-cup muffin tin. </step>
    <step num="5">Bake in preheated oven for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove from oven, loosen the edges of each cake with a knife - invert the pan onto a wire rack. Melt additional cookie butter to drizzle on top. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (175˚C) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Empty half of Cookie Butter into a microwave safe bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Microwave for 50 seconds, stirring halfway. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set aside to cool while you prepare the egg mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a large mixing bowl add sugar and 5 eggs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Beat with an electric mixer on high for 6 to 8 minutes, until tripled in size. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">With a rubber spoon, fold some of the egg mixture into the slightly cooled cookie butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Gradually fold the cookie butter mixture back into the remaining egg mixture (this will help prevent the eggs from deflating) until fully incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Pour batter into a greased 12-cup muffin tin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Bake in preheated oven for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Remove from oven, loosen the edges of each cake with a knife - invert the pan onto a wire rack. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Melt additional cookie butter to drizzle on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>