<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Giant Chocolate Soufflé Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/giant-chocolate-souffle</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, softened, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¾ cup ; granulated sugar, divided ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ½ cups ; whole milk ; (600 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">12 oz ; semisweet chocolate, chopped ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">6 ; large eggs, separated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; all-purpose flour ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ teaspoon ; cream of tartar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">powdered sugar, for topping </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">whipped cream, for topping </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ½ qt ; ramekins ; (1 ½ L) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">French</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Date Night</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/107630/hls24_1535742487.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/107630/landscape_720/1535742487</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C) and position a rack at the bottom of the oven, removing the other rack. </step>
    <step num="1">Grease the ramekin with the softened butter and pour in ¼ cup (50 g) of sugar. Tilt the ramekin to coat with sugar evenly, then pour out the excess and set the ramekin aside. </step>
    <step num="2">In a medium saucepan, scald the milk over medium heat. Just before boiling, remove the milk from the heat and whisk in the chopped chocolate until melted. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">In a large bowl, whisk together the egg yolks, ¼ cup (50 g) of sugar, the flour, salt, and vanilla, until smooth. </step>
    <step num="4">Add ½ cup (120 ml) of the chocolate milk mixture to the yolks and whisk until combined. This will temper the egg yolks so they don’t curdle when added to the rest of the chocolate mixture. </step>
    <step num="5">Return the pan with the remaining chocolate milk mixture back to the stove over medium heat and pour in the chocolate egg yolk mixture. Whisk constantly until thick. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove the chocolate pastry cream from the heat and transfer to a large bowl. Cover with plastic wrap, making sure the plastic touches the surface to prevent a skin from forming. Chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">In a large bowl, combine the egg whites and cream of tartar. With an electric hand mixer, whip the egg whites until they turn opaque and leave trails. Gradually add the remaining ¼ cup (50 g) of sugar and beat until stiff peaks form. </step>
    <step num="8">Spoon about 1 cup (240 ml) of the whites into the chocolate pastry cream. Fold until no white streaks remain. Gently fold in the rest of the whites in 2 additions, being careful not to deflate the whites. Once no white streaks are visible, transfer the batter to the prepared ramekin and smooth out the top. </step>
    <step num="9">Run your thumb between the outside edge of the dish and the batter to create a border. </step>
    <step num="10">Reduce the oven temperature to 375°F (190°C), then immediately place the soufflé in the oven and bake for 45-50 minutes, until the soufflé has risen over the edge of the dish. Do not open the oven while baking. </step>
    <step num="11">Dust the soufflé with powdered sugar and top with whipped cream. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C) and position a rack at the bottom of the oven, removing the other rack. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Grease the ramekin with the softened butter and pour in ¼ cup (50 g) of sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Tilt the ramekin to coat with sugar evenly, then pour out the excess and set the ramekin aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a medium saucepan, scald the milk over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Just before boiling, remove the milk from the heat and whisk in the chopped chocolate until melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a large bowl, whisk together the egg yolks, ¼ cup (50 g) of sugar, the flour, salt, and vanilla, until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add ½ cup (120 ml) of the chocolate milk mixture to the yolks and whisk until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">This will temper the egg yolks so they don’t curdle when added to the rest of the chocolate mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Return the pan with the remaining chocolate milk mixture back to the stove over medium heat and pour in the chocolate egg yolk mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Whisk constantly until thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove the chocolate pastry cream from the heat and transfer to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cover with plastic wrap, making sure the plastic touches the surface to prevent a skin from forming. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">In a large bowl, combine the egg whites and cream of tartar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">With an electric hand mixer, whip the egg whites until they turn opaque and leave trails. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Gradually add the remaining ¼ cup (50 g) of sugar and beat until stiff peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Spoon about 1 cup (240 ml) of the whites into the chocolate pastry cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Fold until no white streaks remain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Gently fold in the rest of the whites in 2 additions, being careful not to deflate the whites. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Once no white streaks are visible, transfer the batter to the prepared ramekin and smooth out the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Run your thumb between the outside edge of the dish and the batter to create a border. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Reduce the oven temperature to 375°F (190°C), then immediately place the soufflé in the oven and bake for 45-50 minutes, until the soufflé has risen over the edge of the dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Do not open the oven while baking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Dust the soufflé with powdered sugar and top with whipped cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>