<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Lasagna Dome Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/lasagna-dome</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 tablespoons ; olive oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ ; medium yellow onion, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">4 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 lb ; ground beef ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">15 oz ; tomato sauce ; (425 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 oz ; tomato paste ; (85 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">15 oz ; ricotta cheese ; (425 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; fresh basil, chopped ; (10 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; large egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ cup ; parmesan cheese ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">30 ; lasagna noodles, boiled until al dente </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 cups ; shredded mozzarella cheese ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">2 tablespoons ; all-purpose flour </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 ½ cups ; milk, hot ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">freshly ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">¼ cup ; shredded parmesan cheese ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">fresh basil, chopped, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">shredded parmesan cheese, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Fusion</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97070/hls24_1528135191.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97070/landscape_720/1528135191</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Heat 2 tablespoons of olive oil in a large pot over high heat. Add the onion and garlic. Cook until starting to brown, stirring occasionally, 3-4 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the beef, salt, and pepper. Cook until all of the moisture has evaporated and the meat is starting to brown on the edges, breaking the meat up as you stir, 10-12 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the tomato sauce and tomato paste, then reduce the heat to medium and bring the sauce to a simmer. Cook it down until the mixture becomes thick, about 15 minutes. Remove the pot from the heat and set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">In a small bowl, combine the ricotta, basil, egg, and Parmesan. Stir until smooth. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">Grease a large oven-safe metal bowl with the remaining tablespoon of olive oil, then lay about 25 lasagna noodles along the sides and bottom of the bowl, fanning them out in an overlapping pattern. The ends of the noodles should hang over the sides of the bowl. </step>
    <step num="6">Slice the remaining lasagna noodles in half crosswise. These will serve as the layers between the meat and the cheese mixtures. </step>
    <step num="7">Sprinkle half of the mozzarella into the bottom of the bowl on top of the noodles. This will help bind the noodles together when cooked. Spread half of the meat mixture evenly over the mozzarella, then lay half of the cut noodles over the sauce. </step>
    <step num="8">Spread all of the ricotta mixture over the noodles, then layer with the rest of the noodles, then the rest of the mozzarella, and the rest of the meat sauce. </step>
    <step num="9">Fold the edges of the lasagna noodles hanging over the sides of the bowl back towards the center, creating another overlapping pattern. </step>
    <step num="10">Cover with foil and bake for about 45 minutes, until cooked through. </step>
    <step num="11">Meanwhile, make the béchamel: In a saucepan over medium heat, melt the butter. Add the flour and cook, whisking continuously, for about 2 minutes until a paste forms. </step>
    <step num="12">Add the hot milk and continue to whisk as the sauce thickens and comes to a boil. Season with salt and pepper and add the Parmesan. Reduce the heat to low, and cook, still whisking, for 2-3 minutes more. </step>
    <step num="13">Invert the lasagna dome onto a cutting board. </step>
    <step num="14">Pour the béchamel sauce over the dome and top with basil. </step>
    <step num="15">Slice the dome, then top with more Parmesan and basil, if desired. </step>
    <step num="16">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Heat 2 tablespoons of olive oil in a large pot over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the onion and garlic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cook until starting to brown, stirring occasionally, 3-4 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the beef, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cook until all of the moisture has evaporated and the meat is starting to brown on the edges, breaking the meat up as you stir, 10-12 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the tomato sauce and tomato paste, then reduce the heat to medium and bring the sauce to a simmer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cook it down until the mixture becomes thick, about 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Remove the pot from the heat and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">In a small bowl, combine the ricotta, basil, egg, and Parmesan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Stir until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Grease a large oven-safe metal bowl with the remaining tablespoon of olive oil, then lay about 25 lasagna noodles along the sides and bottom of the bowl, fanning them out in an overlapping pattern. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">The ends of the noodles should hang over the sides of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Slice the remaining lasagna noodles in half crosswise. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">These will serve as the layers between the meat and the cheese mixtures. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Sprinkle half of the mozzarella into the bottom of the bowl on top of the noodles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">This will help bind the noodles together when cooked. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Spread half of the meat mixture evenly over the mozzarella, then lay half of the cut noodles over the sauce </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Spread all of the ricotta mixture over the noodles, then layer with the rest of the noodles, then the rest of the mozzarella, and the rest of the meat sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Fold the edges of the lasagna noodles hanging over the sides of the bowl back towards the center, creating another overlapping pattern. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Cover with foil and bake for about 45 minutes, until cooked through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Meanwhile, make the béchamel: In a saucepan over medium heat, melt the butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Add the flour and cook, whisking continuously, for about 2 minutes until a paste forms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Add the hot milk and continue to whisk as the sauce thickens and comes to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Season with salt and pepper and add the Parmesan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Reduce the heat to low, and cook, still whisking, for 2-3 minutes more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Invert the lasagna dome onto a cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Pour the béchamel sauce over the dome and top with basil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Slice the dome, then top with more Parmesan and basil, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>