<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Blue Drip 'Boxed' Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/blue-drip-boxed-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 boxes ; white cake mix, prepared </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; heavy cream ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ½ cups ; white chocolate chunk ; (255 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">blue food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">vanilla frosting </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/51931/low_1505247740.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/51931/mp4_720x1280/1505247740</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Prepare 2 boxes of white cake mix according to instructions on box. </step>
    <step num="1">Separate batter evenly into 3 bowls. Add 1 drop of blue coloring to one bowl, stir until color is mixed thoroughly. Repeat with the next 2 bowls adding more food coloring until the desired colors are reached. </step>
    <step num="2">Grease three 6-inch (15 cm) cake pans and line with parchment paper. Pour each colored batter into a separate pan. Bake according to box instructions. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove cake from pans and let cool. Use a serrated knife cut the round top off of the cake so the cakes are even and flat. </step>
    <step num="4">Place the first cake on a cake stand and add a thick layer of frosting. Place the second cake on top, and add more frosting. Place the third cake on top and frost the cake until completely covered. </step>
    <step num="5">Frost the entire cake until smooth. Chill in the refrigerator for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="6">For the ganache, heat the heavy cream in the microwave until bubbling, about 45 seconds. Add the white chocolate and stir until smooth. You may need to microwave the ganache for 10-20 seconds to melt any lumps. </step>
    <step num="7">Separate the ganache into 3 bowls. Add one drop of food coloring to one bowl. Stir until the color is evenly mixed. Repeat the the next 2 bowls adding more food coloring until the desired color is reached. </step>
    <step num="8">Spoon ganache in circles one on top of the other, making sure the ganache is not too thick. Continue until the ganache starts dripping over the edge. </step>
    <step num="9">Slice and serve. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Prepare 2 boxes of white cake mix according to instructions on box. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Separate batter evenly into 3 bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add 1 drop of blue coloring to one bowl, stir until color is mixed thoroughly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Repeat with the next 2 bowls adding more food coloring until the desired colors are reached. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Grease three 6-inch (15 cm) cake pans and line with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour each colored batter into a separate pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Bake according to box instructions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove cake from pans and let cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Use a serrated knife cut the round top off of the cake so the cakes are even and flat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Place the first cake on a cake stand and add a thick layer of frosting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place the second cake on top, and add more frosting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place the third cake on top and frost the cake until completely covered. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Frost the entire cake until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Chill in the refrigerator for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">For the ganache, heat the heavy cream in the microwave until bubbling, about 45 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the white chocolate and stir until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">You may need to microwave the ganache for 10-20 seconds to melt any lumps. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Separate the ganache into 3 bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add one drop of food coloring to one bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Stir until the color is evenly mixed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Repeat the the next 2 bowls adding more food coloring until the desired color is reached. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Spoon ganache in circles one on top of the other, making sure the ganache is not too thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Continue until the ganache starts dripping over the edge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Slice and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>