<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Low-Carb Eggplant Lasagna Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/low-carb-eggplant-lasagna</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ; large eggplants </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 teaspoon ; sea salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">olive oil, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">5 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ teaspoon ; red pepper flakes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">28 oz ; crushed san marzano tomato, 2 can ; (795 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">6 leaves ; fresh basil, thinly sliced, plus more for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; large egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">15 oz ; ricotta cheese, 1 container ; (425 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 cups ; shredded mozzarella cheese, divided ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; grated parmesan cheese, divided ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 teaspoons ; italian seasoning </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Healthy</category>
    <category num="3">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="4">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="5">Dinner</category>
    <category num="6">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="7">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117321/hls24_1543518255.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117321/landscape_720/1543518255</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Cut off the ends of the eggplant, then slice lengthwise about ⅛-inch (3-mm) thick. </step>
    <step num="2">Sprinkle the eggplant slices with sea salt on both sides and let sit for 10 minutes to draw out moisture. Pat dry with paper towels to remove excess liquid. </step>
    <step num="3">Lightly grease a griddle pan with olive oil and heat over medium heat. Grill the eggplant slices for 2-3 minutes on each side, or until grill marks are visible. Remove from the pan and set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">In a medium saucepan, heat a drizzle of olive oil over medium-low heat, then add the garlic and red pepper flakes. Sauté for about 3 minutes, until the garlic is fragrant but not browned. Add the crushed tomatoes and 1 teaspoon of salt, stirring well to incorporate the garlic and red pepper. Simmer for 10 minutes, reducing the heat if the sauce begins to bubble too much. Add the basil and stir to combine. Remove from the heat and set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">In a medium bowl, beat the egg, then add the ricotta, 1½ cups (150 g) of mozzarella, ¾ cup (80 g) of Parmesan, and the Italian seasoning. Mix well to combine. </step>
    <step num="6">Assemble the lasagna. In a 9x13-inch (23x33-cm) baking dish, add enough sauce to cover the bottom of the dish and spread in an even layer. Add a layer of eggplant slices, covering the bottom of the dish completely. It’s okay if the eggplant slices overlap slightly. Add a layer of the ricotta mixture and spread in a thin, even layer. Repeat with the remaining ingredients, finishing with a layer of sauce. Sprinkle the remaining mozzarella and Parmesan on top. </step>
    <step num="7">Bake for 45 minutes, until cheese is fully melted. </step>
    <step num="8">Turn the broiler on high and broil for 5 minutes, or until the cheese on top is browned and bubbly. </step>
    <step num="9">Remove the lasagna from the oven and let rest for 15-20 minutes before serving to give the lasagna time to set. </step>
    <step num="10">Serve garnished with fresh basil. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cut off the ends of the eggplant, then slice lengthwise about ⅛-inch (3-mm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Sprinkle the eggplant slices with sea salt on both sides and let sit for 10 minutes to draw out moisture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Pat dry with paper towels to remove excess liquid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Lightly grease a griddle pan with olive oil and heat over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Grill the eggplant slices for 2-3 minutes on each side, or until grill marks are visible. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove from the pan and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a medium saucepan, heat a drizzle of olive oil over medium-low heat, then add the garlic and red pepper flakes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Sauté for about 3 minutes, until the garlic is fragrant but not browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the crushed tomatoes and 1 teaspoon of salt, stirring well to incorporate the garlic and red pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Simmer for 10 minutes, reducing the heat if the sauce begins to bubble too much. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the basil and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove from the heat and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">In a medium bowl, beat the egg, then add the ricotta, 1½ cups (150 g) of mozzarella, ¾ cup (80 g) of Parmesan, and the Italian seasoning. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Mix well to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Assemble the lasagna. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">In a 9x13-inch (23x33-cm) baking dish, add enough sauce to cover the bottom of the dish and spread in an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Add a layer of eggplant slices, covering the bottom of the dish completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">It’s okay if the eggplant slices overlap slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add a layer of the ricotta mixture and spread in a thin, even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Repeat with the remaining ingredients, finishing with a layer of sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Sprinkle the remaining mozzarella and Parmesan on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Bake for 45 minutes, until cheese is fully melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Turn the broiler on high and broil for 5 minutes, or until the cheese on top is browned and bubbly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Remove the lasagna from the oven and let rest for 15-20 minutes before serving to give the lasagna time to set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Serve garnished with fresh basil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>