<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>12 Layer Turkey Pesto Panini Bread Bowl Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/12-layer-turkey-pesto-panini-bread-bowl</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 cups ; fresh basil, washed and dried ; (160 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 cloves ; garlic </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">⅓ cup ; pine nuts ; (45 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; olive oil ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; grated parmesan cheese ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; bread, medium round loaf </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ tablespoon ; unsalted butter, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">7 slices ; mozzarella cheese </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">8 slices ; tomato </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">10 slices ; turkey </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">8 slices ; bacon, cooked and chopped </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="4">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/89303/hls24_1523574938.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/89303/landscape_720/1523574938</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Make the pesto: In a food processor, combine the basil, garlic, pine nuts, and olive oil. Blend for 30 seconds, or until thick and saucy. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the Parmesan and salt and blend for another 30 seconds, or until thoroughly combined. </step>
    <step num="3">Cut the top off the loaf of bread. Use a serrated knife to cut a circle in the center of the bread, then use a large spoon to scoop out the inside. Try to keep bread in one piece. </step>
    <step num="4">Use a rolling pin to roll the excess bread into one flat piece of bread. Spread melted butter on both side of the rolled out bread and bake for 10 minutes, or until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="5">Remove the toasted bread from the oven. </step>
    <step num="6">Assemble the sandwich: Place bread bowl in an oven-safe pan. Spread pesto on the bottom of the inside of the bread bowl, then layer in half of the mozzarella slices, 4 slices of tomatoes, 5 slices of turkey, and 4 chopped slices of bacon. </step>
    <step num="7">Top with the toasted bread and brush with pesto. Add the remaining bacon, turkey, tomato, and cheese. Finally, spread pesto on the bottom lid of the bread and over the cheese. Place the lid of bread on top of it and then press down with a heavy oven-safe pan. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake for 20 minutes, or until golden brown. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Make the pesto: In a food processor, combine the basil, garlic, pine nuts, and olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Blend for 30 seconds, or until thick and saucy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the Parmesan and salt and blend for another 30 seconds, or until thoroughly combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Cut the top off the loaf of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Use a serrated knife to cut a circle in the center of the bread, then use a large spoon to scoop out the inside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Try to keep bread in one piece. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Use a rolling pin to roll the excess bread into one flat piece of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Spread melted butter on both side of the rolled out bread and bake for 10 minutes, or until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove the toasted bread from the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Assemble the sandwich: Place bread bowl in an oven-safe pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Spread pesto on the bottom of the inside of the bread bowl, then layer in half of the mozzarella slices, 4 slices of tomatoes, 5 slices of turkey, and 4 chopped slices of bacon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Top with the toasted bread and brush with pesto. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the remaining bacon, turkey, tomato, and cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Finally, spread pesto on the bottom lid of the bread and over the cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Place the lid of bread on top of it and then press down with a heavy oven-safe pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Bake for 20 minutes, or until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>