<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Sweet Potato-Pecan Cinnamon Rolls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/sweet-potato-pecan-cinnamon-rolls</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; plain unsweetened soy milk, or other non-dairy milk ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; vegan butter ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; mashed sweet potato, from 1 baked medium sweet potato ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 cups ; unbleached all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (375 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; granulated sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 ¼ teaspoons ; active dry yeast, 1 packet </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ teaspoon ; grapeseed oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ cup ; brown sugar, or coconut sugar, or a mix of the two ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ tablespoon ; ground cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¾ cup ; toasted pecans ; (95 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">⅓ cup ; vegan butter ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ cup ; vegan cream cheese ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ cup ; confectioners sugar ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">¼ cup ; mashed sweet potato, from ¼ baked medium sweet potato ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">½ teaspoon ; pure vanilla extract </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Healthy</category>
    <category num="3">Vegan</category>
    <category num="4">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="5">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="6">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="7">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="8">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="9">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/94681/hls24_1526592767.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/94681/landscape_720/1526592767</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a small saucepan, warm the soy milk and vegan butter over medium heat until the butter has melted. Do not boil it. Remove from the heat and stir in the mashed sweet potato. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, mix together the flour, granulated sugar, salt, and yeast. Pour the liquid ingredients into the dry and use a wooden spoon to combine. Once it gets too difficult to stir, use your hands to combine the ingredients. </step>
    <step num="2">Flour a clean work surface and transfer the dough onto the prepared work space. Knead it until you’ve got a smooth dough ball. Lightly oil a large bowl. Place the dough ball in it, cover with plastic wrap or a kitchen towel, and let rise for 1 hour. The dough should double in size. </step>
    <step num="3">Make the filling: In a small bowl, combine the brown sugar and cinnamon and set aside. Chop the pecans into small pieces and set aside. In a small saucepan, melt the vegan butter and set aside. </step>
    <step num="4">Once the dough has doubled in size, preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </step>
    <step num="5">Press the air out of the dough, then transfer it back onto your floured work space. Roll the dough until it is about ¼-inch (6 mm) thick. You should end up with a roughly rectangular oval, about 12x16 inches (30x40 cm). </step>
    <step num="6">Brush the dough with the melted butter, sprinkle with the cinnamon-sugar mix, and then top with the chopped pecans. Fold the short side of the dough over and roll tightly until you have a log. </step>
    <step num="7">Carefully cut the log into twelve 1-inch (2 cm) slices. Grease a large skillet or a 10-inch (25 cm) round baking dish and place the rolls in it cut-side down. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake for 25 minutes, or until they've expanded and turned slightly golden on top. </step>
    <step num="9">Meanwhile, make the frosting: Place all the ingredients in a food processor or standing mixer with the whisk attachment on high and blend until creamy. </step>
    <step num="10">Remove the rolls from the oven and let cool for 5 to 10 minutes. Top with the sweet potato frosting and serve immediately. They will stay fresh for up to 2 days, but they’re best eaten the day you bake them. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a small saucepan, warm the soy milk and vegan butter over medium heat until the butter has melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Do not boil it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Remove from the heat and stir in the mashed sweet potato. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a large bowl, mix together the flour, granulated sugar, salt, and yeast. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour the liquid ingredients into the dry and use a wooden spoon to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Once it gets too difficult to stir, use your hands to combine the ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Flour a clean work surface and transfer the dough onto the prepared work space. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Knead it until you’ve got a smooth dough ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Lightly oil a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Place the dough ball in it, cover with plastic wrap or a kitchen towel, and let rise for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">The dough should double in size. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Make the filling: In a small bowl, combine the brown sugar and cinnamon and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Chop the pecans into small pieces and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">In a small saucepan, melt the vegan butter and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Once the dough has doubled in size, preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Press the air out of the dough, then transfer it back onto your floured work space. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Roll the dough until it is about ¼-inch (6 mm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">You should end up with a roughly rectangular oval, about 12x16 inches (30x40 cm). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Brush the dough with the melted butter, sprinkle with the cinnamon-sugar mix, and then top with the chopped pecans. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Fold the short side of the dough over and roll tightly until you have a log. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Carefully cut the log into twelve 1-inch (2 cm) slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Grease a large skillet or a 10-inch (25 cm) round baking dish and place the rolls in it cut-side down. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Bake for 25 minutes, or until they've expanded and turned slightly golden on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Meanwhile, make the frosting: Place all the ingredients in a food processor or standing mixer with the whisk attachment on high and blend until creamy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Remove the rolls from the oven and let cool for 5 to 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Top with the sweet potato frosting and serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">They will stay fresh for up to 2 days, but they’re best eaten the day you bake them. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>