<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Creamy Garlic Dijon Chicken Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/creamy-garlic-dijon-chicken</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ lb ; boneless, skinless chicken breast ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ tablespoons ; kosher salt, plus 1/2 teaspoon, plus more to taste, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3 tablespoons ; olive oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; all purpose flour </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ½ cups ; chicken broth </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 tablespoons ; French's Dijon Mustard </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ teaspoon ; freshly ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">3 tablespoons ; heavy cream </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 tablespoon ; fresh parsley, minced, for garnish, </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ ; lemon, zested </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ lb ; baby bella mushrooms, sliced ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ lb ; asparagus, woody ends removed, stalks cut into 2 in (5 cm) pieces ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">½ cup ; peas, fresh or frozen ; (75 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dinner</category>
    <category num="1">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/132667/hls24_1557803392.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/132667/landscape_720/1557803392</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Season the chicken evenly on both sides with 1½ tablespoons salt. Heat 1 tablespoon olive oil in a shallow pan over medium-high heat. Add the chicken and sear for 3-4 minutes on each side. Remove chicken from the pan (it will not be fully cooked) and set aside. Wipe out the pan if it looks charred. </step>
    <step num="1">Melt the butter in the pan over low heat. Add the garlic and cook, stirring, until fragrant, about 1 minute, then whisk in flour. Pour in the chicken broth, whisking, then add French’s Dijon Mustard, ½ teaspoon salt, and ¼ teaspoon pepper, and whisk until smooth. Simmer sauce for 1-2 minutes, then stir in the heavy cream. Return the sauce to a simmer, place the chicken in the sauce, and cover the pan with a lid. Simmer until chicken is fully cooked through, 5–10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Remove chicken from the pan. Stir the minced parsley and lemon zest into the sauce, then taste for seasoning. Slice the chicken. Remove the sauce from the heat. </step>
    <step num="3">Heat 1 tablespoon olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat. When the oil is hot, add the mushrooms and season with salt to taste. Saute mushrooms, stirring occasionally, until golden brown, 7–10 minutes. Remove mushrooms from the pan. </step>
    <step num="4">Heat remaining 1 tablespoon olive oil in the pan. Add asparagus and sauté, stirring occasionally, until tender, about 3 minutes. Season with salt to taste. Add the peas and cook 1 minute more. </step>
    <step num="5">Place the vegetables on a plate. Top with sliced chicken and drizzle with the dijon sauce. Garnish with chopped parsley. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Season the chicken evenly on both sides with 1½ tablespoons salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Heat 1 tablespoon olive oil in a shallow pan over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the chicken and sear for 3-4 minutes on each side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Remove chicken from the pan (it will not be fully cooked) and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Wipe out the pan if it looks charred. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Melt the butter in the pan over low heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the garlic and cook, stirring, until fragrant, about 1 minute, then whisk in flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Pour in the chicken broth, whisking, then add French’s Dijon Mustard, ½ teaspoon salt, and ¼ teaspoon pepper, and whisk until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Simmer sauce for 1-2 minutes, then stir in the heavy cream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Return the sauce to a simmer, place the chicken in the sauce, and cover the pan with a lid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Simmer until chicken is fully cooked through, 5–10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove chicken from the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Stir the minced parsley and lemon zest into the sauce, then taste for seasoning. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Slice the chicken. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove the sauce from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Heat 1 tablespoon olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">When the oil is hot, add the mushrooms and season with salt to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Saute mushrooms, stirring occasionally, until golden brown, 7–10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Remove mushrooms from the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Heat remaining 1 tablespoon olive oil in the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Add asparagus and sauté, stirring occasionally, until tender, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Season with salt to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add the peas and cook 1 minute more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Place the vegetables on a plate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Top with sliced chicken and drizzle with the dijon sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Garnish with chopped parsley. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>