<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Kenyan Beef Samosas Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/kenyan-beef-samosas</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ tablespoons ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 lb ; ground beef ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; medium red onion, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 clove ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ; jalapeño, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; ground coriander </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; cumin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">4 ; scallions, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; frozen peas, defrosted ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 tablespoons ; fresh cilantro, chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">3 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (375 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">¼ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 teaspoons ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 cup ; water, plus 2 tablespoons more ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">1 tablespoon ; flour, mixed with 1 tablespoon of water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">3 cups ; canola oil ; (720 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">lime wedge, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="2">Snacks</category>
    <category num="3">Game Day</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/81196/hls24_1519669906.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/81196/landscape_720/1519669906</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large pan over medium-high heat, heat the olive oil. Once hot, add the ground beef. Use a spatula to break apart the meat and cook for 3 minutes. Add onion and cook until beef is brown and onion is translucent, about 4 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the garlic, jalapeño, salt, pepper, coriander, cumin, and scallions to the meat. Cook for 2 minutes. Add the peas and cilantro, then cook for another 2 minutes. Remove the meat filling from the heat and let cool. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large bowl, combine the flour, salt, olive oil, and water. Use your hand or a spatula to mix together. Once the dough pulls away from sides of the bowl, transfer to a lightly floured surface and knead for 4 minutes or until the dough is smooth and soft. </step>
    <step num="3">Shape dough into a ball and brush with olive oil. Cover with plastic wrap and a warm damp tea towel. Let rest for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Remove tea towel and plastic wrap and roll the dough out into a 10-inch (25-cm) long log. Cut into 10 even sections. Take one section and roll it into a ball. Place the ball on a lightly floured surface and use a rolling pin to roll it out into a thin circle about 10 inches (25-cm) in diameter. Repeat with the remaining dough. Stack the dough circles as you roll them out, sprinkling a bit of flour between each one and keeping them covered with plastic wrap so they don't dry out. </step>
    <step num="5">In a greased large pan over high heat, place one of the circles of dough and cook for 10 seconds on each side. Repeat with remaining dough. </step>
    <step num="6">Cut one of the par-cooked dough circles into four quarters. Take one quarter and, with the round side closest to you, fold the bottom half to the right. Use the flour paste to seal the fold. Repeat with the left side, crossing over your previous fold to create a cone like pocket. Fill the pocket with meat filling, then fold the remaining tip of the dough towards you and seal with flour paste. Repeat with the remaining dough and filling. </step>
    <step num="7">In a large, deep pan, heat the canola oil to 350°F (180°C). Once the oil is at the correct temperature, carefully place 4-6 sambusas in the pan. Fry for about 5 minutes, flipping once, until light, golden brown. Remove from oil and drain on paper towels. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large pan over medium-high heat, heat the olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Once hot, add the ground beef. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Use a spatula to break apart the meat and cook for 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add onion and cook until beef is brown and onion is translucent, about 4 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the garlic, jalapeño, salt, pepper, coriander, cumin, and scallions to the meat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cook for 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the peas and cilantro, then cook for another 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Remove the meat filling from the heat and let cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">In a large bowl, combine the flour, salt, olive oil, and water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Use your hand or a spatula to mix together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Once the dough pulls away from sides of the bowl, transfer to a lightly floured surface and knead for 4 minutes or until the dough is smooth and soft. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Shape dough into a ball and brush with olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cover with plastic wrap and a warm damp tea towel. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Let rest for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove tea towel and plastic wrap and roll the dough out into a 10-inch (25-cm) long log. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cut into 10 even sections. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Take one section and roll it into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Place the ball on a lightly floured surface and use a rolling pin to roll it out into a thin circle about 10 inches (25-cm) in diameter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Repeat with the remaining dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Stack the dough circles as you roll them out, sprinkling a bit of flour between each one and keeping them covered with plastic wrap so they don't dry out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">In a greased large pan over high heat, place one of the circles of dough and cook for 10 seconds on each side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Repeat with remaining dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Cut one of the par-cooked dough circles into four quarters. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Take one quarter and, with the round side closest to you, fold the bottom half to the right. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Use the flour paste to seal the fold. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Repeat with the left side, crossing over your previous fold to create a cone like pocket. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Fill the pocket with meat filling, then fold the remaining tip of the dough towards you and seal with flour paste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Repeat with the remaining dough and filling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">In a large, deep pan, heat the canola oil to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Once the oil is at the correct temperature, carefully place 4-6 sambusas in the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Fry for about 5 minutes, flipping once, until light, golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Remove from oil and drain on paper towels. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>