<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>The Ultimate Dinner Rolls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/the-ultimate-dinner-rolls</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; whole milk ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; warm water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; unsalted butter, melted ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 ¼ teaspoons ; active dry yeast, 1 packet </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 cups ; all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (500 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ½ teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 ; large eggs, room temperature </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">neutral oil, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">sea salt, for sprinkling </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/115922/hls24_1542417061.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/115922/landscape_720/1542417061</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, combine the warm milk, warm water, melted butter, and sugar. </step>
    <step num="1">Sprinkle the yeast evenly over the wet ingredients, stir to combine, and let stand for 5 minutes, until foamy </step>
    <step num="2">In a large bowl, combine the flour and salt, and stir to combine. Beat 1 egg, then add to the bloomed yeast mixture. Pour the wet ingredients into the flour and use a knife to stir until the mixture just comes together and forms a dough. Turn the dough out onto a lightly floured surface and knead for 5-10 minutes, or until the dough becomes smooth. Add more flour as needed to keep the dough from sticking. To test if it’s done, tear off a small piece of dough and stretch into a thin layer. If the dough doesn’t rip, it’s ready. Or, press a finger into the dough to see if it bounces back. </step>
    <step num="3">Lightly grease a large glass bowl with oil. Add the dough, cover with plastic wrap, and let rest for 1 hour, or until doubled in size. </step>
    <step num="4">Punch down the dough, then turn out onto a floured surface. Knead for a few more minutes, just until the dough is smooth, about 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Divide the dough into 16 equal balls, roughly the size of tangerines. </step>
    <step num="6">Knead the balls, gathering the edges of the dough toward the center to make a taut, round ball with a smooth top. </step>
    <step num="7">Place the rolls on a parchment paper-lined baking sheet. Cover with plastic wrap and let rise for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </step>
    <step num="9">Beat the remaining egg in a small bowl. Uncover the rolls and brush with the egg wash. Lightly sprinkle the rolls with sea salt. </step>
    <step num="10">Bake for 25-30 minutes, or until the rolls have lightly browned and doubled in size. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, combine the warm milk, warm water, melted butter, and sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Sprinkle the yeast evenly over the wet ingredients, stir to combine, and let stand for 5 minutes, until foamy </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a large bowl, combine the flour and salt, and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Beat 1 egg, then add to the bloomed yeast mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour the wet ingredients into the flour and use a knife to stir until the mixture just comes together and forms a dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Turn the dough out onto a lightly floured surface and knead for 5-10 minutes, or until the dough becomes smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add more flour as needed to keep the dough from sticking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">To test if it’s done, tear off a small piece of dough and stretch into a thin layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">If the dough doesn’t rip, it’s ready. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Or, press a finger into the dough to see if it bounces back. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Lightly grease a large glass bowl with oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the dough, cover with plastic wrap, and let rest for 1 hour, or until doubled in size. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Punch down the dough, then turn out onto a floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Knead for a few more minutes, just until the dough is smooth, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Divide the dough into 16 equal balls, roughly the size of tangerines. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Knead the balls, gathering the edges of the dough toward the center to make a taut, round ball with a smooth top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Place the rolls on a parchment paper-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Cover with plastic wrap and let rise for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Beat the remaining egg in a small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Uncover the rolls and brush with the egg wash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Lightly sprinkle the rolls with sea salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Bake for 25-30 minutes, or until the rolls have lightly browned and doubled in size. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>