<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Healthy Veggie Curry With Garlic Naan Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/healthy-veggie-curry-with-garlic-naan</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; white rice, rinsed ; (400 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">4 cups ; water ; (960 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; coconut oil, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; vegetable oil, divided ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 ; small yellow onions, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; idaho potato, cubed ; (450 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 tablespoon ; tomato paste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 tablespoons ; fresh ginger, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">3 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ½ teaspoons ; garam masala </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 tablespoons ; curry powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 head ; cauliflower, cut into small florets </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">15 oz ; diced tomato, 1 can ; (425 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">15 oz ; chickpeas, 1 can, drained ; (425 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 ¼ cups ; water ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">¾ cup ; coconut milk ; (180 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 ¼ cups ; frozen peas ; (190 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">2 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">1 teaspoon ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">2 tablespoons ; ghee, melted, divided, plus more as needed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="24">4 tablespoons ; whole-fat yogurt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="25">2 tablespoons ; skim milk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="26">6 tablespoons ; water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="27">1 clove ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Indian</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Healthy</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Dinner</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113332/hls24_1540514302.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/113332/landscape_720/1540514302</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium pot, combine the rice, water, coconut oil, and salt. Bring to a boil, then cover and simmer over low heat for 15-20 minutes, until the water is absorbed. Once finished cooking, remove the rice from the heat and fluff. </step>
    <step num="1">Heat 3 tablespoons of vegetable oil in a large Dutch oven over medium-high heat until shimmering. Add the onions and potatoes and cook, stirring occasionally, until the onions are caramelized and potatoes are golden brown around the edges, about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Reduce the heat to medium. Add the remaining tablespoon of oil, the tomato paste, ginger, and garlic. Cook, stirring constantly, until fragrant, about 30 seconds. Add the garam masala and curry powder and cook, stirring constantly, about 1 minute longer. </step>
    <step num="3">Add cauliflower and cook, stirring constantly, until the spices coat the florets, about 2 minutes longer. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the tomatoes, chickpeas, water, and salt and stir to combine. Increase the heat to medium-high and bring the mixture to a boil. Reduce the heat to medium. Simmer, stirring occasionally, until the vegetables are tender, 10-15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Stir in the coconut milk and frozen peas. Cook until heated through, about 2 minutes longer. Remove from the heat. </step>
    <step num="6">Meanwhile, in a large bowl, stir together the flour, salt, baking powder, and sugar. Create a well in the middle of the dry ingredients and pour in 1 tablespoon of melted ghee, the yogurt, skim milk, and a bit of the water. Mix until combined, adding more water as needed until the dough comes together. </step>
    <step num="7">Transfer the dough to a lightly floured surface and knead until no longer sticky, then shape into a ball and divide into quarters. Roll out the dough portions to ¼ inch (6 mm) thick. </step>
    <step num="8">In a small bowl, combine the remaining tablespoon of melted ghee with the garlic. </step>
    <step num="9">Heat a bit of ghee in a medium nonstick pan over medium-high heat. Add a dough round and brush with the ghee and garlic mixture. Cook for 3-4 minutes, until the dough bubbles up and forms a nice brown crust, then flip and cook on the other side. Repeat with the remaining dough. </step>
    <step num="10">Serve the curry over the rice with the naan on the side. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium pot, combine the rice, water, coconut oil, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Bring to a boil, then cover and simmer over low heat for 15-20 minutes, until the water is absorbed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Once finished cooking, remove the rice from the heat and fluff. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Heat 3 tablespoons of vegetable oil in a large Dutch oven over medium-high heat until shimmering. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the onions and potatoes and cook, stirring occasionally, until the onions are caramelized and potatoes are golden brown around the edges, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Reduce the heat to medium. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the remaining tablespoon of oil, the tomato paste, ginger, and garlic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cook, stirring constantly, until fragrant, about 30 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the garam masala and curry powder and cook, stirring constantly, about 1 minute longer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add cauliflower and cook, stirring constantly, until the spices coat the florets, about 2 minutes longer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the tomatoes, chickpeas, water, and salt and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Increase the heat to medium-high and bring the mixture to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Reduce the heat to medium. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Simmer, stirring occasionally, until the vegetables are tender, 10-15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Stir in the coconut milk and frozen peas. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Cook until heated through, about 2 minutes longer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Remove from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Meanwhile, in a large bowl, stir together the flour, salt, baking powder, and sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Create a well in the middle of the dry ingredients and pour in 1 tablespoon of melted ghee, the yogurt, skim milk, and a bit of the water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Mix until combined, adding more water as needed until the dough comes together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Transfer the dough to a lightly floured surface and knead until no longer sticky, then shape into a ball and divide into quarters. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Roll out the dough portions to ¼ inch (6 mm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">In a small bowl, combine the remaining tablespoon of melted ghee with the garlic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Heat a bit of ghee in a medium nonstick pan over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Add a dough round and brush with the ghee and garlic mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Cook for 3-4 minutes, until the dough bubbles up and forms a nice brown crust, then flip and cook on the other side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Repeat with the remaining dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Serve the curry over the rice with the naan on the side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>