<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Hasselback Butternut Squash Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/hasselback-butternut-squash</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ; medium butternut squash </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; olive oil, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">⅓ cup ; shallot, finely chopped ; (35 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 tablespoons ; dijon mustard </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 tablespoons ; maple syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 tablespoons ; apple cider vinegar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ cup ; hazelnuts, blanched, toasted and roughly chopped ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">⅓ cup ; pomegranate seeds ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¼ cup ; chives, thinly sliced ; (10 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Vegan</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Dinner</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124201/hls24_1549315870.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124201/landscape_720/1549315870</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 425˚F (220˚C). Place a rack in the upper third of the oven. </step>
    <step num="1">Using a vegetable peeler, peel the skin and the white flesh directly beneath the skin from the butternut squash until the deep orange flesh is exposed. Leave the stem intact if possible. Cut the squash in half lengthwise. Remove the seeds and pulp. </step>
    <step num="2">Place the squash cut-side down on a rimmed baking sheet and pour in the water. Bake the squash for 20 minutes, until the flesh is softened but not fully cooked. This par-cooking will making the cutting much easier. </step>
    <step num="3">Cool the squash until it can be safely handled with your bare hands. Place one squash half cut-side down on a cutting board. Using a sharp knife, carefully cut very thin slits, about ⅛-inch (3 MM) wide, about ¾ of the way through the squash, being careful not to cut all the way through. Repeat with the second half. </step>
    <step num="4">Grease the baking sheet with olive oil and return the squash to the pan, cut-side down. Brush more olive oil all over the squash. Season with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="5">Bake for another 35 minutes, until the squash is fork tender and golden brown on top. </step>
    <step num="6">While the squash finishes baking, make the sauce. In a small saucepan over medium heat, warm 2 tablespoons of olive oil. Add the shallots, season with salt, and cook for 10-12 minutes, stirring, until they begin to caramelize. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the mustard, maple syrup, and apple cider vinegar and whisk to combine. Simmer for 3 minutes, until the sauce is slightly reduced and thickened. Season with salt and pepper to taste. Remove from the heat. </step>
    <step num="8">Drizzle the warm sauce over the butternut squash, making sure to get the sauce in between the slits as best you can. Top with the hazelnuts, pomegranate seeds, and chives. Serve warm. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 425˚F (220˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Place a rack in the upper third of the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Using a vegetable peeler, peel the skin and the white flesh directly beneath the skin from the butternut squash until the deep orange flesh is exposed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Leave the stem intact if possible. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Cut the squash in half lengthwise. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Remove the seeds and pulp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Place the squash cut-side down on a rimmed baking sheet and pour in the water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Bake the squash for 20 minutes, until the flesh is softened but not fully cooked. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">This par-cooking will making the cutting much easier. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Cool the squash until it can be safely handled with your bare hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place one squash half cut-side down on a cutting board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Using a sharp knife, carefully cut very thin slits, about ⅛-inch (3 MM) wide, about ¾ of the way through the squash, being careful not to cut all the way through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Repeat with the second half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Grease the baking sheet with olive oil and return the squash to the pan, cut-side down. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Brush more olive oil all over the squash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Bake for another 35 minutes, until the squash is fork tender and golden brown on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">While the squash finishes baking, make the sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">In a small saucepan over medium heat, warm 2 tablespoons of olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add the shallots, season with salt, and cook for 10-12 minutes, stirring, until they begin to caramelize. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Add the mustard, maple syrup, and apple cider vinegar and whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Simmer for 3 minutes, until the sauce is slightly reduced and thickened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Season with salt and pepper to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Remove from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Drizzle the warm sauce over the butternut squash, making sure to get the sauce in between the slits as best you can. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Top with the hazelnuts, pomegranate seeds, and chives. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Serve warm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>