<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Brownie Stuffed Strawberries Recipe</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/brownie-truffle-stuffed-strawberries</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">18 oz ; chocolate fudge brownie mix, 1 box, prepared according to package instructions ; (515 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">24 ; large strawberries </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">4 oz ; cream cheese ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ cup ; mini chocolate chips ; (85 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 cup ; high quality dark chocolate ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 cup ; high quality white chocolate ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">8 ; cookies and cream dipped cookie sticks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">8 ; chocolate dipped cookie sticks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">8 ; strawberry dipped cookie sticks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">4 ; chocolate sandwich cookies, crushed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">3 tablespoons ; red sprinkles </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">3 tablespoons ; freeze-dried strawberry, crushed </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Date Night</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124178/hls24_1549309868.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/124178/landscape_720/1549309868</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Prepare the brownies according to the package instructions, then remove from the oven and let cool in the refrigerator for about 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">While the brownies cool, use a melon baller or teaspoon to scoop out the tops and centers of each strawberry. Set each strawberry in the cup of a mini muffin tin. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large bowl, beat the cream cheese with an electric hand mixer until soft. Add the mini chocolate chips, vanilla, and cooled brownies and stir until mixture has a thick, dough-like texture. </step>
    <step num="3">Take 1 tablespoon of the brownie mixture in your hands and roll it into a ball. Place the brownie truffle inside a strawberry. Repeating with remaining ingredients. </step>
    <step num="4">Chill the strawberries in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the dark chocolate and white chocolate to 2 separate small bowl. Microwave each bowl separately in 30-second intervals, stirring between each, until melted, about 1 minute total. </step>
    <step num="6">Dip the top of 1 strawberry in the melted white chocolate, poke a cookies and cream-dipped cookie stick through the top, and sprinkle with chocolate sandwich cookie crumbs. Repeat with 7 more strawberries. </step>
    <step num="7">Dip the top of another strawberry in the melted dark chocolate, poke a chocolate-dipped cookie stick through the top, and sprinkle with red sprinkles. Repeat with 7 more strawberries. </step>
    <step num="8">Dip the top of another strawberry in the melted white chocolate, poke a strawberry-dipped cookie stick through the top, and sprinkle with freeze-dried strawberries. Repeat with the remaining strawberries. </step>
    <step num="9">Let the chocolate set, about 5 minutes, then serve. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Prepare the brownies according to the package instructions, then remove from the oven and let cool in the refrigerator for about 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">While the brownies cool, use a melon baller or teaspoon to scoop out the tops and centers of each strawberry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Set each strawberry in the cup of a mini muffin tin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a large bowl, beat the cream cheese with an electric hand mixer until soft. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the mini chocolate chips, vanilla, and cooled brownies and stir until mixture has a thick, dough-like texture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Take 1 tablespoon of the brownie mixture in your hands and roll it into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Place the brownie truffle inside a strawberry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Repeating with remaining ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Chill the strawberries in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add the dark chocolate and white chocolate to 2 separate small bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Microwave each bowl separately in 30-second intervals, stirring between each, until melted, about 1 minute total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Dip the top of 1 strawberry in the melted white chocolate, poke a cookies and cream-dipped cookie stick through the top, and sprinkle with chocolate sandwich cookie crumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Repeat with 7 more strawberries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Dip the top of another strawberry in the melted dark chocolate, poke a chocolate-dipped cookie stick through the top, and sprinkle with red sprinkles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Repeat with 7 more strawberries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Dip the top of another strawberry in the melted white chocolate, poke a strawberry-dipped cookie stick through the top, and sprinkle with freeze-dried strawberries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Repeat with the remaining strawberries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Let the chocolate set, about 5 minutes, then serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>