<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Ice Cream 'Box' Cake Pops Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/ice-cream-box-cake-pops</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">15 oz ; yellow cake mix, 1 box, prepared according to package instructions, cooled ; (450 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; vanilla frosting ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; vanilla ice cream, softened ; (145 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; chocolate cookie, crushed ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; chocolate ice cream, softened ; (145 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 cups ; white chocolate, melted, plus 2 tablespoons, divided ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">whipped cream, for decorating, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">sprinkles, for decorating, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">24 ; ice pop sticks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">foam board, optional </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98144/hls24_1528763129.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98144/landscape_720/1528763129</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, crumble the cake into fine uniform crumbs. Add the vanilla frosting and mix thoroughly. </step>
    <step num="1">Press 1 tablespoon of the cake mixture into each of the divots of an ice cube tray. </step>
    <step num="2">Spread 1 tablespoon of vanilla ice cream over the cake. Sprinkle with 1 teaspoon of crushed cookies. </step>
    <step num="3">Spread 1 tablespoon of chocolate ice cream on top (the ice cream might melt and mix slightly). </step>
    <step num="4">Freeze for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Dip the ice pop sticks into 2 tablespoons of melted white chocolate and press them into the centers of the ice cream cake pops. Freeze for at least 8 hours, until solid. </step>
    <step num="6">To make the cake pop holder, cut 3 2-foot by 5-inch (½ meter by 13 cm) strips of foam board. Place tape in between each layer, one on top of the other, so you have 3 layers of foam board. Carefully create 24 ½-inch (1 cm) slits 2 inches (2 cm) apart with a precision knife. Cut deep enough so you puncture the second layer of foam board. Each cake pop should easily push into the board and stand upright. </step>
    <step num="7">Use a butter knife or offset spatula to loosen the ice cream cake pops from the ice cube tray. </step>
    <step num="8">Add the remaining melted white chocolate to a tall drinking glass. Working 1 at a time, pull each cake pop from the ice cube mold and dip into the melted white chocolate. Place the cake pops in the cake pop holder or on a plate and keep in the freezer until ready to serve. </step>
    <step num="9">Decorate the cake pops with whipped cream and sprinkles, if desired. </step>
    <step num="10">Serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, crumble the cake into fine uniform crumbs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the vanilla frosting and mix thoroughly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Press 1 tablespoon of the cake mixture into each of the divots of an ice cube tray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Spread 1 tablespoon of vanilla ice cream over the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Sprinkle with 1 teaspoon of crushed cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Spread 1 tablespoon of chocolate ice cream on top (the ice cream might melt and mix slightly). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Freeze for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Dip the ice pop sticks into 2 tablespoons of melted white chocolate and press them into the centers of the ice cream cake pops. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Freeze for at least 8 hours, until solid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">To make the cake pop holder, cut 3 2-foot by 5-inch (½ meter by 13 cm) strips of foam board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place tape in between each layer, one on top of the other, so you have 3 layers of foam board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Carefully create 24 ½-inch (1 cm) slits 2 inches (2 cm) apart with a precision knife. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cut deep enough so you puncture the second layer of foam board. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Each cake pop should easily push into the board and stand upright. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Use a butter knife or offset spatula to loosen the ice cream cake pops from the ice cube tray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the remaining melted white chocolate to a tall drinking glass. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Working 1 at a time, pull each cake pop from the ice cube mold and dip into the melted white chocolate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Place the cake pops in the cake pop holder or on a plate and keep in the freezer until ready to serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Decorate the cake pops with whipped cream and sprinkles, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>