<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>5-Ingredient Zucchini Noodles With Spicy Peanut Sauce Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/5-ingredient-zucchini-noodles-with-spicy-peanut-sauce</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ cup ; peanut butter, chunky ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; siracha, to taste, plus more for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ ; lime, juiced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 ; medium zucchinis, or 2 large </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 ; green onions, chopped, light and dark parts divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/130560/hls24_1555952110.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/130560/landscape_720/1555952110</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a large bowl, combine the peanut butter, Sriracha, lime juice, and water. Use a fork or whisk to mix until smooth. </step>
    <step num="1">Using a vegetable peeler, shave the zucchini into wide ribbons. You should have about 8 cups (990 grams) of zucchini ribbons total. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the zucchini ribbons and light parts of the green onions to the sauce and toss until coated. The sauce may seem thick at first, but the zucchini will release some water and thin the sauce a bit. Season with salt to taste. </step>
    <step num="3">Divide the noodles between serving bowls. Garnish with the dark scallion parts. </step>
    <step num="4">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a large bowl, combine the peanut butter, Sriracha, lime juice, and water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Use a fork or whisk to mix until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Using a vegetable peeler, shave the zucchini into wide ribbons. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">You should have about 8 cups (990 grams) of zucchini ribbons total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the zucchini ribbons and light parts of the green onions to the sauce and toss until coated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">The sauce may seem thick at first, but the zucchini will release some water and thin the sauce a bit. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Season with salt to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Divide the noodles between serving bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Garnish with the dark scallion parts. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>