<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chocolate-Dipped Ice Cream Tacos Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chocolate-dipped-ice-cream-tacos</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; milk ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; unsalted butter, 1/4 stick, melted ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ cup ; all purpose flour ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; cocoa powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">18 oz ; good-quality chocolate, finely chopped ; (510 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ cup ; coconut oil, melted ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">4 cups ; vanilla ice cream, softened ; (575 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; salted peanut, crushed ; (125 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/101027/hls24_1530811191.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/101027/landscape_720/1530811191</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the taco shells: in a medium bowl, whisk together the eggs and sugar until combined. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the milk, vanilla, and butter, and whisk until fully incorporated. </step>
    <step num="2">Sift in the flour and cocoa powder. Whisk until smooth. </step>
    <step num="3">Heat a small non-stick pan over medium-low heat, then add ⅓ cup (95 g) of batter at a time and tilt the pan to spread the batter evenly like a crepe. </step>
    <step num="4">Cook until bubbles appear on the surface and the batter is set, about 6-8 minutes. Flip the taco shell and cook on other side for another 3-4 minutes, until cooked through. </step>
    <step num="5">If desired, remove the taco shell from pan and place on a grated cooling rack while still hot. Place a sheet of parchment over the shell and press into the rack, allowing the grate marks to set into the shell. Rotate the shell 90 degrees and press the cone into the grates again for a waffled look. Or, skip to the next step. </step>
    <step num="6">Place the taco shells between the cups of an inverted muffin tin to form their shape. Let set for about 10 minutes, then freeze for 20 minutes to harden. </step>
    <step num="7">Make the magic shell: combine the chocolate and coconut oil in a medium bowl and microwave for 2 minutes, stirring every 30 seconds until melted and shiny. </step>
    <step num="8">Remove the taco shells from the freezer and use a spoon to coat the inside of each taco shell with melted magic shell. Return to the freezer for 20 minutes, until the magic shell hardens. Reserve the leftover magic shell. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the ice cream to a piping bag fitted with a round tip or a zip-top bag with the corner cut off. </step>
    <step num="10">Remove the shells from the freezer and pipe in the ice cream, filling the tacos. Smooth out the tops with a knife or rubber spatula. Freeze for 2 hours. </step>
    <step num="11">Microwave the reserved magic shell, if needed, to re-melt. Remove the tacos from the freezer and dip the tops of each taco in the magic shell, then immediately sprinkle with the crushed peanuts. </step>
    <step num="12">Serve immediately or return to the freezer until ready to eat. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the taco shells: in a medium bowl, whisk together the eggs and sugar until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the milk, vanilla, and butter, and whisk until fully incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Sift in the flour and cocoa powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Whisk until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Heat a small non-stick pan over medium-low heat, then add ⅓ cup (95 g) of batter at a time and tilt the pan to spread the batter evenly like a crepe. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cook until bubbles appear on the surface and the batter is set, about 6-8 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Flip the taco shell and cook on other side for another 3-4 minutes, until cooked through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">If desired, remove the taco shell from pan and place on a grated cooling rack while still hot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Place a sheet of parchment over the shell and press into the rack, allowing the grate marks to set into the shell. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Rotate the shell 90 degrees and press the cone into the grates again for a waffled look. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Or, skip to the next step. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place the taco shells between the cups of an inverted muffin tin to form their shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Let set for about 10 minutes, then freeze for 20 minutes to harden. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Make the magic shell: combine the chocolate and coconut oil in a medium bowl and microwave for 2 minutes, stirring every 30 seconds until melted and shiny. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove the taco shells from the freezer and use a spoon to coat the inside of each taco shell with melted magic shell. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Return to the freezer for 20 minutes, until the magic shell hardens. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Reserve the leftover magic shell. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Add the ice cream to a piping bag fitted with a round tip or a zip-top bag with the corner cut off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Remove the shells from the freezer and pipe in the ice cream, filling the tacos. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Smooth out the tops with a knife or rubber spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Freeze for 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Microwave the reserved magic shell, if needed, to re-melt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Remove the tacos from the freezer and dip the tops of each taco in the magic shell, then immediately sprinkle with the crushed peanuts. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Serve immediately or return to the freezer until ready to eat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>