<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chocolate Rainbow Surprise 'Box' Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chocolate-rainbow-surprise-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 box ; chocolate cake mix, plus corresponding ingredients - eggs, oil, water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 box ; white cake mix, plus corresponding ingredients - eggs, oil, water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">cake frosting </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32002/low_1495124965.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32002/mp4_720x1280/1495124965</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Prepare Chocolate and White Cake Mixes according to directions on the box. </step>
    <step num="1">NOTE: It is recommended that you use the same brand of cake mix for each, and ensure they share a similar bake time. </step>
    <step num="2">Divide prepared White Cake Batter into 4 separate bowls. Use food coloring to create vivid Red, Yellow, Green, and Blue Batter. </step>
    <step num="3">In a greased bundt pan, spoon about ⅓ of the prepared Chocolate Cake Mix onto the bottom. Using a tablespoon, carefully spoon a thin ring of Red Cake Batter on top of the chocolate layer - being careful to keep it centered and ensure it does not spread to the edge of the pan. </step>
    <step num="4">Repeat with Yellow, Green, and Blue Batter, carefully spooning each on top of the previous. Finish by carefully covering the colored layers with an additional ⅓ of the Chocolate Cake Mix (leaving about ⅓ extra so as not to overfill the pan). </step>
    <step num="5">Bake in a preheated oven for 35 minutes at 175°C (350°F). Remove from oven and allow cake to cool. </step>
    <step num="6">Turn out onto a plate and decorate. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Prepare Chocolate and White Cake Mixes according to directions on the box. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">NOTE: It is recommended that you use the same brand of cake mix for each, and ensure they share a similar bake time. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Divide prepared White Cake Batter into 4 separate bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Use food coloring to create vivid Red, Yellow, Green, and Blue Batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a greased bundt pan, spoon about ⅓ of the prepared Chocolate Cake Mix onto the bottom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Using a tablespoon, carefully spoon a thin ring of Red Cake Batter on top of the chocolate layer - being careful to keep it centered and ensure it does not spread to the edge of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Repeat with Yellow, Green, and Blue Batter, carefully spooning each on top of the previous. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Finish by carefully covering the colored layers with an additional ⅓ of the Chocolate Cake Mix (leaving about ⅓ extra so as not to overfill the pan). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Bake in a preheated oven for 35 minutes at 175°C (350°F). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove from oven and allow cake to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Turn out onto a plate and decorate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>