<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chicken Alfredo Bread Boat Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chicken-alfredo-bread-boat</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; whole milk ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ½ cups ; all-purpose flour, plus 3 tablespoons, divided ; (310 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; grated parmesan cheese ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 tablespoons ; olive oil, plus more as needed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 ½ cups ; chicken, cooked, shredded ; (310 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 ½ cups ; shredded mozzarella cheese, divided ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ cup ; grated parmesan cheese ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 tablespoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 cups ; alfredo sauce ; (520 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 ; egg, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">3 tablespoons ; fresh parsley, chopped </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Game Day</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/89641/hls24_1523896348.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/89641/landscape_720/1523896348</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a microwave-proof liquid measuring cup, combine the water and the milk. Microwave on high for 45 seconds. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, combine the flour, sugar, salt, garlic powder, Parmesan, and yeast. Mix thoroughly. Pour the milk mixture over the dry ingredients. Stir to combine. Knead the dough on a clean surface for 5 minutes until smooth, if the dough is sticking to the surface add olive oil 1 teaspoon at a time, then form into a tight ball. </step>
    <step num="2">Drizzle 2 tablespoons olive oil in a large bowl. Place the dough in the bowl and cover with plastic wrap. Let rise for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="3">Preheat the oven to 450˚F (230˚C). </step>
    <step num="4">In a separate large bowl, combine the chicken, 2 cups (200 g) mozzarella, Parmesan, garlic powder, pepper, and alfredo sauce. Mix thoroughly. </step>
    <step num="5">Place the risen dough onto a floured surface. Roll out the dough so it is twice as long as it is wide and about ¼ inch (½ cm) thick. </step>
    <step num="6">Transfer the dough to a parchment-lined baking sheet. Roll up all of the sides of the dough to create an oval shape. Pinch the dough and pull it while twisting, wrapping the dough into little spirals and placing it onto the rolled edge of the dough. Continue all the way around until you have several little spirals of dough. </step>
    <step num="7">Pour the chicken alfredo mixture over the dough and spread it until it reaches the edges of the dough. Brush the sides of the dough with egg wash. Sprinkle the rest of the mozzarella on top of the chicken alfredo mixture. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake for 30 minutes, until the crust is golden brown. </step>
    <step num="9">Sprinkle with parsley. Serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a microwave-proof liquid measuring cup, combine the water and the milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Microwave on high for 45 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a large bowl, combine the flour, sugar, salt, garlic powder, Parmesan, and yeast. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Mix thoroughly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour the milk mixture over the dry ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Knead the dough on a clean surface for 5 minutes until smooth, if the dough is sticking to the surface add olive oil 1 teaspoon at a time, then form into a tight ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Drizzle 2 tablespoons olive oil in a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Place the dough in the bowl and cover with plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Let rise for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Preheat the oven to 450˚F (230˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">In a separate large bowl, combine the chicken, 2 cups (200 g) mozzarella, Parmesan, garlic powder, pepper, and alfredo sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Mix thoroughly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Place the risen dough onto a floured surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Roll out the dough so it is twice as long as it is wide and about ¼ inch (½ cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Transfer the dough to a parchment-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Roll up all of the sides of the dough to create an oval shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Pinch the dough and pull it while twisting, wrapping the dough into little spirals and placing it onto the rolled edge of the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Continue all the way around until you have several little spirals of dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Pour the chicken alfredo mixture over the dough and spread it until it reaches the edges of the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Brush the sides of the dough with egg wash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Sprinkle the rest of the mozzarella on top of the chicken alfredo mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Bake for 30 minutes, until the crust is golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Sprinkle with parsley. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>