<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Lil’ Merri’s As Made By Elizabeth Belkind Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/lil-merris-as-made-by-elizabeth-belkind</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; pastry flour ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 cups ; rolled oats ; (160 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; ground cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¾ cup ; unsalted butter, room temperature </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; light brown sugar ; (440 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ½ teaspoons ; boiling water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 teaspoons ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 ½ cups ; unsalted butter, room temperature ; (570 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 cup ; unrefined grade b dark amber maple syrup ; (335 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ½ teaspoons ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 cups ; powdered sugar ; (240 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="2">Bakery Goods</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/119969/hls24_1544824088.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/119969/landscape_720/1544824088</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the cookie dough: In a large bowl, combine the flour, salt, cinnamon, oats and baking powder. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">In the bowl of a stand mixer fitted with a paddle attachment, or in a separate large bowl with an electric hand mixer, cream together the butter and sugar for about 2 minutes on medium speed, until well-combined. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the eggs, 1 at a time, incorporating each egg before adding the next. Scrape down the sides of the bowl. </step>
    <step num="3">Slowly add the dry ingredients to the butter mixture and beat until just combined. Scrape down the sides of the bowl if needed. </step>
    <step num="4">In a small bowl, combine the boiling water and baking soda. Add to the dough and beat thoroughly to combine. </step>
    <step num="5">Chill the dough in the refrigerator for 4 hours. </step>
    <step num="6">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="7">Make the maple buttercream: In the bowl of a stand mixer fitted with a paddle attachment, or in a large bowl with an electric hand mixer, cream the butter on medium speed until smooth and pale in color. Scrape the sides of the bowl down with a spatula as needed. </step>
    <step num="8">With the mixer running, slowly drizzle the maple syrup into the butter. Beat until well-combined. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the salt and vanilla. Mix well, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed. </step>
    <step num="10">Add the powdered sugar and beat until well-combined. Set the buttercream aside. </step>
    <step num="11">Scoop ¾-ounce (20 grams) balls of the chilled dough and onto a parchment-lined baking sheet, spacing about 3 inches apart. (You may need to bake in multiple batches). Moisten your fingers with water and gently flatten each scoop of dough into an even round about ¼-inch (½ cm) thick. </step>
    <step num="12">Bake the cookies for 8-10 minutes, until the edges are golden brown and the centers are dry, but still chewy and pliable. Using a small spatula, gently coax any overly spread cookies back into a round shape. </step>
    <step num="13">Let the cookies cool completely. </step>
    <step num="14">Fill a piping bag with the maple buttercream. Pipe a flat round of buttercream onto half of the cookies. Then, top with the other cookies. </step>
    <step num="15">Freeze any extra cookies in an airtight container for up to 10 days. Exposure to moisture in the air both in the freezer and at room temperature will cause the cookies to get sticky and soggy. </step>
    <step num="16">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the cookie dough: In a large bowl, combine the flour, salt, cinnamon, oats and baking powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In the bowl of a stand mixer fitted with a paddle attachment, or in a separate large bowl with an electric hand mixer, cream together the butter and sugar for about 2 minutes on medium speed, until well-combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the eggs, 1 at a time, incorporating each egg before adding the next. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Scrape down the sides of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Slowly add the dry ingredients to the butter mixture and beat until just combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Scrape down the sides of the bowl if needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a small bowl, combine the boiling water and baking soda. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add to the dough and beat thoroughly to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Chill the dough in the refrigerator for 4 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Make the maple buttercream: In the bowl of a stand mixer fitted with a paddle attachment, or in a large bowl with an electric hand mixer, cream the butter on medium speed until smooth and pale in color. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Scrape the sides of the bowl down with a spatula as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">With the mixer running, slowly drizzle the maple syrup into the butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Beat until well-combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the salt and vanilla. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Mix well, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Add the powdered sugar and beat until well-combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Set the buttercream aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Scoop ¾-ounce (20 grams) balls of the chilled dough and onto a parchment-lined baking sheet, spacing about 3 inches apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">(You may need to bake in multiple batches). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Moisten your fingers with water and gently flatten each scoop of dough into an even round about ¼-inch (½ cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Bake the cookies for 8-10 minutes, until the edges are golden brown and the centers are dry, but still chewy and pliable. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Using a small spatula, gently coax any overly spread cookies back into a round shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Let the cookies cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Fill a piping bag with the maple buttercream. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Pipe a flat round of buttercream onto half of the cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Then, top with the other cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Freeze any extra cookies in an airtight container for up to 10 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Exposure to moisture in the air both in the freezer and at room temperature will cause the cookies to get sticky and soggy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>