<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Grilled Honey Chipotle Wings Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/grilled-honey-chipotle-wings</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 lb ; chicken wing and drumette ; (2 kg) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; cornstarch ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 teaspoons ; salt, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ½ cups ; chipotle peppers in adobo ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; lime juice ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¼ cup ; honey ; (85 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">BBQ</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Game Day</category>
    <category num="4">BBQ</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/57170/low_1508436123.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/57170/mp4_720x1280/1508436123</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Pat dry chicken and place in a large mixing bowl or plastic bag. Toss with cornstarch, garlic powder, and one teaspoon of kosher salt. </step>
    <step num="1">Place chicken in a single layer on a cookie sheet or wire rack and refrigerate for at least an hour, up to overnight. </step>
    <step num="2">In a food processor or blender, combine chipotles, lime juice, honey, and the remaining salt. Puree until smooth. Set aside until ready to grill. </step>
    <step num="3">Preheat grill to medium high heat. Grill wings until just starting to brown on the underside, about 5 minutes, then flip and repeat. </step>
    <step num="4">Using a basting brush, coat the top side of the wings with chipotle puree. Flip and cook until exterior just starts to char. Baste the other side, flip and repeat. </step>
    <step num="5">Remove wings from heat and let cool for at least 5 minutes. Serve with your preferred garnish and dipping sauce. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Pat dry chicken and place in a large mixing bowl or plastic bag. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Toss with cornstarch, garlic powder, and one teaspoon of kosher salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Place chicken in a single layer on a cookie sheet or wire rack and refrigerate for at least an hour, up to overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a food processor or blender, combine chipotles, lime juice, honey, and the remaining salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Puree until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Set aside until ready to grill. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Preheat grill to medium high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Grill wings until just starting to brown on the underside, about 5 minutes, then flip and repeat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Using a basting brush, coat the top side of the wings with chipotle puree. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Flip and cook until exterior just starts to char. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Baste the other side, flip and repeat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove wings from heat and let cool for at least 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Serve with your preferred garnish and dipping sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>