<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Thai Tea Pie By Ray Pajar Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/thai-tea-pie-by-ray-pajar</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 cups ; cornflakes ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">6 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">⅓ cup ; sugar ; (65 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 ½ cups ; whole milk ; (600 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; thai tea, loose leaf ; (120 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">5 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 tablespoons ; cornstarch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ cup ; granulated sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, room temperature </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; chocolate hazelnut spread, melted ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 tablespoons ; toasted coconut flakes </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 cup ; whipped cream, for topping ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Thai</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="7">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/116106/hls24_1542669274.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/116106/landscape_720/1542669274</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (160˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Make the crust: Add the cornflakes to a zip-top bag, seal, and crush into crumbs with a rolling pin. </step>
    <step num="2">Transfer the crumbs to a large bowl and add the melted butter and sugar. Stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the crumb mixture to a 9½-inch (24 cm) pie dish and press evenly into a ¼-inch-thick (6 mm) layer against the bottom and up the sides of the pan. </step>
    <step num="4">Bake until the crust is golden brown, about 15 minutes. Let cool completely. </step>
    <step num="5">Make the filling: In a small saucepan over medium heat, bring the milk to a simmer. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the Thai tea leaves and stir into the hot milk. Turn off the heat and let the tea steep for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">In a medium bowl, whisk together the egg yolks, salt, cornstarch, and sugar. </step>
    <step num="8">Line a fine-mesh sieve with cheesecloth and set over the bowl with the egg mixture. Slowly pour in the Thai tea mixture, pressing the leaves to extract as much liquid as possible. Whisk to combine. </step>
    <step num="9">Return the Thai tea mixture to the saucepan over medium heat and cook, stirring constantly, until thickened, about 8 minutes. Add the butter and whisk until melted and the filling is smooth. Remove from the heat. </step>
    <step num="10">Brush the chocolate hazelnut spread over the bottom of the cooled crust. Sprinkle the toasted coconut flakes over the chocolate hazelnut spread. </step>
    <step num="11">Pour the Thai tea filling into the crust and spread evenly. While still hot, cover the pudding with plastic wrap to prevent a skin from forming . Refrigerate the pie until set, at least 4 hours. </step>
    <step num="12">Before serving, remove the plastic wrap and spread whipped cream over the top of the pie. Serve chilled. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 325˚F (160˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Make the crust: Add the cornflakes to a zip-top bag, seal, and crush into crumbs with a rolling pin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Transfer the crumbs to a large bowl and add the melted butter and sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the crumb mixture to a 9½-inch (24 cm) pie dish and press evenly into a ¼-inch-thick (6 mm) layer against the bottom and up the sides of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Bake until the crust is golden brown, about 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Make the filling: In a small saucepan over medium heat, bring the milk to a simmer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the Thai tea leaves and stir into the hot milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Turn off the heat and let the tea steep for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a medium bowl, whisk together the egg yolks, salt, cornstarch, and sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Line a fine-mesh sieve with cheesecloth and set over the bowl with the egg mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Slowly pour in the Thai tea mixture, pressing the leaves to extract as much liquid as possible. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Return the Thai tea mixture to the saucepan over medium heat and cook, stirring constantly, until thickened, about 8 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the butter and whisk until melted and the filling is smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Remove from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Brush the chocolate hazelnut spread over the bottom of the cooled crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Sprinkle the toasted coconut flakes over the chocolate hazelnut spread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Pour the Thai tea filling into the crust and spread evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">While still hot, cover the pudding with plastic wrap to prevent a skin from forming . </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Refrigerate the pie until set, at least 4 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Before serving, remove the plastic wrap and spread whipped cream over the top of the pie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Serve chilled. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>