<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chocolate Cheesecake Pudding Cups Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chocolate-cheesecake-pudding-cups</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 ; chocolate pudding cups </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; semisweet chocolate ; (170 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 teaspoons ; coconut oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">8 oz ; cream cheese, softened ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">peanuts, crushed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">caramel </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">cookies, crushed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">strawberry, sliced </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/101963/hls24_1531522208.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/101963/landscape_720/1531522208</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Open the chocolate pudding cups and spoon the pudding into a medium bowl. Place the pudding in the refrigerator and wash out the plastic cups. </step>
    <step num="1">Using scissors, cut the cups down one side and across the bottom, leaving one side of the cup intact. Tape the cut edges together to seal the cups. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">Place the chocolate chips in a medium microwave-safe bowl. Add the coconut oil and melt in the microwave in 30-second intervals for 1 minute total. Stir the chocolate until smooth. </step>
    <step num="3">Spoon the melted chocolate into the plastic cups. Tilt the cups to coat the insides completely and pour any excess chocolate back into the bowl. </step>
    <step num="4">Place the cups on a baking sheet and refrigerate until set, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the cream cheese to a medium bowl with the sugar and vanilla. Stir until smooth and well-combined. Transfer to a piping bag or zip-top plastic bag with a corner cut off. </step>
    <step num="6">Transfer the reserved chocolate pudding to another piping bag or zip-top plastic bag with a corner cut off. </step>
    <step num="7">Peel the tape off the pudding cups and carefully remove the plastic from the chocolate cups. </step>
    <step num="8">Flip the cups upright and pipe the chocolate pudding into the bottom of the cups. Top the pudding with the cheesecake mixture and your favorite dessert toppings, such as crushed peanuts, caramel sauce, crushed cookies, and/or strawberries. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Open the chocolate pudding cups and spoon the pudding into a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Place the pudding in the refrigerator and wash out the plastic cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Using scissors, cut the cups down one side and across the bottom, leaving one side of the cup intact. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Tape the cut edges together to seal the cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Place the chocolate chips in a medium microwave-safe bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the coconut oil and melt in the microwave in 30-second intervals for 1 minute total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Stir the chocolate until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Spoon the melted chocolate into the plastic cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Tilt the cups to coat the insides completely and pour any excess chocolate back into the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place the cups on a baking sheet and refrigerate until set, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the cream cheese to a medium bowl with the sugar and vanilla. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Stir until smooth and well-combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Transfer to a piping bag or zip-top plastic bag with a corner cut off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Transfer the reserved chocolate pudding to another piping bag or zip-top plastic bag with a corner cut off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Peel the tape off the pudding cups and carefully remove the plastic from the chocolate cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Flip the cups upright and pipe the chocolate pudding into the bottom of the cups. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Top the pudding with the cheesecake mixture and your favorite dessert toppings, such as crushed peanuts, caramel sauce, crushed cookies, and/or strawberries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>