<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chocolate Peanut Butter CBD Cups Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chocolate-peanut-butter-cbd-cups</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">12 oz ; dark chocolate ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">7 tablespoons ; coconut oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; CBD oil, 100% </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; natural peanut butter, or other nut butter ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; honey ; (85 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">hemp hearts, for garnish (optional) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">muffin tin, or silicone molds or mini paper liners </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegan</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/131052/hls24_1556326082.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/131052/landscape_720/1556326082</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a microwave-safe bowl, combine the dark chocolate and 5 tablespoons of coconut oil. Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until melted. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the vanilla and CBD oil and stir until combined. The mixture should be smooth and pourable. </step>
    <step num="2">Pour ½ of the chocolate mixture into the molds, enough to come about ⅓ of the way up the sides of each cup. Freeze for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">In a separate microwave-safe bowl, combine the peanut butter, honey, and remaining 2 tablespoons coconut oil. Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until smooth and pourable. </step>
    <step num="4">Pour the peanut butter mixture evenly over the chocolate layers in the molds. Make sure to leave enough room for the second layer of chocolate. Freeze for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="5">Pour the remaining chocolate mixture evenly over the peanut butter layers in the molds, filling completely to the rim of each. Wipe off any excess that spills over the edges. If desired, sprinkle the cups with hemp hearts for added crunch. Freeze for 1 hour, until set, then pop out of the molds. The cups will keep in an airtight container in the refrigerator for up to 1 month. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a microwave-safe bowl, combine the dark chocolate and 5 tablespoons of coconut oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the vanilla and CBD oil and stir until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">The mixture should be smooth and pourable. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour ½ of the chocolate mixture into the molds, enough to come about ⅓ of the way up the sides of each cup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Freeze for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a separate microwave-safe bowl, combine the peanut butter, honey, and remaining 2 tablespoons coconut oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until smooth and pourable. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Pour the peanut butter mixture evenly over the chocolate layers in the molds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Make sure to leave enough room for the second layer of chocolate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Freeze for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Pour the remaining chocolate mixture evenly over the peanut butter layers in the molds, filling completely to the rim of each. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Wipe off any excess that spills over the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">If desired, sprinkle the cups with hemp hearts for added crunch. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Freeze for 1 hour, until set, then pop out of the molds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">The cups will keep in an airtight container in the refrigerator for up to 1 month. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>