<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>New Year’s Eve Champagne Cookies Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/new-years-eve-champagne-cookies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; champagne ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; heavy cream ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">11 oz ; white chocolate chips ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ¼ cups ; unsalted butter, softened, divided ; (280 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 tablespoons ; powdered sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; all purpose flour ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 cups ; walnuts, finely ground ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 tablespoon ; heavy cream </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">5 oz ; semisweet chocolate chips </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">edible gold dust, for sprinkling </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="2">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/121028/hls24_1545418892.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/121028/landscape_720/1545418892</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the cookies: In a small saucepan, bring the champagne to a boil and reduce by half, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="1">In a liquid measuring cup or microwave-safe bowl, microwave the heavy cream until boiling. </step>
    <step num="2">Pour the hot heavy cream and half of the heated champagne over the white chocolate chips in a heatproof bowl and let rest for 1 minute. Whisk until smooth. Add 4 tbsp of unsalted butter and whisk until melted and well combined. Cover and chill in the refrigerator for 2 hours. </step>
    <step num="3">In a large bowl, cream the remaining cup of unsalted butter and the powdered sugar with an electric hand mixer until fluffy. Add the vanilla and beat to combine. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the flour, 1 cup at a time, and beat until just incorporated. To the last addition, add the salt. </step>
    <step num="5">Add the walnuts and beat to incorporate. Using your hands, press the dough together in a ball and wrap in plastic wrap. Refrigerate the dough at least 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="7">Use a 2 tablespoon (1 ounce) scoop to scoop balls of cookie dough onto the prepared baking sheet. Pat each ball into a disc in your palm and fill with 1 teaspoon of the white chocolate ganache. Fold the edges in to completely cover the ganache and roll back into a ball. Once all of the cookies are filled, refrigerate for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Bake the cookies for 15 minutes, until set and not too browned. Let cool. </step>
    <step num="9">Make the glaze: Microwave the heavy cream until boiling. </step>
    <step num="10">Pour the hot heavy cream and the remaining reduced champagne over the semisweet chocolate chips in a heatproof bowl and whisk until smooth. </step>
    <step num="11">Dip the cooled cookies in the chocolate ganache and sprinkle with edible gold dust. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the cookies: In a small saucepan, bring the champagne to a boil and reduce by half, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a liquid measuring cup or microwave-safe bowl, microwave the heavy cream until boiling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Pour the hot heavy cream and half of the heated champagne over the white chocolate chips in a heatproof bowl and let rest for 1 minute. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Whisk until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add 4 tbsp of unsalted butter and whisk until melted and well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cover and chill in the refrigerator for 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a large bowl, cream the remaining cup of unsalted butter and the powdered sugar with an electric hand mixer until fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the vanilla and beat to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the flour, 1 cup at a time, and beat until just incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">To the last addition, add the salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the walnuts and beat to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Using your hands, press the dough together in a ball and wrap in plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Refrigerate the dough at least 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Preheat the oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Use a 2 tablespoon (1 ounce) scoop to scoop balls of cookie dough onto the prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Pat each ball into a disc in your palm and fill with 1 teaspoon of the white chocolate ganache. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Fold the edges in to completely cover the ganache and roll back into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Once all of the cookies are filled, refrigerate for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Bake the cookies for 15 minutes, until set and not too browned. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Let cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Make the glaze: Microwave the heavy cream until boiling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Pour the hot heavy cream and the remaining reduced champagne over the semisweet chocolate chips in a heatproof bowl and whisk until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Dip the cooled cookies in the chocolate ganache and sprinkle with edible gold dust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>