<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Unicorn Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/unicorn-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 boxes ; vanilla cake mix, prepare according to box instructions </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ teaspoon ; pink food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ teaspoon ; purple food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; blue food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">5 cups ; powdered sugar ; (600 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ cups ; butter, softened ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; milk ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ teaspoon ; pink food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ teaspoon ; black food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 ; ice cream cone </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 cup ; pink sprinkle ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">candles </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/48829/low_1503448375.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/48829/mp4_720x1280/1503448375</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, prepare 2 boxes of vanilla cake mix according to the package instructions. </step>
    <step num="2">Fill 3 separate bowls with 1 cup (225 grams) each of cake batter and dye one batter pink, one purple, and the last one blue. </step>
    <step num="3">Pour the remaining batter into two round 8-inch (20 cm) baking pans and one loaf pan that have been lined with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="4">In random places, place spoonfuls of colored batter on top of the plain batter. </step>
    <step num="5">Using a toothpick, mix the colors together until the batter looks marbled. </step>
    <step num="6">Bake all 3 cakes for 20 minutes or until a toothpick comes out clean. Let cakes cool on a cooling rack completely before assembling. </step>
    <step num="7">Using a hand mixer, mix powdered sugar, butter, vanilla extract, and milk until well combined to make the frosting. Set aside 2 small bowls of frosting and dye one pink and the other black. </step>
    <step num="8">Assemble the cake by placing one round cake on the serving dish and spread a layer of plain buttercream frosting on top. Place the second round cake on top of the frosting. </step>
    <step num="9">Cut two of the corners off of the loaf cake to make ears. Spread frosting on the inside of the ear and stick to the top of the round cakes at 10 o’clock &amp; 2 o’clock. Cover the top and sides of the cake with the plain buttercream leaving a semicircle at the bottom for the pink frosting. Frost the semi circle and the side with the pink buttercream, saving some for later. </step>
    <step num="10">Put the black frosting into a resealable bag and cut off the tip of the corner. Decorate the cake with eyes, nostrils, and a smile. </step>
    <step num="11">Cover an ice cream cone with the remaining pink frosting and pink sprinkles. Place the cone in between the ears and gently push into the cake to secure. Decorate with more pink sprinkles around the horn and on the ears. </step>
    <step num="12">Place the cone in the middle of the cake (between the ears) and sprinkle the area around the cone and the ears with the pink sprinkles. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a large bowl, prepare 2 boxes of vanilla cake mix according to the package instructions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Fill 3 separate bowls with 1 cup (225 grams) each of cake batter and dye one batter pink, one purple, and the last one blue. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Pour the remaining batter into two round 8-inch (20 cm) baking pans and one loaf pan that have been lined with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In random places, place spoonfuls of colored batter on top of the plain batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Using a toothpick, mix the colors together until the batter looks marbled. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Bake all 3 cakes for 20 minutes or until a toothpick comes out clean. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Let cakes cool on a cooling rack completely before assembling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Using a hand mixer, mix powdered sugar, butter, vanilla extract, and milk until well combined to make the frosting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Set aside 2 small bowls of frosting and dye one pink and the other black. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Assemble the cake by placing one round cake on the serving dish and spread a layer of plain buttercream frosting on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Place the second round cake on top of the frosting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cut two of the corners off of the loaf cake to make ears. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Spread frosting on the inside of the ear and stick to the top of the round cakes at 10 o’clock &amp; 2 o’clock. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Cover the top and sides of the cake with the plain buttercream leaving a semicircle at the bottom for the pink frosting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Frost the semi circle and the side with the pink buttercream, saving some for later. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Put the black frosting into a resealable bag and cut off the tip of the corner. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Decorate the cake with eyes, nostrils, and a smile. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Cover an ice cream cone with the remaining pink frosting and pink sprinkles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Place the cone in between the ears and gently push into the cake to secure. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Decorate with more pink sprinkles around the horn and on the ears. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Place the cone in the middle of the cake (between the ears) and sprinkle the area around the cone and the ears with the pink sprinkles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>