<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Instant-Pot Short Ribs Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/instant-pot-short-ribs</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; soy sauce ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; rice vinegar ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; sesame oil, toasted ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; gochujang, or to taste ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; honey </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 lb ; flanken beef short ribs, 1/2 inch (1 1/4 cm) thick, each rib cut in half ; (910 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">ground black pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; coconut oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ; bosc pear, or D’Anjou pear, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; shallot, finely chopped ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">3 tablespoons ; fresh ginger, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 tablespoon ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 tablespoons ; water </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 tablespoon ; cornstarch </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">white rice, for serving </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">sesame seeds, toasted, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">fresh cilantro, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">scallions, thinly sliced, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">kimchi, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Korean</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Healthy</category>
    <category num="4">Dinner</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/122609/hls24_1547504989.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/122609/landscape_720/1547504989</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a liquid measuring cup or medium bowl, whisk together the soy sauce, rice vinegar, sesame oil, gochujang (adjust the quantity based on your preferred spice level), and honey. </step>
    <step num="1">Place the short ribs in a deep baking dish or large bowl and season generously on both sides with salt and pepper. Pour the soy sauce mixture over the ribs. Cover with plastic wrap and marinate in the refrigerator for at least 1 hour, up to overnight. </step>
    <step num="2">Preheat a 6-quart (6 Liter) Instant Pot on the high sauté setting. Once hot, add the coconut oil. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove the short ribs from the marinade and let any excess marinade drip off. Reserve the marinade for later. </step>
    <step num="4">Working in batches, add the short ribs to the Instant Pot and sear for 3-4 minutes on each side, until deeply caramelized. Transfer the short ribs to a baking sheet as they finish cooking and repeat with the remaining ribs. </step>
    <step num="5">After the short ribs are seared, add the pear, shallot, ginger, and garlic to the Instant Pot. Season with salt and pepper, and sauté for 4-5 minutes, or until the mixture is golden brown. </step>
    <step num="6">Return the short ribs to the Instant Pot, then pour in the reserved marinade. Place the lid on the Instant Pot, make sure the lid is set to “Sealing,” and change the setting to high pressure cooker. Set the timer for 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">At the end of 20 minutes, carefully release the pressure from the Instant Pot by turning the knob from “Sealing” to “Venting,” making sure your hand is not over the release switch as the hot steam will come out of the top. Wait for the pressure to release and the Instant Pot to unlock before taking off the lid. </step>
    <step num="8">Remove the short ribs from the pot and change the setting to high sauté. Bring the sauce to a simmer and cook for about 5 minutes, or until reduced to about 2 cups (480 ml) </step>
    <step num="9">Add the cornstarch to the water and mix until completely dissolved. Add the slurry to the sauce and whisk continuously for another 3 minutes, or until the sauce thickens. Remove from the heat and let cool slightly. Skim off any excess oil from the top of the sauce, if desired. </step>
    <step num="10">Serve the short ribs over white rice. Pour about ½ cup (120 ml) of the sauce over the ribs and serve the rest on the side. Garnish with toasted sesame seeds, cilantro, and scallions, and serve with kimchi, if desired. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a liquid measuring cup or medium bowl, whisk together the soy sauce, rice vinegar, sesame oil, gochujang (adjust the quantity based on your preferred spice level), and honey. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Place the short ribs in a deep baking dish or large bowl and season generously on both sides with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Pour the soy sauce mixture over the ribs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cover with plastic wrap and marinate in the refrigerator for at least 1 hour, up to overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Preheat a 6-quart (6 Liter) Instant Pot on the high sauté setting. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Once hot, add the coconut oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Remove the short ribs from the marinade and let any excess marinade drip off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Reserve the marinade for later. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Working in batches, add the short ribs to the Instant Pot and sear for 3-4 minutes on each side, until deeply caramelized. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Transfer the short ribs to a baking sheet as they finish cooking and repeat with the remaining ribs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">After the short ribs are seared, add the pear, shallot, ginger, and garlic to the Instant Pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Season with salt and pepper, and sauté for 4-5 minutes, or until the mixture is golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Return the short ribs to the Instant Pot, then pour in the reserved marinade. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Place the lid on the Instant Pot, make sure the lid is set to “Sealing,” and change the setting to high pressure cooker. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Set the timer for 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">At the end of 20 minutes, carefully release the pressure from the Instant Pot by turning the knob from “Sealing” to “Venting,” making sure your hand is not over the release switch as the hot steam will come out of the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Wait for the pressure to release and the Instant Pot to unlock before taking off the lid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Remove the short ribs from the pot and change the setting to high sauté. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Bring the sauce to a simmer and cook for about 5 minutes, or until reduced to about 2 cups (480 ml) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add the cornstarch to the water and mix until completely dissolved. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Add the slurry to the sauce and whisk continuously for another 3 minutes, or until the sauce thickens. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Remove from the heat and let cool slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Skim off any excess oil from the top of the sauce, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Serve the short ribs over white rice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Pour about ½ cup (120 ml) of the sauce over the ribs and serve the rest on the side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Garnish with toasted sesame seeds, cilantro, and scallions, and serve with kimchi, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>