<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Crème Brûlée French Toast Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/creme-brulee-french-toast</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 cups ; heavy cream ; (960 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ¼ cups ; sugar, divided ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">6 ; large egg yolks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 teaspoons ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">18 slices ; brioche bread </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ lb ; strawberry ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 cup ; whipped cream ; (60 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="3">Brunch</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/95543/hls24_1527107474.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/95543/landscape_720/1527107474</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Pour the heavy cream into a 9x13-inch (23x33 cm) baking dish. </step>
    <step num="1">Mix 1 cup of sugar (200 g) and the cinnamon in a small bowl and add to the cream, followed by the egg yolks and vanilla. Whisk well to combine. </step>
    <step num="2">Dip each slice of bread into the cream mixture, coating both sides well. Place the dipped bread on the wire rack set over the baking sheet. Bake for 15 minutes, flip the bread over, then bake for another 15 minutes, until slightly crispy. </step>
    <step num="3">Slice the strawberries into decorative shapes of your choosing. For a strawberry rose, place a strawberry stem side down and carefully make thin slices around the outer edge of the strawberry, making sure not to cut all the way through. Continue cutting and rotating the strawberry until you get to the center. Fan out the “petals”. </step>
    <step num="4">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper and set a wire rack on top. </step>
    <step num="5">For a strawberry fan, lay a strawberry on its flattest side. Tilt the knife at a 45˚ angle and make thin, angled slices through the strawberry, keeping the top of the strawberry connected and slicing all the way through the bottom of the berry. Fan out the slices. </step>
    <step num="6">Sprinkle the remaining sugar on top of the bread and broil on high for 3 minutes, until the sugar has melted and browned, or carefully use a kitchen torch to brûlée the sugar. </step>
    <step num="7">Top with whipped cream and strawberries and serve. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Pour the heavy cream into a 9x13-inch (23x33 cm) baking dish. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Mix 1 cup of sugar (200 g) and the cinnamon in a small bowl and add to the cream, followed by the egg yolks and vanilla. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Whisk well to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Dip each slice of bread into the cream mixture, coating both sides well. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Place the dipped bread on the wire rack set over the baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Bake for 15 minutes, flip the bread over, then bake for another 15 minutes, until slightly crispy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Slice the strawberries into decorative shapes of your choosing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">For a strawberry rose, place a strawberry stem side down and carefully make thin slices around the outer edge of the strawberry, making sure not to cut all the way through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Continue cutting and rotating the strawberry until you get to the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Fan out the “petals”. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper and set a wire rack on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">For a strawberry fan, lay a strawberry on its flattest side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Tilt the knife at a 45˚ angle and make thin, angled slices through the strawberry, keeping the top of the strawberry connected and slicing all the way through the bottom of the berry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Fan out the slices. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Sprinkle the remaining sugar on top of the bread and broil on high for 3 minutes, until the sugar has melted and browned, or carefully use a kitchen torch to brûlée the sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Top with whipped cream and strawberries and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>