<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>How To Make The Best Homemade Pizza Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/pizza-dough</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 ½ cups ; warm water ; (600 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 teaspoon ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 teaspoons ; active dry yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">7 cups ; all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (875 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">6 tablespoons ; extra virgin olive oil, plus more for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ teaspoons ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¼ cup ; semolina flour ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">28 oz ; canned whole tomatoes ; (795 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 tablespoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">tomato sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">fresh mozzarella cheese, torn into small pieces </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">fresh basil leaf </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">extra virgin olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">fresh mozzarella cheese, torn into small pieces </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">ricotta cheese </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">fresh basil pesto </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">dried oregano </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">tomato sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">fresh mozzarella cheese, torn into small pieces </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">spicy pepperoni slices </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">freshly grated parmesan cheese </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="6">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/101990/hls24_1531532303.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/101990/landscape_720/1531532303</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">“Bloom” the yeast by sprinkling the sugar and yeast in the warm water. Let sit for 10 minutes, until bubbles form on the surface. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large bowl, combine the flour and salt. Make a well in the middle and add the olive oil and bloomed yeast mixture. Using a spoon, mix until a shaggy dough begins to form. </step>
    <step num="2">Once the flour is mostly hydrated, turn the dough out onto a clean work surface and knead for 10-15 minutes. The dough should be soft, smooth, and bouncy. Form the dough into a taut round. </step>
    <step num="3">Grease a clean, large bowl with olive oil and place the dough inside, turning to coat with the oil. Cover with plastic wrap. Let rise for at least an hour, or up to 24 hours. </step>
    <step num="4">Punch down the dough and turn it out onto a lightly floured work surface. Knead for another minute or so, then cut into 4 equal portions and shape into rounds. </step>
    <step num="5">Lightly flour the dough, then cover with a kitchen towel and let rest for another 30 minutes to an hour while you prepare the sauce and any other ingredients. </step>
    <step num="6">Preheat the oven as high as your oven will allow, between 450-500˚F (230-260˚C). Place a pizza stone, heavy baking sheet (turn upside down so the surface is flat), or cast iron skillet in the oven. </step>
    <step num="7">Meanwhile, make the tomato sauce: Add the salt to the can of tomatoes and puree with an immersion blender, or transfer to a blender or food processor, and puree until smooth. </step>
    <step num="8">Once the dough has rested, take a portion and start by poking the surface with your fingertips, until bubbles form and do not deflate. </step>
    <step num="9">Then, stretch and press the dough into a thin round. Make it thinner than you think it should be, as it will slightly shrink and puff up during baking. </step>
    <step num="10">Sprinkle semolina onto an upside down baking sheet and place the stretched crust onto it. Add the sauce and ingredients of your choice. </step>
    <step num="11">Slide the pizza onto the preheated pizza stone or pan. Bake for 15 minutes, or until the crust and cheese are golden brown. </step>
    <step num="12">Add any garnish of your preference. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">“Bloom” the yeast by sprinkling the sugar and yeast in the warm water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Let sit for 10 minutes, until bubbles form on the surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a large bowl, combine the flour and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Make a well in the middle and add the olive oil and bloomed yeast mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Using a spoon, mix until a shaggy dough begins to form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Once the flour is mostly hydrated, turn the dough out onto a clean work surface and knead for 10-15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">The dough should be soft, smooth, and bouncy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Form the dough into a taut round. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Grease a clean, large bowl with olive oil and place the dough inside, turning to coat with the oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Cover with plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Let rise for at least an hour, or up to 24 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Punch down the dough and turn it out onto a lightly floured work surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Knead for another minute or so, then cut into 4 equal portions and shape into rounds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Lightly flour the dough, then cover with a kitchen towel and let rest for another 30 minutes to an hour while you prepare the sauce and any other ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Preheat the oven as high as your oven will allow, between 450-500˚F (230-260˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Place a pizza stone, heavy baking sheet (turn upside down so the surface is flat), or cast iron skillet in the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Meanwhile, make the tomato sauce: Add the salt to the can of tomatoes and puree with an immersion blender, or transfer to a blender or food processor, and puree until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Once the dough has rested, take a portion and start by poking the surface with your fingertips, until bubbles form and do not deflate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Then, stretch and press the dough into a thin round. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Make it thinner than you think it should be, as it will slightly shrink and puff up during baking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Sprinkle semolina onto an upside down baking sheet and place the stretched crust onto it. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Add the sauce and ingredients of your choice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Slide the pizza onto the preheated pizza stone or pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Bake for 15 minutes, or until the crust and cheese are golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Add any garnish of your preference. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>