<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>How To Make A Croquembouche (Cream Puff Tower) Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/croquembouche</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">6 cups ; milk ; (1 ½ L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ; vanilla beans, scraped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">18 ; egg yolks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 ¼ cups ; sugar ; (450 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¾ cup ; cornstarch ; (95 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 tablespoons ; butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">4 cups ; water ; (945 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">4 sticks ; butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 teaspoons ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">6 tablespoons ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">4 cups ; flour ; (500 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">12 ; eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">egg wash </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 cups ; sugar ; (400 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 tablespoons ; dark corn syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">⅔ cup ; water ; (160 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">⅔ cup ; heavy cream ; (160 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">French</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/70027/hls24_1513990673.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/70027/landscape_720/1513990673</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 425˚F (220˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">In a pot, heat the milk and vanilla bean pod and seeds over medium heat, bringing it to a boil. Once it begins to boil, turn off the heat and let steep for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Using a hand mixer, beat the egg yolks and sugar until light and fluffy, about 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the cornstarch and mix until fully incorporated. </step>
    <step num="4">Remove the vanilla bean pod from the milk. Add ½ cup (120 ml) of the milk to the egg yolk mixture and mix until well combined. Add the remaining milk mixture and beat until fully incorporated. </step>
    <step num="5">Over medium heat, whisk the mixture constantly until thickened, about 7-10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Remove from the heat and add the butter, whisking to combine. </step>
    <step num="7">Strain the custard into a bowl to ensure a creamy custard (optional). Cover the custard with plastic wrap, making sure that the plastic touches the custard, and chill for at least 2 hour. </step>
    <step num="8">In a large pot, bring the water, butter, salt, and sugar to a boil over high heat. </step>
    <step num="9">Once the water begins to boil, remove the pot from the heat and immediately add the flour, stirring constantly with a wooden spoon until the liquid is absorbed and the mixture begins to form a ball. </step>
    <step num="10">Return the pot to the heat and cook for another 30 seconds to remove excess moisture. Remove the pot from the heat. </step>
    <step num="11">Working quickly, add the eggs, one at a time, stirring until fully incorporated. Continue stirring until the dough starts to pull away from the sides of the pan and is thick and glossy. Alternatively, you can use a stand mixer with the paddle attachment. </step>
    <step num="12">Using a piping bag with a standard round tip, fill the bag with the batter. </step>
    <step num="13">Place 1-inch (2 cm) dollops on a parchment paper-lined baking sheet, spaced at least 1-inch (2 cm) apart. </step>
    <step num="14">Use a wet fingertip to gently press down any points on the puffs. Brush the egg wash over the the puffs. </step>
    <step num="15">Bake for 15 minutes. Reduce heat to 375˚F (190˚C), and bake for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="16">Let puffs cool completely. </step>
    <step num="17">Use the bottom of a wooden skewer to create an opening in the bottom of the cream puff shells, just big enough for a piping tip to insert. </step>
    <step num="18">Fill a piping bag fitting with a small round tip with the custard. Gently fill the puff shells with the custard. </step>
    <step num="19">Add the sugar, corn syrup, and water to a pan over medium heat. Bring to a boil and put the lid on, cooking for 5 minutes without moving. Remove the lid and cook for an additional 7-10 minutes, until the caramel is a deep amber color and reaches 300˚F (150˚C). </step>
    <step num="20">Remove the pan from the heat and add the heavy cream, stirring vigorously. </step>
    <step num="21">Working quickly, dip the cream puffs into the caramel and arrange on a serving platter in a circular pattern. </step>
    <step num="22">Continue to stack caramel-dipped cream puffs in a tower shape. </step>
    <step num="23">Once your tower is completed, dip a fork into the caramel sauce and drizzle it around the tower. </step>
    <step num="24">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 425˚F (220˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a pot, heat the milk and vanilla bean pod and seeds over medium heat, bringing it to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Once it begins to boil, turn off the heat and let steep for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Using a hand mixer, beat the egg yolks and sugar until light and fluffy, about 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the cornstarch and mix until fully incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Remove the vanilla bean pod from the milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add ½ cup (120 ml) of the milk to the egg yolk mixture and mix until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the remaining milk mixture and beat until fully incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Over medium heat, whisk the mixture constantly until thickened, about 7-10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove from the heat and add the butter, whisking to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Strain the custard into a bowl to ensure a creamy custard (optional). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cover the custard with plastic wrap, making sure that the plastic touches the custard, and chill for at least 2 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">In a large pot, bring the water, butter, salt, and sugar to a boil over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Once the water begins to boil, remove the pot from the heat and immediately add the flour, stirring constantly with a wooden spoon until the liquid is absorbed and the mixture begins to form a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Return the pot to the heat and cook for another 30 seconds to remove excess moisture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove the pot from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Working quickly, add the eggs, one at a time, stirring until fully incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Continue stirring until the dough starts to pull away from the sides of the pan and is thick and glossy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Alternatively, you can use a stand mixer with the paddle attachment. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Using a piping bag with a standard round tip, fill the bag with the batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Place 1-inch (2 cm) dollops on a parchment paper-lined baking sheet, spaced at least 1-inch (2 cm) apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Use a wet fingertip to gently press down any points on the puffs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Brush the egg wash over the the puffs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Bake for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Reduce heat to 375˚F (190˚C), and bake for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Let puffs cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Use the bottom of a wooden skewer to create an opening in the bottom of the cream puff shells, just big enough for a piping tip to insert. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Fill a piping bag fitting with a small round tip with the custard. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Gently fill the puff shells with the custard. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Add the sugar, corn syrup, and water to a pan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Bring to a boil and put the lid on, cooking for 5 minutes without moving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Remove the lid and cook for an additional 7-10 minutes, until the caramel is a deep amber color and reaches 300˚F (150˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Remove the pan from the heat and add the heavy cream, stirring vigorously. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Working quickly, dip the cream puffs into the caramel and arrange on a serving platter in a circular pattern. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Continue to stack caramel-dipped cream puffs in a tower shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Once your tower is completed, dip a fork into the caramel sauce and drizzle it around the tower. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>