<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Dairy-Free Pumpkin Spice Panna Cotta Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/dairy-free-pumpkin-spice-panna-cotta</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>nan</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¾ cup ; raw cashews ; (95 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">warm water, for soaking </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">coconut oil, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ¼ cups ; water ; (300 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 pinch of ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">6 tablespoons ; maple syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">⅓ cup ; unsweetened pumpkin puree ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 tablespoon ; pumpkin spice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ cup ; hot water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; agar agar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">ground cinnamon, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">cinnamon stick, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="3">Vegan</category>
    <category num="4">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="5">Desserts</category>
    <category num="6">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="7">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/118145/hls24_1543952614.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/118145/landscape_720/1543952614</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>114.333</start_time>
    <end_time>204.416</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Add the cashews to a medium bowl. Pour in enough warm water to completely cover the cashews, then soak for at least 2 hours, or overnight. Drain. </step>
    <step num="1">Grease 4 4-ounce ramekins with coconut oil and set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the cashews to a blender with the water and a pinch of salt. Blend on high speed for 2 minutes, or until very creamy. </step>
    <step num="3">In a medium saucepan over medium-low heat, combine the cashew cream, maple syrup, pumpkin puree, and pumpkin spice. Warm slowly, stirring occasionally, until the sugar is dissolved and the mixture is simmering. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the agar agar to hot water and stir until there are no lumps and the agar agar is fully dissolved. </step>
    <step num="5">Pour the agar mixture into the warm cashew cream and whisk to combine. Increase the heat to medium, bring to a gentle boil, and whisk continuously for 3 minutes, until thickened. Remove from the heat and immediately divide between the greased ramekins. Smooth the tops. </step>
    <step num="6">Refrigerate for at least 30 minutes. (The agar will set at room temperature, but chilling the panna cotta in the fridge will expedite the process.) </step>
    <step num="7">When ready to serve, use an offset spatula or butter knife to carefully work around the edges of the ramekins to loosen the panna cotta. Invert onto serving plates and garnish with ground cinnamon and cinnamon sticks. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Add the cashews to a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pour in enough warm water to completely cover the cashews, then soak for at least 2 hours, or overnight. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Grease 4 4-ounce ramekins with coconut oil and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the cashews to a blender with the water and a pinch of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Blend on high speed for 2 minutes, or until very creamy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a medium saucepan over medium-low heat, combine the cashew cream, maple syrup, pumpkin puree, and pumpkin spice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Warm slowly, stirring occasionally, until the sugar is dissolved and the mixture is simmering. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the agar agar to hot water and stir until there are no lumps and the agar agar is fully dissolved. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Pour the agar mixture into the warm cashew cream and whisk to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Increase the heat to medium, bring to a gentle boil, and whisk continuously for 3 minutes, until thickened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove from the heat and immediately divide between the greased ramekins. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Smooth the tops. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Refrigerate for at least 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">(The agar will set at room temperature, but chilling the panna cotta in the fridge will expedite the process.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">When ready to serve, use an offset spatula or butter knife to carefully work around the edges of the ramekins to loosen the panna cotta. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Invert onto serving plates and garnish with ground cinnamon and cinnamon sticks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>