<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Jam-Stuffed Peanut Butter Balls Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/jam-stuffed-peanut-butter-balls</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; peanut butter, creamy or chunky ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; quick-cook oats, plus more for coating ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; powdered sugar ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; strawberry jam, to taste, or whatever your favorite jam is </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Low-Carb</category>
    <category num="4">Vegan</category>
    <category num="5">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="6">Desserts</category>
    <category num="7">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="8">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="9">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32165/low_1495125411.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/32165/mp4_720x1280/1495125411</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Using a small spoon or a teaspoon measuring spoon, scoop out balls of jam and lay them on a sheet pan or plate lined with parchment paper. Pop the jam balls in the freezer for around a half hour, or until they’ve firmed up a bit. </step>
    <step num="1">In a mixing bowl, combine the peanut butter, one cup of oats, and powdered sugar, and mix them all together until they’re well combined. </step>
    <step num="2">Grab a palmful of the peanut butter mixture (around the size of a golf ball) and then, using your hand and fingers, shape it into a mini pancake. </step>
    <step num="3">Grab one of the firmed-up jam balls and twist it around until it’s even more of a sphere, then lay it in the middle of your mini peanut butter pancake. </step>
    <step num="4">Using your fingers, lift up and pinch the edges of the peanut butter so that they’re coming up around the jam ball. Continue this until the peanut butter mixture totally encloses the jam and you’ve created a ball. Roll each ball in your hands so that it’s nice a smooth. </step>
    <step num="5">Once you’ve created all of the balls, roll each one in oats and then pop in the refrigerator or freezer to chill. (If you’re freezing, make sure to bring the balls back to room temperature before serving). </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Using a small spoon or a teaspoon measuring spoon, scoop out balls of jam and lay them on a sheet pan or plate lined with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pop the jam balls in the freezer for around a half hour, or until they’ve firmed up a bit. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a mixing bowl, combine the peanut butter, one cup of oats, and powdered sugar, and mix them all together until they’re well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Grab a palmful of the peanut butter mixture (around the size of a golf ball) and then, using your hand and fingers, shape it into a mini pancake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Grab one of the firmed-up jam balls and twist it around until it’s even more of a sphere, then lay it in the middle of your mini peanut butter pancake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Using your fingers, lift up and pinch the edges of the peanut butter so that they’re coming up around the jam ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Continue this until the peanut butter mixture totally encloses the jam and you’ve created a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Roll each ball in your hands so that it’s nice a smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Once you’ve created all of the balls, roll each one in oats and then pop in the refrigerator or freezer to chill. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">(If you’re freezing, make sure to bring the balls back to room temperature before serving). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>