<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Country Fried Steak And Gravy Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/country-fried-steak-and-gravy</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">8 oz ; cube steak, 4 steaks, 8 oz (225 g) each ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ½ teaspoons ; kosher salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; black pepper, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 ¾ cups ; whole milk, divided ; (660 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ cups ; all-purpose flour, divided, plus 3 tablespoons ; (190 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; onion powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; vegetable oil ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">3 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ cup ; heavy cream ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Date Night</category>
    <category num="4">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/132194/hls24_1557425801.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/132194/landscape_720/1557425801</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 225˚F (110˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Set a steak in the center of a cutting board and cover with a piece of plastic wrap. Using a meat mallet, pound the steak evenly to ¼-inch (½ cm) thick. Season with salt and pepper on both sides. Repeat with the remaining meat. </step>
    <step num="2">In a wide, shallow dish, whisk together the eggs and 1 cup (240 ml) of milk. In a separate shallow dish, mix together the 1 ½ cups (190 g) of flour, pepper, salt, garlic powder, onion powder, and paprika. </step>
    <step num="3">Dredge the steaks in the flour mixture, then dip in the egg mixture, letting any excess egg drip off. Coat again in the flour mixture. Set aside for 10-15 minutes, until the coating has dried out a bit. </step>
    <step num="4">Meanwhile, heat the oil in a 10-inch (25.5 cm) pan over medium-high heat until it reaches 375˚F (190˚C). </step>
    <step num="5">Fry the steaks, 2 at a time, for 3 minutes, until golden brown and crispy. Flip and cook on the other side for 3 minutes more, until golden brown and cooked through when the internal temperature reaches 155˚-165˚F (170˚-175˚C). Transfer the steaks to a paper towel-lined plate or baking sheet and immediately season with salt. Once all of the steaks are done frying, transfer to the oven while you prepare the gravy. </step>
    <step num="6">Pour the hot oil into a heatproof bowl and let cool before discarding. 9. Leave any browned bits in the pan. </step>
    <step num="7">In the same pan, without wiping it out, melt the butter over medium heat. Add the remaining 3 tablespoons of flour, whisking to incorporate. Cook for 2-3 minutes, until the roux is a light brown color. Add the heavy cream and remaining milk. Bring to a simmer and cook, whisking constantly, until thickened, 5-7 minutes. Season with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="8">Ladle the gravy over the steaks and serve with your favorite side dishes. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 225˚F (110˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Set a steak in the center of a cutting board and cover with a piece of plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Using a meat mallet, pound the steak evenly to ¼-inch (½ cm) thick. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Season with salt and pepper on both sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Repeat with the remaining meat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In a wide, shallow dish, whisk together the eggs and 1 cup (240 ml) of milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a separate shallow dish, mix together the 1 ½ cups (190 g) of flour, pepper, salt, garlic powder, onion powder, and paprika. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Dredge the steaks in the flour mixture, then dip in the egg mixture, letting any excess egg drip off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Coat again in the flour mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Set aside for 10-15 minutes, until the coating has dried out a bit. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Meanwhile, heat the oil in a 10-inch (25.5 cm) pan over medium-high heat until it reaches 375˚F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Fry the steaks, 2 at a time, for 3 minutes, until golden brown and crispy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Flip and cook on the other side for 3 minutes more, until golden brown and cooked through when the internal temperature reaches 155˚-165˚F (170˚-175˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Transfer the steaks to a paper towel-lined plate or baking sheet and immediately season with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Once all of the steaks are done frying, transfer to the oven while you prepare the gravy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Pour the hot oil into a heatproof bowl and let cool before discarding. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">9. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Leave any browned bits in the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">In the same pan, without wiping it out, melt the butter over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Add the remaining 3 tablespoons of flour, whisking to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Cook for 2-3 minutes, until the roux is a light brown color. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Add the heavy cream and remaining milk. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Bring to a simmer and cook, whisking constantly, until thickened, 5-7 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Ladle the gravy over the steaks and serve with your favorite side dishes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>