<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Flower Sushi Roll Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/flower-sushi-roll</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ cups ; cooked sushi rice ; (345 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ tablespoon ; sesame seed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">3.5 oz ; spicy cod roe ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 sheets ; dried seaweed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">⅓ ; cucumber, julienned </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; cheese-stuffed fish cake </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; vinegar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 tablespoon ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Japanese</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Appetizers</category>
    <category num="3">Date Night</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/33029/low_1496163062.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/33029/mp4_720x1280/1496163062</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium bowl, add the vinegar, sugar, and salt to the cooked rice, and stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="1">Transfer half of the rice to another medium bowl. To one bowl, add the sesame seeds and stir to combine. To the other bowl of rice, add the spicy cod roe, and stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="2">Cut one sheet of seaweed into six equal rectangles. </step>
    <step num="3">Put one of the cut seaweed sheets on a bamboo mat (makisu). Add two teaspoons of the cod roe rice on the seaweed, and roll into a cylinder. Repeat to make five rolls total. </step>
    <step num="4">Transfer the rolls to the bamboo mat, placing the cheese-stuffed fish cake in the center. Use the bamboo mat to roll the rolls into one cylinder. Place pieces of cucumber between the cod roe-filled rolls. </step>
    <step num="5">Use the remaining cut seaweed sheet to wrap around the cylinders, bundling them together. </step>
    <step num="6">On the large sheet of seaweed, use a spoon to evenly spread the sesame rice. Add the bundled flower roll to the bottom edge of the rice-covered seaweed sheet, and gently roll up. </step>
    <step num="7">Cut the sushi into four equal sections. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium bowl, add the vinegar, sugar, and salt to the cooked rice, and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Transfer half of the rice to another medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">To one bowl, add the sesame seeds and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">To the other bowl of rice, add the spicy cod roe, and stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Cut one sheet of seaweed into six equal rectangles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Put one of the cut seaweed sheets on a bamboo mat (makisu). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add two teaspoons of the cod roe rice on the seaweed, and roll into a cylinder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Repeat to make five rolls total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Transfer the rolls to the bamboo mat, placing the cheese-stuffed fish cake in the center. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Use the bamboo mat to roll the rolls into one cylinder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place pieces of cucumber between the cod roe-filled rolls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Use the remaining cut seaweed sheet to wrap around the cylinders, bundling them together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">On the large sheet of seaweed, use a spoon to evenly spread the sesame rice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add the bundled flower roll to the bottom edge of the rice-covered seaweed sheet, and gently roll up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Cut the sushi into four equal sections. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>