<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Meal-Prep Garlic Chicken And Veggie Pasta Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/meal-prep-garlic-chicken-and-veggie-pasta</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 tablespoons ; olive oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 lb ; chicken breast, diced ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ; carrots, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 ; zucchini, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ; yellow squash, sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">4 cups ; kale, chopped ; (270 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">3 cups ; whole grain whole wheat rotini pasta, cooked al dente according to package instructions ; (600 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 teaspoons ; oregano, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 teaspoons ; salt, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 teaspoons ; pepper, divided </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Italian</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
    <category num="3">Lunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/16083/low_1480447476.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/16083/mp4_720x1280/1480447476</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Heat a large skillet with 2 tablespoons of olive oil on medium-high heat. </step>
    <step num="1">Add in diced chicken breast, followed by 1 teaspoon salt, 1 teaspoon pepper, and 1 teaspoon oregano. Cook until no longer pink. Remove chicken from skillet and set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">Add carrots to skillet and sauté for 2-3 minutes until tender. </step>
    <step num="3">Add in zucchini and yellow squash, and sauté for an additional minute until they become slightly translucent. </step>
    <step num="4">Add in the kale, followed by 2 tablespoons olive oil, 1 teaspoon salt, and 1 teaspoon pepper. Sauté until kale begins to wilt. </step>
    <step num="5">Move veggies aside with spatula and add in garlic. Sauté for about 30 seconds and then combine with the veggies. (This works best if you add garlic to the center of the skillet where there is more heat.) </step>
    <step num="6">Add in the cooked rotini pasta and chicken, followed by 1 teaspoon oregano and mix until evenly incorporated. Remove skillet from heat. </step>
    <step num="7">If using plastic tupperware for your weekday meal prep, allow pasta to cool for about 10 minutes before filling the containers. Refrigerate up to 4 days. </step>
    <step num="8">Or serve immediately for a family dinner. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Heat a large skillet with 2 tablespoons of olive oil on medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add in diced chicken breast, followed by 1 teaspoon salt, 1 teaspoon pepper, and 1 teaspoon oregano. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cook until no longer pink. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Remove chicken from skillet and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add carrots to skillet and sauté for 2-3 minutes until tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add in zucchini and yellow squash, and sauté for an additional minute until they become slightly translucent. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add in the kale, followed by 2 tablespoons olive oil, 1 teaspoon salt, and 1 teaspoon pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Sauté until kale begins to wilt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Move veggies aside with spatula and add in garlic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Sauté for about 30 seconds and then combine with the veggies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">(This works best if you add garlic to the center of the skillet where there is more heat.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add in the cooked rotini pasta and chicken, followed by 1 teaspoon oregano and mix until evenly incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove skillet from heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">If using plastic tupperware for your weekday meal prep, allow pasta to cool for about 10 minutes before filling the containers. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Refrigerate up to 4 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Or serve immediately for a family dinner. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>