<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Dark Chocolate Peanut Butter Cups Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/dark-chocolate-peanut-butter-cups</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">12 oz ; dark chocolate ; (340 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">7 tablespoons ; coconut oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; peanut butter, or nut butter of choice ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; honey ; (84 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">hemp hearts, for garnish, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">muffin tin </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Snacks</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/125031/hls24_1550189068.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/125031/landscape_720/1550189068</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a microwave-safe bowl, combine the dark chocolate and 5 tablespoons of coconut oil. Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until melted. Add the vanilla and stir until combined. The mixture should be smooth and pourable. </step>
    <step num="1">Pour ½ of the chocolate mixture into the molds, enough to cover the bottom of the mold and come about ⅓ of the way up the sides. Freeze for 15 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">In another microwave safe bowl, mix together the peanut butter, honey, and remaining 2 tablespoons of coconut oil. Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until smooth and pourable. </step>
    <step num="3">Pour the peanut butter mixture evenly over the chocolate layers in the molds. Make sure to leave enough room for the second layer of chocolate. Freeze for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Pour the remaining chocolate on top of the peanut butter layer, up to the rims of the molds. Wipe off any excess that spills over the edges. If desired, sprinkle the cups with hemp hearts for added crunch. Freeze for 1 hour, until set, then pop out of the molds. </step>
    <step num="5">The cups will keep in the refrigerator for up to 1 month. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a microwave-safe bowl, combine the dark chocolate and 5 tablespoons of coconut oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the vanilla and stir until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">The mixture should be smooth and pourable. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour ½ of the chocolate mixture into the molds, enough to cover the bottom of the mold and come about ⅓ of the way up the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Freeze for 15 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In another microwave safe bowl, mix together the peanut butter, honey, and remaining 2 tablespoons of coconut oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Microwave in 30-second intervals, stirring in between, until smooth and pourable. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Pour the peanut butter mixture evenly over the chocolate layers in the molds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Make sure to leave enough room for the second layer of chocolate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Freeze for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Pour the remaining chocolate on top of the peanut butter layer, up to the rims of the molds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Wipe off any excess that spills over the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">If desired, sprinkle the cups with hemp hearts for added crunch. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Freeze for 1 hour, until set, then pop out of the molds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">The cups will keep in the refrigerator for up to 1 month. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>