<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Sheet Tray Puff Pastry Pockets Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/sheet-tray-puff-pastry-pockets</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">4 sheets ; puff pastry </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ lb ; ground beef ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; russet potato, diced ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; tomato, diced ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; taco seasoning </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">¼ cup ; water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; shredded mexican cheese blend ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; grated parmesan cheese ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ cup ; mozzarella cheese ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ cup ; shredded provolone cheese ; (25 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; ricotta cheese ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¼ teaspoon ; italian seasoning </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">¼ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ cup ; shredded cheddar cheese ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 ; eggs, scrambled </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">6 slices ; bacon, cooked </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">2 tablespoons ; pizza sauce </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">½ cup ; shredded mozzarella cheese ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">10 slices ; pepperoni </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">1 ; egg, beaten </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="3">Lunch</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/82402/hls24_1520274446.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/82402/landscape_720/1520274446</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a skillet over medium-high heat, add the ground beef, potatoes, tomatoes, and taco seasoning. Cook until the beef begins to brown. Then add the water, cover with a lid, and let simmer for 10 minutes. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">Preheat oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </step>
    <step num="2">In a bowl, mix together parmesan, mozzarella, provolone, ricotta, Italian seasoning, and salt. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">Flour a clean working surface and place two sheets of puff pastry next to one another, slightly overlapping on the edge. Press overlapping edges together firmly and roll out with a rolling pin to match the size of an 18x13-inch (45x30-cm) sheet tray. Repeat with two more sheets of puff pastry and set aside under a slightly damp towel until you’re ready to start assembling. </step>
    <step num="4">To assemble, spray an 18x13-inch (45x30-cm) sheet tray with cooking spray and place one of the big pieces of puff pastry on the sheet. Press the dough into the corners. </step>
    <step num="5">Divide the sheet tray into eight sections. First, place half of the four-cheese mixture onto the dough and shape into a small rectangle that takes up about ⅛ of the sheet pan, leaving about half an inch from the edges of the corner of the pan. Repeat below with the rest of the four-cheese mixture. </step>
    <step num="6">Next to the four-cheese pockets, make a rectangle with cheddar, followed by scrambled eggs, bacon, and more cheddar on top. Repeat for another egg, bacon, and cheese-flavored pocket. </step>
    <step num="7">Then, sprinkle some Mexican blend cheese in the shape of a rectangle, followed by the cooked taco meat, and topped with more Mexican blend cheese. Repeat for another taco-flavored pocket. </step>
    <step num="8">Lastly, spread some pizza sauce in a rectangle shape and top with mozzarella cheese, pepperoni, and a little more cheese on top. Repeat for another pizza-flavored pocket. </step>
    <step num="9">Using a pastry brush, brush around each rectangle with egg wash. Cover the whole sheet pan with the other puff pastry sheet and press firmly down in between each rectangle to seal and form an isolated pocket. </step>
    <step num="10">Once those feel secure, cut the dough into 8 rectangular pockets, and remove any excess dough from the sides. Using a fork, poke each pocket 4 times for ventilation and brush each pocket with egg wash. </step>
    <step num="11">Bake for 28-30 minutes, or until the top is golden brown and the pockets have puffed up. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a skillet over medium-high heat, add the ground beef, potatoes, tomatoes, and taco seasoning. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cook until the beef begins to brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Then add the water, cover with a lid, and let simmer for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Preheat oven to 375˚F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In a bowl, mix together parmesan, mozzarella, provolone, ricotta, Italian seasoning, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Flour a clean working surface and place two sheets of puff pastry next to one another, slightly overlapping on the edge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Press overlapping edges together firmly and roll out with a rolling pin to match the size of an 18x13-inch (45x30-cm) sheet tray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Repeat with two more sheets of puff pastry and set aside under a slightly damp towel until you’re ready to start assembling. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">To assemble, spray an 18x13-inch (45x30-cm) sheet tray with cooking spray and place one of the big pieces of puff pastry on the sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Press the dough into the corners. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Divide the sheet tray into eight sections. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">First, place half of the four-cheese mixture onto the dough and shape into a small rectangle that takes up about ⅛ of the sheet pan, leaving about half an inch from the edges of the corner of the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Repeat below with the rest of the four-cheese mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Next to the four-cheese pockets, make a rectangle with cheddar, followed by scrambled eggs, bacon, and more cheddar on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Repeat for another egg, bacon, and cheese-flavored pocket. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Then, sprinkle some Mexican blend cheese in the shape of a rectangle, followed by the cooked taco meat, and topped with more Mexican blend cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Repeat for another taco-flavored pocket. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Lastly, spread some pizza sauce in a rectangle shape and top with mozzarella cheese, pepperoni, and a little more cheese on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Repeat for another pizza-flavored pocket. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Using a pastry brush, brush around each rectangle with egg wash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Cover the whole sheet pan with the other puff pastry sheet and press firmly down in between each rectangle to seal and form an isolated pocket. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Once those feel secure, cut the dough into 8 rectangular pockets, and remove any excess dough from the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Using a fork, poke each pocket 4 times for ventilation and brush each pocket with egg wash. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Bake for 28-30 minutes, or until the top is golden brown and the pockets have puffed up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>