<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Crunchy California Roll Sushi Bowl Recipe By Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/crunchy-california-roll-sushi-bowl</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; water ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; sushi rice, rinsed until the water runs clear ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ cup ; rice vinegar ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 tablespoon ; canola oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">⅓ cup ; panko breadcrumbs ; (15 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ teaspoon ; pepper, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ cup ; mayonnaise ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 tablespoon ; siracha </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">16 oz ; crab, 2 cans, drained ; (455 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ; persian cucumber, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">4 ; radishes, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 tablespoons ; nori, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 bunch ; scallion, thinly sliced on the bias </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 tablespoon ; sesame seed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">2 tablespoons ; pickled ginger </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">1 ; avocado, diced </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dinner</category>
    <category num="1">Date Night</category>
    <category num="2">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/119634/hls24_1544739524.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/119634/landscape_720/1544739524</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a small pot, season the water with a pinch of salt. Bring to a boil over high heat. Add the rinsed rice and return to a boil. Cover, reduce the heat to simmer, and cook for 20 minutes, until the water is absorbed and the rice is tender. </step>
    <step num="1">In a small bowl, stir together the sugar, salt, and rice vinegar. Microwave for 2 minutes, or until the sugar dissolves. </step>
    <step num="2">Transfer the cooked rice to a medium bowl and pour the vinegar mixture over it, then stir well using a wooden spoon. </step>
    <step num="3">Heat the canola oil in a medium pan over medium-high heat. Once the oil begins to shimmer, add the panko and cook, stirring frequently, until golden brown, 1-2 minutes. Season with salt and pepper, and remove from the heat. </step>
    <step num="4">In a small bowl, stir together the mayonnaise and Sriracha until smooth. </step>
    <step num="5">To assemble the bowls, divide the seasoned rice between 2 serving bowls. Top with the crab, crispy panko, cucumber, radish, nori, scallions, sesame seeds, pickled ginger, and avocado. Drizzle the Sriracha mayonnaise over the top. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a small pot, season the water with a pinch of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Bring to a boil over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the rinsed rice and return to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cover, reduce the heat to simmer, and cook for 20 minutes, until the water is absorbed and the rice is tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a small bowl, stir together the sugar, salt, and rice vinegar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Microwave for 2 minutes, or until the sugar dissolves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Transfer the cooked rice to a medium bowl and pour the vinegar mixture over it, then stir well using a wooden spoon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Heat the canola oil in a medium pan over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Once the oil begins to shimmer, add the panko and cook, stirring frequently, until golden brown, 1-2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Season with salt and pepper, and remove from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a small bowl, stir together the mayonnaise and Sriracha until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">To assemble the bowls, divide the seasoned rice between 2 serving bowls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Top with the crab, crispy panko, cucumber, radish, nori, scallions, sesame seeds, pickled ginger, and avocado. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Drizzle the Sriracha mayonnaise over the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>