<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Easily The Best Garlic Herb Roasted Potatoes Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/easily-the-best-garlic-herb-roasted-potatoes</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">13 ; russet potatoes, cut into 1-inch (2 1/2 cm) pieces </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 teaspoon ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; olive oil ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 tablespoons ; fresh rosemary, or fresh thyme, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 small handful ; fresh parsley leaf, minced to garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="5">Brunch</category>
    <category num="6">Kid-Friendly</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/33063/low_1496182080.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/33063/mp4_720x1280/1496182080</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 425°F (220°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Fill a large pot with water and boil. Add salt, baking soda, and potatoes, and stir. </step>
    <step num="2">Return to a boil, reduce to a simmer, and cook for 10 minutes after returning to a boil. A fork should easily pierce the potato pieces by the end. Drain and let sit one minute while moisture evaporates. </step>
    <step num="3">Combine olive oil, rosemary (or thyme), garlic, and a few grinds of black pepper in a small saucepan and heat over medium heat. Stir constantly until garlic just begins to turn golden, about 2-3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Immediately strain oil through a fine-mesh strainer over the potatoes. Add salt and pepper to taste, and mix. </step>
    <step num="5">Shake the pot that the potatoes are in so that they slam against all sides of the pot, this will loosen the outer layer of the potatoes to form a mashed layer around each potato piece. </step>
    <step num="6">Transfer potatoes to a large rimmed baking sheet and separate them, spreading them out evenly. </step>
    <step num="7">Transfer to oven and roast, without moving, for 30-35 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Using a thin, flexible metal spatula flip potatoes. Continue roasting until potatoes are deep brown and crisp all over, turning and shaking them a few times during cooking, 30 to 40 minutes longer. </step>
    <step num="9">Transfer potatoes to a large bowl and add the garlic-rosemary mixture (optional) and minced parsley. Toss to coat and season with more salt and pepper to taste. Serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 425°F (220°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Fill a large pot with water and boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add salt, baking soda, and potatoes, and stir. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Return to a boil, reduce to a simmer, and cook for 10 minutes after returning to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">A fork should easily pierce the potato pieces by the end. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Drain and let sit one minute while moisture evaporates. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Combine olive oil, rosemary (or thyme), garlic, and a few grinds of black pepper in a small saucepan and heat over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Stir constantly until garlic just begins to turn golden, about 2-3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Immediately strain oil through a fine-mesh strainer over the potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Add salt and pepper to taste, and mix. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Shake the pot that the potatoes are in so that they slam against all sides of the pot, this will loosen the outer layer of the potatoes to form a mashed layer around each potato piece. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Transfer potatoes to a large rimmed baking sheet and separate them, spreading them out evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Transfer to oven and roast, without moving, for 30-35 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Using a thin, flexible metal spatula flip potatoes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Continue roasting until potatoes are deep brown and crisp all over, turning and shaking them a few times during cooking, 30 to 40 minutes longer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Transfer potatoes to a large bowl and add the garlic-rosemary mixture (optional) and minced parsley. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Toss to coat and season with more salt and pepper to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>