<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Thanksgiving Leftover Pizza 2 Ways Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/thanksgiving-leftover-pizza-2-ways</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 tablespoon ; active dry yeast </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 tablespoon ; honey, or maple syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">⅔ cup ; warm water ; (160 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; whole wheat flour ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ½ tablespoons ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; warm water ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 ½ cups ; whole wheat flour, plus more for dusting ; (325 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">olive oil, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">semolina flour, for sprinkling </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; gravy ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 cup ; stuffing ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 ½ cups ; shredded turkey ; (185 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 cup ; shredded cheese, of your choice ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">5 sprigs ; fresh rosemary, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 ½ cups ; cranberry sauce ; (415 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">water, as needed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">1 cup ; mashed sweet potato ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">1 cup ; brussel sprout, cooked ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">⅓ cup ; goat cheese ; (75 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/116192/hls24_1542736450.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/116192/landscape_720/1542736450</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the sponge: Stir together the yeast, honey or maple syrup, water, and flour together in a medium bowl. Some lumps are okay. Cover with a kitchen towel and let sit in a warm place for 20-30 minutes, until foamy and expanded in volume. </step>
    <step num="1">To finish the dough, add the salt, olive oil, and warm water to the bowl with the sponge. Add the flour in ½-cup (60 g) increments, stirring to incorporate each addition before adding the next, until the dough comes together enough to knead with your hands. Knead in the bowl briefly, until most of the flour in the bowl is incorporated. </step>
    <step num="2">Turn the dough out onto a floured surface and continue kneading, adding more flour as needed, until it is soft, pliable, and does not stick to your hands, 8-10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Transfer the dough to a clean bowl lightly greased with olive oil. Cover with a towel and let rise in a warm place for 40 minutes, or until doubled in volume. </step>
    <step num="4">Preheat the oven to 475˚F (240˚C). </step>
    <step num="5">Remove the dough from the bowl and punch down. Cut in half. Dust a piece of dough with flour and roll out to about a 13x18-inch (33x46-cm) rectangle or oval.  Repeat with the remaining dough portion if making 2 pizzas, or wrap the leftover dough tightly in plastic wrap and keep in the fridge for up to 3 days. </step>
    <step num="6">Drizzle a baking sheet with olive oil and sprinkle with semolina flour. Transfer the rolled out dough to the baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="7">Add your toppings of choice. For a gravy, turkey, and stuffing pizza, spread the gravy over the pizza dough. Top with the stuffing, turkey, cheese, and rosemary, if using. </step>
    <step num="8">For a cranberry sauce, Brussels sprout, and sweet potato pizza, add the cranberry sauce to a blender with a bit of water and puree until smooth. </step>
    <step num="9">Spread over the pizza dough and top with dollops of mashed sweet potato, the Brussels sprouts, and spoonfuls of the goat cheese. </step>
    <step num="10">Bake the pizza for 12-15 minutes, until the dough is crispy and golden brown and the toppings are warmed through. </step>
    <step num="11">Slice and serve immediately. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the sponge: Stir together the yeast, honey or maple syrup, water, and flour together in a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Some lumps are okay. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cover with a kitchen towel and let sit in a warm place for 20-30 minutes, until foamy and expanded in volume. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">To finish the dough, add the salt, olive oil, and warm water to the bowl with the sponge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the flour in ½-cup (60 g) increments, stirring to incorporate each addition before adding the next, until the dough comes together enough to knead with your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Knead in the bowl briefly, until most of the flour in the bowl is incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Turn the dough out onto a floured surface and continue kneading, adding more flour as needed, until it is soft, pliable, and does not stick to your hands, 8-10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Transfer the dough to a clean bowl lightly greased with olive oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Cover with a towel and let rise in a warm place for 40 minutes, or until doubled in volume. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Preheat the oven to 475˚F (240˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Remove the dough from the bowl and punch down. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cut in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Dust a piece of dough with flour and roll out to about a 13x18-inch (33x46-cm) rectangle or oval. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Repeat with the remaining dough portion if making 2 pizzas, or wrap the leftover dough tightly in plastic wrap and keep in the fridge for up to 3 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Drizzle a baking sheet with olive oil and sprinkle with semolina flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Transfer the rolled out dough to the baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add your toppings of choice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">For a gravy, turkey, and stuffing pizza, spread the gravy over the pizza dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Top with the stuffing, turkey, cheese, and rosemary, if using. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">For a cranberry sauce, Brussels sprout, and sweet potato pizza, add the cranberry sauce to a blender with a bit of water and puree until smooth </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Spread over the pizza dough and top with dollops of mashed sweet potato, the Brussels sprouts, and spoonfuls of the goat cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Bake the pizza for 12-15 minutes, until the dough is crispy and golden brown and the toppings are warmed through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Slice and serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>