<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>4-Ingredient Holiday Truffles Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/4-ingredient-holiday-truffles</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; full-fat coconut milk, mixed well ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">20 oz ; dark chocolate, chopped ; (440 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">kosher salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">cocoa powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">pistachio, crushed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">unsweetened coconut flake </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">hazelnuts, crushed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">freeze-dried strawberry </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">matcha powder </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Vegan</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Desserts</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/121196/hls24_1545497608.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/121196/landscape_720/1545497608</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the truffles: In a small saucepan over medium heat, bring the coconut milk to a simmer. Pour the warm coconut milk over the chopped chocolate in a heatproof bowl and stir until melted and smooth. Add the vanilla and salt and use a rubber spatula to combine. </step>
    <step num="1">Cover and cool in the refrigerator for 2 hours, until set. When you press the mixture with your fingertip, it should create create an indentation. Do not chill for too long--the mixture will be extremely difficult to scoop if it hardens too much. </step>
    <step num="2">Using a 1 tablespoon measuring spoon, portion out the truffle mixture and place onto the baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="3">Roll each truffle between your palms to create a sphere. Your hands will get messy during the process. The outside should be slightly tacky from the heat of your palms. This will help the topping stick best. If they get too soft, place in the fridge for 10 minutes. Roll the truffles in your toppings of choice. </step>
    <step num="4">Serve immediately or refrigerate for 1 hour for firmer truffles. The uncoated truffle balls will keep in the fridge for up 10 days. Coat in the toppings just before serving. </step>
    <step num="5">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the truffles: In a small saucepan over medium heat, bring the coconut milk to a simmer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pour the warm coconut milk over the chopped chocolate in a heatproof bowl and stir until melted and smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the vanilla and salt and use a rubber spatula to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Cover and cool in the refrigerator for 2 hours, until set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">When you press the mixture with your fingertip, it should create create an indentation. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Do not chill for too long--the mixture will be extremely difficult to scoop if it hardens too much. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Using a 1 tablespoon measuring spoon, portion out the truffle mixture and place onto the baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Roll each truffle between your palms to create a sphere. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Your hands will get messy during the process. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">The outside should be slightly tacky from the heat of your palms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">This will help the topping stick best. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">If they get too soft, place in the fridge for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Roll the truffles in your toppings of choice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Serve immediately or refrigerate for 1 hour for firmer truffles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">The uncoated truffle balls will keep in the fridge for up 10 days. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Coat in the toppings just before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>