<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chicken And Dumplings Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chicken-and-dumplings</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 lb ; bone-in, skin-on chicken thighs ; (910 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">5 teaspoons ; kosher salt, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ½ teaspoons ; black pepper, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 tablespoon ; Poultry Seasoning </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 teaspoons ; vegetable oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">8 cups ; water ; (2 L) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; small yellow onion, quartered </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; medium carrot, roughly chopped, plus 2 sliced, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 stalk ; celery, roughly chopped, plus 2 sliced, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 bunch ; fresh parsley, stems and leaves separated, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">2 teaspoons ; Garlic Powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 cups ; all-purpose flour, divided ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 ½ teaspoons ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">3 tablespoons ; schmaltz, reserved from chicken thighs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">¾ cup ; buttermilk ; (180 mL) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dinner</category>
    <category num="1">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/126020/hls24_1551378093.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/126020/landscape_720/1551378093</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Season the chicken thighs all over with 2 teaspoons of salt, 1 teaspoon of pepper, and the poultry seasoning. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large Dutch oven, heat the vegetable oil over medium heat. Place seasoned chicken, skin-side down, in the hot oil and begin to render the chicken fat, about 5 minutes. Once the skin in crispy, flip the chicken and continue cooking for 3 minutes more. Remove the chicken from pot and set aside. Pour the chicken fat into a small bowl and reserve. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the water, onion, the chopped carrot, chopped celery, and parsley stems to the pot. Return the chicken thighs to the pot and bring to a boil over medium high heat. Once boiling, reduce the heat to low and simmer for 30 minutes, or until the chicken is cooked through. </step>
    <step num="3">Remove the chicken from the pot and discard the skin and bones. Shred the meat and set aside. Strain the stock through a fine-mesh sieve and discard the vegetables. </step>
    <step num="4">Add 1 tablespoon of the reserved chicken fat to the pot over medium heat, along with the sliced carrots, sliced celery, garlic, and 2 tablespoons of flour. Stir to combine. </step>
    <step num="5">Slowly add the reserved chicken stock, 2 teaspoons of salt, 1 teaspoon of pepper, and the garlic powder. Add the shredded chicken back to the pot and bring to a simmer over low heat and continue cooking for 20 minutes or until the vegetables are tender. </step>
    <step num="6">Meanwhile, make the dumplings: In a medium bowl, combine the remaining cups of flour, the baking powder, remaining teaspoon of salt, remaining ½ teaspoon of pepper, and the remaining 3 tablespoons of reserved chicken fat. Mix with a fork to combine. Add the buttermilk and mix to incorporate, then knead for 2 minutes, until the dough comes together. </step>
    <step num="7">Pull off about 1 tablespoon of dough at a time and add to the soup. Continue cooking until the dumplings are cooked through, about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="8">Ladle into bowls and garnish with the parsley leaves. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Season the chicken thighs all over with 2 teaspoons of salt, 1 teaspoon of pepper, and the poultry seasoning. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In a large Dutch oven, heat the vegetable oil over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Place seasoned chicken, skin-side down, in the hot oil and begin to render the chicken fat, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Once the skin in crispy, flip the chicken and continue cooking for 3 minutes more. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Remove the chicken from pot and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour the chicken fat into a small bowl and reserve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the water, onion, the chopped carrot, chopped celery, and parsley stems to the pot. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Return the chicken thighs to the pot and bring to a boil over medium high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Once boiling, reduce the heat to low and simmer for 30 minutes, or until the chicken is cooked through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Remove the chicken from the pot and discard the skin and bones. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Shred the meat and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Strain the stock through a fine-mesh sieve and discard the vegetables. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add 1 tablespoon of the reserved chicken fat to the pot over medium heat, along with the sliced carrots, sliced celery, garlic, and 2 tablespoons of flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Slowly add the reserved chicken stock, 2 teaspoons of salt, 1 teaspoon of pepper, and the garlic powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the shredded chicken back to the pot and bring to a simmer over low heat and continue cooking for 20 minutes or until the vegetables are tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Meanwhile, make the dumplings: In a medium bowl, combine the remaining cups of flour, the baking powder, remaining teaspoon of salt, remaining ½ teaspoon of pepper, and the remaining 3 tablespoons of reserved chicken fat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Mix with a fork to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Add the buttermilk and mix to incorporate, then knead for 2 minutes, until the dough comes together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Pull off about 1 tablespoon of dough at a time and add to the soup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Continue cooking until the dumplings are cooked through, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Ladle into bowls and garnish with the parsley leaves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>