<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>How To Make Crispy Tempura At Home Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/how-to-make-crispy-tempura-at-home</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; cake flour, sifted, plus more for dusting ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; ice cold water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; large egg, cold </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">4 ; jumbo shrimps, peeled and deveined, tail-on </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 ; japanese eggplants </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">canola oil, for frying </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 oz ; kabocha squash, sliced into wedges ; (85 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Japanese</category>
    <category num="1">Seafood</category>
    <category num="2">Dinner</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/136821/hls24_1561137694.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/136821/landscape_720/1561137694</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the tempura batter: Sift the flour into a large bowl. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="1">In a medium bowl, whisk together the egg and water until lightly frothy. Add the flour in 3 additions, stirring with chopsticks just to combine. Refrigerate until ready to use. </step>
    <step num="2">Prepare the shrimp: Trim the tails, then use your knife to scrape the dirt and water from the remaining tail shell. Cut small incisions crosswise on both the top and bottom of the shrimp. This will prevent the shrimp from curling up as it cooks. Do not cut too deep, or the shrimp will fall apart. Pat the shrimp dry between paper towels, then refrigerate until ready to fry. </step>
    <step num="3">Prepare the eggplant: Trim the stem, then cut in half lengthwise. Leaving the top ½ inch (1 ¼ cm) intact, cut 5-6 ½-inch (¼ cm) thick slices down the length of the eggplant. </step>
    <step num="4">Fry the kabocha squash: Fill a medium pot about halfway with oil. Heat over medium heat until it reaches 320°F (160°C). </step>
    <step num="5">Coat the kabocha wedges lightly with flour, dusting off any excess. Dip the wedges in the tempura batter. Fry in the hot oil for 4-5 minutes, or until tender. Let any excess oil drip off, then transfer to a wire rack set over a paper towel-lined baking sheet to drain. </step>
    <step num="6">Fry the eggplant: Increase the oil temperature to 340°F (170°C). </step>
    <step num="7">Coat the eggplant lightly with flour, dusting off any excess. Dip in the tempura batter. Fry in the hot oil for 2-3 minutes, or until tender. Transfer to the wire rack to drain. </step>
    <step num="8">Fry the shrimp: Increase the oil temperature to 350°F (180°C). </step>
    <step num="9">Lightly coat the shrimp with flour, dusting off any excess. Dip in the tempura batter. Add the shrimp to the hot oil. Dip your fingers into the tempura batter and drizzle over the shrimp. This will make them extra crunchy. Fry the shrimp for 3-4 minutes, or until cooked through. Transfer to the wire rack to drain. </step>
    <step num="10">Serve the tempura immediately with dipping sauce or seasoned salt alongside. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the tempura batter: Sift the flour into a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a medium bowl, whisk together the egg and water until lightly frothy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the flour in 3 additions, stirring with chopsticks just to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Refrigerate until ready to use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Prepare the shrimp: Trim the tails, then use your knife to scrape the dirt and water from the remaining tail shell. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cut small incisions crosswise on both the top and bottom of the shrimp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">This will prevent the shrimp from curling up as it cooks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Do not cut too deep, or the shrimp will fall apart. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Pat the shrimp dry between paper towels, then refrigerate until ready to fry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Prepare the eggplant: Trim the stem, then cut in half lengthwise. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Leaving the top ½ inch (1 ¼ cm) intact, cut 5-6 ½-inch (¼ cm) thick slices down the length of the eggplant. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Fry the kabocha squash: Fill a medium pot about halfway with oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Heat over medium heat until it reaches 320°F (160°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Coat the kabocha wedges lightly with flour, dusting off any excess. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Dip the wedges in the tempura batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Fry in the hot oil for 4-5 minutes, or until tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Let any excess oil drip off, then transfer to a wire rack set over a paper towel-lined baking sheet to drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Fry the eggplant: Increase the oil temperature to 340°F (170°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Coat the eggplant lightly with flour, dusting off any excess. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Dip in the tempura batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Fry in the hot oil for 2-3 minutes, or until tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Transfer to the wire rack to drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Fry the shrimp: Increase the oil temperature to 350°F (180°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Lightly coat the shrimp with flour, dusting off any excess. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Dip in the tempura batter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Add the shrimp to the hot oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Dip your fingers into the tempura batter and drizzle over the shrimp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">This will make them extra crunchy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Fry the shrimp for 3-4 minutes, or until cooked through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Transfer to the wire rack to drain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Serve the tempura immediately with dipping sauce or seasoned salt alongside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>