<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Raspberry Poppyseed Linzer Cookies Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/raspberry-poppyseed-linzer-cookies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; raspberry ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 cup ; all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; almond flour </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">8 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, plus 2 tablespoons, softened </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 pinch of ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ teaspoon ; lemon zest </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; McCormick vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">3 tablespoons ; McCormick poppy seed, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 ; large egg </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Desserts</category>
    <category num="1">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="2">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/119380/hls24_1544639611.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/119380/landscape_720/1544639611</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the raspberry jam: In a medium pot over medium heat, combine the raspberries, sugar, and lemon juice. Cook for 10 minutes, stirring occasionally, until thickened. Remove from the heat and refrigerate for at least 2 hours before assembling the cookies. </step>
    <step num="1">Make the cookies: In a medium bowl, mix together the all-purpose flour and almond flour. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large bowl, cream together the butter, sugar, salt, lemon zest, and vanilla with an electric hand mixer until fluffy, about 3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the poppy seeds and beat for 1 minute to distribute evenly. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the egg and beat for 1–2 minutes, until well incorporated. </step>
    <step num="5">Pour in the flour mixture and fold with a spatula, just until no streaks of flour remain. Wrap the dough in plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for at least 1 hour or until firm. </step>
    <step num="6">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="7">Unwrap the dough on a floured surface and dust the top of the dough with more flour. Roll out the dough to ¼-inch (½ cm) thickness. </step>
    <step num="8">Using a 2½-inch (6 ⅓ cm) round cookie cutter with ridged edges, cut out cookies, chilling and re-rolling the dough as needed to cut out more cookies. You should have about 38 total. </step>
    <step num="9">Use a ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) cutter to cut out the centers of half of the cookies. Transfer cookies to the prepared baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="10">Bake the cookies for 12 minutes or until the edges are golden brown. Let cool completely. </step>
    <step num="11">To assemble, spread 1 teaspoon of jam onto the whole cookies. Top with the cut-out cookies. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the raspberry jam: In a medium pot over medium heat, combine the raspberries, sugar, and lemon juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Cook for 10 minutes, stirring occasionally, until thickened. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Remove from the heat and refrigerate for at least 2 hours before assembling the cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Make the cookies: In a medium bowl, mix together the all-purpose flour and almond flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In a large bowl, cream together the butter, sugar, salt, lemon zest, and vanilla with an electric hand mixer until fluffy, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the poppy seeds and beat for 1 minute to distribute evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the egg and beat for 1–2 minutes, until well incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Pour in the flour mixture and fold with a spatula, just until no streaks of flour remain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Wrap the dough in plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for at least 1 hour or until firm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Unwrap the dough on a floured surface and dust the top of the dough with more flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Roll out the dough to ¼-inch (½ cm) thickness. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Using a 2½-inch (6 ⅓ cm) round cookie cutter with ridged edges, cut out cookies, chilling and re-rolling the dough as needed to cut out more cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">You should have about 38 total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Use a ½-inch (1 ¼ cm) cutter to cut out the centers of half of the cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Transfer cookies to the prepared baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Bake the cookies for 12 minutes or until the edges are golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Let cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">To assemble, spread 1 teaspoon of jam onto the whole cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Top with the cut-out cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>