<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Stuffed Chocolate Chip Cookies</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/stuffed-chocolate-chip-cookies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; unsalted butter, 2 sticks ; (230 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; granulated sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ½ cups ; dark brown sugar ; (330 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 teaspoons ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; greek yogurt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ; large egg </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; large egg yolk </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 ½ cups ; all-purpose flour ; (310 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ teaspoon ; baking soda </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¾ cup ; milk chocolate chips ; (130 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ cup ; mini chocolate chips ; (85 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 tablespoon ; caramel, per cooking </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 tablespoon ; cookie butter, per cookie </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 tablespoon ; chocolate hazelnut spread, per cookie </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 tablespoon ; peanut butter, per cookie </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">¼ cup ; mini marshmallows ; (10 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">¼ cup ; chocolate caramel candy, chopped ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">¼ cup ; chocolate chips ; (45 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="19">¼ cup ; chocolate sandwich cookie, crushed ; (25 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="20">¼ cup ; white chocolate chip ; (45 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="21">¾ cup ; rainbow sprinkles ; (130 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="22">¼ cup ; pretzel, crushed ; (40 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="23">¼ cup ; potato chip, crushed ; (25 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="7">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="8">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/102621/hls24_1532112720.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/102621/landscape_720/1532112720</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium saucepan over medium heat, melt the butter and toast for about 5 minutes until it turns brown and smells nutty. Pour the brown butter into a large bowl. Let sit for 30 minutes to cool before starting to make the dough. </step>
    <step num="1">To the bowl with the cooled butter, add the granulated sugar, brown sugar, vanilla, and yogurt. Using an electric hand mixer or stand mixer, beat for 2-3 minutes until fluffy. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the egg and egg yolk and beat again until fluffy and well-combined. </step>
    <step num="3">In a separate large bowl, whisk together the flour, baking soda, and salt. Sift ⅓ of the dry ingredients at a time into the wet ingredients. Beat just until incorporated, then scrape down the sides of the bowl with a rubber spatula between each addition. Make sure not to overmix. </step>
    <step num="4">Add the chocolate chips and mini chocolate chips to the dough and gently fold just to incorporate. Cover the bowl with plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for 2 hours. You can also store the stuffings in the fridge so they’re easier to work with later. </step>
    <step num="5">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). Line a baking sheet (or 2) with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="6">Using an ice cream scooper, scoop out 3 tablespoons of chilled dough and flatten out into a ¼-inch (6 mm) thick circle. </step>
    <step num="7">Add 1 tablespoon of your stuffing of choice, such as caramel, cookie butter, chocolate hazelnut spread, or peanut butter, to the center of the dough round, and fold the edges of the dough around the stuffing. Seal tightly and roll into a ball. Repeat with the rest of the dough and stuffings. </step>
    <step num="8">To the outside of the cookie dough balls, add your choice of toppings, such as mini marshmallows, chopped candy bar, chocolate chips, crushed chocolate sandwich cookies, white chocolate chips, rainbow sprinkles, pretzel pieces, or crushed potato chips. Press the toppings firmly into the dough, so they don’t fall off. Repeat with the remaining stuffed cookie dough balls. </step>
    <step num="9">Place the stuffed and decorated cookie dough balls onto the prepared baking sheet approximately 3 inches (7 cm) apart, so the cookies don’t spread into one another. You may need to use 2 baking sheets. </step>
    <step num="10">Bake for 11-14 minutes, or until the cookies are golden brown and evenly spread. </step>
    <step num="11">Cool on a cooling rack for 10 minutes before devouring! </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium saucepan over medium heat, melt the butter and toast for about 5 minutes until it turns brown and smells nutty. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Pour the brown butter into a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Let sit for 30 minutes to cool before starting to make the dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">To the bowl with the cooled butter, add the granulated sugar, brown sugar, vanilla, and yogurt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Using an electric hand mixer or stand mixer, beat for 2-3 minutes until fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add the egg and egg yolk and beat again until fluffy and well-combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">In a separate large bowl, whisk together the flour, baking soda, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Sift ⅓ of the dry ingredients at a time into the wet ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Beat just until incorporated, then scrape down the sides of the bowl with a rubber spatula between each addition. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Make sure not to overmix. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add the chocolate chips and mini chocolate chips to the dough and gently fold just to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cover the bowl with plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for 2 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">You can also store the stuffings in the fridge so they’re easier to work with later. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Line a baking sheet (or 2) with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Using an ice cream scooper, scoop out 3 tablespoons of chilled dough and flatten out into a ¼-inch (6 mm) thick circle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add 1 tablespoon of your stuffing of choice, such as caramel, cookie butter, chocolate hazelnut spread, or peanut butter, to the center of the dough round, and fold the edges of the dough around the stuffing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Seal tightly and roll into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Repeat with the rest of the dough and stuffings. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">To the outside of the cookie dough balls, add your choice of toppings, such as mini marshmallows, chopped candy bar, chocolate chips, crushed chocolate sandwich cookies, white chocolate chips, rainbow sprinkles, pretzel pieces, or crushed potato chips. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Press the toppings firmly into the dough, so they don’t fall off. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Repeat with the remaining stuffed cookie dough balls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Place the stuffed and decorated cookie dough balls onto the prepared baking sheet approximately 3 inches (7 cm) apart, so the cookies don’t spread into one another. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">You may need to use 2 baking sheets. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Bake for 11-14 minutes, or until the cookies are golden brown and evenly spread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Cool on a cooling rack for 10 minutes before devouring! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>