<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Teriyaki Chicken Fried Rice Dome</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/teriyaki-chicken-fried-rice-dome</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">¼ cup ; sugar ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; soy sauce, plus 3 tablespoons, divided ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; mirin ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 lb ; boneless, skinless chicken thighs, sliced ; (910 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; canola oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 ; carrots, peeled and minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 ; medium onion, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ; red bell pepper, seeded and minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 cup ; peas ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 cup ; broccoli florets ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">3 tablespoons ; sesame oil, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 tablespoons ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 tablespoon ; ginger, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">4 cups ; white rice, cooled ; (800 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">6 ; large eggs, beaten </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">1 ; sesame seeds, for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="18">scallions, sliced, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Japanese</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/102361/hls24_1531933606.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/102361/landscape_720/1531933606</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, mix together the sugar, ½ cup (120 ml) soy sauce, and the mirin. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the chicken to a large bowl. Pour ½ cup (120 ml) of the marinade over the chicken and save the rest for later. Toss the chicken to coat, cover with plastic wrap, and marinate in the fridge for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the canola oil to a wok or a large skillet over high heat. When the oil begins to shimmer, add the carrots, onion, and pepper. Season with salt and pepper. Cook, stirring occasionally, until starting to soften, 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the peas and broccoli florets to the skillet. Cook, shaking the pan or stirring, for about 3 more minutes, until the broccoli becomes slightly tender. Remove the vegetables from the skillet. </step>
    <step num="4">Add 2 tablespoons of sesame oil to the skillet and heat until it shimmers, then add the minced garlic and ginger. When the mixture is fragrant, about 15 seconds later, add the cooked rice, breaking up clumps with a spoon and tossing in the oil. </step>
    <step num="5">When the rice is well-coated, push to one side of the skillet and add the beaten eggs to the other side. Scramble until it starts to set, then return the veggies to the pan and stir into the rice to incorporate. Add the remaining 3 tablespoons of soy sauce. Stir until well-combined. </step>
    <step num="6">Transfer the rice mixture to a greased bundt pan. Pack the rice down slightly. Cover and set aside. </step>
    <step num="7">Heat the remaining tablespoon of sesame oil in the skillet. Add the marinated chicken and cook until browned on all sides, about 10 minutes. Add the reserved teriyaki sauce and cook until reduced and thickened slightly. Sprinkle with sesame seeds. </step>
    <step num="8">Invert the fried rice dome onto a serving platter. Pour the hot teriyaki chicken into the center of the dome and garnish with sliced scallions. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, mix together the sugar, ½ cup (120 ml) soy sauce, and the mirin. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add the chicken to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Pour ½ cup (120 ml) of the marinade over the chicken and save the rest for later. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Toss the chicken to coat, cover with plastic wrap, and marinate in the fridge for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the canola oil to a wok or a large skillet over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">When the oil begins to shimmer, add the carrots, onion, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Season with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cook, stirring occasionally, until starting to soften, 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the peas and broccoli florets to the skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Cook, shaking the pan or stirring, for about 3 more minutes, until the broccoli becomes slightly tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Remove the vegetables from the skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add 2 tablespoons of sesame oil to the skillet and heat until it shimmers, then add the minced garlic and ginger. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">When the mixture is fragrant, about 15 seconds later, add the cooked rice, breaking up clumps with a spoon and tossing in the oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">When the rice is well-coated, push to one side of the skillet and add the beaten eggs to the other side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Scramble until it starts to set, then return the veggies to the pan and stir into the rice to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the remaining 3 tablespoons of soy sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Stir until well-combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Transfer the rice mixture to a greased bundt pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Pack the rice down slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Cover and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Heat the remaining tablespoon of sesame oil in the skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Add the marinated chicken and cook until browned on all sides, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add the reserved teriyaki sauce and cook until reduced and thickened slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Sprinkle with sesame seeds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Invert the fried rice dome onto a serving platter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Pour the hot teriyaki chicken into the center of the dome and garnish with sliced scallions. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>