<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Lemon Ricotta Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/lemon-ricotta-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; water ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; granulated sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ; lemon, thinly sliced, about 9 slices </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">8 tablespoons ; unsalted butter, room temperature, divided, plus 1 tablespoon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 cup ; flour, divided, plus 3 tablespoons ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 ¼ cups ; granulated sugar ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">4 ; large eggs, room temperature </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">½ teaspoon ; lemon extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">2 teaspoons ; lemon zest, packed, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; stone ground yellow cornmeal ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 ½ teaspoons ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 cup ; whole milk ricotta cheese, room temperature ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 tablespoons ; powdered sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">4 ; strawberries, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">¼ cup ; blueberry ; (25 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="3">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/132435/hls24_1557527057.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/132435/landscape_720/1557527057</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">Make the candied lemons: In a high-walled, wide pan, combine the sugar and water. Bring to a boil over medium-high heat, stirring to dissolve the sugar. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the lemon slices to the pan, making sure they are submerged in the syrup. Reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer until the lemons have softened and have started to caramelize, about 35 minutes. </step>
    <step num="3">Gently transfer the lemon slices to the prepared baking sheet and let cool completely, about 20 minutes. The candied lemons can be made up to 2 days in advance. Store in an airtight container in the refrigerator and bring to room temperature before using. (The syrup can be strained, cooled, and kept in the refrigerator for up to 2 weeks. Try adding it to cocktails and desserts!) </step>
    <step num="4">Make the cake: Arrange a rack in the center of the oven. Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). Grease a 9-inch (23 cm) nonstick springform pan with 1 tablespoon of butter. Add 3 tablespoons of flour to the greased pan and tilt to coat completely. Turn the pan over and tap out any excess flour. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">In a large bowl, beat the remaining butter with an electric hand mixer on high speed until light and fluffy, about 3 minutes. With the mixer running, add the sugar and beat until evenly incorporated, about 3 minutes. Reduce the mixer speed to medium-low and add the eggs, 1 at a time, making sure to fully incorporate each before adding the next. Stir in the lemon extract and 1 teaspoon of lemon zest. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="6">In a medium bowl, whisk together the remaining cup of flour, the cornmeal, baking powder, and salt. </step>
    <step num="7">Add the wet ingredients to the flour mixture and whisk until the batter is smooth, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed. Add the ricotta and stir just until combined, but do not overmix. </step>
    <step num="8">Set the prepared pan on a baking sheet. Pour the batter into the pan and use a spatula to smooth the top. </step>
    <step num="9">Bake for 45 minutes, or until the sides and top of the cake are golden brown and a toothpick inserted in the center comes out clean. </step>
    <step num="10">Transfer the cake to a wire rack and let cool for at least 45 minutes. Once the cake begins to pull away from the sides of the pan, release the springform. With a wide metal spatula, gently transfer the cooled cake to a cake platter. </step>
    <step num="11">Dust the top of the cake with the powdered sugar. Top with the strawberries, blueberries, and lemon slices and sprinkle with the remaining teaspoon of lemon zest. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Make the candied lemons: In a high-walled, wide pan, combine the sugar and water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Bring to a boil over medium-high heat, stirring to dissolve the sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the lemon slices to the pan, making sure they are submerged in the syrup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer until the lemons have softened and have started to caramelize, about 35 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Gently transfer the lemon slices to the prepared baking sheet and let cool completely, about 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">The candied lemons can be made up to 2 days in advance. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Store in an airtight container in the refrigerator and bring to room temperature before using. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">(The syrup can be strained, cooled, and kept in the refrigerator for up to 2 weeks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Try adding it to cocktails and desserts!) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Make the cake: Arrange a rack in the center of the oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Grease a 9-inch (23 cm) nonstick springform pan with 1 tablespoon of butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Add 3 tablespoons of flour to the greased pan and tilt to coat completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Turn the pan over and tap out any excess flour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">In a large bowl, beat the remaining butter with an electric hand mixer on high speed until light and fluffy, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">With the mixer running, add the sugar and beat until evenly incorporated, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Reduce the mixer speed to medium-low and add the eggs, 1 at a time, making sure to fully incorporate each before adding the next. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Stir in the lemon extract and 1 teaspoon of lemon zest. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">In a medium bowl, whisk together the remaining cup of flour, the cornmeal, baking powder, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add the wet ingredients to the flour mixture and whisk until the batter is smooth, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Add the ricotta and stir just until combined, but do not overmix. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Set the prepared pan on a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Pour the batter into the pan and use a spatula to smooth the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Bake for 45 minutes, or until the sides and top of the cake are golden brown and a toothpick inserted in the center comes out clean. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Transfer the cake to a wire rack and let cool for at least 45 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Once the cake begins to pull away from the sides of the pan, release the springform. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">With a wide metal spatula, gently transfer the cooled cake to a cake platter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Dust the top of the cake with the powdered sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Top with the strawberries, blueberries, and lemon slices and sprinkle with the remaining teaspoon of lemon zest. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>