<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Giant BBQ Rib Sandwich (To Feed A Crowd) Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/giant-bbq-rib-sandwich-to-feed-a-crowd</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 rack ; baby back ribs, membrane removed (this is essential for de-boning) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 tablespoons ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 tablespoons ; brown sugar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 teaspoons ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 teaspoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; onion powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 teaspoon ; cumin </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; chili powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; barbecue sauce ; (290 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; honey ; (85 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 loaf ; bread, large loaf </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">¼ cup ; butter, melted ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 tablespoon ; sesame seed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">2 ; large onions, sliced and caramelized </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">2 tablespoons ; fresh parsley, chopped </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">BBQ</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Lunch</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">BBQ</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/33168/low_1496279059.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/33168/mp4_720x1280/1496279059</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 300°F (150°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Lay the ribs on a long sheet of aluminum foil. Combine the paprika, pepper, brown sugar, salt, garlic powder, onion powder, cumin, and chili powder in a small bowl, then cover the ribs evenly on both sides, pressing the rub into any cracks and smoothing out any large lumps. Wrap the foil around the ribs, making sure they’re completely sealed. It’s important that the juices of the ribs stay inside the foil to keep the ribs moist during cooking. Use more sheets of foil if necessary. </step>
    <step num="2">Bake the ribs for 3-3½ hours, until tender. Unwrap the ribs carefully, then wiggle the bones out slowly. If you’re having trouble removing the bones, use a knife to make small cuts in the meat to aid their removal. Preheat the broiler on your oven. </step>
    <step num="3">Combine the barbecue sauce and honey in a small bowl and brush both sides of the deboned slab of ribs generously, being sure to carefully handle the ribs since the meat will be super tender. </step>
    <step num="4">Broil the ribs for about 5 minutes until the glaze is bubbling and starting to brown. </step>
    <step num="5">Slice the bread loaf in half lengthwise, then butter both sides of the bread. Sprinkle sesame seeds on the outside of the bread, then toast under the broiler for a few minutes. Keep a careful eye on it as they will burn extremely quickly. </step>
    <step num="6">With two long spatulas or knives, carefully transfer the glazed ribs to the bottom bread half, then top with the caramelized onions, parsley, and the top half of bread. Cut into about 8 2-inch (5-cm) sandwiches, and serve. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 300°F (150°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Lay the ribs on a long sheet of aluminum foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Combine the paprika, pepper, brown sugar, salt, garlic powder, onion powder, cumin, and chili powder in a small bowl, then cover the ribs evenly on both sides, pressing the rub into any cracks and smoothing out any large lumps. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Wrap the foil around the ribs, making sure they’re completely sealed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">It’s important that the juices of the ribs stay inside the foil to keep the ribs moist during cooking. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Use more sheets of foil if necessary. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Bake the ribs for 3-3½ hours, until tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Unwrap the ribs carefully, then wiggle the bones out slowly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">If you’re having trouble removing the bones, use a knife to make small cuts in the meat to aid their removal. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Preheat the broiler on your oven. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Combine the barbecue sauce and honey in a small bowl and brush both sides of the deboned slab of ribs generously, being sure to carefully handle the ribs since the meat will be super tender. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Broil the ribs for about 5 minutes until the glaze is bubbling and starting to brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Slice the bread loaf in half lengthwise, then butter both sides of the bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Sprinkle sesame seeds on the outside of the bread, then toast under the broiler for a few minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Keep a careful eye on it as they will burn extremely quickly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">With two long spatulas or knives, carefully transfer the glazed ribs to the bottom bread half, then top with the caramelized onions, parsley, and the top half of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Cut into about 8 2-inch (5-cm) sandwiches, and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>