<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Sweet And Salty Pretzel Cakes Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/sweet-and-salty-pretzel-cakes</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ cup ; milk chocolate, or dark chocolate, broken into small pieces ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 tablespoons ; butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; golden syrup </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¾ cup ; pretzel, crushed, plus more for decoration ; (75 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31871/low_1495124862.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31871/mp4_720x1280/1495124862</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make a bain-marie by filling a pot with a little water. Rest a heatproof bowl on the rim of the pot, making sure that the water doesn’t touch the bottom of the bowl. </step>
    <step num="1">Cook on a low heat and when the water starts to simmer add the chocolate, butter, and golden syrup to the heatproof bowl and allow it to melt - when it’s nearly there, give it a quick stir and take it off the heat. </step>
    <step num="2">Stir the crushed pretzels in to the chocolate mixture. </step>
    <step num="3">Line a muffin tin with muffin cases - if you have the time, you can line each muffin case with 5 pretzels to form a little holder for the mixture. one on the base, and 4 walls, but this isn’t totally necessary, the mixture will hold on it’s own when set. A single pretzel on top is a fairly good compromise! </step>
    <step num="4">Fill the muffin cases with the chocolate mixture and allow to set in the fridge for at least 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="5">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make a bain-marie by filling a pot with a little water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Rest a heatproof bowl on the rim of the pot, making sure that the water doesn’t touch the bottom of the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cook on a low heat and when the water starts to simmer add the chocolate, butter, and golden syrup to the heatproof bowl and allow it to melt - when it’s nearly there, give it a quick stir and take it off the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Stir the crushed pretzels in to the chocolate mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Line a muffin tin with muffin cases - if you have the time, you can line each muffin case with 5 pretzels to form a little holder for the mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">one on the base, and 4 walls, but this isn’t totally necessary, the mixture will hold on it’s own when set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">A single pretzel on top is a fairly good compromise! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Fill the muffin cases with the chocolate mixture and allow to set in the fridge for at least 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>