<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Dairy-Free Strawberry Cheesecake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/dairy-free-strawberry-cheesecake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">½ cup ; raw pecan ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; almond flour ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 ; pitted dates </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 teaspoon ; cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 tablespoons ; coconut oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; raw cashew ; (260 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">cold water, for soaking </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ cup ; canned coconut milk, mixed ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 tablespoons ; fresh lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; coconut oil, melted and cooled ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">⅓ cup ; maple syrup ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 tablespoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ cup ; strawberry, fresh or frozen ; (75 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">strawberry, sliced, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="2">Healthy</category>
    <category num="3">Vegan</category>
    <category num="4">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="5">Desserts</category>
    <category num="6">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="7">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="8">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/49940/low_1504026571.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/49940/mp4_720x1280/1504026571</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Place the cashews in a medium bowl and cover with cold water. Let the cashews soak for at least for 4 hours, or overnight, until soft. </step>
    <step num="1">Make the crust: Using a food processor, pulse together the pecans, almond flour, dates, cinnamon, coconut oil, and a pinch of salt. Pulse until the pecans have been broken down into crumbs and the crust begins to stick together. </step>
    <step num="2">Transfer the crust to a greased and parchment paper-lined 8-inch (20 cm) springform pan. Use your fingers to press the crust into the bottom of the pan in an even layer. </step>
    <step num="3">Make the filling: Drain the soaked cashews and place them in the bowl of the food processor. Add the coconut milk, lemon juice, coconut oil, maple syrup, and vanilla. Blend until very smooth, 5-7 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Pour roughly ⅔ of the cashew filling over the crust. Use a spatula to gently spread the mixture to the sides, then tap and shake the pan on the counter to achieve a smooth, even layer. </step>
    <step num="5">Freeze the pan while preparing the strawberry layer, about 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the strawberries into the remaining cashew mixture in the food processor and puree until smooth, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed, about 5 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Scrape the strawberry filling over the first layer. Use a spatula to gently push the layer out to the sides of the pan and tap and shake the pan on the counter to achieve a smooth, even layer. </step>
    <step num="8">Top the cheesecake with sliced strawberries. </step>
    <step num="9">Freeze the cheesecake until solid, at least 4 hours. </step>
    <step num="10">To serve, let the cheesecake thaw at room temperature for at least 10 minutes before slicing. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Place the cashews in a medium bowl and cover with cold water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Let the cashews soak for at least for 4 hours, or overnight, until soft. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Make the crust: Using a food processor, pulse together the pecans, almond flour, dates, cinnamon, coconut oil, and a pinch of salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Pulse until the pecans have been broken down into crumbs and the crust begins to stick together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Transfer the crust to a greased and parchment paper-lined 8-inch (20 cm) springform pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Use your fingers to press the crust into the bottom of the pan in an even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Make the filling: Drain the soaked cashews and place them in the bowl of the food processor. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the coconut milk, lemon juice, coconut oil, maple syrup, and vanilla. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Blend until very smooth, 5-7 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Pour roughly ⅔ of the cashew filling over the crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Use a spatula to gently spread the mixture to the sides, then tap and shake the pan on the counter to achieve a smooth, even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Freeze the pan while preparing the strawberry layer, about 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the strawberries into the remaining cashew mixture in the food processor and puree until smooth, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Scrape the strawberry filling over the first layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Use a spatula to gently push the layer out to the sides of the pan and tap and shake the pan on the counter to achieve a smooth, even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Top the cheesecake with sliced strawberries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Freeze the cheesecake until solid, at least 4 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">To serve, let the cheesecake thaw at room temperature for at least 10 minutes before slicing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>