<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Slice and Bake Rainbow Cookies Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/slice-bake-rainbow-cookies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; butter, softened ; (230 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 ½ cups ; powdered sugar ; (300 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; vanilla </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 ; eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 ½ cups ; flour ; (440 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¼ teaspoon ; red food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ teaspoon ; orange food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">¼ teaspoon ; yellow food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">¼ teaspoon ; green food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ teaspoon ; blue food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¼ teaspoon ; purple food coloring </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Desserts</category>
    <category num="3">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/34629/low_1498062604.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/34629/mp4_720x1280/1498062604</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Using a hand mixer or standing mixer, beat butter until creamy. </step>
    <step num="2">Add powdered sugar and beat until combined. Add the eggs, vanilla, and salt. Beat until well combined. </step>
    <step num="3">Gradually, add the flour until dough is moist and holds together, but doesn’t stick to your hands. </step>
    <step num="4">Place dough on a cutting board and form into a ball. Cut in half, then cover one half with plastic wrap and set aside. </step>
    <step num="5">Divide the other half into 6 pieces. The outer layers of the rainbow will need a little bit more dough, so make two of them slightly larger than the others. </step>
    <step num="6">Dye the dough with food coloring by placing a ¼ teaspoon of dye on the ball of dough and kneading it until it is one solid color. Gloves optional but suggested. </step>
    <step num="7">Starting with purple, roll the dough into a log about 6-8 inches (15-20 cm) long. This will be the center of the rainbow. </step>
    <step num="8">Next, roll out the blue dough with a rolling pin until it’s about ¼ inch (6 mm) thick, slightly longer than the purple, and wide enough to wrap around the purple dough. Repeat with the green, yellow, orange, and red doughs. The further away from the purple you get, the wider the dough needs to be to go around the previous color, making the red dough the widest. </step>
    <step num="9">Wrap the blue dough around the purple, pinching together any cracks that form, cutting off any excess dough. Repeat with the rest of the colors. </step>
    <step num="10">Wrap in plastic wrap and chill for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="11">Once chilled, remove the plastic wrap, and cut the dough in half to make 2 rainbow shapes. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="12">Cut the reserved dough in half, roll out to ¼-inch (6 mm) thickness, and make it slightly longer than the rainbow log. </step>
    <step num="13">Place the rainbow dough in the center and wrap the plain dough around it, again, pinching together any cracks and smoothing out the surface. </step>
    <step num="14">Repeat with the other halves. Wrap with plastic wrap and chill for another 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="15">Once chilled, remove the plastic wrap. Slice cookies about ½-inch (1 cm) thick and place on a parchment paper-lined baking sheet. </step>
    <step num="16">Bake for 20 minutes or until the bottom has browned slightly. </step>
    <step num="17">Cool on a cooling rack. </step>
    <step num="18">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Using a hand mixer or standing mixer, beat butter until creamy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add powdered sugar and beat until combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the eggs, vanilla, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Beat until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Gradually, add the flour until dough is moist and holds together, but doesn’t stick to your hands. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Place dough on a cutting board and form into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Cut in half, then cover one half with plastic wrap and set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Divide the other half into 6 pieces. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">The outer layers of the rainbow will need a little bit more dough, so make two of them slightly larger than the others. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Dye the dough with food coloring by placing a ¼ teaspoon of dye on the ball of dough and kneading it until it is one solid color. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Gloves optional but suggested. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Starting with purple, roll the dough into a log about 6-8 inches (15-20 cm) long. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">This will be the center of the rainbow. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Next, roll out the blue dough with a rolling pin until it’s about ¼ inch (6 mm) thick, slightly longer than the purple, and wide enough to wrap around the purple dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Repeat with the green, yellow, orange, and red doughs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">The further away from the purple you get, the wider the dough needs to be to go around the previous color, making the red dough the widest. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Wrap the blue dough around the purple, pinching together any cracks that form, cutting off any excess dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Repeat with the rest of the colors. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Wrap in plastic wrap and chill for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Once chilled, remove the plastic wrap, and cut the dough in half to make 2 rainbow shapes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Cut the reserved dough in half, roll out to ¼-inch (6 mm) thickness, and make it slightly longer than the rainbow log. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Place the rainbow dough in the center and wrap the plain dough around it, again, pinching together any cracks and smoothing out the surface. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Repeat with the other halves. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Wrap with plastic wrap and chill for another 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Once chilled, remove the plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Slice cookies about ½-inch (1 cm) thick and place on a parchment paper-lined baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Bake for 20 minutes or until the bottom has browned slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Cool on a cooling rack. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>