<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>BBQ Smoker Pork Ribs Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/bbq-smoker-pork-ribs</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 rack ; pork rib, St. Louis-style or baby back </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 cups ; BBQ sauce, optional ; (580 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 tablespoon ; ground ginger </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ tablespoon ; cayenne pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 tablespoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 tablespoons ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 tablespoon ; minced garlic </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 tablespoons ; onion powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 ½ tablespoons ; ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 ½ tablespoons ; mustard powder </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">BBQ</category>
    <category num="2">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Game Day</category>
    <category num="6">BBQ</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/62778/low_1510938773.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/62778/mp4_720x1280/1510938773</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Using a charcoal chimney or lighter fluid, light 6-8 pieces of lump charcoal and let them come to a full burn. Add to your firebox and preheat the smoker to roughly 225°F (105°C), adding charcoal to the fire as necessary. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the ginger, cayenne, garlic powder, paprika, minced garlic, onion powder, black pepper, and mustard powder in a medium bowl and mix thoroughly. </step>
    <step num="2">Place ribs on a large sheet of aluminum foil and coat liberally with spice rub on all sides. </step>
    <step num="3">Place a metal pan filled with water at the end of the smoker’s cooking chamber closest to the firebox. Place ribs directly on the grate of your cooking chamber and close the smoker. Open the vents at both ends of the smoker. </step>
    <step num="4">Add a chunk or two of smoking wood to the firebox each half hour to create a stream of thin but visible smoke that is somewhat blue in appearance. Too much wood may result in thick, gray smoke. If this happens, open the smoker and clear the smoke out, waiting to close it until you’re able to achieve manageable smoke again. </step>
    <step num="5">Maintain the heat by adding additional charcoal as necessary. </step>
    <step num="6">Smoke ribs for 3-5 hours, spraying each hour with water to keep the surface from drying out. </step>
    <step num="7">Cook time will vary based on the size and type of rib (baby backs will cook faster than spareribs). Use a meat thermometer to gauge doneness. </step>
    <step num="8">At 170°F (75°C), remove the ribs from the smoker and place onto a large sheet of aluminum foil. If using barbecue sauce, apply now with a basting brush. Wrap the aluminum foil up to enclose the ribs, and place them back in your smoker for an additional 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="9">Let meat rest at least 15 minutes off the heat before slicing. Serve with remaining barbecue sauce and preferred sides. </step>
    <step num="10">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Using a charcoal chimney or lighter fluid, light 6-8 pieces of lump charcoal and let them come to a full burn. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add to your firebox and preheat the smoker to roughly 225°F (105°C), adding charcoal to the fire as necessary. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the ginger, cayenne, garlic powder, paprika, minced garlic, onion powder, black pepper, and mustard powder in a medium bowl and mix thoroughly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Place ribs on a large sheet of aluminum foil and coat liberally with spice rub on all sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Place a metal pan filled with water at the end of the smoker’s cooking chamber closest to the firebox. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Place ribs directly on the grate of your cooking chamber and close the smoker. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Open the vents at both ends of the smoker. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add a chunk or two of smoking wood to the firebox each half hour to create a stream of thin but visible smoke that is somewhat blue in appearance. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Too much wood may result in thick, gray smoke. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">If this happens, open the smoker and clear the smoke out, waiting to close it until you’re able to achieve manageable smoke again. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Maintain the heat by adding additional charcoal as necessary. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Smoke ribs for 3-5 hours, spraying each hour with water to keep the surface from drying out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cook time will vary based on the size and type of rib (baby backs will cook faster than spareribs). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Use a meat thermometer to gauge doneness. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">At 170°F (75°C), remove the ribs from the smoker and place onto a large sheet of aluminum foil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">If using barbecue sauce, apply now with a basting brush. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Wrap the aluminum foil up to enclose the ribs, and place them back in your smoker for an additional 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Let meat rest at least 15 minutes off the heat before slicing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Serve with remaining barbecue sauce and preferred sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>