<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Dairy-Free Peach Tart Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/dairy-free-peach-tart</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ cups ; whole wheat flour ; (185 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ cup ; coconut oil ; (120 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">⅓ cup ; coconut sugar, or sugar of choice ; (65 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">3 tablespoons ; coconut oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">⅓ cup ; coconut sugar, or sugar of choice ; (65 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ cup ; almond flour ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 tablespoon ; arrowroot powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ teaspoon ; ground cinnamon </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; almond milk, or non-dairy milk of choice ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">5 ; ripe peaches, pitted and thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">ice cream, of choice, for serving </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Healthy</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98502/hls24_1528937438.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/98502/landscape_720/1528937438</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium bowl, combine the flour, coconut oil, coconut sugar, and salt. Use a flexible spatula to combine the ingredients, mashing the contents thoroughly until a uniform dough forms. </step>
    <step num="1">Transfer the dough to a floured silicone baking mat. Flour the top of the dough and the rolling pin and begin rolling out the crust into a circle about 12 inches (30 cm) wide. If you do not have a silicone baking mat or other flexible surface, you can roll out the dough between two sheets of plastic wrap. </step>
    <step num="2">Roll the baking mat and crust onto the rolling pin and transfer to a 10-inch (25-cm) tart pan. Unroll the baking mat over the pan, crust side down, and peel off the baking mat. If the dough is sticking to the baking mat, transfer the baking mat and dough to the fridge for a few minutes, then try transferring the dough to the tart pan again. </step>
    <step num="3">Press the crust against the bottom and sides of the tart pan. Roll the rolling pin across the top of the tart pan to cut off any excess dough. </step>
    <step num="4">Refrigerate the crust for about 20 minutes while you prepare the filling, until the dough has firmed. </step>
    <step num="5">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). </step>
    <step num="6">In a medium bowl, combine the coconut oil, coconut sugar, almond flour, arrowroot, cinnamon, and vanilla with an electric hand mixer. Pour in the milk and continue mixing until the filling is thick and well-mixed. </step>
    <step num="7">Transfer the chilled tart crust to a baking sheet. Pour the filling into the crust and smooth into an even layer with a spatula. </step>
    <step num="8">Arrange the peach slices over the filling in concentric circles. </step>
    <step num="9">Bake for 25-30 minutes, until the crust begins to darken and the peaches start to dry out. </step>
    <step num="10">Let the tart cool for at least 1 hour before unmolding. </step>
    <step num="11">Slice and serve with ice cream, if desired. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium bowl, combine the flour, coconut oil, coconut sugar, and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Use a flexible spatula to combine the ingredients, mashing the contents thoroughly until a uniform dough forms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Transfer the dough to a floured silicone baking mat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Flour the top of the dough and the rolling pin and begin rolling out the crust into a circle about 12 inches (30 cm) wide. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">If you do not have a silicone baking mat or other flexible surface, you can roll out the dough between two sheets of plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Roll the baking mat and crust onto the rolling pin and transfer to a 10-inch (25-cm) tart pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Unroll the baking mat over the pan, crust side down, and peel off the baking mat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">If the dough is sticking to the baking mat, transfer the baking mat and dough to the fridge for a few minutes, then try transferring the dough to the tart pan again. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Press the crust against the bottom and sides of the tart pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Roll the rolling pin across the top of the tart pan to cut off any excess dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Refrigerate the crust for about 20 minutes while you prepare the filling, until the dough has firmed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">In a medium bowl, combine the coconut oil, coconut sugar, almond flour, arrowroot, cinnamon, and vanilla with an electric hand mixer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Pour in the milk and continue mixing until the filling is thick and well-mixed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Transfer the chilled tart crust to a baking sheet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Pour the filling into the crust and smooth into an even layer with a spatula. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Arrange the peach slices over the filling in concentric circles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Bake for 25-30 minutes, until the crust begins to darken and the peaches start to dry out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Let the tart cool for at least 1 hour before unmolding. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Slice and serve with ice cream, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>