<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Strawberries And Cream Soufflé Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/strawberries-and-cream-souffle</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; milk ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; heavy cream ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ cup ; sugar, divided ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ pod ; vanilla bean, slit down the middle (or 1 teaspoon vanilla extract, added while cooling) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 ; large egg yolks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 cup ; strawberry, hulled and quartered ; (150 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">⅓ cup ; sugar, plus 4 tablespoons sugar, divided ; (65 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 tablespoon ; butter, softened </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">4 ; large egg whites </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¼ teaspoon ; cream of tartar </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">1 pinch ; salt </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">French</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="5">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="6">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/99203/hls24_1529434654.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/99203/landscape_720/1529434654</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C) </step>
    <step num="1">Prepare an ice bath and place a strainer over a medium bowl. Set nearby. </step>
    <step num="2">Make the crème anglaise: In a small saucepan, heat the milk, heavy cream, ¼ cup (50 g) of sugar, and the vanilla bean pod over medium heat for 2-3 minutes, until it begins to steam. Remove the pan from the heat. </step>
    <step num="3">In a medium bowl, combine the egg yolks, remaining ¼ cup (50 g) of sugar, and the salt and whisk together. Continue whisking and ladle in the milk mixture. Once combined, return the saucepan to medium heat, begin to whisk the milk mixture, and slowly pour in the egg mixture. </step>
    <step num="4">Cook the custard, continuously whisking to ensure the egg yolks don’t cook on the bottom, for about 5 minutes, until it coats the the back of a spoon. </step>
    <step num="5">Set the bowl with the strainer in the ice bath and strain the creme into the bowl. Whisk until cooled, about 5 minutes. Cover and refrigerate until ready to serve. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the strawberries, 2 tablespoons of sugar, and the lemon juice to a small saucepan. Cook over medium heat for about 5 minutes, stirring occasionally, until the strawberries are softened but still vibrant red. Remove the pan from the heat. </step>
    <step num="7">Strain the strawberry mixture through a fine-mesh sieve into a medium bowl. Use a spatula to press the berries through, making a strawberry puree. Discard the pulp and set the puree in the refrigerator to cool. </step>
    <step num="8">Set 6 ramekins on a baking sheet and coat the insides with the softened butter. Sprinkle 2 tablespoons of sugar among the ramekins and shake each to coat the bottom and sides with sugar. </step>
    <step num="9">Add the egg whites, cream of tartar, and salt to a large bowl. Using an electric hand mixer, beat the whites on medium-high speed until foamy. Add the remaining ⅓ cup (65 g) of sugar in small increments, continuing to beat until the whites are stiff and glossy. </step>
    <step num="10">Using a spatula, carefully fold in the strawberry puree. </step>
    <step num="11">Fill each ramekin with the strawberry-egg white mixture and level off the tops with a butter knife. Run a clean thumb around the inside edge of each ramekin to allow the soufflés to rise properly. </step>
    <step num="12">Bake the soufflés for 10-12 minutes, until the tops are light brown. Avoid opening the oven prematurely, so the soufflés don’t fall. </step>
    <step num="13">Serve the soufflés immediately with the crème anglaise poured over the top. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 400˚F (200˚C) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Prepare an ice bath and place a strainer over a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Set nearby. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Make the crème anglaise: In a small saucepan, heat the milk, heavy cream, ¼ cup (50 g) of sugar, and the vanilla bean pod over medium heat for 2-3 minutes, until it begins to steam. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Remove the pan from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In a medium bowl, combine the egg yolks, remaining ¼ cup (50 g) of sugar, and the salt and whisk together. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Continue whisking and ladle in the milk mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Once combined, return the saucepan to medium heat, begin to whisk the milk mixture, and slowly pour in the egg mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Cook the custard, continuously whisking to ensure the egg yolks don’t cook on the bottom, for about 5 minutes, until it coats the the back of a spoon. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Set the bowl with the strainer in the ice bath and strain the creme into the bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Whisk until cooled, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Cover and refrigerate until ready to serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add the strawberries, 2 tablespoons of sugar, and the lemon juice to a small saucepan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Cook over medium heat for about 5 minutes, stirring occasionally, until the strawberries are softened but still vibrant red. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Remove the pan from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Strain the strawberry mixture through a fine-mesh sieve into a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Use a spatula to press the berries through, making a strawberry puree. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Discard the pulp and set the puree in the refrigerator to cool. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Set 6 ramekins on a baking sheet and coat the insides with the softened butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Sprinkle 2 tablespoons of sugar among the ramekins and shake each to coat the bottom and sides with sugar. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Add the egg whites, cream of tartar, and salt to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Using an electric hand mixer, beat the whites on medium-high speed until foamy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Add the remaining ⅓ cup (65 g) of sugar in small increments, continuing to beat until the whites are stiff and glossy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Using a spatula, carefully fold in the strawberry puree. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Fill each ramekin with the strawberry-egg white mixture and level off the tops with a butter knife. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Run a clean thumb around the inside edge of each ramekin to allow the soufflés to rise properly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Bake the soufflés for 10-12 minutes, until the tops are light brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Avoid opening the oven prematurely, so the soufflés don’t fall. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Serve the soufflés immediately with the crème anglaise poured over the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>