<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Sweet Potato Guerrilla Tacos Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/sweet-potato-guerrilla-tacos</url>
  <type>compilation</type>
  <comp_url>https://tasty.co/compilation/sweet-potato-guerrilla-tacos-with-almond-salsa</comp_url>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ lb ; sweet potato, preferably japanese, diced ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 bottle ; white wine </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">5 sprigs ; fresh thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">5 sprigs ; fresh parsley </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">2 ; leeks </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 tablespoons ; butter, melted </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">3 cloves ; garlic </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">12 ; corn tortillas </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">12 oz ; oaxacan cheese, or panela cheese ; (350 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">½ cup ; feta cheese, crumbled ; (110 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">¼ cup ; toasted pine nut, or slivered almonds ; (35 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">1 cup ; scallion, green parts only, thinly sliced ; (100 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Mexican</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Weeknight</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/14751/low_1479233437.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/14751/mp4_720x1280/1479233437</high>
  </video>
  <duration>
    <start_time>0</start_time>
    <end_time>67.2</end_time>
  </duration>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat oven to 425°F (220°C). </step>
    <step num="1">Trim and discard the tough green parts from the leeks, then cut them in in half lengthwise. Swirl in water to remove any sand. Pat dry. </step>
    <step num="2">On a large baking tray, place the leeks, sweet potatoes and garlic. Pour melted butter and salt evenly over the vegetables. </step>
    <step num="3">Bake for 25 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">In a large saucepan, bring the white wine, thyme and parsley to a boil and cook until it loses the raw alcohol smell, about 5 minutes. Reduce the heat to a bare simmer. </step>
    <step num="5">When the leeks are golden take both leeks and garlic off the tray. Place potatoes back in the oven for another 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="6">Add leeks and garlic into the simmering wine sauce. Cook until leeks are tender, about 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Melt 2 tablespoons butter in a nonstick skillet over medium-high heat. Pull the leeks from the cooking liquid, pat them dry and add to the butter to cook briefly on both sides, about 3 minutes total. </step>
    <step num="8">Remove the stem ends from the leeks and cut into 2-inch (5 cm) lengths. </step>
    <step num="9">For each taco, heat 2 tortillas on a griddle or in a large skillet over medium-high heat with a little butter. Place 2 slices of Oaxaca cheese next to them on the griddle. When the tortillas are warmed through, stack them on top of the cheese. </step>
    <step num="10">When the cheese has browned on one side, remove the tortillas and cheese to a plate, cheese-side up. </step>
    <step num="11">Add 2 to 3 strips of leek and some sweet potato. Spoon over 1½ to 2 teaspoons salsa and sprinkle with 2 teaspoons crumbled feta, a few toasted pine nuts, and 1 teaspoon minced green onions and serve immediately. Repeat using the remaining ingredients. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat oven to 425°F (220°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Trim and discard the tough green parts from the leeks, then cut them in in half lengthwise. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Swirl in water to remove any sand. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Pat dry. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">On a large baking tray, place the leeks, sweet potatoes and garlic. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Pour melted butter and salt evenly over the vegetables. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Bake for 25 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">In a large saucepan, bring the white wine, thyme and parsley to a boil and cook until it loses the raw alcohol smell, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Reduce the heat to a bare simmer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">When the leeks are golden take both leeks and garlic off the tray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place potatoes back in the oven for another 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add leeks and garlic into the simmering wine sauce. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cook until leeks are tender, about 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Melt 2 tablespoons butter in a nonstick skillet over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Pull the leeks from the cooking liquid, pat them dry and add to the butter to cook briefly on both sides, about 3 minutes total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Remove the stem ends from the leeks and cut into 2-inch (5 cm) lengths. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">For each taco, heat 2 tortillas on a griddle or in a large skillet over medium-high heat with a little butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Place 2 slices of Oaxaca cheese next to them on the griddle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">When the tortillas are warmed through, stack them on top of the cheese. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">When the cheese has browned on one side, remove the tortillas and cheese to a plate, cheese-side up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Add 2 to 3 strips of leek and some sweet potato. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Spoon over 1½ to 2 teaspoons salsa and sprinkle with 2 teaspoons crumbled feta, a few toasted pine nuts, and 1 teaspoon minced green onions and serve immediately. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Repeat using the remaining ingredients. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>