<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Homemade Vegetable Stock Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/homemade-vegetable-stock</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">onion, tops,bottoms, and skins </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">celery, tops and bottoms </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">carrot, tops, bottoms, and skins </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">mushroom stems </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">garlic, tops, bottoms, and skins </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">potato, tops, bottoms, and skins </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">fresh parsley stems </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">water, as needed </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Vegan</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129583/hls24_1554916152.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/129583/landscape_720/1554916152</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Reserve any parts that you are trimming off or peeling away (including tops, bottoms, skins, and stems) from the vegetables and herbs suggested above. (Avoid scraps from vegetables like Brussels sprouts, broccoli, or cauliflower, as their strong flavors can overpower your stock.) Place the scraps in a one-gallon airtight storage container, and keep them in the freezer for up to six months. You can add many other vegetable and herb scraps, including corn cobs, winter squash, zucchini, summer squash, beet greens, fennel fronds, chard stems, lettuce, parsnips, green beans, pea pods, bell peppers, eggplant, asparagus, and herbs like dill, thyme, parsley, cilantro, and basil. </step>
    <step num="1">Keep adding scraps until the storage container is full. </step>
    <step num="2">Transfer the contents of the container into a large pot and fill three-quarters of the pot (or until the scraps just start to float) with water. </step>
    <step num="3">Bring water to a boil and then let it simmer for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="4">Using a sieve, strain the stock to remove the solids. Let stock cool completely. </step>
    <step num="5">Stock can be refrigerated in an airtight container for up to 4 days, or frozen for up to 3 months. </step>
    <step num="6">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Reserve any parts that you are trimming off or peeling away (including tops, bottoms, skins, and stems) from the vegetables and herbs suggested above. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">(Avoid scraps from vegetables like Brussels sprouts, broccoli, or cauliflower, as their strong flavors can overpower your stock.) Place the scraps in a one-gallon airtight storage container, and keep them in the freezer for up to six months. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">You can add many other vegetable and herb scraps, including corn cobs, winter squash, zucchini, summer squash, beet greens, fennel fronds, chard stems, lettuce, parsnips, green beans, pea pods, bell peppers, eggplant, asparagus, and herbs like dill, thyme, parsley, cilantro, and basil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Keep adding scraps until the storage container is full. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Transfer the contents of the container into a large pot and fill three-quarters of the pot (or until the scraps just start to float) with water. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Bring water to a boil and then let it simmer for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Using a sieve, strain the stock to remove the solids. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Let stock cool completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Stock can be refrigerated in an airtight container for up to 4 days, or frozen for up to 3 months. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>