<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Cod With Confetti Coconut Rice Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/cod-with-confetti-coconut-rice</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; basmati rice, rinsed ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; red bell pepper, finely chopped, seeds and ribs removed ; (25 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">¼ cup ; carrot, finely chopped ; (30 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ cup ; jalapeño, seeded and minced ; (25 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">4 teaspoons ; salt, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">Thai Kitchen® coconut milk, 1 can </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">¼ cup ; water ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">24 oz ; cod fillets, pacific ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ teaspoon ; ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; dried cilantro leaves </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">1 tablespoon ; vegetable oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">Lime wedges, for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Seafood</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
    <category num="2">Date Night</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
    <category num="4">Pescatarian</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/125464/hls24_1550865305.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/125464/landscape_720/1550865305</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">In a medium saucepan, combine the rice, bell pepper, carrots, jalapeño, 2 teaspoons salt, Thai Kitchen coconut milk, and water, then stir to combine. Turn the heat to medium-high and bring to a boil. Cover, reduce the heat to low, and simmer for 10–12 minutes or until the rice is tender and the liquid has been absorbed. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large skillet, heat the vegetable oil over medium-high heat. Once the oil is almost smoking, lay each fillet in the pan. Sear until fish releases from pan with ease and is golden brown, about 5 minutes. Using a fish spatula, flip each fillet and sear on the other side until cooked through, about 3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">To serve, scoop rice onto each plate and top with a cod fillet. Serve with lime wedges. </step>
    <step num="3">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">In a medium saucepan, combine the rice, bell pepper, carrots, jalapeño, 2 teaspoons salt, Thai Kitchen coconut milk, and water, then stir to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Turn the heat to medium-high and bring to a boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cover, reduce the heat to low, and simmer for 10–12 minutes or until the rice is tender and the liquid has been absorbed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a large skillet, heat the vegetable oil over medium-high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Once the oil is almost smoking, lay each fillet in the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Sear until fish releases from pan with ease and is golden brown, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Using a fish spatula, flip each fillet and sear on the other side until cooked through, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">To serve, scoop rice onto each plate and top with a cod fillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Serve with lime wedges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>