<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Ice Cream Sandwich Swirl Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/ice-cream-sandwich-swirl-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">18 slices ; sandwich bread, crusts removed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">¼ cup ; unsalted butter, 1/2 stick, melted ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; chocolate hazelnut spread, divided ; (225 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">3 cups ; vanilla ice cream, softened ; (455 g) </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="3">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="4">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/99531/hls24_1529602996.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/99531/landscape_720/1529602996</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">On a large cutting board, lay out 9 slices of bread in a 3x3 (7x7 cm) grid. Brush the melted butter where the bread slices will touch, then overlap the bread pieces until you have one large square of bread. </step>
    <step num="1">Cover with another cutting board and a heavy pan to weigh it down and let sit for 10 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Remove the pan and cutting board and roll the square with a rolling pin to flatten. </step>
    <step num="3">Pour half of the hazelnut spread on the sheet of bread and spread evenly, leaving a 1-inch (1 cm) gap around the edges. </step>
    <step num="4">Starting at the bottom, carefully roll up the bread to form a log and wrap in plastic wrap. </step>
    <step num="5">Using the remaining 9 slices of bread and remaining hazelnut spread, make another log. </step>
    <step num="6">Freeze for 20 minutes. </step>
    <step num="7">Slice the chilled logs into ½-inch (1 cm) thick rounds. There will be about 18 slices per log. </step>
    <step num="8">Place the rolls from 1 log in a parchment-lined 10-inch (25-cm) springform pan. Slice any extra rolls into smaller pieces to fill in the gaps between the whole rolls. </step>
    <step num="9">Place a sheet of parchment on top of the rolls and use a smaller cake pan to press the rolls together, creating a compressed layer. Remove the cake pan and parchment and freeze until solid, about 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="10">Scoop softened ice cream on top of the rolls and spread evenly. Freeze until solid, about 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="11">Add another layer of rolls from the second log on top of the ice cream layer, filling the gaps with smaller pieces of rolls again. Place a sheet of parchment paper on top and use the smaller cake pan to compress the rolls. Remove the pan and parchment and freeze for another hour. </step>
    <step num="12">Remove from the springform pan, slice, and serve. </step>
    <step num="13">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">On a large cutting board, lay out 9 slices of bread in a 3x3 (7x7 cm) grid. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Brush the melted butter where the bread slices will touch, then overlap the bread pieces until you have one large square of bread. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Cover with another cutting board and a heavy pan to weigh it down and let sit for 10 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Remove the pan and cutting board and roll the square with a rolling pin to flatten. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Pour half of the hazelnut spread on the sheet of bread and spread evenly, leaving a 1-inch (1 cm) gap around the edges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Starting at the bottom, carefully roll up the bread to form a log and wrap in plastic wrap. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Using the remaining 9 slices of bread and remaining hazelnut spread, make another log. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Freeze for 20 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Slice the chilled logs into ½-inch (1 cm) thick rounds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">There will be about 18 slices per log. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Place the rolls from 1 log in a parchment-lined 10-inch (25-cm) springform pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Slice any extra rolls into smaller pieces to fill in the gaps between the whole rolls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Place a sheet of parchment on top of the rolls and use a smaller cake pan to press the rolls together, creating a compressed layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Remove the cake pan and parchment and freeze until solid, about 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Scoop softened ice cream on top of the rolls and spread evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Freeze until solid, about 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add another layer of rolls from the second log on top of the ice cream layer, filling the gaps with smaller pieces of rolls again. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Place a sheet of parchment paper on top and use the smaller cake pan to compress the rolls. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Remove the pan and parchment and freeze for another hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Remove from the springform pan, slice, and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>