<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Rib Eye Steak With Blue Cheese Compound Butter And Crispy Onion Strings Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/rib-eye-steak-with-blue-cheese-compound-butter-and-crispy-onion-strings</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 cup ; unsalted butter, room temperature ; (125 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 cup ; crumbled blue cheese ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">2 tablespoons ; chives, finely chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¼ teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">¼ teaspoon ; freshly ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ ; medium yellow onion, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; buttermilk ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; paprika </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt, plus more to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">½ teaspoon ; freshly ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">4 cups ; canola oil, for frying ; (960 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">2 ; rib eye steaks, 1 1/2 in (3 cm) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">1 tablespoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">1 tablespoon ; freshly ground black pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">2 teaspoons ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="16">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="17">5 sprigs ; fresh thyme </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="1">Dinner</category>
    <category num="2">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/135613/hls24_1560284586.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/135613/landscape_720/1560284586</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Make the compound butter: In a medium bowl, mix together the butter, blue cheese, chives, salt, and pepper until well combined. </step>
    <step num="1">Transfer the butter to a piece of plastic wrap and roll into a log. Refrigerate for at least 1 hour, or until ready to use. </step>
    <step num="2">Make the fried onions: In a shallow bowl, combine the onions and buttermilk and let sit at room temperature for 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="3">In a medium bowl, whisk together the flour, paprika, salt, and pepper. Dip the buttermilk-coated onions into the flour mixture, shaking off any excess. </step>
    <step num="4">Fill a large skillet with high sides with the canola oil. Heat the oil over medium-high heat until it reaches 375˚F (190˚C). Once the oil is hot, add the onions in batches and fry for 3 minutes, until golden brown. Transfer the onions to a wire rack to drain and season with salt. </step>
    <step num="5">Generously season the steaks all over with salt and pepper. </step>
    <step num="6">Add the olive oil to a large cast-iron or stainless-steel pan over high heat. Once the oil begins to shimmer, add the steaks and cook, without disturbing, until a brown crust forms, about 7 minutes. Flip the steaks and continue to cook for 7 minutes more, until the steak is browned on both sides. Sear the sides of the steak to render any fat. Add the butter and thyme to the pan. Tilt the pan toward you and baste the steaks with the melted butter for 2 minutes, until the internal temperature reaches 135°F (60°C) for medium rare. </step>
    <step num="7">Serve the steak with the crispy onions and blue cheese compound butter. </step>
    <step num="8">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Make the compound butter: In a medium bowl, mix together the butter, blue cheese, chives, salt, and pepper until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Transfer the butter to a piece of plastic wrap and roll into a log. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Refrigerate for at least 1 hour, or until ready to use. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Make the fried onions: In a shallow bowl, combine the onions and buttermilk and let sit at room temperature for 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">In a medium bowl, whisk together the flour, paprika, salt, and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Dip the buttermilk-coated onions into the flour mixture, shaking off any excess. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Fill a large skillet with high sides with the canola oil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Heat the oil over medium-high heat until it reaches 375˚F (190˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Once the oil is hot, add the onions in batches and fry for 3 minutes, until golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Transfer the onions to a wire rack to drain and season with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Generously season the steaks all over with salt and pepper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add the olive oil to a large cast-iron or stainless-steel pan over high heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Once the oil begins to shimmer, add the steaks and cook, without disturbing, until a brown crust forms, about 7 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Flip the steaks and continue to cook for 7 minutes more, until the steak is browned on both sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Sear the sides of the steak to render any fat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the butter and thyme to the pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Tilt the pan toward you and baste the steaks with the melted butter for 2 minutes, until the internal temperature reaches 135°F (60°C) for medium rare. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Serve the steak with the crispy onions and blue cheese compound butter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>