<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Lemon Bundt Cake</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/lemon-bundt-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">3 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (375 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">2 teaspoons ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; unsalted butter, 2 sticks, room temperature ; (230 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 cups ; granulated sugar ; (400 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 teaspoon ; kosher salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">3 ; large eggs, room temperature </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 tablespoons ; lemon zest </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">¼ cup ; lemon juice ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 cup ; whole milk ; (240 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">nonstick cooking spray, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">½ cup ; granulated sugar ; (100 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">¼ cup ; lemon juice ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">2 cups ; powdered sugar, sifted ; (240 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">3 tablespoons ; lemon juice </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="15">1 ; lemon, zested </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="3">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117197/hls24_1543445513.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/117197/landscape_720/1543445513</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </step>
    <step num="1">Make the cake: In a medium bowl, whisk together the flour and baking powder. </step>
    <step num="2">In a large bowl, cream the butter, sugar, and salt with an electric hand mixer until fluffy, about 3 minutes. Add the eggs, one at a time, beating until fully incorporated before adding the next. Add the lemon zest, lemon juice, and vanilla and beat to combine. </step>
    <step num="3">Add half the flour and beat to combine, then beat in the milk, then add the rest of the flour and beat just until incorporated. Scrape down the sides of the bowl with a rubber spatula and make sure any floury spots are incorporated. </step>
    <step num="4">Grease a 10-inch (25-cm) bundt pan with nonstick spray. Spoon the batter into the pan and smooth the top. Gently tap the pan against the counter to release any air bubbles. </step>
    <step num="5">Bake the cake for 50 minutes, until a toothpick inserted in the center comes out clean. </step>
    <step num="6">While the cake is baking, make the lemon glaze: In a small microwave-safe bowl, combine the sugar and lemon juice. Microwave for 1 minute, stirring halfway through, until the sugar is completely dissolved. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="7">Make the lemon icing: Sift the powdered sugar into a medium bowl. Add the lemon juice and whisk until smooth. </step>
    <step num="8">After the cake is done baking, let cool in the pan for 10 minutes, then invert onto a wire rack set over a baking sheet and remove the bundt pan. Use a knife to loosen the cake around the edges, if needed. </step>
    <step num="9">Use a skewer or fork to poke holes all over the top and sides of the cake. Brush the cake with the lemon glaze. If the glaze drips off, let the cake cool for a few more minutes, then continue brushing on the glaze. Let cool completely, at least 1 hour. </step>
    <step num="10">Pour the icing over the top of the cake, letting it drip down the sides. Grate lemon zest over the icing. Let the glaze dry completely, about 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="11">Transfer the cake to a serving platter, slice, and serve. </step>
    <step num="12">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 350˚F (180˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Make the cake: In a medium bowl, whisk together the flour and baking powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a large bowl, cream the butter, sugar, and salt with an electric hand mixer until fluffy, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the eggs, one at a time, beating until fully incorporated before adding the next. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the lemon zest, lemon juice, and vanilla and beat to combine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add half the flour and beat to combine, then beat in the milk, then add the rest of the flour and beat just until incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Scrape down the sides of the bowl with a rubber spatula and make sure any floury spots are incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Grease a 10-inch (25-cm) bundt pan with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Spoon the batter into the pan and smooth the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Gently tap the pan against the counter to release any air bubbles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Bake the cake for 50 minutes, until a toothpick inserted in the center comes out clean. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">While the cake is baking, make the lemon glaze: In a small microwave-safe bowl, combine the sugar and lemon juice. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Microwave for 1 minute, stirring halfway through, until the sugar is completely dissolved. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Make the lemon icing: Sift the powdered sugar into a medium bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Add the lemon juice and whisk until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">After the cake is done baking, let cool in the pan for 10 minutes, then invert onto a wire rack set over a baking sheet and remove the bundt pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Use a knife to loosen the cake around the edges, if needed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Use a skewer or fork to poke holes all over the top and sides of the cake. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Brush the cake with the lemon glaze. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">If the glaze drips off, let the cake cool for a few more minutes, then continue brushing on the glaze. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Let cool completely, at least 1 hour. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Pour the icing over the top of the cake, letting it drip down the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Grate lemon zest over the icing. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Let the glaze dry completely, about 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Transfer the cake to a serving platter, slice, and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>