<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Creamy Tomato Basil Zucchini “Linguini” Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/creamy-tomato-basil-zucchini-linguini</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 tablespoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ; chicken breast, diced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; cherry tomatoes, halved ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ teaspoon ; pepper </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ teaspoon ; garlic powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">1 teaspoon ; dried basil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">2 ; zucchinis, peeled </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">1 teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">1 tablespoon ; olive oil </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 cloves ; garlic, minced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">¼ cup ; chicken broth ; (60 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">½ cup ; greek yogurt ; (140 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="13">½ cup ; parmesan cheese, grated ; (55 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="14">½ teaspoon ; dried basil </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Italian</category>
    <category num="2">Healthy</category>
    <category num="3">Dinner</category>
    <category num="4">Weeknight</category>
    <category num="5">Fusion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/22222/low_1485481933.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/22222/mp4_720x1280/1485481933</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Use a peeler to thinly slice zucchini into “linguini” noodles. Set aside in a bowl and mix with salt. Let sit for 20 minutes to draw moisture out of the noodles. Drain the zucchini with a clean dish cloth or paper towels. </step>
    <step num="1">Heat olive oil in a large skillet. Add in chicken breast, salt, pepper, and garlic powder. Cook until no longer pink. Add in zucchini noodles, cherry tomatoes, and dried basil. Cook for an additional minute and remove from heat. Set aside in a bowl. </step>
    <step num="2">Heat olive oil for for the creamy sauce in the skillet. Add in garlic cloves and cook for about 30 seconds. Add in chicken broth to cool skillet, and reduce heat to low. (This step is important: if skillet is too hot, the Greek yogurt will curdle, so allow it to cool down before adding it in). </step>
    <step num="3">Add in Greek yogurt, parmesan, and dried basil. Mix until well combined. Add in the chicken, zoodles, and tomato mixture. Mix together and then remove from heat. </step>
    <step num="4">Serve and garnish with fresh chopped basil, as desired. </step>
    <step num="5">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Use a peeler to thinly slice zucchini into “linguini” noodles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Set aside in a bowl and mix with salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Let sit for 20 minutes to draw moisture out of the noodles. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Drain the zucchini with a clean dish cloth or paper towels. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Heat olive oil in a large skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Add in chicken breast, salt, pepper, and garlic powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cook until no longer pink. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add in zucchini noodles, cherry tomatoes, and dried basil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Cook for an additional minute and remove from heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Set aside in a bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Heat olive oil for for the creamy sauce in the skillet. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Add in garlic cloves and cook for about 30 seconds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add in chicken broth to cool skillet, and reduce heat to low. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">(This step is important: if skillet is too hot, the Greek yogurt will curdle, so allow it to cool down before adding it in). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Add in Greek yogurt, parmesan, and dried basil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Mix until well combined. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add in the chicken, zoodles, and tomato mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Mix together and then remove from heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Serve and garnish with fresh chopped basil, as desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>