<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Rosé Gummy Bears Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/rose-gummy-bears</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 cups ; rosé, divided ; (480 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">⅓ cup ; unflavored gelatin powder, (about 5 .25-ounce envelopes) ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 cup ; sugar ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">1 drop ; pink food coloring, optional </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">gummy bear mold, optional </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Dairy-Free</category>
    <category num="1">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="2">Snacks</category>
    <category num="3">Happy Hour</category>
    <category num="4">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97756/hls24_1528414131.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/97756/landscape_720/1528414131</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Place 1 cup of rosé (240 ml) in a small saucepan over medium heat. Bring to a simmer and cook until reduced by half, about 5 minutes. Remove the pan from the heat. </step>
    <step num="1">In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, combine the gelatin powder and remaining rosé wine. Let sit for 5 minutes. The gelatin should give off a “blooming” effect, thickening the mixture. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the gelatin mixture to the saucepan with the concentrated rosé. Add the sugar and return the pan to medium-low heat, whisking continuously. Do not let the mixture boil. Cook until the gelatin is dissolved, about 5 minutes. The mixture should have a syrupy consistency, similar to maple syrup. Remove the pan from the heat. Add a drop of pink food coloring, if desired. </step>
    <step num="3">Use a squeeze bottle, spouted measuring cup, or dropper to distribute the mixture into the gummy bear molds. If you don’t have a gummy bear mold, pour the mixture into a parchment-lined, 8-inch (20 cm), square baking pan. </step>
    <step num="4">Refrigerate for 90 minutes, or until set. </step>
    <step num="5">Carefully pop the bears out of the molds or, if using a baking pan, cut into small squares with a pizza cutter. </step>
    <step num="6">Store in airtight container in the refrigerator for up to 2 weeks. </step>
    <step num="7">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Place 1 cup of rosé (240 ml) in a small saucepan over medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Bring to a simmer and cook until reduced by half, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Remove the pan from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">In a liquid measuring cup or small bowl, combine the gelatin powder and remaining rosé wine. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Let sit for 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">The gelatin should give off a “blooming” effect, thickening the mixture. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the gelatin mixture to the saucepan with the concentrated rosé. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Add the sugar and return the pan to medium-low heat, whisking continuously. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Do not let the mixture boil. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Cook until the gelatin is dissolved, about 5 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">The mixture should have a syrupy consistency, similar to maple syrup. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Remove the pan from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Add a drop of pink food coloring, if desired. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Use a squeeze bottle, spouted measuring cup, or dropper to distribute the mixture into the gummy bear molds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">If you don’t have a gummy bear mold, pour the mixture into a parchment-lined, 8-inch (20 cm), square baking pan. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Refrigerate for 90 minutes, or until set. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Carefully pop the bears out of the molds or, if using a baking pan, cut into small squares with a pizza cutter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Store in airtight container in the refrigerator for up to 2 weeks. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>