<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Stuffed Hash Brown Omelette Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/stuffed-hash-brown-omelette</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 tablespoons ; butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">½ ; yellow onion, thinly sliced </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">½ ; red pepper, sliced into strips </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">2 cups ; spinach ; (450 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">1 ½ cups ; frozen hash brown ; (215 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ cup ; shredded cheddar cheese ; (50 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">salt, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">pepper, to taste </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">chipotle sour cream, optional for garnish </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">scallion, chopped, optional for garnish </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Gluten-Free</category>
    <category num="3">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="4">Breakfast</category>
    <category num="5">Brunch</category>
    <category num="6">Kid-Friendly</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31935/low_1495124904.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/31935/mp4_720x1280/1495124904</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Take your hash browns out of the freezer to allow them to begin to thaw. </step>
    <step num="1">In an eight-inch nonstick pan, melt one Tbsp. of butter on medium heat and add onions, occasionally stirring. Allow to cook until they have softened and begin to brown. Add the peppers, stir, and salt to taste. Cook until they begin to soften. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the spinach and allow it to wilt for a couple of minutes. Transfer this filling to a bowl. </step>
    <step num="3">Put your pan back on the heat and add one Tbsp. of butter, melting on medium heat. Add your hash browns and season with salt and pepper to taste, stirring until the butter and seasoning are evenly distributed. </step>
    <step num="4">Arrange the potatoes in a flat even layer. Sprinkle cheese evenly on top and allow it to melt. Then, sprinkle the filling evenly on top. When the bottom of the hash browns has crisped up and browned, your hash brown omelette is ready. </step>
    <step num="5">Shake the pan to make sure it’s not sticking to the bottom, then bring it over to your plate and carefully tilt the pan, using the edge to help fold it over in half. </step>
    <step num="6">Add your favorite toppings and enjoy! (We used chopped scallions and a chipotle sour cream.) </step>
    <step num="7">For the chipotle sour cream: </step>
    <step num="8">Combine ½ cup sour cream or crema, one Tbsp. chipotle in adobo (finely chopped), a pinch of salt, and a splash of water to thin it out. </step>
    <step num="9">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Take your hash browns out of the freezer to allow them to begin to thaw. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">In an eight-inch nonstick pan, melt one Tbsp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">of butter on medium heat and add onions, occasionally stirring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Allow to cook until they have softened and begin to brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Add the peppers, stir, and salt to taste. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cook until they begin to soften. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the spinach and allow it to wilt for a couple of minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Transfer this filling to a bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Put your pan back on the heat and add one Tbsp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">of butter, melting on medium heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Add your hash browns and season with salt and pepper to taste, stirring until the butter and seasoning are evenly distributed. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Arrange the potatoes in a flat even layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Sprinkle cheese evenly on top and allow it to melt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Then, sprinkle the filling evenly on top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">When the bottom of the hash browns has crisped up and browned, your hash brown omelette is ready. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Shake the pan to make sure it’s not sticking to the bottom, then bring it over to your plate and carefully tilt the pan, using the edge to help fold it over in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Add your favorite toppings and enjoy! </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">(We used chopped scallions and a chipotle sour cream.) </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">For the chipotle sour cream: </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Combine ½ cup sour cream or crema, one Tbsp. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">chipotle in adobo (finely chopped), a pinch of salt, and a splash of water to thin it out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>