<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Vertical Layered Cookies &amp; Cream Cake Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/vertical-layered-cookies-cream-cake</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">10 ; large eggs, seperated </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">1 ¼ cups ; sugar, divided ; (250 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 teaspoon ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">¾ cup ; cake flour ; (90 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">½ cup ; cocoa powder, divided ; (60 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ teaspoon ; baking powder </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">24 oz ; cream cheese, room temperature ; (680 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">½ cup ; unsalted butter, 1 stick, room temperature ; (115 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">4 cups ; powdered sugar ; (640 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">2 teaspoons ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">15 ; chocolate sandwich cookies, crushed </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">5 ; chocolate sandwich cookies, halved </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="3">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="4">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="5">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/85168/hls24_1521233045.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/85168/landscape_720/1521233045</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). Line two baking sheets with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="1">In a large mixing bowl, beat the egg yolks with 1 cup (200 g) of sugar and the vanilla extract until pale and fluffy, about 3 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Sift in the flour, half of the cocoa powder, baking powder and salt. Mix until just combined, and set aside </step>
    <step num="3">In a separate large mixing bowl, using a hand mixer, beat the egg whites until soft peaks form. Add the remaining sugar and beat until stiff peaks form. </step>
    <step num="4">Beat a third of the egg whites into the chocolate mixture, then gently fold in the remaining egg whites. </step>
    <step num="5">Divide the batter between the two baking sheets. Spread evenly and bake for 10-12 minutes. Let cool at room temperature until the pans are cool to touch. </step>
    <step num="6">Dust the tops of the cakes with the remaining cocoa powder. Cover with parchment paper, and flip the cakes over to remove from the pans. </step>
    <step num="7">Carefully peel away the baked parchment paper and discard. Cut each cake in half vertically, then set aside. </step>
    <step num="8">In a large bowl, whip the cream cheese and butter until fluffy. Gradually incorporate the powdered sugar, then the vanilla extract. </step>
    <step num="9">Use a spatula to fold in the crushed cookies. </step>
    <step num="10">Evenly spread a thin layer of icing onto a cake quarter. </step>
    <step num="11">Starting from one short end, tightly roll the cake into a spiral. Repeat with the remaining cake layers, placing the rolled piece at the start of each new layer. </step>
    <step num="12">Wrap the cake tightly in plastic wrap and chill for at least an hour until icing in center is slightly firm. </step>
    <step num="13">Use the remaining icing to cover the cake and pipe small swirls on the top. Garnish the top with the sandwich cookie halves, and chill for at least an hour before serving. </step>
    <step num="14">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Preheat the oven to 400°F (200°C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Line two baking sheets with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">In a large mixing bowl, beat the egg yolks with 1 cup (200 g) of sugar and the vanilla extract until pale and fluffy, about 3 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Sift in the flour, half of the cocoa powder, baking powder and salt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Mix until just combined, and set aside </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">In a separate large mixing bowl, using a hand mixer, beat the egg whites until soft peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Add the remaining sugar and beat until stiff peaks form. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Beat a third of the egg whites into the chocolate mixture, then gently fold in the remaining egg whites. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Divide the batter between the two baking sheets. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Spread evenly and bake for 10-12 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Let cool at room temperature until the pans are cool to touch. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Dust the tops of the cakes with the remaining cocoa powder. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Cover with parchment paper, and flip the cakes over to remove from the pans. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Carefully peel away the baked parchment paper and discard. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Cut each cake in half vertically, then set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">In a large bowl, whip the cream cheese and butter until fluffy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Gradually incorporate the powdered sugar, then the vanilla extract. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Use a spatula to fold in the crushed cookies. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Evenly spread a thin layer of icing onto a cake quarter. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Starting from one short end, tightly roll the cake into a spiral. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Repeat with the remaining cake layers, placing the rolled piece at the start of each new layer. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Wrap the cake tightly in plastic wrap and chill for at least an hour until icing in center is slightly firm. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Use the remaining icing to cover the cake and pipe small swirls on the top. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Garnish the top with the sandwich cookie halves, and chill for at least an hour before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>