<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Double-Sided Sugar Cookies Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/double-sided-sugar-cookies</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">1 ½ cups ; unsalted butter, 3 sticks, softened ; (345 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">3 ¾ cups ; powdered sugar ; (450 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">1 ½ teaspoons ; vanilla extract </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">4 ; large eggs </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">5 cups ; all-purpose flour ; (625 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">½ teaspoon ; salt </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">10 drops ; yellow food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">10 drops ; red food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">10 drops ; blue food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">5 drops ; black food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">10 drops ; green food coloring </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="11">electric hand mixer </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="12">food-safe glove </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">American</category>
    <category num="1">Comfort Food</category>
    <category num="2">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="3">Desserts</category>
    <category num="4">Kid-Friendly</category>
    <category num="5">Casual Party</category>
    <category num="6">Indulgent Sweets</category>
    <category num="7">Bakery Goods</category>
    <category num="8">Special Occasion</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105697/hls24_1534522891.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105697/landscape_720/1534522891</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Add the butter, powdered sugar, and vanilla to a large bowl. Beat with an electric hand mixer on low speed until smooth and creamy. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the eggs 1 at a time and beat on medium speed to incorporate, scraping down the sides of the bowl with a spatula halfway through. </step>
    <step num="2">Add the salt and incorporate the flour in 3 additions, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed, until a dough forms. </step>
    <step num="3">Turn the dough out onto a clean, floured surface and form into a ball. Cut the ball of dough in half. Cut one of the halves in half, and the other half into thirds, so you have 5 pieces total. Take one of the larger pieces and cover the rest with plastic wrap so they don’t dry out. </step>
    <step num="4">Wearing gloves, add the yellow food coloring and knead into the dough until fully incorporated. Cover and set aside each piece of dough after working the color in. Dye the other large piece with red food coloring. Set aside one of the smaller pieces to remain plain. Remove a 1-tablespoon chunk from 1 of the 2 remaining pieces and dye with black food coloring. Dye the rest of that piece blue. Dye the remaining piece of dough green. </step>
    <step num="5">Roll out 1 tablespoon of the the plain dough into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) rope. Roll the rest into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) log and cut crosswise into thirds. Shape the logs into 6-inch-long (15-cm) triangle wedges. </step>
    <step num="6">Roll a third of the red dough into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) triangle wedge. </step>
    <step num="7">Roll the blue piece into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) triangle wedge. Roll half of the green dough into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) triangle wedge. </step>
    <step num="8">Form a beach ball shape by placing the plain rope in the middle and alternating the plain dough triangle wedges with the colored triangle wedges. Roll together to fuse, then wrap tightly in plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes while you assemble the other shape. </step>
    <step num="9">Roll the remaining red dough into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) log, then shape into a triangle wedge. </step>
    <step num="10">Roll the remaining green dough into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) log, then flatten. </step>
    <step num="11">Place the red triangle on top and trim the edges with a bench scraper or knife. </step>
    <step num="12">Cut the yellow dough in half. Set aside one half, then cut the other half in half again and roll into 2 6-inch-long (15-cm) logs and flatten slightly. Place the yellow pieces over each exposed side of the red dough, then pinch the yellow and green dough together to completely cover the red. Roll together to fuse, then wrap tightly in plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="13">Use a ruler and a knife to score ¼-inch (6 mm) marks across both chilled logs. Cut into slices with a sharp knife, cleaning the knife after each slice, if necessary. </step>
    <step num="14">Roll out the rest of the yellow dough to make a 6-inch (15-cm) by 12-inch (30-cm) rectangle. </step>
    <step num="15">Build a single dough log by stacking alternating watermelon slices and beach ball slices over the center of the yellow dough. Wrap the yellow dough around the log, roll together to fuse, then wrap tightly in plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </step>
    <step num="16">Preheat the oven to 300˚F (150˚C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </step>
    <step num="17">Use a ruler and a knife to score ¼-inch (6 mm) marks across the chilled dough. Cut into slices with a sharp knife, cleaning the knife after each slice, if necessary. Each slice should have a beach ball side and a strawberry side. </step>
    <step num="18">Set the cookies on the prepared baking sheet, strawberry-side up. Break off tiny pieces of the black dough, roll into seeds, and press onto the strawberries. </step>
    <step num="19">Bake the cookies for 10-12 minutes, or just until they begin to start turning golden brown. Cool on a wire rack for 5-10 minutes before serving. </step>
    <step num="20">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Add the butter, powdered sugar, and vanilla to a large bowl. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Beat with an electric hand mixer on low speed until smooth and creamy. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Add the eggs 1 at a time and beat on medium speed to incorporate, scraping down the sides of the bowl with a spatula halfway through. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the salt and incorporate the flour in 3 additions, scraping down the sides of the bowl as needed, until a dough forms. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Turn the dough out onto a clean, floured surface and form into a ball. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Cut the ball of dough in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Cut one of the halves in half, and the other half into thirds, so you have 5 pieces total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Take one of the larger pieces and cover the rest with plastic wrap so they don’t dry out. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Wearing gloves, add the yellow food coloring and knead into the dough until fully incorporated. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Cover and set aside each piece of dough after working the color in. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">Dye the other large piece with red food coloring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Set aside one of the smaller pieces to remain plain. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Remove a 1-tablespoon chunk from 1 of the 2 remaining pieces and dye with black food coloring. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Dye the rest of that piece blue. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">Dye the remaining piece of dough green. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Roll out 1 tablespoon of the the plain dough into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) rope. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Roll the rest into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) log and cut crosswise into thirds. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Shape the logs into 6-inch-long (15-cm) triangle wedges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Roll a third of the red dough into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) triangle wedge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Roll the blue piece into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) triangle wedge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Roll half of the green dough into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) triangle wedge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="21">Form a beach ball shape by placing the plain rope in the middle and alternating the plain dough triangle wedges with the colored triangle wedges. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="22">Roll together to fuse, then wrap tightly in plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes while you assemble the other shape. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="23">Roll the remaining red dough into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) log, then shape into a triangle wedge. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="24">Roll the remaining green dough into a 6-inch-long (15-cm) log, then flatten. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="25">Place the red triangle on top and trim the edges with a bench scraper or knife. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="26">Cut the yellow dough in half. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="27">Set aside one half, then cut the other half in half again and roll into 2 6-inch-long (15-cm) logs and flatten slightly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="28">Place the yellow pieces over each exposed side of the red dough, then pinch the yellow and green dough together to completely cover the red. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="29">Roll together to fuse, then wrap tightly in plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="30">Use a ruler and a knife to score ¼-inch (6 mm) marks across both chilled logs. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="31">Cut into slices with a sharp knife, cleaning the knife after each slice, if necessary. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="32">Roll out the rest of the yellow dough to make a 6-inch (15-cm) by 12-inch (30-cm) rectangle. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="33">Build a single dough log by stacking alternating watermelon slices and beach ball slices over the center of the yellow dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="34">Wrap the yellow dough around the log, roll together to fuse, then wrap tightly in plastic wrap and chill in the refrigerator for 30 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="35">Preheat the oven to 300˚F (150˚C). </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="36">Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="37">Use a ruler and a knife to score ¼-inch (6 mm) marks across the chilled dough. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="38">Cut into slices with a sharp knife, cleaning the knife after each slice, if necessary. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="39">Each slice should have a beach ball side and a strawberry side. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="40">Set the cookies on the prepared baking sheet, strawberry-side up. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="41">Break off tiny pieces of the black dough, roll into seeds, and press onto the strawberries. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="42">Bake the cookies for 10-12 minutes, or just until they begin to start turning golden brown. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="43">Cool on a wire rack for 5-10 minutes before serving. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="44">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>