<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<recipe>
  <title>Chocolate Peanut Butter Popcorn Pie Recipe by Tasty</title>
  <url>https://tasty.co/recipe/chocolate-peanut-butter-popcorn-pie</url>
  <type>single</type>
  <ingredients>
    <ingredient num="0">2 tablespoons ; unsalted butter </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="1">7 oz ; marshmallow ; (200 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="2">⅔ cup ; peanut butter, divided ; (160 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="3">8 cups ; popcorn, popped ; (80 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="4">nonstick cooking spray, for greasing </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="5">2 cups ; dark chocolate chip ; (350 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="6">2 cups ; milk chocolate chips ; (350 g) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="7">1 ½ cups ; heavy cream ; (360 mL) </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="8">4 tablespoons ; powdered sugar, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="9">2 teaspoons ; vanilla extract, divided </ingredient>
    <ingredient num="10">3 tablespoons ; milk </ingredient>
  </ingredients>
  <categories>
    <category num="0">Vegetarian</category>
    <category num="1">Desserts</category>
    <category num="2">Indulgent Sweets</category>
  </categories>
  <video>
    <low>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105595/hls24_1534438446.m3u8</low>
    <high>https://vid.tasty.co/output/105595/landscape_720/1534438446</high>
  </video>
  <steps>
    <step num="0">Melt the butter in a large pot over medium heat, then add the marshmallows and stir until starting to melt. Add ⅓ cup (80 g) of peanut butter and stir until completely melted. Remove the pot from the heat. </step>
    <step num="1">Add the popcorn to the pot and stir to coat completely. Let cool for 2 minutes. </step>
    <step num="2">Grease a 9-inch (23-cm) springform pan with nonstick spray. Press the popcorn mixture into the pan using the bottom of a measuring cup, creating an even layer along the bottom and halfway up the sides. Set aside. </step>
    <step num="3">Add the dark chocolate chips and milk chocolate chips to a medium bowl and melt in the microwave, stirring every 30 seconds, about 2 minutes total. Set aside to cool to room temperature. </step>
    <step num="4">In a separate medium bowl, whip the cream with an electric hand mixer until stiff peaks form, then add 3 tablespoons of powdered sugar and 1 teaspoon of vanilla and beat to incorporate. </step>
    <step num="5">Fold the whipped cream into the cooled chocolate. </step>
    <step num="6">Spoon the chocolate mixture into the popcorn crust. Spread evenly. </step>
    <step num="7">In a small bowl, combine the remaining ⅓ cup (80 g) peanut butter, 1 tablespoon powdered sugar, 1 teaspoon of vanilla, and the milk, stirring until smooth. Transfer to a small piping bag or zip-top bag. </step>
    <step num="8">Pipe lines across the surface of the pie. Drag a toothpick through, perpendicular to the lines, alternating directions from top to bottom. </step>
    <step num="9">Chill the pie in the refrigerator for at least 4 hours. </step>
    <step num="10">Release the springform, then slice and serve. </step>
    <step num="11">Enjoy! </step>
  </steps>
  <steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="0">Melt the butter in a large pot over medium heat, then add the marshmallows and stir until starting to melt. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="1">Add ⅓ cup (80 g) of peanut butter and stir until completely melted. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="2">Remove the pot from the heat. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="3">Add the popcorn to the pot and stir to coat completely. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="4">Let cool for 2 minutes. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="5">Grease a 9-inch (23-cm) springform pan with nonstick spray. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="6">Press the popcorn mixture into the pan using the bottom of a measuring cup, creating an even layer along the bottom and halfway up the sides. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="7">Set aside. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="8">Add the dark chocolate chips and milk chocolate chips to a medium bowl and melt in the microwave, stirring every 30 seconds, about 2 minutes total. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="9">Set aside to cool to room temperature. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="10">In a separate medium bowl, whip the cream with an electric hand mixer until stiff peaks form, then add 3 tablespoons of powdered sugar and 1 teaspoon of vanilla and beat to incorporate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="11">Fold the whipped cream into the cooled chocolate. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="12">Spoon the chocolate mixture into the popcorn crust. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="13">Spread evenly. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="14">In a small bowl, combine the remaining ⅓ cup (80 g) peanut butter, 1 tablespoon powdered sugar, 1 teaspoon of vanilla, and the milk, stirring until smooth. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="15">Transfer to a small piping bag or zip-top bag. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="16">Pipe lines across the surface of the pie. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="17">Drag a toothpick through, perpendicular to the lines, alternating directions from top to bottom. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="18">Chill the pie in the refrigerator for at least 4 hours. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="19">Release the springform, then slice and serve. </steps_updated>
    <steps_updated num="20">Enjoy! </steps_updated>
  </steps_updated>
</recipe>